"use strict";(self.webpackChunkseamen_mcq=self.webpackChunkseamen_mcq||[]).push([[179],{959:()=>{function Q(e){return"function"==typeof e}function za(e){const t=e(a=>{Error.call(a),a.stack=(new Error).stack});return t.prototype=Object.create(Error.prototype),t.prototype.constructor=t,t}const $a=za(e=>function(t){e(this),this.message=t?`${t.length} errors occurred during unsubscription:\n${t.map((a,n)=>`${n+1}) ${a.toString()}`).join("\n  ")}`:"",this.name="UnsubscriptionError",this.errors=t});function Jt(e,o){if(e){const t=e.indexOf(o);0<=t&&e.splice(t,1)}}class io{constructor(o){this.initialTeardown=o,this.closed=!1,this._parentage=null,this._teardowns=null}unsubscribe(){let o;if(!this.closed){this.closed=!0;const{_parentage:t}=this;if(t)if(this._parentage=null,Array.isArray(t))for(const s of t)s.remove(this);else t.remove(this);const{initialTeardown:a}=this;if(Q(a))try{a()}catch(s){o=s instanceof $a?s.errors:[s]}const{_teardowns:n}=this;if(n){this._teardowns=null;for(const s of n)try{Ll(s)}catch(i){o=null!=o?o:[],i instanceof $a?o=[...o,...i.errors]:o.push(i)}}if(o)throw new $a(o)}}add(o){var t;if(o&&o!==this)if(this.closed)Ll(o);else{if(o instanceof io){if(o.closed||o._hasParent(this))return;o._addParent(this)}(this._teardowns=null!==(t=this._teardowns)&&void 0!==t?t:[]).push(o)}}_hasParent(o){const{_parentage:t}=this;return t===o||Array.isArray(t)&&t.includes(o)}_addParent(o){const{_parentage:t}=this;this._parentage=Array.isArray(t)?(t.push(o),t):t?[t,o]:o}_removeParent(o){const{_parentage:t}=this;t===o?this._parentage=null:Array.isArray(t)&&Jt(t,o)}remove(o){const{_teardowns:t}=this;t&&Jt(t,o),o instanceof io&&o._removeParent(this)}}io.EMPTY=(()=>{const e=new io;return e.closed=!0,e})();const Rl=io.EMPTY;function Ml(e){return e instanceof io||e&&"closed"in e&&Q(e.remove)&&Q(e.add)&&Q(e.unsubscribe)}function Ll(e){Q(e)?e():e.unsubscribe()}const Uo={onUnhandledError:null,onStoppedNotification:null,Promise:void 0,useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling:!1,useDeprecatedNextContext:!1},Ka={setTimeout(...e){const{delegate:o}=Ka;return((null==o?void 0:o.setTimeout)||setTimeout)(...e)},clearTimeout(e){const{delegate:o}=Ka;return((null==o?void 0:o.clearTimeout)||clearTimeout)(e)},delegate:void 0};function xl(e){Ka.setTimeout(()=>{const{onUnhandledError:o}=Uo;if(!o)throw e;o(e)})}function Qa(){}const kf=bs("C",void 0,void 0);function bs(e,o,t){return{kind:e,value:o,error:t}}let jo=null;function Za(e){if(Uo.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling){const o=!jo;if(o&&(jo={errorThrown:!1,error:null}),e(),o){const{errorThrown:t,error:a}=jo;if(jo=null,t)throw a}}else e()}class ms extends io{constructor(o){super(),this.isStopped=!1,o?(this.destination=o,Ml(o)&&o.add(this)):this.destination=Df}static create(o,t,a){return new ws(o,t,a)}next(o){this.isStopped?vs(function Tf(e){return bs("N",e,void 0)}(o),this):this._next(o)}error(o){this.isStopped?vs(function qf(e){return bs("E",void 0,e)}(o),this):(this.isStopped=!0,this._error(o))}complete(){this.isStopped?vs(kf,this):(this.isStopped=!0,this._complete())}unsubscribe(){this.closed||(this.isStopped=!0,super.unsubscribe(),this.destination=null)}_next(o){this.destination.next(o)}_error(o){try{this.destination.error(o)}finally{this.unsubscribe()}}_complete(){try{this.destination.complete()}finally{this.unsubscribe()}}}class ws extends ms{constructor(o,t,a){let n;if(super(),Q(o))n=o;else if(o){let s;({next:n,error:t,complete:a}=o),this&&Uo.useDeprecatedNextContext?(s=Object.create(o),s.unsubscribe=()=>this.unsubscribe()):s=o,n=null==n?void 0:n.bind(s),t=null==t?void 0:t.bind(s),a=null==a?void 0:a.bind(s)}this.destination={next:n?ys(n):Qa,error:ys(null!=t?t:Fl),complete:a?ys(a):Qa}}}function ys(e,o){return(...t)=>{try{e(...t)}catch(a){Uo.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling?function Af(e){Uo.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling&&jo&&(jo.errorThrown=!0,jo.error=e)}(a):xl(a)}}}function Fl(e){throw e}function vs(e,o){const{onStoppedNotification:t}=Uo;t&&Ka.setTimeout(()=>t(e,o))}const Df={closed:!0,next:Qa,error:Fl,complete:Qa},ks="function"==typeof Symbol&&Symbol.observable||"@@observable";function Wl(e){return e}let qe=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){t&&(this._subscribe=t)}lift(t){const a=new e;return a.source=this,a.operator=t,a}subscribe(t,a,n){const s=function Sf(e){return e&&e instanceof ms||function Cf(e){return e&&Q(e.next)&&Q(e.error)&&Q(e.complete)}(e)&&Ml(e)}(t)?t:new ws(t,a,n);return Za(()=>{const{operator:i,source:r}=this;s.add(i?i.call(s,r):r?this._subscribe(s):this._trySubscribe(s))}),s}_trySubscribe(t){try{return this._subscribe(t)}catch(a){t.error(a)}}forEach(t,a){return new(a=Pl(a))((n,s)=>{let i;i=this.subscribe(r=>{try{t(r)}catch(l){s(l),null==i||i.unsubscribe()}},s,n)})}_subscribe(t){var a;return null===(a=this.source)||void 0===a?void 0:a.subscribe(t)}[ks](){return this}pipe(...t){return function Ol(e){return 0===e.length?Wl:1===e.length?e[0]:function(t){return e.reduce((a,n)=>n(a),t)}}(t)(this)}toPromise(t){return new(t=Pl(t))((a,n)=>{let s;this.subscribe(i=>s=i,i=>n(i),()=>a(s))})}}return e.create=o=>new e(o),e})();function Pl(e){var o;return null!==(o=null!=e?e:Uo.Promise)&&void 0!==o?o:Promise}const Ef=za(e=>function(){e(this),this.name="ObjectUnsubscribedError",this.message="object unsubscribed"});let qs=(()=>{class e extends qe{constructor(){super(),this.closed=!1,this.observers=[],this.isStopped=!1,this.hasError=!1,this.thrownError=null}lift(t){const a=new Nl(this,this);return a.operator=t,a}_throwIfClosed(){if(this.closed)throw new Ef}next(t){Za(()=>{if(this._throwIfClosed(),!this.isStopped){const a=this.observers.slice();for(const n of a)n.next(t)}})}error(t){Za(()=>{if(this._throwIfClosed(),!this.isStopped){this.hasError=this.isStopped=!0,this.thrownError=t;const{observers:a}=this;for(;a.length;)a.shift().error(t)}})}complete(){Za(()=>{if(this._throwIfClosed(),!this.isStopped){this.isStopped=!0;const{observers:t}=this;for(;t.length;)t.shift().complete()}})}unsubscribe(){this.isStopped=this.closed=!0,this.observers=null}get observed(){var t;return(null===(t=this.observers)||void 0===t?void 0:t.length)>0}_trySubscribe(t){return this._throwIfClosed(),super._trySubscribe(t)}_subscribe(t){return this._throwIfClosed(),this._checkFinalizedStatuses(t),this._innerSubscribe(t)}_innerSubscribe(t){const{hasError:a,isStopped:n,observers:s}=this;return a||n?Rl:(s.push(t),new io(()=>Jt(s,t)))}_checkFinalizedStatuses(t){const{hasError:a,thrownError:n,isStopped:s}=this;a?t.error(n):s&&t.complete()}asObservable(){const t=new qe;return t.source=this,t}}return e.create=(o,t)=>new Nl(o,t),e})();class Nl extends qs{constructor(o,t){super(),this.destination=o,this.source=t}next(o){var t,a;null===(a=null===(t=this.destination)||void 0===t?void 0:t.next)||void 0===a||a.call(t,o)}error(o){var t,a;null===(a=null===(t=this.destination)||void 0===t?void 0:t.error)||void 0===a||a.call(t,o)}complete(){var o,t;null===(t=null===(o=this.destination)||void 0===o?void 0:o.complete)||void 0===t||t.call(o)}_subscribe(o){var t,a;return null!==(a=null===(t=this.source)||void 0===t?void 0:t.subscribe(o))&&void 0!==a?a:Rl}}function at(e){return o=>{if(function If(e){return Q(null==e?void 0:e.lift)}(o))return o.lift(function(t){try{return e(t,this)}catch(a){this.error(a)}});throw new TypeError("Unable to lift unknown Observable type")}}class ea extends ms{constructor(o,t,a,n,s){super(o),this.onFinalize=s,this._next=t?function(i){try{t(i)}catch(r){o.error(r)}}:super._next,this._error=n?function(i){try{n(i)}catch(r){o.error(r)}finally{this.unsubscribe()}}:super._error,this._complete=a?function(){try{a()}catch(i){o.error(i)}finally{this.unsubscribe()}}:super._complete}unsubscribe(){var o;const{closed:t}=this;super.unsubscribe(),!t&&(null===(o=this.onFinalize)||void 0===o||o.call(this))}}function Ho(e){return this instanceof Ho?(this.v=e,this):new Ho(e)}function xf(e,o,t){if(!Symbol.asyncIterator)throw new TypeError("Symbol.asyncIterator is not defined.");var n,a=t.apply(e,o||[]),s=[];return n={},i("next"),i("throw"),i("return"),n[Symbol.asyncIterator]=function(){return this},n;function i(c){a[c]&&(n[c]=function(u){return new Promise(function(_,g){s.push([c,u,_,g])>1||r(c,u)})})}function r(c,u){try{!function l(c){c.value instanceof Ho?Promise.resolve(c.value.v).then(p,h):d(s[0][2],c)}(a[c](u))}catch(_){d(s[0][3],_)}}function p(c){r("next",c)}function h(c){r("throw",c)}function d(c,u){c(u),s.shift(),s.length&&r(s[0][0],s[0][1])}}function Ff(e){if(!Symbol.asyncIterator)throw new TypeError("Symbol.asyncIterator is not defined.");var t,o=e[Symbol.asyncIterator];return o?o.call(e):(e=function Ul(e){var o="function"==typeof Symbol&&Symbol.iterator,t=o&&e[o],a=0;if(t)return t.call(e);if(e&&"number"==typeof e.length)return{next:function(){return e&&a>=e.length&&(e=void 0),{value:e&&e[a++],done:!e}}};throw new TypeError(o?"Object is not iterable.":"Symbol.iterator is not defined.")}(e),t={},a("next"),a("throw"),a("return"),t[Symbol.asyncIterator]=function(){return this},t);function a(s){t[s]=e[s]&&function(i){return new Promise(function(r,l){!function n(s,i,r,l){Promise.resolve(l).then(function(p){s({value:p,done:r})},i)}(r,l,(i=e[s](i)).done,i.value)})}}}const jl=e=>e&&"number"==typeof e.length&&"function"!=typeof e;function Hl(e){return Q(null==e?void 0:e.then)}function Yl(e){return Q(e[ks])}function Vl(e){return Symbol.asyncIterator&&Q(null==e?void 0:e[Symbol.asyncIterator])}function zl(e){return new TypeError(`You provided ${null!==e&&"object"==typeof e?"an invalid object":`'${e}'`} where a stream was expected. You can provide an Observable, Promise, ReadableStream, Array, AsyncIterable, or Iterable.`)}const $l=function Of(){return"function"==typeof Symbol&&Symbol.iterator?Symbol.iterator:"@@iterator"}();function Kl(e){return Q(null==e?void 0:e[$l])}function Ql(e){return xf(this,arguments,function*(){const t=e.getReader();try{for(;;){const{value:a,done:n}=yield Ho(t.read());if(n)return yield Ho(void 0);yield yield Ho(a)}}finally{t.releaseLock()}})}function Zl(e){return Q(null==e?void 0:e.getReader)}function nt(e){if(e instanceof qe)return e;if(null!=e){if(Yl(e))return function Pf(e){return new qe(o=>{const t=e[ks]();if(Q(t.subscribe))return t.subscribe(o);throw new TypeError("Provided object does not correctly implement Symbol.observable")})}(e);if(jl(e))return function Nf(e){return new qe(o=>{for(let t=0;t<e.length&&!o.closed;t++)o.next(e[t]);o.complete()})}(e);if(Hl(e))return function Bf(e){return new qe(o=>{e.then(t=>{o.closed||(o.next(t),o.complete())},t=>o.error(t)).then(null,xl)})}(e);if(Vl(e))return Xl(e);if(Kl(e))return function Gf(e){return new qe(o=>{for(const t of e)if(o.next(t),o.closed)return;o.complete()})}(e);if(Zl(e))return function Uf(e){return Xl(Ql(e))}(e)}throw zl(e)}function Xl(e){return new qe(o=>{(function jf(e,o){var t,a,n,s;return function Mf(e,o,t,a){return new(t||(t=Promise))(function(s,i){function r(h){try{p(a.next(h))}catch(d){i(d)}}function l(h){try{p(a.throw(h))}catch(d){i(d)}}function p(h){h.done?s(h.value):function n(s){return s instanceof t?s:new t(function(i){i(s)})}(h.value).then(r,l)}p((a=a.apply(e,o||[])).next())})}(this,void 0,void 0,function*(){try{for(t=Ff(e);!(a=yield t.next()).done;)if(o.next(a.value),o.closed)return}catch(i){n={error:i}}finally{try{a&&!a.done&&(s=t.return)&&(yield s.call(t))}finally{if(n)throw n.error}}o.complete()})})(e,o).catch(t=>o.error(t))})}function Eo(e,o,t,a=0,n=!1){const s=o.schedule(function(){t(),n?e.add(this.schedule(null,a)):this.unsubscribe()},a);if(e.add(s),!n)return s}function Jl(e,o,t=1/0){return Q(o)?Jl((a,n)=>function Rf(e,o){return at((t,a)=>{let n=0;t.subscribe(new ea(a,s=>{a.next(e.call(o,s,n++))}))})}((s,i)=>o(a,s,n,i))(nt(e(a,n))),t):("number"==typeof o&&(t=o),at((a,n)=>function Hf(e,o,t,a,n,s,i,r){const l=[];let p=0,h=0,d=!1;const c=()=>{d&&!l.length&&!p&&o.complete()},u=g=>p<a?_(g):l.push(g),_=g=>{s&&o.next(g),p++;let m=!1;nt(t(g,h++)).subscribe(new ea(o,w=>{null==n||n(w),s?u(w):o.next(w)},()=>{m=!0},void 0,()=>{if(m)try{for(p--;l.length&&p<a;){const w=l.shift();i?Eo(o,i,()=>_(w)):_(w)}c()}catch(w){o.error(w)}}))};return e.subscribe(new ea(o,u,()=>{d=!0,c()})),()=>{null==r||r()}}(a,n,e,t)))}const As=new qe(e=>e.complete());function Ds(e){return e[e.length-1]}function ep(e,o=0){return at((t,a)=>{t.subscribe(new ea(a,n=>Eo(a,e,()=>a.next(n),o),()=>Eo(a,e,()=>a.complete(),o),n=>Eo(a,e,()=>a.error(n),o)))})}function op(e,o=0){return at((t,a)=>{a.add(e.schedule(()=>t.subscribe(a),o))})}function tp(e,o){if(!e)throw new Error("Iterable cannot be null");return new qe(t=>{Eo(t,o,()=>{const a=e[Symbol.asyncIterator]();Eo(t,o,()=>{a.next().then(n=>{n.done?t.complete():t.next(n.value)})},0,!0)})})}function ap(e,o){return o?function og(e,o){if(null!=e){if(Yl(e))return function Qf(e,o){return nt(e).pipe(op(o),ep(o))}(e,o);if(jl(e))return function Xf(e,o){return new qe(t=>{let a=0;return o.schedule(function(){a===e.length?t.complete():(t.next(e[a++]),t.closed||this.schedule())})})}(e,o);if(Hl(e))return function Zf(e,o){return nt(e).pipe(op(o),ep(o))}(e,o);if(Vl(e))return tp(e,o);if(Kl(e))return function Jf(e,o){return new qe(t=>{let a;return Eo(t,o,()=>{a=e[$l](),Eo(t,o,()=>{let n,s;try{({value:n,done:s}=a.next())}catch(i){return void t.error(i)}s?t.complete():t.next(n)},0,!0)}),()=>Q(null==a?void 0:a.return)&&a.return()})}(e,o);if(Zl(e))return function eg(e,o){return tp(Ql(e),o)}(e,o)}throw zl(e)}(e,o):nt(e)}function tg(...e){const o=function $f(e){return function zf(e){return e&&Q(e.schedule)}(Ds(e))?e.pop():void 0}(e),t=function Kf(e,o){return"number"==typeof Ds(e)?e.pop():o}(e,1/0),a=e;return a.length?1===a.length?nt(a[0]):function Yf(e=1/0){return Jl(Wl,e)}(t)(ap(a,o)):As}function Cs(e,o,...t){return!0===o?(e(),null):!1===o?null:o(...t).pipe(function ag(e){return e<=0?()=>As:at((o,t)=>{let a=0;o.subscribe(new ea(t,n=>{++a<=e&&(t.next(n),e<=a&&t.complete())}))})}(1)).subscribe(()=>e())}function U(e){for(let o in e)if(e[o]===U)return o;throw Error("Could not find renamed property on target object.")}function N(e){if("string"==typeof e)return e;if(Array.isArray(e))return"["+e.map(N).join(", ")+"]";if(null==e)return""+e;if(e.overriddenName)return`${e.overriddenName}`;if(e.name)return`${e.name}`;const o=e.toString();if(null==o)return""+o;const t=o.indexOf("\n");return-1===t?o:o.substring(0,t)}function Es(e,o){return null==e||""===e?null===o?"":o:null==o||""===o?e:e+" "+o}const sg=U({__forward_ref__:U});function Is(e){return e.__forward_ref__=Is,e.toString=function(){return N(this())},e}function S(e){return function np(e){return"function"==typeof e&&e.hasOwnProperty(sg)&&e.__forward_ref__===Is}(e)?e():e}class P extends Error{constructor(o,t){super(function Rs(e,o){return`NG0${Math.abs(e)}${o?": "+o:""}`}(o,t)),this.code=o}}function D(e){return"string"==typeof e?e:null==e?"":String(e)}function be(e){return"function"==typeof e?e.name||e.toString():"object"==typeof e&&null!=e&&"function"==typeof e.type?e.type.name||e.type.toString():D(e)}function Xa(e,o){const t=o?` in ${o}`:"";throw new P(-201,`No provider for ${be(e)} found${t}`)}function Se(e,o){null==e&&function z(e,o,t,a){throw new Error(`ASSERTION ERROR: ${e}`+(null==a?"":` [Expected=> ${t} ${a} ${o} <=Actual]`))}(o,e,null,"!=")}function Z(e){return{token:e.token,providedIn:e.providedIn||null,factory:e.factory,value:void 0}}function st(e){return{providers:e.providers||[],imports:e.imports||[]}}function Ms(e){return sp(e,Ja)||sp(e,rp)}function sp(e,o){return e.hasOwnProperty(o)?e[o]:null}function ip(e){return e&&(e.hasOwnProperty(Ls)||e.hasOwnProperty(cg))?e[Ls]:null}const Ja=U({\u0275prov:U}),Ls=U({\u0275inj:U}),rp=U({ngInjectableDef:U}),cg=U({ngInjectorDef:U});var E=(()=>((E=E||{})[E.Default=0]="Default",E[E.Host=1]="Host",E[E.Self=2]="Self",E[E.SkipSelf=4]="SkipSelf",E[E.Optional=8]="Optional",E))();let xs;function Io(e){const o=xs;return xs=e,o}function lp(e,o,t){const a=Ms(e);return a&&"root"==a.providedIn?void 0===a.value?a.value=a.factory():a.value:t&E.Optional?null:void 0!==o?o:void Xa(N(e),"Injector")}function Ro(e){return{toString:e}.toString()}var ze=(()=>((ze=ze||{})[ze.OnPush=0]="OnPush",ze[ze.Default=1]="Default",ze))(),ro=(()=>{return(e=ro||(ro={}))[e.Emulated=0]="Emulated",e[e.None=2]="None",e[e.ShadowDom=3]="ShadowDom",ro;var e})();const _g="undefined"!=typeof globalThis&&globalThis,fg="undefined"!=typeof window&&window,gg="undefined"!=typeof self&&"undefined"!=typeof WorkerGlobalScope&&self instanceof WorkerGlobalScope&&self,G=_g||"undefined"!=typeof global&&global||fg||gg,it={},j=[],en=U({\u0275cmp:U}),Fs=U({\u0275dir:U}),Ws=U({\u0275pipe:U}),pp=U({\u0275mod:U}),vo=U({\u0275fac:U}),oa=U({__NG_ELEMENT_ID__:U});let bg=0;function Os(e){return Ro(()=>{const t={},a={type:e.type,providersResolver:null,decls:e.decls,vars:e.vars,factory:null,template:e.template||null,consts:e.consts||null,ngContentSelectors:e.ngContentSelectors,hostBindings:e.hostBindings||null,hostVars:e.hostVars||0,hostAttrs:e.hostAttrs||null,contentQueries:e.contentQueries||null,declaredInputs:t,inputs:null,outputs:null,exportAs:e.exportAs||null,onPush:e.changeDetection===ze.OnPush,directiveDefs:null,pipeDefs:null,selectors:e.selectors||j,viewQuery:e.viewQuery||null,features:e.features||null,data:e.data||{},encapsulation:e.encapsulation||ro.Emulated,id:"c",styles:e.styles||j,_:null,setInput:null,schemas:e.schemas||null,tView:null},n=e.directives,s=e.features,i=e.pipes;return a.id+=bg++,a.inputs=up(e.inputs,t),a.outputs=up(e.outputs),s&&s.forEach(r=>r(a)),a.directiveDefs=n?()=>("function"==typeof n?n():n).map(hp):null,a.pipeDefs=i?()=>("function"==typeof i?i():i).map(dp):null,a})}function hp(e){return ce(e)||function Mo(e){return e[Fs]||null}(e)}function dp(e){return function Yo(e){return e[Ws]||null}(e)}const cp={};function ta(e){return Ro(()=>{const o={type:e.type,bootstrap:e.bootstrap||j,declarations:e.declarations||j,imports:e.imports||j,exports:e.exports||j,transitiveCompileScopes:null,schemas:e.schemas||null,id:e.id||null};return null!=e.id&&(cp[e.id]=e.type),o})}function up(e,o){if(null==e)return it;const t={};for(const a in e)if(e.hasOwnProperty(a)){let n=e[a],s=n;Array.isArray(n)&&(s=n[1],n=n[0]),t[n]=a,o&&(o[n]=s)}return t}const Oe=Os;function ce(e){return e[en]||null}function Pe(e,o){const t=e[pp]||null;if(!t&&!0===o)throw new Error(`Type ${N(e)} does not have '\u0275mod' property.`);return t}const I=11,H=20;function lo(e){return Array.isArray(e)&&"object"==typeof e[1]}function Ke(e){return Array.isArray(e)&&!0===e[1]}function Bs(e){return 0!=(8&e.flags)}function nn(e){return 2==(2&e.flags)}function sn(e){return 1==(1&e.flags)}function Qe(e){return null!==e.template}function qg(e){return 0!=(512&e[2])}function Ko(e,o){return e.hasOwnProperty(vo)?e[vo]:null}class Dg{constructor(o,t,a){this.previousValue=o,this.currentValue=t,this.firstChange=a}isFirstChange(){return this.firstChange}}function fp(e){return e.type.prototype.ngOnChanges&&(e.setInput=Sg),Cg}function Cg(){const e=bp(this),o=null==e?void 0:e.current;if(o){const t=e.previous;if(t===it)e.previous=o;else for(let a in o)t[a]=o[a];e.current=null,this.ngOnChanges(o)}}function Sg(e,o,t,a){const n=bp(e)||function Eg(e,o){return e[gp]=o}(e,{previous:it,current:null}),s=n.current||(n.current={}),i=n.previous,r=this.declaredInputs[t],l=i[r];s[r]=new Dg(l&&l.currentValue,o,i===it),e[a]=o}const gp="__ngSimpleChanges__";function bp(e){return e[gp]||null}let js;function X(e){return!!e.listen}const yp={createRenderer:(e,o)=>function Hs(){return void 0!==js?js:"undefined"!=typeof document?document:void 0}()};function ae(e){for(;Array.isArray(e);)e=e[0];return e}function Ge(e,o){return ae(o[e.index])}function Ys(e,o){return e.data[o]}function Ie(e,o){const t=o[e];return lo(t)?t:t[0]}function Vs(e){return 128==(128&e[2])}function Lo(e,o){return null==o?null:e[o]}function kp(e){e[18]=0}function zs(e,o){e[5]+=o;let t=e,a=e[3];for(;null!==a&&(1===o&&1===t[5]||-1===o&&0===t[5]);)a[5]+=o,t=a,a=a[3]}const A={lFrame:Ip(null),bindingsEnabled:!0,isInCheckNoChangesMode:!1};function qp(){return A.bindingsEnabled}function b(){return A.lFrame.lView}function W(){return A.lFrame.tView}function re(){let e=Tp();for(;null!==e&&64===e.type;)e=e.parent;return e}function Tp(){return A.lFrame.currentTNode}function po(e,o){const t=A.lFrame;t.currentTNode=e,t.isParent=o}function $s(){return A.lFrame.isParent}function pn(){return A.isInCheckNoChangesMode}function hn(e){A.isInCheckNoChangesMode=e}function ct(){return A.lFrame.bindingIndex++}function Hg(e,o){const t=A.lFrame;t.bindingIndex=t.bindingRootIndex=e,Qs(o)}function Qs(e){A.lFrame.currentDirectiveIndex=e}function Xs(e){A.lFrame.currentQueryIndex=e}function Vg(e){const o=e[1];return 2===o.type?o.declTNode:1===o.type?e[6]:null}function Sp(e,o,t){if(t&E.SkipSelf){let n=o,s=e;for(;!(n=n.parent,null!==n||t&E.Host||(n=Vg(s),null===n||(s=s[15],10&n.type))););if(null===n)return!1;o=n,e=s}const a=A.lFrame=Ep();return a.currentTNode=o,a.lView=e,!0}function dn(e){const o=Ep(),t=e[1];A.lFrame=o,o.currentTNode=t.firstChild,o.lView=e,o.tView=t,o.contextLView=e,o.bindingIndex=t.bindingStartIndex,o.inI18n=!1}function Ep(){const e=A.lFrame,o=null===e?null:e.child;return null===o?Ip(e):o}function Ip(e){const o={currentTNode:null,isParent:!0,lView:null,tView:null,selectedIndex:-1,contextLView:null,elementDepthCount:0,currentNamespace:null,currentDirectiveIndex:-1,bindingRootIndex:-1,bindingIndex:-1,currentQueryIndex:0,parent:e,child:null,inI18n:!1};return null!==e&&(e.child=o),o}function Rp(){const e=A.lFrame;return A.lFrame=e.parent,e.currentTNode=null,e.lView=null,e}const Mp=Rp;function cn(){const e=Rp();e.isParent=!0,e.tView=null,e.selectedIndex=-1,e.contextLView=null,e.elementDepthCount=0,e.currentDirectiveIndex=-1,e.currentNamespace=null,e.bindingRootIndex=-1,e.bindingIndex=-1,e.currentQueryIndex=0}function we(){return A.lFrame.selectedIndex}function xo(e){A.lFrame.selectedIndex=e}function un(e,o){for(let t=o.directiveStart,a=o.directiveEnd;t<a;t++){const s=e.data[t].type.prototype,{ngAfterContentInit:i,ngAfterContentChecked:r,ngAfterViewInit:l,ngAfterViewChecked:p,ngOnDestroy:h}=s;i&&(e.contentHooks||(e.contentHooks=[])).push(-t,i),r&&((e.contentHooks||(e.contentHooks=[])).push(t,r),(e.contentCheckHooks||(e.contentCheckHooks=[])).push(t,r)),l&&(e.viewHooks||(e.viewHooks=[])).push(-t,l),p&&((e.viewHooks||(e.viewHooks=[])).push(t,p),(e.viewCheckHooks||(e.viewCheckHooks=[])).push(t,p)),null!=h&&(e.destroyHooks||(e.destroyHooks=[])).push(t,h)}}function _n(e,o,t){Lp(e,o,3,t)}function fn(e,o,t,a){(3&e[2])===t&&Lp(e,o,t,a)}function Js(e,o){let t=e[2];(3&t)===o&&(t&=2047,t+=1,e[2]=t)}function Lp(e,o,t,a){const s=null!=a?a:-1,i=o.length-1;let r=0;for(let l=void 0!==a?65535&e[18]:0;l<i;l++)if("number"==typeof o[l+1]){if(r=o[l],null!=a&&r>=a)break}else o[l]<0&&(e[18]+=65536),(r<s||-1==s)&&(ob(e,t,o,l),e[18]=(4294901760&e[18])+l+2),l++}function ob(e,o,t,a){const n=t[a]<0,s=t[a+1],r=e[n?-t[a]:t[a]];if(n){if(e[2]>>11<e[18]>>16&&(3&e[2])===o){e[2]+=2048;try{s.call(r)}finally{}}}else try{s.call(r)}finally{}}class ra{constructor(o,t,a){this.factory=o,this.resolving=!1,this.canSeeViewProviders=t,this.injectImpl=a}}function gn(e,o,t){const a=X(e);let n=0;for(;n<t.length;){const s=t[n];if("number"==typeof s){if(0!==s)break;n++;const i=t[n++],r=t[n++],l=t[n++];a?e.setAttribute(o,r,l,i):o.setAttributeNS(i,r,l)}else{const i=s,r=t[++n];oi(i)?a&&e.setProperty(o,i,r):a?e.setAttribute(o,i,r):o.setAttribute(i,r),n++}}return n}function xp(e){return 3===e||4===e||6===e}function oi(e){return 64===e.charCodeAt(0)}function bn(e,o){if(null!==o&&0!==o.length)if(null===e||0===e.length)e=o.slice();else{let t=-1;for(let a=0;a<o.length;a++){const n=o[a];"number"==typeof n?t=n:0===t||Fp(e,t,n,null,-1===t||2===t?o[++a]:null)}}return e}function Fp(e,o,t,a,n){let s=0,i=e.length;if(-1===o)i=-1;else for(;s<e.length;){const r=e[s++];if("number"==typeof r){if(r===o){i=-1;break}if(r>o){i=s-1;break}}}for(;s<e.length;){const r=e[s];if("number"==typeof r)break;if(r===t){if(null===a)return void(null!==n&&(e[s+1]=n));if(a===e[s+1])return void(e[s+2]=n)}s++,null!==a&&s++,null!==n&&s++}-1!==i&&(e.splice(i,0,o),s=i+1),e.splice(s++,0,t),null!==a&&e.splice(s++,0,a),null!==n&&e.splice(s++,0,n)}function Wp(e){return-1!==e}function ut(e){return 32767&e}function _t(e,o){let t=function ib(e){return e>>16}(e),a=o;for(;t>0;)a=a[15],t--;return a}let ti=!0;function mn(e){const o=ti;return ti=e,o}let rb=0;function pa(e,o){const t=ni(e,o);if(-1!==t)return t;const a=o[1];a.firstCreatePass&&(e.injectorIndex=o.length,ai(a.data,e),ai(o,null),ai(a.blueprint,null));const n=wn(e,o),s=e.injectorIndex;if(Wp(n)){const i=ut(n),r=_t(n,o),l=r[1].data;for(let p=0;p<8;p++)o[s+p]=r[i+p]|l[i+p]}return o[s+8]=n,s}function ai(e,o){e.push(0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,o)}function ni(e,o){return-1===e.injectorIndex||e.parent&&e.parent.injectorIndex===e.injectorIndex||null===o[e.injectorIndex+8]?-1:e.injectorIndex}function wn(e,o){if(e.parent&&-1!==e.parent.injectorIndex)return e.parent.injectorIndex;let t=0,a=null,n=o;for(;null!==n;){const s=n[1],i=s.type;if(a=2===i?s.declTNode:1===i?n[6]:null,null===a)return-1;if(t++,n=n[15],-1!==a.injectorIndex)return a.injectorIndex|t<<16}return-1}function yn(e,o,t){!function lb(e,o,t){let a;"string"==typeof t?a=t.charCodeAt(0)||0:t.hasOwnProperty(oa)&&(a=t[oa]),null==a&&(a=t[oa]=rb++);const n=255&a;o.data[e+(n>>5)]|=1<<n}(e,o,t)}function Np(e,o,t){if(t&E.Optional)return e;Xa(o,"NodeInjector")}function Bp(e,o,t,a){if(t&E.Optional&&void 0===a&&(a=null),0==(t&(E.Self|E.Host))){const n=e[9],s=Io(void 0);try{return n?n.get(o,a,t&E.Optional):lp(o,a,t&E.Optional)}finally{Io(s)}}return Np(a,o,t)}function Gp(e,o,t,a=E.Default,n){if(null!==e){const s=function cb(e){if("string"==typeof e)return e.charCodeAt(0)||0;const o=e.hasOwnProperty(oa)?e[oa]:void 0;return"number"==typeof o?o>=0?255&o:hb:o}(t);if("function"==typeof s){if(!Sp(o,e,a))return a&E.Host?Np(n,t,a):Bp(o,t,a,n);try{const i=s(a);if(null!=i||a&E.Optional)return i;Xa(t)}finally{Mp()}}else if("number"==typeof s){let i=null,r=ni(e,o),l=-1,p=a&E.Host?o[16][6]:null;for((-1===r||a&E.SkipSelf)&&(l=-1===r?wn(e,o):o[r+8],-1!==l&&Hp(a,!1)?(i=o[1],r=ut(l),o=_t(l,o)):r=-1);-1!==r;){const h=o[1];if(jp(s,r,h.data)){const d=db(r,o,t,i,a,p);if(d!==Up)return d}l=o[r+8],-1!==l&&Hp(a,o[1].data[r+8]===p)&&jp(s,r,o)?(i=h,r=ut(l),o=_t(l,o)):r=-1}}}return Bp(o,t,a,n)}const Up={};function hb(){return new ft(re(),b())}function db(e,o,t,a,n,s){const i=o[1],r=i.data[e+8],h=function vn(e,o,t,a,n){const s=e.providerIndexes,i=o.data,r=1048575&s,l=e.directiveStart,h=s>>20,c=n?r+h:e.directiveEnd;for(let u=a?r:r+h;u<c;u++){const _=i[u];if(u<l&&t===_||u>=l&&_.type===t)return u}if(n){const u=i[l];if(u&&Qe(u)&&u.type===t)return l}return null}(r,i,t,null==a?nn(r)&&ti:a!=i&&0!=(3&r.type),n&E.Host&&s===r);return null!==h?ha(o,i,h,r):Up}function ha(e,o,t,a){let n=e[t];const s=o.data;if(function tb(e){return e instanceof ra}(n)){const i=n;i.resolving&&function ig(e,o){const t=o?`. Dependency path: ${o.join(" > ")} > ${e}`:"";throw new P(-200,`Circular dependency in DI detected for ${e}${t}`)}(be(s[t]));const r=mn(i.canSeeViewProviders);i.resolving=!0;const l=i.injectImpl?Io(i.injectImpl):null;Sp(e,a,E.Default);try{n=e[t]=i.factory(void 0,s,e,a),o.firstCreatePass&&t>=a.directiveStart&&function eb(e,o,t){const{ngOnChanges:a,ngOnInit:n,ngDoCheck:s}=o.type.prototype;if(a){const i=fp(o);(t.preOrderHooks||(t.preOrderHooks=[])).push(e,i),(t.preOrderCheckHooks||(t.preOrderCheckHooks=[])).push(e,i)}n&&(t.preOrderHooks||(t.preOrderHooks=[])).push(0-e,n),s&&((t.preOrderHooks||(t.preOrderHooks=[])).push(e,s),(t.preOrderCheckHooks||(t.preOrderCheckHooks=[])).push(e,s))}(t,s[t],o)}finally{null!==l&&Io(l),mn(r),i.resolving=!1,Mp()}}return n}function jp(e,o,t){return!!(t[o+(e>>5)]&1<<e)}function Hp(e,o){return!(e&E.Self||e&E.Host&&o)}class ft{constructor(o,t){this._tNode=o,this._lView=t}get(o,t,a){return Gp(this._tNode,this._lView,o,a,t)}}const bt="__parameters__";function wt(e,o,t){return Ro(()=>{const a=function ri(e){return function(...t){if(e){const a=e(...t);for(const n in a)this[n]=a[n]}}}(o);function n(...s){if(this instanceof n)return a.apply(this,s),this;const i=new n(...s);return r.annotation=i,r;function r(l,p,h){const d=l.hasOwnProperty(bt)?l[bt]:Object.defineProperty(l,bt,{value:[]})[bt];for(;d.length<=h;)d.push(null);return(d[h]=d[h]||[]).push(i),l}}return t&&(n.prototype=Object.create(t.prototype)),n.prototype.ngMetadataName=e,n.annotationCls=n,n})}class B{constructor(o,t){this._desc=o,this.ngMetadataName="InjectionToken",this.\u0275prov=void 0,"number"==typeof t?this.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=t:void 0!==t&&(this.\u0275prov=Z({token:this,providedIn:t.providedIn||"root",factory:t.factory}))}toString(){return`InjectionToken ${this._desc}`}}function ho(e,o){e.forEach(t=>Array.isArray(t)?ho(t,o):o(t))}function Vp(e,o,t){o>=e.length?e.push(t):e.splice(o,0,t)}function kn(e,o){return o>=e.length-1?e.pop():e.splice(o,1)[0]}const _a={},di="__NG_DI_FLAG__",Tn="ngTempTokenPath",Tb=/\n/gm,Zp="__source",Db=U({provide:String,useValue:U});let fa;function Xp(e){const o=fa;return fa=e,o}function Cb(e,o=E.Default){if(void 0===fa)throw new P(203,"");return null===fa?lp(e,void 0,o):fa.get(e,o&E.Optional?null:void 0,o)}function Y(e,o=E.Default){return(function ug(){return xs}()||Cb)(S(e),o)}function ci(e){const o=[];for(let t=0;t<e.length;t++){const a=S(e[t]);if(Array.isArray(a)){if(0===a.length)throw new P(900,"");let n,s=E.Default;for(let i=0;i<a.length;i++){const r=a[i],l=Sb(r);"number"==typeof l?-1===l?n=r.token:s|=l:n=r}o.push(Y(n,s))}else o.push(Y(a))}return o}function ga(e,o){return e[di]=o,e.prototype[di]=o,e}function Sb(e){return e[di]}const An=ga(wt("Inject",e=>({token:e})),-1),vt=ga(wt("Optional"),8),ba=ga(wt("SkipSelf"),4),mh="__ngContext__";function _e(e,o){e[mh]=o}function vi(e){const o=function ka(e){return e[mh]||null}(e);return o?Array.isArray(o)?o:o.lView:null}function qi(e){return e.ngOriginalError}function ym(e,...o){e.error(...o)}class Tt{constructor(){this._console=console}handleError(o){const t=this._findOriginalError(o),a=function wm(e){return e&&e.ngErrorLogger||ym}(o);a(this._console,"ERROR",o),t&&a(this._console,"ORIGINAL ERROR",t)}_findOriginalError(o){let t=o&&qi(o);for(;t&&qi(t);)t=qi(t);return t||null}}const qh=(()=>("undefined"!=typeof requestAnimationFrame&&requestAnimationFrame||setTimeout).bind(G))();function uo(e){return e instanceof Function?e():e}var Me=(()=>((Me=Me||{})[Me.Important=1]="Important",Me[Me.DashCase=2]="DashCase",Me))();function Ai(e,o){return undefined(e,o)}function qa(e){const o=e[3];return Ke(o)?o[3]:o}function Di(e){return Sh(e[13])}function Ci(e){return Sh(e[4])}function Sh(e){for(;null!==e&&!Ke(e);)e=e[4];return e}function Dt(e,o,t,a,n){if(null!=a){let s,i=!1;Ke(a)?s=a:lo(a)&&(i=!0,a=a[0]);const r=ae(a);0===e&&null!==t?null==n?xh(o,t,r):Qo(o,t,r,n||null,!0):1===e&&null!==t?Qo(o,t,r,n||null,!0):2===e?function Gh(e,o,t){const a=Rn(e,o);a&&function jm(e,o,t,a){X(e)?e.removeChild(o,t,a):o.removeChild(t)}(e,a,o,t)}(o,r,i):3===e&&o.destroyNode(r),null!=s&&function Vm(e,o,t,a,n){const s=t[7];s!==ae(t)&&Dt(o,e,a,s,n);for(let r=10;r<t.length;r++){const l=t[r];Ta(l[1],l,e,o,a,s)}}(o,e,s,t,n)}}function Ei(e,o,t){return X(e)?e.createElement(o,t):null===t?e.createElement(o):e.createElementNS(t,o)}function Ih(e,o){const t=e[9],a=t.indexOf(o),n=o[3];1024&o[2]&&(o[2]&=-1025,zs(n,-1)),t.splice(a,1)}function Ii(e,o){if(e.length<=10)return;const t=10+o,a=e[t];if(a){const n=a[17];null!==n&&n!==e&&Ih(n,a),o>0&&(e[t-1][4]=a[4]);const s=kn(e,10+o);!function Fm(e,o){Ta(e,o,o[I],2,null,null),o[0]=null,o[6]=null}(a[1],a);const i=s[19];null!==i&&i.detachView(s[1]),a[3]=null,a[4]=null,a[2]&=-129}return a}function Rh(e,o){if(!(256&o[2])){const t=o[I];X(t)&&t.destroyNode&&Ta(e,o,t,3,null,null),function Pm(e){let o=e[13];if(!o)return Ri(e[1],e);for(;o;){let t=null;if(lo(o))t=o[13];else{const a=o[10];a&&(t=a)}if(!t){for(;o&&!o[4]&&o!==e;)lo(o)&&Ri(o[1],o),o=o[3];null===o&&(o=e),lo(o)&&Ri(o[1],o),t=o&&o[4]}o=t}}(o)}}function Ri(e,o){if(!(256&o[2])){o[2]&=-129,o[2]|=256,function Um(e,o){let t;if(null!=e&&null!=(t=e.destroyHooks))for(let a=0;a<t.length;a+=2){const n=o[t[a]];if(!(n instanceof ra)){const s=t[a+1];if(Array.isArray(s))for(let i=0;i<s.length;i+=2){const r=n[s[i]],l=s[i+1];try{l.call(r)}finally{}}else try{s.call(n)}finally{}}}}(e,o),function Gm(e,o){const t=e.cleanup,a=o[7];let n=-1;if(null!==t)for(let s=0;s<t.length-1;s+=2)if("string"==typeof t[s]){const i=t[s+1],r="function"==typeof i?i(o):ae(o[i]),l=a[n=t[s+2]],p=t[s+3];"boolean"==typeof p?r.removeEventListener(t[s],l,p):p>=0?a[n=p]():a[n=-p].unsubscribe(),s+=2}else{const i=a[n=t[s+1]];t[s].call(i)}if(null!==a){for(let s=n+1;s<a.length;s++)a[s]();o[7]=null}}(e,o),1===o[1].type&&X(o[I])&&o[I].destroy();const t=o[17];if(null!==t&&Ke(o[3])){t!==o[3]&&Ih(t,o);const a=o[19];null!==a&&a.detachView(e)}}}function Mh(e,o,t){return function Lh(e,o,t){let a=o;for(;null!==a&&40&a.type;)a=(o=a).parent;if(null===a)return t[0];if(2&a.flags){const n=e.data[a.directiveStart].encapsulation;if(n===ro.None||n===ro.Emulated)return null}return Ge(a,t)}(e,o.parent,t)}function Qo(e,o,t,a,n){X(e)?e.insertBefore(o,t,a,n):o.insertBefore(t,a,n)}function xh(e,o,t){X(e)?e.appendChild(o,t):o.appendChild(t)}function Fh(e,o,t,a,n){null!==a?Qo(e,o,t,a,n):xh(e,o,t)}function Rn(e,o){return X(e)?e.parentNode(o):o.parentNode}let Ph=function Oh(e,o,t){return 40&e.type?Ge(e,t):null};function Mn(e,o,t,a){const n=Mh(e,a,o),s=o[I],r=function Wh(e,o,t){return Ph(e,o,t)}(a.parent||o[6],a,o);if(null!=n)if(Array.isArray(t))for(let l=0;l<t.length;l++)Fh(s,n,t[l],r,!1);else Fh(s,n,t,r,!1)}function Ln(e,o){if(null!==o){const t=o.type;if(3&t)return Ge(o,e);if(4&t)return Li(-1,e[o.index]);if(8&t){const a=o.child;if(null!==a)return Ln(e,a);{const n=e[o.index];return Ke(n)?Li(-1,n):ae(n)}}if(32&t)return Ai(o,e)()||ae(e[o.index]);{const a=Bh(e,o);return null!==a?Array.isArray(a)?a[0]:Ln(qa(e[16]),a):Ln(e,o.next)}}return null}function Bh(e,o){return null!==o?e[16][6].projection[o.projection]:null}function Li(e,o){const t=10+e+1;if(t<o.length){const a=o[t],n=a[1].firstChild;if(null!==n)return Ln(a,n)}return o[7]}function xi(e,o,t,a,n,s,i){for(;null!=t;){const r=a[t.index],l=t.type;if(i&&0===o&&(r&&_e(ae(r),a),t.flags|=4),64!=(64&t.flags))if(8&l)xi(e,o,t.child,a,n,s,!1),Dt(o,e,n,r,s);else if(32&l){const p=Ai(t,a);let h;for(;h=p();)Dt(o,e,n,h,s);Dt(o,e,n,r,s)}else 16&l?Uh(e,o,a,t,n,s):Dt(o,e,n,r,s);t=i?t.projectionNext:t.next}}function Ta(e,o,t,a,n,s){xi(t,a,e.firstChild,o,n,s,!1)}function Uh(e,o,t,a,n,s){const i=t[16],l=i[6].projection[a.projection];if(Array.isArray(l))for(let p=0;p<l.length;p++)Dt(o,e,n,l[p],s);else xi(e,o,l,i[3],n,s,!0)}function jh(e,o,t){X(e)?e.setAttribute(o,"style",t):o.style.cssText=t}function Fi(e,o,t){X(e)?""===t?e.removeAttribute(o,"class"):e.setAttribute(o,"class",t):o.className=t}function Hh(e,o,t){let a=e.length;for(;;){const n=e.indexOf(o,t);if(-1===n)return n;if(0===n||e.charCodeAt(n-1)<=32){const s=o.length;if(n+s===a||e.charCodeAt(n+s)<=32)return n}t=n+1}}const Yh="ng-template";function $m(e,o,t){let a=0;for(;a<e.length;){let n=e[a++];if(t&&"class"===n){if(n=e[a],-1!==Hh(n.toLowerCase(),o,0))return!0}else if(1===n){for(;a<e.length&&"string"==typeof(n=e[a++]);)if(n.toLowerCase()===o)return!0;return!1}}return!1}function Vh(e){return 4===e.type&&e.value!==Yh}function Km(e,o,t){return o===(4!==e.type||t?e.value:Yh)}function Qm(e,o,t){let a=4;const n=e.attrs||[],s=function Jm(e){for(let o=0;o<e.length;o++)if(xp(e[o]))return o;return e.length}(n);let i=!1;for(let r=0;r<o.length;r++){const l=o[r];if("number"!=typeof l){if(!i)if(4&a){if(a=2|1&a,""!==l&&!Km(e,l,t)||""===l&&1===o.length){if(Ze(a))return!1;i=!0}}else{const p=8&a?l:o[++r];if(8&a&&null!==e.attrs){if(!$m(e.attrs,p,t)){if(Ze(a))return!1;i=!0}continue}const d=Zm(8&a?"class":l,n,Vh(e),t);if(-1===d){if(Ze(a))return!1;i=!0;continue}if(""!==p){let c;c=d>s?"":n[d+1].toLowerCase();const u=8&a?c:null;if(u&&-1!==Hh(u,p,0)||2&a&&p!==c){if(Ze(a))return!1;i=!0}}}}else{if(!i&&!Ze(a)&&!Ze(l))return!1;if(i&&Ze(l))continue;i=!1,a=l|1&a}}return Ze(a)||i}function Ze(e){return 0==(1&e)}function Zm(e,o,t,a){if(null===o)return-1;let n=0;if(a||!t){let s=!1;for(;n<o.length;){const i=o[n];if(i===e)return n;if(3===i||6===i)s=!0;else{if(1===i||2===i){let r=o[++n];for(;"string"==typeof r;)r=o[++n];continue}if(4===i)break;if(0===i){n+=4;continue}}n+=s?1:2}return-1}return function ew(e,o){let t=e.indexOf(4);if(t>-1)for(t++;t<e.length;){const a=e[t];if("number"==typeof a)return-1;if(a===o)return t;t++}return-1}(o,e)}function zh(e,o,t=!1){for(let a=0;a<o.length;a++)if(Qm(e,o[a],t))return!0;return!1}function $h(e,o){return e?":not("+o.trim()+")":o}function tw(e){let o=e[0],t=1,a=2,n="",s=!1;for(;t<e.length;){let i=e[t];if("string"==typeof i)if(2&a){const r=e[++t];n+="["+i+(r.length>0?'="'+r+'"':"")+"]"}else 8&a?n+="."+i:4&a&&(n+=" "+i);else""!==n&&!Ze(i)&&(o+=$h(s,n),n=""),a=i,s=s||!Ze(a);t++}return""!==n&&(o+=$h(s,n)),o}const C={};function Xe(e){Kh(W(),b(),we()+e,pn())}function Kh(e,o,t,a){if(!a)if(3==(3&o[2])){const s=e.preOrderCheckHooks;null!==s&&_n(o,s,t)}else{const s=e.preOrderHooks;null!==s&&fn(o,s,0,t)}xo(t)}function id(e,o){const t=e.contentQueries;if(null!==t)for(let a=0;a<t.length;a+=2){const n=t[a],s=t[a+1];if(-1!==s){const i=e.data[s];Xs(n),i.contentQueries(2,o[s],s)}}}function Aa(e,o,t,a,n,s,i,r,l,p){const h=o.blueprint.slice();return h[0]=n,h[2]=140|a,kp(h),h[3]=h[15]=e,h[8]=t,h[10]=i||e&&e[10],h[I]=r||e&&e[I],h[12]=l||e&&e[12]||null,h[9]=p||e&&e[9]||null,h[6]=s,h[16]=2==o.type?e[16]:h,h}function Ct(e,o,t,a,n){let s=e.data[o];if(null===s)s=function zi(e,o,t,a,n){const s=Tp(),i=$s(),l=e.data[o]=function yw(e,o,t,a,n,s){return{type:t,index:a,insertBeforeIndex:null,injectorIndex:o?o.injectorIndex:-1,directiveStart:-1,directiveEnd:-1,directiveStylingLast:-1,propertyBindings:null,flags:0,providerIndexes:0,value:n,attrs:s,mergedAttrs:null,localNames:null,initialInputs:void 0,inputs:null,outputs:null,tViews:null,next:null,projectionNext:null,child:null,parent:o,projection:null,styles:null,stylesWithoutHost:null,residualStyles:void 0,classes:null,classesWithoutHost:null,residualClasses:void 0,classBindings:0,styleBindings:0}}(0,i?s:s&&s.parent,t,o,a,n);return null===e.firstChild&&(e.firstChild=l),null!==s&&(i?null==s.child&&null!==l.parent&&(s.child=l):null===s.next&&(s.next=l)),l}(e,o,t,a,n),function jg(){return A.lFrame.inI18n}()&&(s.flags|=64);else if(64&s.type){s.type=t,s.value=a,s.attrs=n;const i=function ia(){const e=A.lFrame,o=e.currentTNode;return e.isParent?o:o.parent}();s.injectorIndex=null===i?-1:i.injectorIndex}return po(s,!0),s}function St(e,o,t,a){if(0===t)return-1;const n=o.length;for(let s=0;s<t;s++)o.push(a),e.blueprint.push(a),e.data.push(null);return n}function Da(e,o,t){dn(o);try{const a=e.viewQuery;null!==a&&tr(1,a,t);const n=e.template;null!==n&&rd(e,o,n,1,t),e.firstCreatePass&&(e.firstCreatePass=!1),e.staticContentQueries&&id(e,o),e.staticViewQueries&&tr(2,e.viewQuery,t);const s=e.components;null!==s&&function bw(e,o){for(let t=0;t<o.length;t++)Pw(e,o[t])}(o,s)}catch(a){throw e.firstCreatePass&&(e.incompleteFirstPass=!0,e.firstCreatePass=!1),a}finally{o[2]&=-5,cn()}}function Et(e,o,t,a){const n=o[2];if(256==(256&n))return;dn(o);const s=pn();try{kp(o),function Ap(e){return A.lFrame.bindingIndex=e}(e.bindingStartIndex),null!==t&&rd(e,o,t,2,a);const i=3==(3&n);if(!s)if(i){const p=e.preOrderCheckHooks;null!==p&&_n(o,p,null)}else{const p=e.preOrderHooks;null!==p&&fn(o,p,0,null),Js(o,0)}if(function Ww(e){for(let o=Di(e);null!==o;o=Ci(o)){if(!o[2])continue;const t=o[9];for(let a=0;a<t.length;a++){const n=t[a],s=n[3];0==(1024&n[2])&&zs(s,1),n[2]|=1024}}}(o),function Fw(e){for(let o=Di(e);null!==o;o=Ci(o))for(let t=10;t<o.length;t++){const a=o[t],n=a[1];Vs(a)&&Et(n,a,n.template,a[8])}}(o),null!==e.contentQueries&&id(e,o),!s)if(i){const p=e.contentCheckHooks;null!==p&&_n(o,p)}else{const p=e.contentHooks;null!==p&&fn(o,p,1),Js(o,1)}!function fw(e,o){const t=e.hostBindingOpCodes;if(null!==t)try{for(let a=0;a<t.length;a++){const n=t[a];if(n<0)xo(~n);else{const s=n,i=t[++a],r=t[++a];Hg(i,s),r(2,o[s])}}}finally{xo(-1)}}(e,o);const r=e.components;null!==r&&function gw(e,o){for(let t=0;t<o.length;t++)Ow(e,o[t])}(o,r);const l=e.viewQuery;if(null!==l&&tr(2,l,a),!s)if(i){const p=e.viewCheckHooks;null!==p&&_n(o,p)}else{const p=e.viewHooks;null!==p&&fn(o,p,2),Js(o,2)}!0===e.firstUpdatePass&&(e.firstUpdatePass=!1),s||(o[2]&=-73),1024&o[2]&&(o[2]&=-1025,zs(o[3],-1))}finally{cn()}}function mw(e,o,t,a){const n=o[10],s=!pn(),i=function vp(e){return 4==(4&e[2])}(o);try{s&&!i&&n.begin&&n.begin(),i&&Da(e,o,a),Et(e,o,t,a)}finally{s&&!i&&n.end&&n.end()}}function rd(e,o,t,a,n){const s=we(),i=2&a;try{xo(-1),i&&o.length>H&&Kh(e,o,H,pn()),t(a,n)}finally{xo(s)}}function $i(e,o,t){!qp()||(function Cw(e,o,t,a){const n=t.directiveStart,s=t.directiveEnd;e.firstCreatePass||pa(t,o),_e(a,o);const i=t.initialInputs;for(let r=n;r<s;r++){const l=e.data[r],p=Qe(l);p&&Mw(o,t,l);const h=ha(o,e,r,t);_e(h,o),null!==i&&Lw(0,r-n,h,l,0,i),p&&(Ie(t.index,o)[8]=h)}}(e,o,t,Ge(t,o)),128==(128&t.flags)&&function Sw(e,o,t){const a=t.directiveStart,n=t.directiveEnd,i=t.index,r=function Yg(){return A.lFrame.currentDirectiveIndex}();try{xo(i);for(let l=a;l<n;l++){const p=e.data[l],h=o[l];Qs(l),(null!==p.hostBindings||0!==p.hostVars||null!==p.hostAttrs)&&gd(p,h)}}finally{xo(-1),Qs(r)}}(e,o,t))}function Ki(e,o,t=Ge){const a=o.localNames;if(null!==a){let n=o.index+1;for(let s=0;s<a.length;s+=2){const i=a[s+1],r=-1===i?t(o,e):e[i];e[n++]=r}}}function pd(e){const o=e.tView;return null===o||o.incompleteFirstPass?e.tView=On(1,null,e.template,e.decls,e.vars,e.directiveDefs,e.pipeDefs,e.viewQuery,e.schemas,e.consts):o}function On(e,o,t,a,n,s,i,r,l,p){const h=H+a,d=h+n,c=function ww(e,o){const t=[];for(let a=0;a<o;a++)t.push(a<e?null:C);return t}(h,d),u="function"==typeof p?p():p;return c[1]={type:e,blueprint:c,template:t,queries:null,viewQuery:r,declTNode:o,data:c.slice().fill(null,h),bindingStartIndex:h,expandoStartIndex:d,hostBindingOpCodes:null,firstCreatePass:!0,firstUpdatePass:!0,staticViewQueries:!1,staticContentQueries:!1,preOrderHooks:null,preOrderCheckHooks:null,contentHooks:null,contentCheckHooks:null,viewHooks:null,viewCheckHooks:null,destroyHooks:null,cleanup:null,contentQueries:null,components:null,directiveRegistry:"function"==typeof s?s():s,pipeRegistry:"function"==typeof i?i():i,firstChild:null,schemas:l,consts:u,incompleteFirstPass:!1}}function ud(e,o,t){for(let a in e)if(e.hasOwnProperty(a)){const n=e[a];(t=null===t?{}:t).hasOwnProperty(a)?t[a].push(o,n):t[a]=[o,n]}return t}function Qi(e,o,t,a){let n=!1;if(qp()){const s=function Ew(e,o,t){const a=e.directiveRegistry;let n=null;if(a)for(let s=0;s<a.length;s++){const i=a[s];zh(t,i.selectors,!1)&&(n||(n=[]),yn(pa(t,o),e,i.type),Qe(i)?(bd(e,t),n.unshift(i)):n.push(i))}return n}(e,o,t),i=null===a?null:{"":-1};if(null!==s){n=!0,md(t,e.data.length,s.length);for(let h=0;h<s.length;h++){const d=s[h];d.providersResolver&&d.providersResolver(d)}let r=!1,l=!1,p=St(e,o,s.length,null);for(let h=0;h<s.length;h++){const d=s[h];t.mergedAttrs=bn(t.mergedAttrs,d.hostAttrs),wd(e,t,o,p,d),Rw(p,d,i),null!==d.contentQueries&&(t.flags|=8),(null!==d.hostBindings||null!==d.hostAttrs||0!==d.hostVars)&&(t.flags|=128);const c=d.type.prototype;!r&&(c.ngOnChanges||c.ngOnInit||c.ngDoCheck)&&((e.preOrderHooks||(e.preOrderHooks=[])).push(t.index),r=!0),!l&&(c.ngOnChanges||c.ngDoCheck)&&((e.preOrderCheckHooks||(e.preOrderCheckHooks=[])).push(t.index),l=!0),p++}!function vw(e,o){const a=o.directiveEnd,n=e.data,s=o.attrs,i=[];let r=null,l=null;for(let p=o.directiveStart;p<a;p++){const h=n[p],d=h.inputs,c=null===s||Vh(o)?null:xw(d,s);i.push(c),r=ud(d,p,r),l=ud(h.outputs,p,l)}null!==r&&(r.hasOwnProperty("class")&&(o.flags|=16),r.hasOwnProperty("style")&&(o.flags|=32)),o.initialInputs=i,o.inputs=r,o.outputs=l}(e,t)}i&&function Iw(e,o,t){if(o){const a=e.localNames=[];for(let n=0;n<o.length;n+=2){const s=t[o[n+1]];if(null==s)throw new P(-301,`Export of name '${o[n+1]}' not found!`);a.push(o[n],s)}}}(t,a,i)}return t.mergedAttrs=bn(t.mergedAttrs,t.attrs),n}function fd(e,o,t,a,n,s){const i=s.hostBindings;if(i){let r=e.hostBindingOpCodes;null===r&&(r=e.hostBindingOpCodes=[]);const l=~o.index;(function Dw(e){let o=e.length;for(;o>0;){const t=e[--o];if("number"==typeof t&&t<0)return t}return 0})(r)!=l&&r.push(l),r.push(a,n,i)}}function gd(e,o){null!==e.hostBindings&&e.hostBindings(1,o)}function bd(e,o){o.flags|=2,(e.components||(e.components=[])).push(o.index)}function Rw(e,o,t){if(t){if(o.exportAs)for(let a=0;a<o.exportAs.length;a++)t[o.exportAs[a]]=e;Qe(o)&&(t[""]=e)}}function md(e,o,t){e.flags|=1,e.directiveStart=o,e.directiveEnd=o+t,e.providerIndexes=o}function wd(e,o,t,a,n){e.data[a]=n;const s=n.factory||(n.factory=Ko(n.type)),i=new ra(s,Qe(n),null);e.blueprint[a]=i,t[a]=i,fd(e,o,0,a,St(e,t,n.hostVars,C),n)}function Mw(e,o,t){const a=Ge(o,e),n=pd(t),s=e[10],i=Pn(e,Aa(e,n,null,t.onPush?64:16,a,o,s,s.createRenderer(a,t),null,null));e[o.index]=i}function Lw(e,o,t,a,n,s){const i=s[o];if(null!==i){const r=a.setInput;for(let l=0;l<i.length;){const p=i[l++],h=i[l++],d=i[l++];null!==r?a.setInput(t,d,p,h):t[h]=d}}}function xw(e,o){let t=null,a=0;for(;a<o.length;){const n=o[a];if(0!==n)if(5!==n){if("number"==typeof n)break;e.hasOwnProperty(n)&&(null===t&&(t=[]),t.push(n,e[n],o[a+1])),a+=2}else a+=2;else a+=4}return t}function yd(e,o,t,a){return new Array(e,!0,!1,o,null,0,a,t,null,null)}function Ow(e,o){const t=Ie(o,e);if(Vs(t)){const a=t[1];80&t[2]?Et(a,t,a.template,t[8]):t[5]>0&&Xi(t)}}function Xi(e){for(let a=Di(e);null!==a;a=Ci(a))for(let n=10;n<a.length;n++){const s=a[n];if(1024&s[2]){const i=s[1];Et(i,s,i.template,s[8])}else s[5]>0&&Xi(s)}const t=e[1].components;if(null!==t)for(let a=0;a<t.length;a++){const n=Ie(t[a],e);Vs(n)&&n[5]>0&&Xi(n)}}function Pw(e,o){const t=Ie(o,e),a=t[1];(function Nw(e,o){for(let t=o.length;t<e.blueprint.length;t++)o.push(e.blueprint[t])})(a,t),Da(a,t,t[8])}function Pn(e,o){return e[13]?e[14][4]=o:e[13]=o,e[14]=o,o}function or(e,o,t){const a=o[10];a.begin&&a.begin();try{Et(e,o,e.template,t)}catch(n){throw function Ad(e,o){const t=e[9],a=t?t.get(Tt,null):null;a&&a.handleError(o)}(o,n),n}finally{a.end&&a.end()}}function vd(e){!function er(e){for(let o=0;o<e.components.length;o++){const t=e.components[o],a=vi(t),n=a[1];mw(n,a,n.template,t)}}(e[8])}function tr(e,o,t){Xs(0),o(e,t)}const jw=(()=>Promise.resolve(null))();function Dd(e,o,t,a,n){for(let s=0;s<t.length;){const i=t[s++],r=t[s++],l=o[i],p=e.data[i];null!==p.setInput?p.setInput(l,n,a,r):l[r]=n}}function Ao(e,o,t){const a=function ln(e,o){return ae(o[e])}(o,e);!function Eh(e,o,t){X(e)?e.setValue(o,t):o.textContent=t}(e[I],a,t)}function Nn(e,o,t){let a=t?e.styles:null,n=t?e.classes:null,s=0;if(null!==o)for(let i=0;i<o.length;i++){const r=o[i];"number"==typeof r?s=r:1==s?n=Es(n,r):2==s&&(a=Es(a,r+": "+o[++i]+";"))}t?e.styles=a:e.stylesWithoutHost=a,t?e.classes=n:e.classesWithoutHost=n}const ar=new B("INJECTOR",-1);class Cd{get(o,t=_a){if(t===_a){const a=new Error(`NullInjectorError: No provider for ${N(o)}!`);throw a.name="NullInjectorError",a}return t}}const nr=new B("Set Injector scope."),Ca={},Vw={};let sr;function Sd(){return void 0===sr&&(sr=new Cd),sr}function Ed(e,o=null,t=null,a){const n=Id(e,o,t,a);return n._resolveInjectorDefTypes(),n}function Id(e,o=null,t=null,a){return new zw(e,t,o||Sd(),a)}class zw{constructor(o,t,a,n=null){this.parent=a,this.records=new Map,this.injectorDefTypes=new Set,this.onDestroy=new Set,this._destroyed=!1;const s=[];t&&ho(t,r=>this.processProvider(r,o,t)),ho([o],r=>this.processInjectorType(r,[],s)),this.records.set(ar,It(void 0,this));const i=this.records.get(nr);this.scope=null!=i?i.value:null,this.source=n||("object"==typeof o?null:N(o))}get destroyed(){return this._destroyed}destroy(){this.assertNotDestroyed(),this._destroyed=!0;try{this.onDestroy.forEach(o=>o.ngOnDestroy())}finally{this.records.clear(),this.onDestroy.clear(),this.injectorDefTypes.clear()}}get(o,t=_a,a=E.Default){this.assertNotDestroyed();const n=Xp(this),s=Io(void 0);try{if(!(a&E.SkipSelf)){let r=this.records.get(o);if(void 0===r){const l=function oy(e){return"function"==typeof e||"object"==typeof e&&e instanceof B}(o)&&Ms(o);r=l&&this.injectableDefInScope(l)?It(ir(o),Ca):null,this.records.set(o,r)}if(null!=r)return this.hydrate(o,r)}return(a&E.Self?Sd():this.parent).get(o,t=a&E.Optional&&t===_a?null:t)}catch(i){if("NullInjectorError"===i.name){if((i[Tn]=i[Tn]||[]).unshift(N(o)),n)throw i;return function Eb(e,o,t,a){const n=e[Tn];throw o[Zp]&&n.unshift(o[Zp]),e.message=function Ib(e,o,t,a=null){e=e&&"\n"===e.charAt(0)&&"\u0275"==e.charAt(1)?e.substr(2):e;let n=N(o);if(Array.isArray(o))n=o.map(N).join(" -> ");else if("object"==typeof o){let s=[];for(let i in o)if(o.hasOwnProperty(i)){let r=o[i];s.push(i+":"+("string"==typeof r?JSON.stringify(r):N(r)))}n=`{${s.join(", ")}}`}return`${t}${a?"("+a+")":""}[${n}]: ${e.replace(Tb,"\n  ")}`}("\n"+e.message,n,t,a),e.ngTokenPath=n,e[Tn]=null,e}(i,o,"R3InjectorError",this.source)}throw i}finally{Io(s),Xp(n)}}_resolveInjectorDefTypes(){this.injectorDefTypes.forEach(o=>this.get(o))}toString(){const o=[];return this.records.forEach((a,n)=>o.push(N(n))),`R3Injector[${o.join(", ")}]`}assertNotDestroyed(){if(this._destroyed)throw new P(205,"")}processInjectorType(o,t,a){if(!(o=S(o)))return!1;let n=ip(o);const s=null==n&&o.ngModule||void 0,i=void 0===s?o:s,r=-1!==a.indexOf(i);if(void 0!==s&&(n=ip(s)),null==n)return!1;if(null!=n.imports&&!r){let h;a.push(i);try{ho(n.imports,d=>{this.processInjectorType(d,t,a)&&(void 0===h&&(h=[]),h.push(d))})}finally{}if(void 0!==h)for(let d=0;d<h.length;d++){const{ngModule:c,providers:u}=h[d];ho(u,_=>this.processProvider(_,c,u||j))}}this.injectorDefTypes.add(i);const l=Ko(i)||(()=>new i);this.records.set(i,It(l,Ca));const p=n.providers;if(null!=p&&!r){const h=o;ho(p,d=>this.processProvider(d,h,p))}return void 0!==s&&void 0!==o.providers}processProvider(o,t,a){let n=Rt(o=S(o))?o:S(o&&o.provide);const s=function Kw(e,o,t){return Md(e)?It(void 0,e.useValue):It(function Rd(e,o,t){let a;if(Rt(e)){const n=S(e);return Ko(n)||ir(n)}if(Md(e))a=()=>S(e.useValue);else if(function Zw(e){return!(!e||!e.useFactory)}(e))a=()=>e.useFactory(...ci(e.deps||[]));else if(function Qw(e){return!(!e||!e.useExisting)}(e))a=()=>Y(S(e.useExisting));else{const n=S(e&&(e.useClass||e.provide));if(!function Jw(e){return!!e.deps}(e))return Ko(n)||ir(n);a=()=>new n(...ci(e.deps))}return a}(e),Ca)}(o);if(Rt(o)||!0!==o.multi)this.records.get(n);else{let i=this.records.get(n);i||(i=It(void 0,Ca,!0),i.factory=()=>ci(i.multi),this.records.set(n,i)),n=o,i.multi.push(o)}this.records.set(n,s)}hydrate(o,t){return t.value===Ca&&(t.value=Vw,t.value=t.factory()),"object"==typeof t.value&&t.value&&function ey(e){return null!==e&&"object"==typeof e&&"function"==typeof e.ngOnDestroy}(t.value)&&this.onDestroy.add(t.value),t.value}injectableDefInScope(o){if(!o.providedIn)return!1;const t=S(o.providedIn);return"string"==typeof t?"any"===t||t===this.scope:this.injectorDefTypes.has(t)}}function ir(e){const o=Ms(e),t=null!==o?o.factory:Ko(e);if(null!==t)return t;if(e instanceof B)throw new P(204,"");if(e instanceof Function)return function $w(e){const o=e.length;if(o>0)throw function ua(e,o){const t=[];for(let a=0;a<e;a++)t.push(o);return t}(o,"?"),new P(204,"");const t=function hg(e){const o=e&&(e[Ja]||e[rp]);if(o){const t=function dg(e){if(e.hasOwnProperty("name"))return e.name;const o=(""+e).match(/^function\s*([^\s(]+)/);return null===o?"":o[1]}(e);return console.warn(`DEPRECATED: DI is instantiating a token "${t}" that inherits its @Injectable decorator but does not provide one itself.\nThis will become an error in a future version of Angular. Please add @Injectable() to the "${t}" class.`),o}return null}(e);return null!==t?()=>t.factory(e):()=>new e}(e);throw new P(204,"")}function It(e,o,t=!1){return{factory:e,value:o,multi:t?[]:void 0}}function Md(e){return null!==e&&"object"==typeof e&&Db in e}function Rt(e){return"function"==typeof e}let je=(()=>{class e{static create(t,a){var n;if(Array.isArray(t))return Ed({name:""},a,t,"");{const s=null!==(n=t.name)&&void 0!==n?n:"";return Ed({name:s},t.parent,t.providers,s)}}}return e.THROW_IF_NOT_FOUND=_a,e.NULL=new Cd,e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,providedIn:"any",factory:()=>Y(ar)}),e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=-1,e})();function py(e,o){un(vi(e)[1],re())}let Bn=null;function Mt(){if(!Bn){const e=G.Symbol;if(e&&e.iterator)Bn=e.iterator;else{const o=Object.getOwnPropertyNames(Map.prototype);for(let t=0;t<o.length;++t){const a=o[t];"entries"!==a&&"size"!==a&&Map.prototype[a]===Map.prototype.entries&&(Bn=a)}}}return Bn}function Sa(e){return!!hr(e)&&(Array.isArray(e)||!(e instanceof Map)&&Mt()in e)}function hr(e){return null!==e&&("function"==typeof e||"object"==typeof e)}function fe(e,o,t){return!Object.is(e[o],t)&&(e[o]=t,!0)}function x(e,o=E.Default){const t=b();return null===t?Y(e,o):Gp(re(),t,S(e),o)}function Xo(e,o,t){const a=b();return fe(a,ct(),o)&&function Le(e,o,t,a,n,s,i,r){const l=Ge(o,t);let h,p=o.inputs;!r&&null!=p&&(h=p[a])?(Dd(e,t,h,a,n),nn(o)&&function qw(e,o){const t=Ie(o,e);16&t[2]||(t[2]|=64)}(t,o.index)):3&o.type&&(a=function kw(e){return"class"===e?"className":"for"===e?"htmlFor":"formaction"===e?"formAction":"innerHtml"===e?"innerHTML":"readonly"===e?"readOnly":"tabindex"===e?"tabIndex":e}(a),n=null!=i?i(n,o.value||"",a):n,X(s)?s.setProperty(l,a,n):oi(a)||(l.setProperty?l.setProperty(a,n):l[a]=n))}(W(),function J(){const e=A.lFrame;return Ys(e.tView,e.selectedIndex)}(),a,e,o,a[I],t,!1),Xo}function fr(e,o,t,a,n){const i=n?"class":"style";Dd(e,t,o.inputs[i],i,a)}function xe(e,o,t,a){const n=b(),s=W(),i=H+e,r=n[I],l=n[i]=Ei(r,o,function Jg(){return A.lFrame.currentNamespace}()),p=s.firstCreatePass?function jy(e,o,t,a,n,s,i){const r=o.consts,p=Ct(o,e,2,n,Lo(r,s));return Qi(o,t,p,Lo(r,i)),null!==p.attrs&&Nn(p,p.attrs,!1),null!==p.mergedAttrs&&Nn(p,p.mergedAttrs,!0),null!==o.queries&&o.queries.elementStart(o,p),p}(i,s,n,0,o,t,a):s.data[i];po(p,!0);const h=p.mergedAttrs;null!==h&&gn(r,l,h);const d=p.classes;null!==d&&Fi(r,l,d);const c=p.styles;null!==c&&jh(r,l,c),64!=(64&p.flags)&&Mn(s,n,l,p),0===function Wg(){return A.lFrame.elementDepthCount}()&&_e(l,n),function Og(){A.lFrame.elementDepthCount++}(),sn(p)&&($i(s,n,p),function ld(e,o,t){if(Bs(o)){const n=o.directiveEnd;for(let s=o.directiveStart;s<n;s++){const i=e.data[s];i.contentQueries&&i.contentQueries(1,t[s],s)}}}(s,p,n)),null!==a&&Ki(n,p)}function Fe(){let e=re();$s()?function Ks(){A.lFrame.isParent=!1}():(e=e.parent,po(e,!1));const o=e;!function Pg(){A.lFrame.elementDepthCount--}();const t=W();t.firstCreatePass&&(un(t,e),Bs(e)&&t.queries.elementEnd(e)),null!=o.classesWithoutHost&&function nb(e){return 0!=(16&e.flags)}(o)&&fr(t,o,b(),o.classesWithoutHost,!0),null!=o.stylesWithoutHost&&function sb(e){return 0!=(32&e.flags)}(o)&&fr(t,o,b(),o.stylesWithoutHost,!1)}function gr(e){return!!e&&"function"==typeof e.then}const $y=function fc(e){return!!e&&"function"==typeof e.subscribe};function No(e,o=""){const t=b(),a=W(),n=e+H,s=a.firstCreatePass?Ct(a,n,1,o,null):a.data[n],i=t[n]=function Si(e,o){return X(e)?e.createText(o):e.createTextNode(o)}(t[I],o);Mn(a,t,i,s),po(s,!1)}function Jo(e){return yr("",e,""),Jo}function yr(e,o,t){const a=b(),n=function xt(e,o,t,a){return fe(e,ct(),t)?o+D(t)+a:C}(a,e,o,t);return n!==C&&Ao(a,we(),n),yr}const et=void 0;var Ov=["en",[["a","p"],["AM","PM"],et],[["AM","PM"],et,et],[["S","M","T","W","T","F","S"],["Sun","Mon","Tue","Wed","Thu","Fri","Sat"],["Sunday","Monday","Tuesday","Wednesday","Thursday","Friday","Saturday"],["Su","Mo","Tu","We","Th","Fr","Sa"]],et,[["J","F","M","A","M","J","J","A","S","O","N","D"],["Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],["January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"]],et,[["B","A"],["BC","AD"],["Before Christ","Anno Domini"]],0,[6,0],["M/d/yy","MMM d, y","MMMM d, y","EEEE, MMMM d, y"],["h:mm a","h:mm:ss a","h:mm:ss a z","h:mm:ss a zzzz"],["{1}, {0}",et,"{1} 'at' {0}",et],[".",",",";","%","+","-","E","\xd7","\u2030","\u221e","NaN",":"],["#,##0.###","#,##0%","\xa4#,##0.00","#E0"],"USD","$","US Dollar",{},"ltr",function Wv(e){const t=Math.floor(Math.abs(e)),a=e.toString().replace(/^[^.]*\.?/,"").length;return 1===t&&0===a?1:5}];let Ht={};function hu(e){return e in Ht||(Ht[e]=G.ng&&G.ng.common&&G.ng.common.locales&&G.ng.common.locales[e]),Ht[e]}var v=(()=>((v=v||{})[v.LocaleId=0]="LocaleId",v[v.DayPeriodsFormat=1]="DayPeriodsFormat",v[v.DayPeriodsStandalone=2]="DayPeriodsStandalone",v[v.DaysFormat=3]="DaysFormat",v[v.DaysStandalone=4]="DaysStandalone",v[v.MonthsFormat=5]="MonthsFormat",v[v.MonthsStandalone=6]="MonthsStandalone",v[v.Eras=7]="Eras",v[v.FirstDayOfWeek=8]="FirstDayOfWeek",v[v.WeekendRange=9]="WeekendRange",v[v.DateFormat=10]="DateFormat",v[v.TimeFormat=11]="TimeFormat",v[v.DateTimeFormat=12]="DateTimeFormat",v[v.NumberSymbols=13]="NumberSymbols",v[v.NumberFormats=14]="NumberFormats",v[v.CurrencyCode=15]="CurrencyCode",v[v.CurrencySymbol=16]="CurrencySymbol",v[v.CurrencyName=17]="CurrencyName",v[v.Currencies=18]="Currencies",v[v.Directionality=19]="Directionality",v[v.PluralCase=20]="PluralCase",v[v.ExtraData=21]="ExtraData",v))();const Hn="en-US";let du=Hn;class Wu{}class G0{resolveComponentFactory(o){throw function B0(e){const o=Error(`No component factory found for ${N(e)}. Did you add it to @NgModule.entryComponents?`);return o.ngComponent=e,o}(o)}}let Fa=(()=>{class e{}return e.NULL=new G0,e})();function U0(){return Vt(re(),b())}function Vt(e,o){return new zt(Ge(e,o))}let zt=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){this.nativeElement=t}}return e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=U0,e})();class Pu{}let Nu=(()=>{class e{}return e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=()=>function Y0(){const e=b(),t=Ie(re().index,e);return function H0(e){return e[I]}(lo(t)?t:e)}(),e})(),V0=(()=>{class e{}return e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,providedIn:"root",factory:()=>null}),e})();class Cr{constructor(o){this.full=o,this.major=o.split(".")[0],this.minor=o.split(".")[1],this.patch=o.split(".").slice(2).join(".")}}const z0=new Cr("13.1.3"),Sr={};function Kn(e,o,t,a,n=!1){for(;null!==t;){const s=o[t.index];if(null!==s&&a.push(ae(s)),Ke(s))for(let r=10;r<s.length;r++){const l=s[r],p=l[1].firstChild;null!==p&&Kn(l[1],l,p,a)}const i=t.type;if(8&i)Kn(e,o,t.child,a);else if(32&i){const r=Ai(t,o);let l;for(;l=r();)a.push(l)}else if(16&i){const r=Bh(o,t);if(Array.isArray(r))a.push(...r);else{const l=qa(o[16]);Kn(l[1],l,r,a,!0)}}t=n?t.projectionNext:t.next}return a}class Wa{constructor(o,t){this._lView=o,this._cdRefInjectingView=t,this._appRef=null,this._attachedToViewContainer=!1}get rootNodes(){const o=this._lView,t=o[1];return Kn(t,o,t.firstChild,[])}get context(){return this._lView[8]}set context(o){this._lView[8]=o}get destroyed(){return 256==(256&this._lView[2])}destroy(){if(this._appRef)this._appRef.detachView(this);else if(this._attachedToViewContainer){const o=this._lView[3];if(Ke(o)){const t=o[8],a=t?t.indexOf(this):-1;a>-1&&(Ii(o,a),kn(t,a))}this._attachedToViewContainer=!1}Rh(this._lView[1],this._lView)}onDestroy(o){!function cd(e,o,t,a){const n=function kd(e){return e[7]||(e[7]=[])}(o);null===t?n.push(a):(n.push(t),e.firstCreatePass&&function qd(e){return e.cleanup||(e.cleanup=[])}(e).push(a,n.length-1))}(this._lView[1],this._lView,null,o)}markForCheck(){!function Ji(e){for(;e;){e[2]|=64;const o=qa(e);if(qg(e)&&!o)return e;e=o}return null}(this._cdRefInjectingView||this._lView)}detach(){this._lView[2]&=-129}reattach(){this._lView[2]|=128}detectChanges(){or(this._lView[1],this._lView,this.context)}checkNoChanges(){!function Gw(e,o,t){hn(!0);try{or(e,o,t)}finally{hn(!1)}}(this._lView[1],this._lView,this.context)}attachToViewContainerRef(){if(this._appRef)throw new P(902,"");this._attachedToViewContainer=!0}detachFromAppRef(){this._appRef=null,function Om(e,o){Ta(e,o,o[I],2,null,null)}(this._lView[1],this._lView)}attachToAppRef(o){if(this._attachedToViewContainer)throw new P(902,"");this._appRef=o}}class $0 extends Wa{constructor(o){super(o),this._view=o}detectChanges(){vd(this._view)}checkNoChanges(){!function Uw(e){hn(!0);try{vd(e)}finally{hn(!1)}}(this._view)}get context(){return null}}class Bu extends Fa{constructor(o){super(),this.ngModule=o}resolveComponentFactory(o){const t=ce(o);return new Er(t,this.ngModule)}}function Gu(e){const o=[];for(let t in e)e.hasOwnProperty(t)&&o.push({propName:e[t],templateName:t});return o}const Q0=new B("SCHEDULER_TOKEN",{providedIn:"root",factory:()=>qh});class Er extends Wu{constructor(o,t){super(),this.componentDef=o,this.ngModule=t,this.componentType=o.type,this.selector=function aw(e){return e.map(tw).join(",")}(o.selectors),this.ngContentSelectors=o.ngContentSelectors?o.ngContentSelectors:[],this.isBoundToModule=!!t}get inputs(){return Gu(this.componentDef.inputs)}get outputs(){return Gu(this.componentDef.outputs)}create(o,t,a,n){const s=(n=n||this.ngModule)?function Z0(e,o){return{get:(t,a,n)=>{const s=e.get(t,Sr,n);return s!==Sr||a===Sr?s:o.get(t,a,n)}}}(o,n.injector):o,i=s.get(Pu,yp),r=s.get(V0,null),l=i.createRenderer(null,this.componentDef),p=this.componentDef.selectors[0][0]||"div",h=a?function dd(e,o,t){if(X(e))return e.selectRootElement(o,t===ro.ShadowDom);let a="string"==typeof o?e.querySelector(o):o;return a.textContent="",a}(l,a,this.componentDef.encapsulation):Ei(i.createRenderer(null,this.componentDef),p,function K0(e){const o=e.toLowerCase();return"svg"===o?"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg":"math"===o?"http://www.w3.org/1998/MathML/":null}(p)),d=this.componentDef.onPush?576:528,c=function jd(e,o){return{components:[],scheduler:e||qh,clean:jw,playerHandler:o||null,flags:0}}(),u=On(0,null,null,1,0,null,null,null,null,null),_=Aa(null,u,c,d,null,null,i,l,r,s);let g,m;dn(_);try{const w=function Gd(e,o,t,a,n,s){const i=t[1];t[20]=e;const l=Ct(i,20,2,"#host",null),p=l.mergedAttrs=o.hostAttrs;null!==p&&(Nn(l,p,!0),null!==e&&(gn(n,e,p),null!==l.classes&&Fi(n,e,l.classes),null!==l.styles&&jh(n,e,l.styles)));const h=a.createRenderer(e,o),d=Aa(t,pd(o),null,o.onPush?64:16,t[20],l,a,h,s||null,null);return i.firstCreatePass&&(yn(pa(l,t),i,o.type),bd(i,l),md(l,t.length,1)),Pn(t,d),t[20]=d}(h,this.componentDef,_,i,l);if(h)if(a)gn(l,h,["ng-version",z0.full]);else{const{attrs:f,classes:k}=function nw(e){const o=[],t=[];let a=1,n=2;for(;a<e.length;){let s=e[a];if("string"==typeof s)2===n?""!==s&&o.push(s,e[++a]):8===n&&t.push(s);else{if(!Ze(n))break;n=s}a++}return{attrs:o,classes:t}}(this.componentDef.selectors[0]);f&&gn(l,h,f),k&&k.length>0&&Fi(l,h,k.join(" "))}if(m=Ys(u,H),void 0!==t){const f=m.projection=[];for(let k=0;k<this.ngContentSelectors.length;k++){const M=t[k];f.push(null!=M?Array.from(M):null)}}g=function Ud(e,o,t,a,n){const s=t[1],i=function Aw(e,o,t){const a=re();e.firstCreatePass&&(t.providersResolver&&t.providersResolver(t),wd(e,a,o,St(e,o,1,null),t));const n=ha(o,e,a.directiveStart,a);_e(n,o);const s=Ge(a,o);return s&&_e(s,o),n}(s,t,o);if(a.components.push(i),e[8]=i,n&&n.forEach(l=>l(i,o)),o.contentQueries){const l=re();o.contentQueries(1,i,l.directiveStart)}const r=re();return!s.firstCreatePass||null===o.hostBindings&&null===o.hostAttrs||(xo(r.index),fd(t[1],r,0,r.directiveStart,r.directiveEnd,o),gd(o,i)),i}(w,this.componentDef,_,c,[py]),Da(u,_,null)}finally{cn()}return new J0(this.componentType,g,Vt(m,_),_,m)}}class J0 extends class N0{}{constructor(o,t,a,n,s){super(),this.location=a,this._rootLView=n,this._tNode=s,this.instance=t,this.hostView=this.changeDetectorRef=new $0(n),this.componentType=o}get injector(){return new ft(this._tNode,this._rootLView)}destroy(){this.hostView.destroy()}onDestroy(o){this.hostView.onDestroy(o)}}class $t{}const Kt=new Map;class Hu extends $t{constructor(o,t){super(),this._parent=t,this._bootstrapComponents=[],this.injector=this,this.destroyCbs=[],this.componentFactoryResolver=new Bu(this);const a=Pe(o);this._bootstrapComponents=uo(a.bootstrap),this._r3Injector=Id(o,t,[{provide:$t,useValue:this},{provide:Fa,useValue:this.componentFactoryResolver}],N(o)),this._r3Injector._resolveInjectorDefTypes(),this.instance=this.get(o)}get(o,t=je.THROW_IF_NOT_FOUND,a=E.Default){return o===je||o===$t||o===ar?this:this._r3Injector.get(o,t,a)}destroy(){const o=this._r3Injector;!o.destroyed&&o.destroy(),this.destroyCbs.forEach(t=>t()),this.destroyCbs=null}onDestroy(o){this.destroyCbs.push(o)}}class Ir extends class ok{}{constructor(o){super(),this.moduleType=o,null!==Pe(o)&&function tk(e){const o=new Set;!function t(a){const n=Pe(a,!0),s=n.id;null!==s&&(function Uu(e,o,t){if(o&&o!==t)throw new Error(`Duplicate module registered for ${e} - ${N(o)} vs ${N(o.name)}`)}(s,Kt.get(s),a),Kt.set(s,a));const i=uo(n.imports);for(const r of i)o.has(r)||(o.add(r),t(r))}(e)}(o)}create(o){return new Hu(this.moduleType,o)}}function Rr(e){return o=>{setTimeout(e,void 0,o)}}const Do=class yk extends qs{constructor(o=!1){super(),this.__isAsync=o}emit(o){super.next(o)}subscribe(o,t,a){var n,s,i;let r=o,l=t||(()=>null),p=a;if(o&&"object"==typeof o){const d=o;r=null===(n=d.next)||void 0===n?void 0:n.bind(d),l=null===(s=d.error)||void 0===s?void 0:s.bind(d),p=null===(i=d.complete)||void 0===i?void 0:i.bind(d)}this.__isAsync&&(l=Rr(l),r&&(r=Rr(r)),p&&(p=Rr(p)));const h=super.subscribe({next:r,error:l,complete:p});return o instanceof io&&o.add(h),h}};Symbol;let Co=(()=>{class e{}return e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=Tk,e})();const kk=Co,qk=class extends kk{constructor(o,t,a){super(),this._declarationLView=o,this._declarationTContainer=t,this.elementRef=a}createEmbeddedView(o){const t=this._declarationTContainer.tViews,a=Aa(this._declarationLView,t,o,16,null,t.declTNode,null,null,null,null);a[17]=this._declarationLView[this._declarationTContainer.index];const s=this._declarationLView[19];return null!==s&&(a[19]=s.createEmbeddedView(t)),Da(t,a,o),new Wa(a)}};function Tk(){return function Qn(e,o){return 4&e.type?new qk(o,e,Vt(e,o)):null}(re(),b())}let mo=(()=>{class e{}return e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=Ak,e})();function Ak(){return function Xu(e,o){let t;const a=o[e.index];if(Ke(a))t=a;else{let n;if(8&e.type)n=ae(a);else{const s=o[I];n=s.createComment("");const i=Ge(e,o);Qo(s,Rn(s,i),n,function Hm(e,o){return X(e)?e.nextSibling(o):o.nextSibling}(s,i),!1)}o[e.index]=t=yd(a,o,n,e),Pn(o,t)}return new Qu(t,e,o)}(re(),b())}const Dk=mo,Qu=class extends Dk{constructor(o,t,a){super(),this._lContainer=o,this._hostTNode=t,this._hostLView=a}get element(){return Vt(this._hostTNode,this._hostLView)}get injector(){return new ft(this._hostTNode,this._hostLView)}get parentInjector(){const o=wn(this._hostTNode,this._hostLView);if(Wp(o)){const t=_t(o,this._hostLView),a=ut(o);return new ft(t[1].data[a+8],t)}return new ft(null,this._hostLView)}clear(){for(;this.length>0;)this.remove(this.length-1)}get(o){const t=Zu(this._lContainer);return null!==t&&t[o]||null}get length(){return this._lContainer.length-10}createEmbeddedView(o,t,a){const n=o.createEmbeddedView(t||{});return this.insert(n,a),n}createComponent(o,t,a,n,s){const i=o&&!function ca(e){return"function"==typeof e}(o);let r;if(i)r=t;else{const d=t||{};r=d.index,a=d.injector,n=d.projectableNodes,s=d.ngModuleRef}const l=i?o:new Er(ce(o)),p=a||this.parentInjector;if(!s&&null==l.ngModule&&p){const d=p.get($t,null);d&&(s=d)}const h=l.create(p,n,void 0,s);return this.insert(h.hostView,r),h}insert(o,t){const a=o._lView,n=a[1];if(function Fg(e){return Ke(e[3])}(a)){const h=this.indexOf(o);if(-1!==h)this.detach(h);else{const d=a[3],c=new Qu(d,d[6],d[3]);c.detach(c.indexOf(o))}}const s=this._adjustIndex(t),i=this._lContainer;!function Nm(e,o,t,a){const n=10+a,s=t.length;a>0&&(t[n-1][4]=o),a<s-10?(o[4]=t[n],Vp(t,10+a,o)):(t.push(o),o[4]=null),o[3]=t;const i=o[17];null!==i&&t!==i&&function Bm(e,o){const t=e[9];o[16]!==o[3][3][16]&&(e[2]=!0),null===t?e[9]=[o]:t.push(o)}(i,o);const r=o[19];null!==r&&r.insertView(e),o[2]|=128}(n,a,i,s);const r=Li(s,i),l=a[I],p=Rn(l,i[7]);return null!==p&&function Wm(e,o,t,a,n,s){a[0]=n,a[6]=o,Ta(e,a,t,1,n,s)}(n,i[6],l,a,p,r),o.attachToViewContainerRef(),Vp(Lr(i),s,o),o}move(o,t){return this.insert(o,t)}indexOf(o){const t=Zu(this._lContainer);return null!==t?t.indexOf(o):-1}remove(o){const t=this._adjustIndex(o,-1),a=Ii(this._lContainer,t);a&&(kn(Lr(this._lContainer),t),Rh(a[1],a))}detach(o){const t=this._adjustIndex(o,-1),a=Ii(this._lContainer,t);return a&&null!=kn(Lr(this._lContainer),t)?new Wa(a):null}_adjustIndex(o,t=0){return null==o?this.length+t:o}};function Zu(e){return e[8]}function Lr(e){return e[8]||(e[8]=[])}function Jn(...e){}const Hr=new B("Application Initializer");let Zt=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){this.appInits=t,this.resolve=Jn,this.reject=Jn,this.initialized=!1,this.done=!1,this.donePromise=new Promise((a,n)=>{this.resolve=a,this.reject=n})}runInitializers(){if(this.initialized)return;const t=[],a=()=>{this.done=!0,this.resolve()};if(this.appInits)for(let n=0;n<this.appInits.length;n++){const s=this.appInits[n]();if(gr(s))t.push(s);else if($y(s)){const i=new Promise((r,l)=>{s.subscribe({complete:r,error:l})});t.push(i)}}Promise.all(t).then(()=>{a()}).catch(n=>{this.reject(n)}),0===t.length&&a(),this.initialized=!0}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(Hr,8))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const Ba=new B("AppId"),aq={provide:Ba,useFactory:function tq(){return`${Yr()}${Yr()}${Yr()}`},deps:[]};function Yr(){return String.fromCharCode(97+Math.floor(25*Math.random()))}const y_=new B("Platform Initializer"),Vr=new B("Platform ID"),nq=new B("appBootstrapListener");let sq=(()=>{class e{log(t){console.log(t)}warn(t){console.warn(t)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const Bo=new B("LocaleId"),v_=new B("DefaultCurrencyCode");class iq{constructor(o,t){this.ngModuleFactory=o,this.componentFactories=t}}let k_=(()=>{class e{compileModuleSync(t){return new Ir(t)}compileModuleAsync(t){return Promise.resolve(this.compileModuleSync(t))}compileModuleAndAllComponentsSync(t){const a=this.compileModuleSync(t),s=uo(Pe(t).declarations).reduce((i,r)=>{const l=ce(r);return l&&i.push(new Er(l)),i},[]);return new iq(a,s)}compileModuleAndAllComponentsAsync(t){return Promise.resolve(this.compileModuleAndAllComponentsSync(t))}clearCache(){}clearCacheFor(t){}getModuleId(t){}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const lq=(()=>Promise.resolve(0))();function zr(e){"undefined"==typeof Zone?lq.then(()=>{e&&e.apply(null,null)}):Zone.current.scheduleMicroTask("scheduleMicrotask",e)}class ge{constructor({enableLongStackTrace:o=!1,shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection:t=!1,shouldCoalesceRunChangeDetection:a=!1}){if(this.hasPendingMacrotasks=!1,this.hasPendingMicrotasks=!1,this.isStable=!0,this.onUnstable=new Do(!1),this.onMicrotaskEmpty=new Do(!1),this.onStable=new Do(!1),this.onError=new Do(!1),"undefined"==typeof Zone)throw new Error("In this configuration Angular requires Zone.js");Zone.assertZonePatched();const n=this;n._nesting=0,n._outer=n._inner=Zone.current,Zone.TaskTrackingZoneSpec&&(n._inner=n._inner.fork(new Zone.TaskTrackingZoneSpec)),o&&Zone.longStackTraceZoneSpec&&(n._inner=n._inner.fork(Zone.longStackTraceZoneSpec)),n.shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection=!a&&t,n.shouldCoalesceRunChangeDetection=a,n.lastRequestAnimationFrameId=-1,n.nativeRequestAnimationFrame=function pq(){let e=G.requestAnimationFrame,o=G.cancelAnimationFrame;if("undefined"!=typeof Zone&&e&&o){const t=e[Zone.__symbol__("OriginalDelegate")];t&&(e=t);const a=o[Zone.__symbol__("OriginalDelegate")];a&&(o=a)}return{nativeRequestAnimationFrame:e,nativeCancelAnimationFrame:o}}().nativeRequestAnimationFrame,function cq(e){const o=()=>{!function dq(e){e.isCheckStableRunning||-1!==e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId||(e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId=e.nativeRequestAnimationFrame.call(G,()=>{e.fakeTopEventTask||(e.fakeTopEventTask=Zone.root.scheduleEventTask("fakeTopEventTask",()=>{e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId=-1,Kr(e),e.isCheckStableRunning=!0,$r(e),e.isCheckStableRunning=!1},void 0,()=>{},()=>{})),e.fakeTopEventTask.invoke()}),Kr(e))}(e)};e._inner=e._inner.fork({name:"angular",properties:{isAngularZone:!0},onInvokeTask:(t,a,n,s,i,r)=>{try{return q_(e),t.invokeTask(n,s,i,r)}finally{(e.shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection&&"eventTask"===s.type||e.shouldCoalesceRunChangeDetection)&&o(),T_(e)}},onInvoke:(t,a,n,s,i,r,l)=>{try{return q_(e),t.invoke(n,s,i,r,l)}finally{e.shouldCoalesceRunChangeDetection&&o(),T_(e)}},onHasTask:(t,a,n,s)=>{t.hasTask(n,s),a===n&&("microTask"==s.change?(e._hasPendingMicrotasks=s.microTask,Kr(e),$r(e)):"macroTask"==s.change&&(e.hasPendingMacrotasks=s.macroTask))},onHandleError:(t,a,n,s)=>(t.handleError(n,s),e.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.onError.emit(s)),!1)})}(n)}static isInAngularZone(){return!0===Zone.current.get("isAngularZone")}static assertInAngularZone(){if(!ge.isInAngularZone())throw new Error("Expected to be in Angular Zone, but it is not!")}static assertNotInAngularZone(){if(ge.isInAngularZone())throw new Error("Expected to not be in Angular Zone, but it is!")}run(o,t,a){return this._inner.run(o,t,a)}runTask(o,t,a,n){const s=this._inner,i=s.scheduleEventTask("NgZoneEvent: "+n,o,hq,Jn,Jn);try{return s.runTask(i,t,a)}finally{s.cancelTask(i)}}runGuarded(o,t,a){return this._inner.runGuarded(o,t,a)}runOutsideAngular(o){return this._outer.run(o)}}const hq={};function $r(e){if(0==e._nesting&&!e.hasPendingMicrotasks&&!e.isStable)try{e._nesting++,e.onMicrotaskEmpty.emit(null)}finally{if(e._nesting--,!e.hasPendingMicrotasks)try{e.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.onStable.emit(null))}finally{e.isStable=!0}}}function Kr(e){e.hasPendingMicrotasks=!!(e._hasPendingMicrotasks||(e.shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection||e.shouldCoalesceRunChangeDetection)&&-1!==e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId)}function q_(e){e._nesting++,e.isStable&&(e.isStable=!1,e.onUnstable.emit(null))}function T_(e){e._nesting--,$r(e)}class uq{constructor(){this.hasPendingMicrotasks=!1,this.hasPendingMacrotasks=!1,this.isStable=!0,this.onUnstable=new Do,this.onMicrotaskEmpty=new Do,this.onStable=new Do,this.onError=new Do}run(o,t,a){return o.apply(t,a)}runGuarded(o,t,a){return o.apply(t,a)}runOutsideAngular(o){return o()}runTask(o,t,a,n){return o.apply(t,a)}}let Qr=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){this._ngZone=t,this._pendingCount=0,this._isZoneStable=!0,this._didWork=!1,this._callbacks=[],this.taskTrackingZone=null,this._watchAngularEvents(),t.run(()=>{this.taskTrackingZone="undefined"==typeof Zone?null:Zone.current.get("TaskTrackingZone")})}_watchAngularEvents(){this._ngZone.onUnstable.subscribe({next:()=>{this._didWork=!0,this._isZoneStable=!1}}),this._ngZone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{this._ngZone.onStable.subscribe({next:()=>{ge.assertNotInAngularZone(),zr(()=>{this._isZoneStable=!0,this._runCallbacksIfReady()})}})})}increasePendingRequestCount(){return this._pendingCount+=1,this._didWork=!0,this._pendingCount}decreasePendingRequestCount(){if(this._pendingCount-=1,this._pendingCount<0)throw new Error("pending async requests below zero");return this._runCallbacksIfReady(),this._pendingCount}isStable(){return this._isZoneStable&&0===this._pendingCount&&!this._ngZone.hasPendingMacrotasks}_runCallbacksIfReady(){if(this.isStable())zr(()=>{for(;0!==this._callbacks.length;){let t=this._callbacks.pop();clearTimeout(t.timeoutId),t.doneCb(this._didWork)}this._didWork=!1});else{let t=this.getPendingTasks();this._callbacks=this._callbacks.filter(a=>!a.updateCb||!a.updateCb(t)||(clearTimeout(a.timeoutId),!1)),this._didWork=!0}}getPendingTasks(){return this.taskTrackingZone?this.taskTrackingZone.macroTasks.map(t=>({source:t.source,creationLocation:t.creationLocation,data:t.data})):[]}addCallback(t,a,n){let s=-1;a&&a>0&&(s=setTimeout(()=>{this._callbacks=this._callbacks.filter(i=>i.timeoutId!==s),t(this._didWork,this.getPendingTasks())},a)),this._callbacks.push({doneCb:t,timeoutId:s,updateCb:n})}whenStable(t,a,n){if(n&&!this.taskTrackingZone)throw new Error('Task tracking zone is required when passing an update callback to whenStable(). Is "zone.js/plugins/task-tracking" loaded?');this.addCallback(t,a,n),this._runCallbacksIfReady()}getPendingRequestCount(){return this._pendingCount}findProviders(t,a,n){return[]}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(ge))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})(),A_=(()=>{class e{constructor(){this._applications=new Map,Zr.addToWindow(this)}registerApplication(t,a){this._applications.set(t,a)}unregisterApplication(t){this._applications.delete(t)}unregisterAllApplications(){this._applications.clear()}getTestability(t){return this._applications.get(t)||null}getAllTestabilities(){return Array.from(this._applications.values())}getAllRootElements(){return Array.from(this._applications.keys())}findTestabilityInTree(t,a=!0){return Zr.findTestabilityInTree(this,t,a)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();class _q{addToWindow(o){}findTestabilityInTree(o,t,a){return null}}let ao,Zr=new _q;const D_=new B("AllowMultipleToken");function C_(e,o,t=[]){const a=`Platform: ${o}`,n=new B(a);return(s=[])=>{let i=S_();if(!i||i.injector.get(D_,!1))if(e)e(t.concat(s).concat({provide:n,useValue:!0}));else{const r=t.concat(s).concat({provide:n,useValue:!0},{provide:nr,useValue:"platform"});!function mq(e){if(ao&&!ao.destroyed&&!ao.injector.get(D_,!1))throw new P(400,"");ao=e.get(E_);const o=e.get(y_,null);o&&o.forEach(t=>t())}(je.create({providers:r,name:a}))}return function wq(e){const o=S_();if(!o)throw new P(401,"");return o}()}}function S_(){return ao&&!ao.destroyed?ao:null}let E_=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){this._injector=t,this._modules=[],this._destroyListeners=[],this._destroyed=!1}bootstrapModuleFactory(t,a){const r=function yq(e,o){let t;return t="noop"===e?new uq:("zone.js"===e?void 0:e)||new ge({enableLongStackTrace:!1,shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection:!!(null==o?void 0:o.ngZoneEventCoalescing),shouldCoalesceRunChangeDetection:!!(null==o?void 0:o.ngZoneRunCoalescing)}),t}(a?a.ngZone:void 0,{ngZoneEventCoalescing:a&&a.ngZoneEventCoalescing||!1,ngZoneRunCoalescing:a&&a.ngZoneRunCoalescing||!1}),l=[{provide:ge,useValue:r}];return r.run(()=>{const p=je.create({providers:l,parent:this.injector,name:t.moduleType.name}),h=t.create(p),d=h.injector.get(Tt,null);if(!d)throw new P(402,"");return r.runOutsideAngular(()=>{const c=r.onError.subscribe({next:u=>{d.handleError(u)}});h.onDestroy(()=>{Xr(this._modules,h),c.unsubscribe()})}),function vq(e,o,t){try{const a=t();return gr(a)?a.catch(n=>{throw o.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.handleError(n)),n}):a}catch(a){throw o.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.handleError(a)),a}}(d,r,()=>{const c=h.injector.get(Zt);return c.runInitializers(),c.donePromise.then(()=>(function Uv(e){Se(e,"Expected localeId to be defined"),"string"==typeof e&&(du=e.toLowerCase().replace(/_/g,"-"))}(h.injector.get(Bo,Hn)||Hn),this._moduleDoBootstrap(h),h))})})}bootstrapModule(t,a=[]){const n=I_({},a);return function gq(e,o,t){const a=new Ir(t);return Promise.resolve(a)}(0,0,t).then(s=>this.bootstrapModuleFactory(s,n))}_moduleDoBootstrap(t){const a=t.injector.get(es);if(t._bootstrapComponents.length>0)t._bootstrapComponents.forEach(n=>a.bootstrap(n));else{if(!t.instance.ngDoBootstrap)throw new P(403,"");t.instance.ngDoBootstrap(a)}this._modules.push(t)}onDestroy(t){this._destroyListeners.push(t)}get injector(){return this._injector}destroy(){if(this._destroyed)throw new P(404,"");this._modules.slice().forEach(t=>t.destroy()),this._destroyListeners.forEach(t=>t()),this._destroyed=!0}get destroyed(){return this._destroyed}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(je))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();function I_(e,o){return Array.isArray(o)?o.reduce(I_,e):Object.assign(Object.assign({},e),o)}let es=(()=>{class e{constructor(t,a,n,s,i){this._zone=t,this._injector=a,this._exceptionHandler=n,this._componentFactoryResolver=s,this._initStatus=i,this._bootstrapListeners=[],this._views=[],this._runningTick=!1,this._stable=!0,this.componentTypes=[],this.components=[],this._onMicrotaskEmptySubscription=this._zone.onMicrotaskEmpty.subscribe({next:()=>{this._zone.run(()=>{this.tick()})}});const r=new qe(p=>{this._stable=this._zone.isStable&&!this._zone.hasPendingMacrotasks&&!this._zone.hasPendingMicrotasks,this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{p.next(this._stable),p.complete()})}),l=new qe(p=>{let h;this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{h=this._zone.onStable.subscribe(()=>{ge.assertNotInAngularZone(),zr(()=>{!this._stable&&!this._zone.hasPendingMacrotasks&&!this._zone.hasPendingMicrotasks&&(this._stable=!0,p.next(!0))})})});const d=this._zone.onUnstable.subscribe(()=>{ge.assertInAngularZone(),this._stable&&(this._stable=!1,this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{p.next(!1)}))});return()=>{h.unsubscribe(),d.unsubscribe()}});this.isStable=tg(r,l.pipe(function ng(e={}){const{connector:o=(()=>new qs),resetOnError:t=!0,resetOnComplete:a=!0,resetOnRefCountZero:n=!0}=e;return s=>{let i=null,r=null,l=null,p=0,h=!1,d=!1;const c=()=>{null==r||r.unsubscribe(),r=null},u=()=>{c(),i=l=null,h=d=!1},_=()=>{const g=i;u(),null==g||g.unsubscribe()};return at((g,m)=>{p++,!d&&!h&&c();const w=l=null!=l?l:o();m.add(()=>{p--,0===p&&!d&&!h&&(r=Cs(_,n))}),w.subscribe(m),i||(i=new ws({next:f=>w.next(f),error:f=>{d=!0,c(),r=Cs(u,t,f),w.error(f)},complete:()=>{h=!0,c(),r=Cs(u,a),w.complete()}}),ap(g).subscribe(i))})(s)}}()))}bootstrap(t,a){if(!this._initStatus.done)throw new P(405,"");let n;n=t instanceof Wu?t:this._componentFactoryResolver.resolveComponentFactory(t),this.componentTypes.push(n.componentType);const s=function bq(e){return e.isBoundToModule}(n)?void 0:this._injector.get($t),r=n.create(je.NULL,[],a||n.selector,s),l=r.location.nativeElement,p=r.injector.get(Qr,null),h=p&&r.injector.get(A_);return p&&h&&h.registerApplication(l,p),r.onDestroy(()=>{this.detachView(r.hostView),Xr(this.components,r),h&&h.unregisterApplication(l)}),this._loadComponent(r),r}tick(){if(this._runningTick)throw new P(101,"");try{this._runningTick=!0;for(let t of this._views)t.detectChanges()}catch(t){this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>this._exceptionHandler.handleError(t))}finally{this._runningTick=!1}}attachView(t){const a=t;this._views.push(a),a.attachToAppRef(this)}detachView(t){const a=t;Xr(this._views,a),a.detachFromAppRef()}_loadComponent(t){this.attachView(t.hostView),this.tick(),this.components.push(t),this._injector.get(nq,[]).concat(this._bootstrapListeners).forEach(n=>n(t))}ngOnDestroy(){this._views.slice().forEach(t=>t.destroy()),this._onMicrotaskEmptySubscription.unsubscribe()}get viewCount(){return this._views.length}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(ge),Y(je),Y(Tt),Y(Fa),Y(Zt))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();function Xr(e,o){const t=e.indexOf(o);t>-1&&e.splice(t,1)}let M_=!0;class N_{constructor(){}supports(o){return Sa(o)}create(o){return new Mq(o)}}const Rq=(e,o)=>o;class Mq{constructor(o){this.length=0,this._linkedRecords=null,this._unlinkedRecords=null,this._previousItHead=null,this._itHead=null,this._itTail=null,this._additionsHead=null,this._additionsTail=null,this._movesHead=null,this._movesTail=null,this._removalsHead=null,this._removalsTail=null,this._identityChangesHead=null,this._identityChangesTail=null,this._trackByFn=o||Rq}forEachItem(o){let t;for(t=this._itHead;null!==t;t=t._next)o(t)}forEachOperation(o){let t=this._itHead,a=this._removalsHead,n=0,s=null;for(;t||a;){const i=!a||t&&t.currentIndex<G_(a,n,s)?t:a,r=G_(i,n,s),l=i.currentIndex;if(i===a)n--,a=a._nextRemoved;else if(t=t._next,null==i.previousIndex)n++;else{s||(s=[]);const p=r-n,h=l-n;if(p!=h){for(let c=0;c<p;c++){const u=c<s.length?s[c]:s[c]=0,_=u+c;h<=_&&_<p&&(s[c]=u+1)}s[i.previousIndex]=h-p}}r!==l&&o(i,r,l)}}forEachPreviousItem(o){let t;for(t=this._previousItHead;null!==t;t=t._nextPrevious)o(t)}forEachAddedItem(o){let t;for(t=this._additionsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextAdded)o(t)}forEachMovedItem(o){let t;for(t=this._movesHead;null!==t;t=t._nextMoved)o(t)}forEachRemovedItem(o){let t;for(t=this._removalsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextRemoved)o(t)}forEachIdentityChange(o){let t;for(t=this._identityChangesHead;null!==t;t=t._nextIdentityChange)o(t)}diff(o){if(null==o&&(o=[]),!Sa(o))throw new P(900,"");return this.check(o)?this:null}onDestroy(){}check(o){this._reset();let n,s,i,t=this._itHead,a=!1;if(Array.isArray(o)){this.length=o.length;for(let r=0;r<this.length;r++)s=o[r],i=this._trackByFn(r,s),null!==t&&Object.is(t.trackById,i)?(a&&(t=this._verifyReinsertion(t,s,i,r)),Object.is(t.item,s)||this._addIdentityChange(t,s)):(t=this._mismatch(t,s,i,r),a=!0),t=t._next}else n=0,function wy(e,o){if(Array.isArray(e))for(let t=0;t<e.length;t++)o(e[t]);else{const t=e[Mt()]();let a;for(;!(a=t.next()).done;)o(a.value)}}(o,r=>{i=this._trackByFn(n,r),null!==t&&Object.is(t.trackById,i)?(a&&(t=this._verifyReinsertion(t,r,i,n)),Object.is(t.item,r)||this._addIdentityChange(t,r)):(t=this._mismatch(t,r,i,n),a=!0),t=t._next,n++}),this.length=n;return this._truncate(t),this.collection=o,this.isDirty}get isDirty(){return null!==this._additionsHead||null!==this._movesHead||null!==this._removalsHead||null!==this._identityChangesHead}_reset(){if(this.isDirty){let o;for(o=this._previousItHead=this._itHead;null!==o;o=o._next)o._nextPrevious=o._next;for(o=this._additionsHead;null!==o;o=o._nextAdded)o.previousIndex=o.currentIndex;for(this._additionsHead=this._additionsTail=null,o=this._movesHead;null!==o;o=o._nextMoved)o.previousIndex=o.currentIndex;this._movesHead=this._movesTail=null,this._removalsHead=this._removalsTail=null,this._identityChangesHead=this._identityChangesTail=null}}_mismatch(o,t,a,n){let s;return null===o?s=this._itTail:(s=o._prev,this._remove(o)),null!==(o=null===this._unlinkedRecords?null:this._unlinkedRecords.get(a,null))?(Object.is(o.item,t)||this._addIdentityChange(o,t),this._reinsertAfter(o,s,n)):null!==(o=null===this._linkedRecords?null:this._linkedRecords.get(a,n))?(Object.is(o.item,t)||this._addIdentityChange(o,t),this._moveAfter(o,s,n)):o=this._addAfter(new Lq(t,a),s,n),o}_verifyReinsertion(o,t,a,n){let s=null===this._unlinkedRecords?null:this._unlinkedRecords.get(a,null);return null!==s?o=this._reinsertAfter(s,o._prev,n):o.currentIndex!=n&&(o.currentIndex=n,this._addToMoves(o,n)),o}_truncate(o){for(;null!==o;){const t=o._next;this._addToRemovals(this._unlink(o)),o=t}null!==this._unlinkedRecords&&this._unlinkedRecords.clear(),null!==this._additionsTail&&(this._additionsTail._nextAdded=null),null!==this._movesTail&&(this._movesTail._nextMoved=null),null!==this._itTail&&(this._itTail._next=null),null!==this._removalsTail&&(this._removalsTail._nextRemoved=null),null!==this._identityChangesTail&&(this._identityChangesTail._nextIdentityChange=null)}_reinsertAfter(o,t,a){null!==this._unlinkedRecords&&this._unlinkedRecords.remove(o);const n=o._prevRemoved,s=o._nextRemoved;return null===n?this._removalsHead=s:n._nextRemoved=s,null===s?this._removalsTail=n:s._prevRemoved=n,this._insertAfter(o,t,a),this._addToMoves(o,a),o}_moveAfter(o,t,a){return this._unlink(o),this._insertAfter(o,t,a),this._addToMoves(o,a),o}_addAfter(o,t,a){return this._insertAfter(o,t,a),this._additionsTail=null===this._additionsTail?this._additionsHead=o:this._additionsTail._nextAdded=o,o}_insertAfter(o,t,a){const n=null===t?this._itHead:t._next;return o._next=n,o._prev=t,null===n?this._itTail=o:n._prev=o,null===t?this._itHead=o:t._next=o,null===this._linkedRecords&&(this._linkedRecords=new B_),this._linkedRecords.put(o),o.currentIndex=a,o}_remove(o){return this._addToRemovals(this._unlink(o))}_unlink(o){null!==this._linkedRecords&&this._linkedRecords.remove(o);const t=o._prev,a=o._next;return null===t?this._itHead=a:t._next=a,null===a?this._itTail=t:a._prev=t,o}_addToMoves(o,t){return o.previousIndex===t||(this._movesTail=null===this._movesTail?this._movesHead=o:this._movesTail._nextMoved=o),o}_addToRemovals(o){return null===this._unlinkedRecords&&(this._unlinkedRecords=new B_),this._unlinkedRecords.put(o),o.currentIndex=null,o._nextRemoved=null,null===this._removalsTail?(this._removalsTail=this._removalsHead=o,o._prevRemoved=null):(o._prevRemoved=this._removalsTail,this._removalsTail=this._removalsTail._nextRemoved=o),o}_addIdentityChange(o,t){return o.item=t,this._identityChangesTail=null===this._identityChangesTail?this._identityChangesHead=o:this._identityChangesTail._nextIdentityChange=o,o}}class Lq{constructor(o,t){this.item=o,this.trackById=t,this.currentIndex=null,this.previousIndex=null,this._nextPrevious=null,this._prev=null,this._next=null,this._prevDup=null,this._nextDup=null,this._prevRemoved=null,this._nextRemoved=null,this._nextAdded=null,this._nextMoved=null,this._nextIdentityChange=null}}class xq{constructor(){this._head=null,this._tail=null}add(o){null===this._head?(this._head=this._tail=o,o._nextDup=null,o._prevDup=null):(this._tail._nextDup=o,o._prevDup=this._tail,o._nextDup=null,this._tail=o)}get(o,t){let a;for(a=this._head;null!==a;a=a._nextDup)if((null===t||t<=a.currentIndex)&&Object.is(a.trackById,o))return a;return null}remove(o){const t=o._prevDup,a=o._nextDup;return null===t?this._head=a:t._nextDup=a,null===a?this._tail=t:a._prevDup=t,null===this._head}}class B_{constructor(){this.map=new Map}put(o){const t=o.trackById;let a=this.map.get(t);a||(a=new xq,this.map.set(t,a)),a.add(o)}get(o,t){const n=this.map.get(o);return n?n.get(o,t):null}remove(o){const t=o.trackById;return this.map.get(t).remove(o)&&this.map.delete(t),o}get isEmpty(){return 0===this.map.size}clear(){this.map.clear()}}function G_(e,o,t){const a=e.previousIndex;if(null===a)return a;let n=0;return t&&a<t.length&&(n=t[a]),a+o+n}class U_{constructor(){}supports(o){return o instanceof Map||hr(o)}create(){return new Fq}}class Fq{constructor(){this._records=new Map,this._mapHead=null,this._appendAfter=null,this._previousMapHead=null,this._changesHead=null,this._changesTail=null,this._additionsHead=null,this._additionsTail=null,this._removalsHead=null,this._removalsTail=null}get isDirty(){return null!==this._additionsHead||null!==this._changesHead||null!==this._removalsHead}forEachItem(o){let t;for(t=this._mapHead;null!==t;t=t._next)o(t)}forEachPreviousItem(o){let t;for(t=this._previousMapHead;null!==t;t=t._nextPrevious)o(t)}forEachChangedItem(o){let t;for(t=this._changesHead;null!==t;t=t._nextChanged)o(t)}forEachAddedItem(o){let t;for(t=this._additionsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextAdded)o(t)}forEachRemovedItem(o){let t;for(t=this._removalsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextRemoved)o(t)}diff(o){if(o){if(!(o instanceof Map||hr(o)))throw new P(900,"")}else o=new Map;return this.check(o)?this:null}onDestroy(){}check(o){this._reset();let t=this._mapHead;if(this._appendAfter=null,this._forEach(o,(a,n)=>{if(t&&t.key===n)this._maybeAddToChanges(t,a),this._appendAfter=t,t=t._next;else{const s=this._getOrCreateRecordForKey(n,a);t=this._insertBeforeOrAppend(t,s)}}),t){t._prev&&(t._prev._next=null),this._removalsHead=t;for(let a=t;null!==a;a=a._nextRemoved)a===this._mapHead&&(this._mapHead=null),this._records.delete(a.key),a._nextRemoved=a._next,a.previousValue=a.currentValue,a.currentValue=null,a._prev=null,a._next=null}return this._changesTail&&(this._changesTail._nextChanged=null),this._additionsTail&&(this._additionsTail._nextAdded=null),this.isDirty}_insertBeforeOrAppend(o,t){if(o){const a=o._prev;return t._next=o,t._prev=a,o._prev=t,a&&(a._next=t),o===this._mapHead&&(this._mapHead=t),this._appendAfter=o,o}return this._appendAfter?(this._appendAfter._next=t,t._prev=this._appendAfter):this._mapHead=t,this._appendAfter=t,null}_getOrCreateRecordForKey(o,t){if(this._records.has(o)){const n=this._records.get(o);this._maybeAddToChanges(n,t);const s=n._prev,i=n._next;return s&&(s._next=i),i&&(i._prev=s),n._next=null,n._prev=null,n}const a=new Wq(o);return this._records.set(o,a),a.currentValue=t,this._addToAdditions(a),a}_reset(){if(this.isDirty){let o;for(this._previousMapHead=this._mapHead,o=this._previousMapHead;null!==o;o=o._next)o._nextPrevious=o._next;for(o=this._changesHead;null!==o;o=o._nextChanged)o.previousValue=o.currentValue;for(o=this._additionsHead;null!=o;o=o._nextAdded)o.previousValue=o.currentValue;this._changesHead=this._changesTail=null,this._additionsHead=this._additionsTail=null,this._removalsHead=null}}_maybeAddToChanges(o,t){Object.is(t,o.currentValue)||(o.previousValue=o.currentValue,o.currentValue=t,this._addToChanges(o))}_addToAdditions(o){null===this._additionsHead?this._additionsHead=this._additionsTail=o:(this._additionsTail._nextAdded=o,this._additionsTail=o)}_addToChanges(o){null===this._changesHead?this._changesHead=this._changesTail=o:(this._changesTail._nextChanged=o,this._changesTail=o)}_forEach(o,t){o instanceof Map?o.forEach(t):Object.keys(o).forEach(a=>t(o[a],a))}}class Wq{constructor(o){this.key=o,this.previousValue=null,this.currentValue=null,this._nextPrevious=null,this._next=null,this._prev=null,this._nextAdded=null,this._nextRemoved=null,this._nextChanged=null}}function j_(){return new Ga([new N_])}let Ga=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){this.factories=t}static create(t,a){if(null!=a){const n=a.factories.slice();t=t.concat(n)}return new e(t)}static extend(t){return{provide:e,useFactory:a=>e.create(t,a||j_()),deps:[[e,new ba,new vt]]}}find(t){const a=this.factories.find(n=>n.supports(t));if(null!=a)return a;throw new P(901,"")}}return e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,providedIn:"root",factory:j_}),e})();function H_(){return new Xt([new U_])}let Xt=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){this.factories=t}static create(t,a){if(a){const n=a.factories.slice();t=t.concat(n)}return new e(t)}static extend(t){return{provide:e,useFactory:a=>e.create(t,a||H_()),deps:[[e,new ba,new vt]]}}find(t){const a=this.factories.find(s=>s.supports(t));if(a)return a;throw new P(901,"")}}return e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,providedIn:"root",factory:H_}),e})();const Oq=[new U_],Nq=new Ga([new N_]),Bq=new Xt(Oq),Gq=C_(null,"core",[{provide:Vr,useValue:"unknown"},{provide:E_,deps:[je]},{provide:A_,deps:[]},{provide:sq,deps:[]}]),Vq=[{provide:es,useClass:es,deps:[ge,je,Tt,Fa,Zt]},{provide:Q0,deps:[ge],useFactory:function zq(e){let o=[];return e.onStable.subscribe(()=>{for(;o.length;)o.pop()()}),function(t){o.push(t)}}},{provide:Zt,useClass:Zt,deps:[[new vt,Hr]]},{provide:k_,useClass:k_,deps:[]},aq,{provide:Ga,useFactory:function Uq(){return Nq},deps:[]},{provide:Xt,useFactory:function jq(){return Bq},deps:[]},{provide:Bo,useFactory:function Hq(e){return e||function Yq(){return"undefined"!=typeof $localize&&$localize.locale||Hn}()},deps:[[new An(Bo),new vt,new ba]]},{provide:v_,useValue:"USD"}];let $q=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(es))},e.\u0275mod=ta({type:e}),e.\u0275inj=st({providers:Vq}),e})(),ts=null;function Ua(){return ts}const wo=new B("DocumentToken");var se=(()=>((se=se||{})[se.Zero=0]="Zero",se[se.One=1]="One",se[se.Two=2]="Two",se[se.Few=3]="Few",se[se.Many=4]="Many",se[se.Other=5]="Other",se))();const rT=function pu(e){return function ve(e){const o=function Pv(e){return e.toLowerCase().replace(/_/g,"-")}(e);let t=hu(o);if(t)return t;const a=o.split("-")[0];if(t=hu(a),t)return t;if("en"===a)return Ov;throw new Error(`Missing locale data for the locale "${e}".`)}(e)[v.PluralCase]};class cs{}let WT=(()=>{class e extends cs{constructor(t){super(),this.locale=t}getPluralCategory(t,a){switch(rT(a||this.locale)(t)){case se.Zero:return"zero";case se.One:return"one";case se.Two:return"two";case se.Few:return"few";case se.Many:return"many";default:return"other"}}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(Bo))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})(),of=(()=>{class e{constructor(t,a,n,s){this._iterableDiffers=t,this._keyValueDiffers=a,this._ngEl=n,this._renderer=s,this._iterableDiffer=null,this._keyValueDiffer=null,this._initialClasses=[],this._rawClass=null}set klass(t){this._removeClasses(this._initialClasses),this._initialClasses="string"==typeof t?t.split(/\s+/):[],this._applyClasses(this._initialClasses),this._applyClasses(this._rawClass)}set ngClass(t){this._removeClasses(this._rawClass),this._applyClasses(this._initialClasses),this._iterableDiffer=null,this._keyValueDiffer=null,this._rawClass="string"==typeof t?t.split(/\s+/):t,this._rawClass&&(Sa(this._rawClass)?this._iterableDiffer=this._iterableDiffers.find(this._rawClass).create():this._keyValueDiffer=this._keyValueDiffers.find(this._rawClass).create())}ngDoCheck(){if(this._iterableDiffer){const t=this._iterableDiffer.diff(this._rawClass);t&&this._applyIterableChanges(t)}else if(this._keyValueDiffer){const t=this._keyValueDiffer.diff(this._rawClass);t&&this._applyKeyValueChanges(t)}}_applyKeyValueChanges(t){t.forEachAddedItem(a=>this._toggleClass(a.key,a.currentValue)),t.forEachChangedItem(a=>this._toggleClass(a.key,a.currentValue)),t.forEachRemovedItem(a=>{a.previousValue&&this._toggleClass(a.key,!1)})}_applyIterableChanges(t){t.forEachAddedItem(a=>{if("string"!=typeof a.item)throw new Error(`NgClass can only toggle CSS classes expressed as strings, got ${N(a.item)}`);this._toggleClass(a.item,!0)}),t.forEachRemovedItem(a=>this._toggleClass(a.item,!1))}_applyClasses(t){t&&(Array.isArray(t)||t instanceof Set?t.forEach(a=>this._toggleClass(a,!0)):Object.keys(t).forEach(a=>this._toggleClass(a,!!t[a])))}_removeClasses(t){t&&(Array.isArray(t)||t instanceof Set?t.forEach(a=>this._toggleClass(a,!1)):Object.keys(t).forEach(a=>this._toggleClass(a,!1)))}_toggleClass(t,a){(t=t.trim())&&t.split(/\s+/g).forEach(n=>{a?this._renderer.addClass(this._ngEl.nativeElement,n):this._renderer.removeClass(this._ngEl.nativeElement,n)})}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(x(Ga),x(Xt),x(zt),x(Nu))},e.\u0275dir=Oe({type:e,selectors:[["","ngClass",""]],inputs:{klass:["class","klass"],ngClass:"ngClass"}}),e})();class NT{constructor(o,t,a,n){this.$implicit=o,this.ngForOf=t,this.index=a,this.count=n}get first(){return 0===this.index}get last(){return this.index===this.count-1}get even(){return this.index%2==0}get odd(){return!this.even}}let tf=(()=>{class e{constructor(t,a,n){this._viewContainer=t,this._template=a,this._differs=n,this._ngForOf=null,this._ngForOfDirty=!0,this._differ=null}set ngForOf(t){this._ngForOf=t,this._ngForOfDirty=!0}set ngForTrackBy(t){this._trackByFn=t}get ngForTrackBy(){return this._trackByFn}set ngForTemplate(t){t&&(this._template=t)}ngDoCheck(){if(this._ngForOfDirty){this._ngForOfDirty=!1;const t=this._ngForOf;!this._differ&&t&&(this._differ=this._differs.find(t).create(this.ngForTrackBy))}if(this._differ){const t=this._differ.diff(this._ngForOf);t&&this._applyChanges(t)}}_applyChanges(t){const a=this._viewContainer;t.forEachOperation((n,s,i)=>{if(null==n.previousIndex)a.createEmbeddedView(this._template,new NT(n.item,this._ngForOf,-1,-1),null===i?void 0:i);else if(null==i)a.remove(null===s?void 0:s);else if(null!==s){const r=a.get(s);a.move(r,i),af(r,n)}});for(let n=0,s=a.length;n<s;n++){const r=a.get(n).context;r.index=n,r.count=s,r.ngForOf=this._ngForOf}t.forEachIdentityChange(n=>{af(a.get(n.currentIndex),n)})}static ngTemplateContextGuard(t,a){return!0}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(x(mo),x(Co),x(Ga))},e.\u0275dir=Oe({type:e,selectors:[["","ngFor","","ngForOf",""]],inputs:{ngForOf:"ngForOf",ngForTrackBy:"ngForTrackBy",ngForTemplate:"ngForTemplate"}}),e})();function af(e,o){e.context.$implicit=o.item}let _1=(()=>{class e{}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275mod=ta({type:e}),e.\u0275inj=st({providers:[{provide:cs,useClass:WT}]}),e})();class fl extends class y1 extends class Zq{}{constructor(){super(...arguments),this.supportsDOMEvents=!0}}{static makeCurrent(){!function Qq(e){ts||(ts=e)}(new fl)}onAndCancel(o,t,a){return o.addEventListener(t,a,!1),()=>{o.removeEventListener(t,a,!1)}}dispatchEvent(o,t){o.dispatchEvent(t)}remove(o){o.parentNode&&o.parentNode.removeChild(o)}createElement(o,t){return(t=t||this.getDefaultDocument()).createElement(o)}createHtmlDocument(){return document.implementation.createHTMLDocument("fakeTitle")}getDefaultDocument(){return document}isElementNode(o){return o.nodeType===Node.ELEMENT_NODE}isShadowRoot(o){return o instanceof DocumentFragment}getGlobalEventTarget(o,t){return"window"===t?window:"document"===t?o:"body"===t?o.body:null}getBaseHref(o){const t=function v1(){return Ya=Ya||document.querySelector("base"),Ya?Ya.getAttribute("href"):null}();return null==t?null:function k1(e){us=us||document.createElement("a"),us.setAttribute("href",e);const o=us.pathname;return"/"===o.charAt(0)?o:`/${o}`}(t)}resetBaseElement(){Ya=null}getUserAgent(){return window.navigator.userAgent}getCookie(o){return function OT(e,o){o=encodeURIComponent(o);for(const t of e.split(";")){const a=t.indexOf("="),[n,s]=-1==a?[t,""]:[t.slice(0,a),t.slice(a+1)];if(n.trim()===o)return decodeURIComponent(s)}return null}(document.cookie,o)}}let us,Ya=null;const hf=new B("TRANSITION_ID"),T1=[{provide:Hr,useFactory:function q1(e,o,t){return()=>{t.get(Zt).donePromise.then(()=>{const a=Ua(),n=o.querySelectorAll(`style[ng-transition="${e}"]`);for(let s=0;s<n.length;s++)a.remove(n[s])})}},deps:[hf,wo,je],multi:!0}];class gl{static init(){!function fq(e){Zr=e}(new gl)}addToWindow(o){G.getAngularTestability=(a,n=!0)=>{const s=o.findTestabilityInTree(a,n);if(null==s)throw new Error("Could not find testability for element.");return s},G.getAllAngularTestabilities=()=>o.getAllTestabilities(),G.getAllAngularRootElements=()=>o.getAllRootElements(),G.frameworkStabilizers||(G.frameworkStabilizers=[]),G.frameworkStabilizers.push(a=>{const n=G.getAllAngularTestabilities();let s=n.length,i=!1;const r=function(l){i=i||l,s--,0==s&&a(i)};n.forEach(function(l){l.whenStable(r)})})}findTestabilityInTree(o,t,a){if(null==t)return null;const n=o.getTestability(t);return null!=n?n:a?Ua().isShadowRoot(t)?this.findTestabilityInTree(o,t.host,!0):this.findTestabilityInTree(o,t.parentElement,!0):null}}let A1=(()=>{class e{build(){return new XMLHttpRequest}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const _s=new B("EventManagerPlugins");let fs=(()=>{class e{constructor(t,a){this._zone=a,this._eventNameToPlugin=new Map,t.forEach(n=>n.manager=this),this._plugins=t.slice().reverse()}addEventListener(t,a,n){return this._findPluginFor(a).addEventListener(t,a,n)}addGlobalEventListener(t,a,n){return this._findPluginFor(a).addGlobalEventListener(t,a,n)}getZone(){return this._zone}_findPluginFor(t){const a=this._eventNameToPlugin.get(t);if(a)return a;const n=this._plugins;for(let s=0;s<n.length;s++){const i=n[s];if(i.supports(t))return this._eventNameToPlugin.set(t,i),i}throw new Error(`No event manager plugin found for event ${t}`)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(_s),Y(ge))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();class df{constructor(o){this._doc=o}addGlobalEventListener(o,t,a){const n=Ua().getGlobalEventTarget(this._doc,o);if(!n)throw new Error(`Unsupported event target ${n} for event ${t}`);return this.addEventListener(n,t,a)}}let cf=(()=>{class e{constructor(){this._stylesSet=new Set}addStyles(t){const a=new Set;t.forEach(n=>{this._stylesSet.has(n)||(this._stylesSet.add(n),a.add(n))}),this.onStylesAdded(a)}onStylesAdded(t){}getAllStyles(){return Array.from(this._stylesSet)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})(),Va=(()=>{class e extends cf{constructor(t){super(),this._doc=t,this._hostNodes=new Map,this._hostNodes.set(t.head,[])}_addStylesToHost(t,a,n){t.forEach(s=>{const i=this._doc.createElement("style");i.textContent=s,n.push(a.appendChild(i))})}addHost(t){const a=[];this._addStylesToHost(this._stylesSet,t,a),this._hostNodes.set(t,a)}removeHost(t){const a=this._hostNodes.get(t);a&&a.forEach(uf),this._hostNodes.delete(t)}onStylesAdded(t){this._hostNodes.forEach((a,n)=>{this._addStylesToHost(t,n,a)})}ngOnDestroy(){this._hostNodes.forEach(t=>t.forEach(uf))}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(wo))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();function uf(e){Ua().remove(e)}const bl={svg:"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",xhtml:"http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml",xlink:"http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink",xml:"http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace",xmlns:"http://www.w3.org/2000/xmlns/"},ml=/%COMP%/g;function gs(e,o,t){for(let a=0;a<o.length;a++){let n=o[a];Array.isArray(n)?gs(e,n,t):(n=n.replace(ml,e),t.push(n))}return t}function gf(e){return o=>{if("__ngUnwrap__"===o)return e;!1===e(o)&&(o.preventDefault(),o.returnValue=!1)}}let wl=(()=>{class e{constructor(t,a,n){this.eventManager=t,this.sharedStylesHost=a,this.appId=n,this.rendererByCompId=new Map,this.defaultRenderer=new yl(t)}createRenderer(t,a){if(!t||!a)return this.defaultRenderer;switch(a.encapsulation){case ro.Emulated:{let n=this.rendererByCompId.get(a.id);return n||(n=new R1(this.eventManager,this.sharedStylesHost,a,this.appId),this.rendererByCompId.set(a.id,n)),n.applyToHost(t),n}case 1:case ro.ShadowDom:return new M1(this.eventManager,this.sharedStylesHost,t,a);default:if(!this.rendererByCompId.has(a.id)){const n=gs(a.id,a.styles,[]);this.sharedStylesHost.addStyles(n),this.rendererByCompId.set(a.id,this.defaultRenderer)}return this.defaultRenderer}}begin(){}end(){}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(fs),Y(Va),Y(Ba))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();class yl{constructor(o){this.eventManager=o,this.data=Object.create(null),this.destroyNode=null}destroy(){}createElement(o,t){return t?document.createElementNS(bl[t]||t,o):document.createElement(o)}createComment(o){return document.createComment(o)}createText(o){return document.createTextNode(o)}appendChild(o,t){o.appendChild(t)}insertBefore(o,t,a){o&&o.insertBefore(t,a)}removeChild(o,t){o&&o.removeChild(t)}selectRootElement(o,t){let a="string"==typeof o?document.querySelector(o):o;if(!a)throw new Error(`The selector "${o}" did not match any elements`);return t||(a.textContent=""),a}parentNode(o){return o.parentNode}nextSibling(o){return o.nextSibling}setAttribute(o,t,a,n){if(n){t=n+":"+t;const s=bl[n];s?o.setAttributeNS(s,t,a):o.setAttribute(t,a)}else o.setAttribute(t,a)}removeAttribute(o,t,a){if(a){const n=bl[a];n?o.removeAttributeNS(n,t):o.removeAttribute(`${a}:${t}`)}else o.removeAttribute(t)}addClass(o,t){o.classList.add(t)}removeClass(o,t){o.classList.remove(t)}setStyle(o,t,a,n){n&(Me.DashCase|Me.Important)?o.style.setProperty(t,a,n&Me.Important?"important":""):o.style[t]=a}removeStyle(o,t,a){a&Me.DashCase?o.style.removeProperty(t):o.style[t]=""}setProperty(o,t,a){o[t]=a}setValue(o,t){o.nodeValue=t}listen(o,t,a){return"string"==typeof o?this.eventManager.addGlobalEventListener(o,t,gf(a)):this.eventManager.addEventListener(o,t,gf(a))}}class R1 extends yl{constructor(o,t,a,n){super(o),this.component=a;const s=gs(n+"-"+a.id,a.styles,[]);t.addStyles(s),this.contentAttr=function S1(e){return"_ngcontent-%COMP%".replace(ml,e)}(n+"-"+a.id),this.hostAttr=function E1(e){return"_nghost-%COMP%".replace(ml,e)}(n+"-"+a.id)}applyToHost(o){super.setAttribute(o,this.hostAttr,"")}createElement(o,t){const a=super.createElement(o,t);return super.setAttribute(a,this.contentAttr,""),a}}class M1 extends yl{constructor(o,t,a,n){super(o),this.sharedStylesHost=t,this.hostEl=a,this.shadowRoot=a.attachShadow({mode:"open"}),this.sharedStylesHost.addHost(this.shadowRoot);const s=gs(n.id,n.styles,[]);for(let i=0;i<s.length;i++){const r=document.createElement("style");r.textContent=s[i],this.shadowRoot.appendChild(r)}}nodeOrShadowRoot(o){return o===this.hostEl?this.shadowRoot:o}destroy(){this.sharedStylesHost.removeHost(this.shadowRoot)}appendChild(o,t){return super.appendChild(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(o),t)}insertBefore(o,t,a){return super.insertBefore(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(o),t,a)}removeChild(o,t){return super.removeChild(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(o),t)}parentNode(o){return this.nodeOrShadowRoot(super.parentNode(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(o)))}}let L1=(()=>{class e extends df{constructor(t){super(t)}supports(t){return!0}addEventListener(t,a,n){return t.addEventListener(a,n,!1),()=>this.removeEventListener(t,a,n)}removeEventListener(t,a,n){return t.removeEventListener(a,n)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(wo))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const mf=["alt","control","meta","shift"],F1={"\b":"Backspace","\t":"Tab","\x7f":"Delete","\x1b":"Escape",Del:"Delete",Esc:"Escape",Left:"ArrowLeft",Right:"ArrowRight",Up:"ArrowUp",Down:"ArrowDown",Menu:"ContextMenu",Scroll:"ScrollLock",Win:"OS"},wf={A:"1",B:"2",C:"3",D:"4",E:"5",F:"6",G:"7",H:"8",I:"9",J:"*",K:"+",M:"-",N:".",O:"/","`":"0","\x90":"NumLock"},W1={alt:e=>e.altKey,control:e=>e.ctrlKey,meta:e=>e.metaKey,shift:e=>e.shiftKey};let O1=(()=>{class e extends df{constructor(t){super(t)}supports(t){return null!=e.parseEventName(t)}addEventListener(t,a,n){const s=e.parseEventName(a),i=e.eventCallback(s.fullKey,n,this.manager.getZone());return this.manager.getZone().runOutsideAngular(()=>Ua().onAndCancel(t,s.domEventName,i))}static parseEventName(t){const a=t.toLowerCase().split("."),n=a.shift();if(0===a.length||"keydown"!==n&&"keyup"!==n)return null;const s=e._normalizeKey(a.pop());let i="";if(mf.forEach(l=>{const p=a.indexOf(l);p>-1&&(a.splice(p,1),i+=l+".")}),i+=s,0!=a.length||0===s.length)return null;const r={};return r.domEventName=n,r.fullKey=i,r}static getEventFullKey(t){let a="",n=function P1(e){let o=e.key;if(null==o){if(o=e.keyIdentifier,null==o)return"Unidentified";o.startsWith("U+")&&(o=String.fromCharCode(parseInt(o.substring(2),16)),3===e.location&&wf.hasOwnProperty(o)&&(o=wf[o]))}return F1[o]||o}(t);return n=n.toLowerCase()," "===n?n="space":"."===n&&(n="dot"),mf.forEach(s=>{s!=n&&W1[s](t)&&(a+=s+".")}),a+=n,a}static eventCallback(t,a,n){return s=>{e.getEventFullKey(s)===t&&n.runGuarded(()=>a(s))}}static _normalizeKey(t){return"esc"===t?"escape":t}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(wo))},e.\u0275prov=Z({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const U1=C_(Gq,"browser",[{provide:Vr,useValue:"browser"},{provide:y_,useValue:function N1(){fl.makeCurrent(),gl.init()},multi:!0},{provide:wo,useFactory:function G1(){return function Rg(e){js=e}(document),document},deps:[]}]),j1=[{provide:nr,useValue:"root"},{provide:Tt,useFactory:function B1(){return new Tt},deps:[]},{provide:_s,useClass:L1,multi:!0,deps:[wo,ge,Vr]},{provide:_s,useClass:O1,multi:!0,deps:[wo]},{provide:wl,useClass:wl,deps:[fs,Va,Ba]},{provide:Pu,useExisting:wl},{provide:cf,useExisting:Va},{provide:Va,useClass:Va,deps:[wo]},{provide:Qr,useClass:Qr,deps:[ge]},{provide:fs,useClass:fs,deps:[_s,ge]},{provide:class w1{},useClass:A1,deps:[]}];let H1=(()=>{class e{constructor(t){if(t)throw new Error("BrowserModule has already been loaded. If you need access to common directives such as NgIf and NgFor from a lazy loaded module, import CommonModule instead.")}static withServerTransition(t){return{ngModule:e,providers:[{provide:Ba,useValue:t.appId},{provide:hf,useExisting:Ba},T1]}}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Y(e,12))},e.\u0275mod=ta({type:e}),e.\u0275inj=st({providers:j1,imports:[_1,$q]}),e})();function oA(e,o){if(1&e&&(xe(0,"div",4),xe(1,"div",5),xe(2,"h6"),No(3),Fe(),Fe(),xe(4,"div",6),xe(5,"p",7),No(6),Fe(),xe(7,"p",7),No(8),Fe(),xe(9,"p",7),No(10),Fe(),xe(11,"p",7),No(12),Fe(),Fe(),Fe()),2&e){const t=o.$implicit,a=o.index;Xe(3),Jo(a+1+") "+t.question),Xe(2),Xo("ngClass","opa"==t.ans?"active":""),Xe(1),Jo("A) "+t.opa),Xe(1),Xo("ngClass","opb"==t.ans?"active":""),Xe(1),Jo("B) "+t.opb),Xe(1),Xo("ngClass","opc"==t.ans?"active":""),Xe(1),Jo("C) "+t.opc),Xe(1),Xo("ngClass","opd"==t.ans?"active":""),Xe(1),Jo("D) "+t.opd)}}"undefined"!=typeof window&&window;let tA=(()=>{class e{constructor(){this.title="forms",this.data=[{question:"If a tug equipped with flanking rudders is to be turned in a confined circle, when going astern, the stern will move to port the quickest if ____________.",opa:"the rudder is hard to port and the flanking rudders are hard to port",opb:"the rudder is amidships and the flanking rudders are hard to port",opc:"the rudder is hard to port and the flanking rudders are hard to starboard",opd:"all rudders are hard to starboard",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel is wind rode when it is ____________.",opa:"at anchor and heading into the wind",opb:"backing into the wind",opc:"carrying lee rudder",opd:"necessary to apply a leeway correction to the course",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following actions are stated in the correct order prior to loading or discharging cargo on a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Raise/open stern door, lower the stern ramp, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",opb:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, raise/open the stern door, lower the stern ramp",opc:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, lower the stern ramp, raise/open the stern door",opd:"Lower the stern ramp, raise/open the stern door, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",ans:"opd"},{question:"In determining the scope of anchor line to pay out when anchoring a small boat, one must consider the ____________.",opa:"charted depth of water only",opb:"depth of water, including tidal differences",opc:"type of line being used for the anchor rope",opd:"type of anchor being used",ans:"opb"},{question:"Damaged bulkheads often take a permanent set which is independent of the panting or bulge caused by water pressure. To control this, you should ____________.",opa:"install shoring so the shoring supports the damaged bulkheads without pushing on them",opb:"install shoring so that it pushes on the damaged bulkhead while supporting it",opc:"use jacks or chain falls to remove the set before installing shores",opd:"place sandbags by the bulkhead without installing shores",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which material makes the strongest mooring line?",opa:"Sisal",opb:"Manila",opc:"Nylon",opd:"Polypropylene",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is anchored in an open roadstead with three shots of chain out on the port anchor. The wind freshens considerably and the anchor begins to drag. Which action should you take FIRST?",opa:"Drop the starboard anchor short with about one shot of chain.",opb:"Sheer out to starboard using the rudder, then drop the starboard anchor with about four shots of chain.",opc:"Put the engines slow ahead to help the anchor.",opd:"Veer out more chain on the port anchor.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A U.S. or foreign flag vessel that does not comply with the Officers Competency Certificates Convention of 1936 may be detained by certain designated officials. These officials include all of the following EXCEPT a/an ____________.",opa:"State Police officer",opb:"Coast Guard officer",opc:"Coast Guard petty officer",opd:"officer of the U.S. Customs Service",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are carrying triethylamine, methyl methacrylate and isoprene in your multiple-product tankship. Which of the following statements is true?",opa:"Isoprene may be carried in a cargo tank adjacent to either of the other two cargoes.",opb:"Methyl methacrylate may not be carried in a tank adjacent to a pump room.",opc:"Methyl methacrylate must usually be heated to maintain its stability.",opd:"Portable thermometers are not permitted to be used to take the cargo temperature of triethylamine.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the period of validity of a Cargo Ship Safety Radio Certificate?",opa:"6 months",opb:"12 months",opc:"24 months",opd:"60 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"The knot lettered P is a ____________.",opa:"rolling hitch",opb:"clove hitch",opc:"round turn and two half hitches",opd:"marline hitch",ans:"opa"},{question:"The term 'lee side' refers to the ____________.",opa:"side of the vessel exposed to the wind",opb:"side of the vessel sheltered from the wind",opc:"port side",opd:"starboard side",ans:"opb"},{question:"A seaman is entitled by law to a release from Foreign Articles when ____________.",opa:"intoxicated",opb:"the vessel is overloaded",opc:"there is a change of home port",opd:"there is a change of Master",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 5?",opa:"3-2 purchase",opb:"Double luff tackle",opc:"Two-fold purchase",opd:"Four-fold whip",ans:"opb"},{question:"In relation to the turning circle of a ship, the term 'kick' means the distance ____________.",opa:"around the circumference of the turning circle",opb:"gained at right angles to the original course",opc:"gained in the direction of the original course",opd:"or throw of a vessel's stern from her line of advance upon putting the helm hard over",ans:"opd"},{question:"When planning the loading or discharging of a VLCC (100,000 DWT+) what is the most important consideration?",opa:"Draft and trim",opb:"Limits of the bending moments",opc:"Rate of discharging",opd:"Rate of loading",ans:"opb"},{question:"When steering a vessel, a good helmsman will ____________.",opa:"use as much rudder as possible to keep the vessel on course",opb:"apply rudder to move the compass card towards the lubbers line when off course",opc:"repeat back to the watch officer any rudder commands before executing them",opd:"keep the rudder amidships except when changing course",ans:"opc"},{question:"When hooking up a cargo hose to your vessel's manifold, you should use a(n) ____________.",opa:"international shore connection",opb:"insulating flange or single length of non-conducting hose",opc:"self-contained breathing apparatus",opd:"oxygen analyzer",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which method should be used to secure a synthetic fiber line to two bitts?",opa:"Two round turns on the bitt closest to the strain and then figure eights",opb:"Two round turns on the bitt farthest from the strain and then figure eights",opc:"Figure eights and then a round turn at the top of both bitts",opd:"Only figure eights are necessary on both bitts",ans:"opa"},{question:"The objective of shoring a damaged bulkhead is to ____________.",opa:"force the warped, bulged, or deformed sections back into place",opb:"support and hold the area in the damaged position",opc:"withstand subsequent additional damage",opd:"make a watertight seal at the damaged area",ans:"opb"},{question:"Metal plates that cover the top of the hawsepipe are called ____________.",opa:"footings",opb:"plugs",opc:"buckler plates",opd:"stop waters",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on watch and receive word that a person has fallen overboard from the starboard side. What should your first action be?",opa:"notify the Master",opb:"put the wheel hard right",opc:"put the engines full astern",opd:"sound the man overboard alarm",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is used when securing light vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Buckle or ratchet tensioner",opb:"Chain",opc:"Wire",opd:"Manila rope",ans:"opa"},{question:'A "dangerous cargo manifest" is needed for you to carry a combustible cargo. You should obtain the shipping papers to make this "manifest" from the ____________.',opa:"manufacturer",opb:"ABS",opc:"Coast Guard",opd:"shipper",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are to load a consignment of lumber. Each piece measures 3-inches thick, 12-inches wide and 16-feet long. There are 30,000 pieces in the shipment. How many board feet would be listed on the Bill of Lading?",opa:"96000",opb:"1200000",opc:"1440000",opd:"14400000",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is an advantage in the use of a towing hook?",opa:"To prevent the tug from becoming tripped",opb:"To quickly connect or release a tow, especially a sinking tow",opc:"To facilitate berthing maneuvers",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel was damaged and initially assumed a significant list and trim; however, further increase has been slow. Based on this data, what should you expect?",opa:"The slowing is only temporary and the vessel will probably suddenly capsize or plunge from loss of stability due to change in the waterplane area.",opb:"The vessel can probably be saved if further flooding can be stopped.",opc:"The vessel will continue to slowly list and/or trim due to the free surface effect and free communication effect.",opd:"The vessel will suddenly flop to the same or greater angle of list on the other side and may capsize.",ans:"opb"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to lower?",opa:"With forearm vertical and forefinger pointing up, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opb:"With arm extended downwards and forefinger pointing down, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opc:"Extend arm and point finger in the direction to move the boom.",opd:"Extend arm with thumb pointing downward, and flex fingers in and out.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The lower seam of the strake indicated by the letter B is sometimes riveted. This is done to ____________.",opa:"increase the strength in a highly stressed area",opb:"provide the flexibility inherent in a riveted seam",opc:"serve as a crack arrestor and prevent hull girder failure",opd:"reduce construction costs",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel has been surveyed in a foreign port and found unseaworthy as a result of neglect. A seaman on this vessel is entitled to discharge and ____________.",opa:"transportation to the port of engagement",opb:"one month's pay only",opc:"one month's pay or transportation to the nearest U.S. port, whichever is the least amount",opd:"one month's pay or transportation to the nearest U.S. port, whichever is the greater amount",ans:"opd"},{question:"The 30 ton capacity pedestal cranes shown in the illustration can lift a maximum weight of how many tons in the twin mode?",opa:"15 tons",opb:"30 tons",opc:"60 tons",opd:"120 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Is tripping limited to harbor and coastal towing?",opa:"No. Forces tending to capsize a tug are as dangerous on the high seas as they are in harbor and coastal work.",opb:"Yes. The long towing hawser used in ocean towing eliminates the danger of tripping.",opc:"No. Tripping is common in ocean towing because of more frequent maneuvering",opd:"Yes. Because of increased water depths, forces required to capsize a tug are not usually found in ocean towing",ans:"opa"},{question:'A "strongback" refers to a ____________.',opa:"bar securing a cargo port",opb:"centerline vertical bulkhead",opc:"deep beam",opd:"spanner stay",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the manufacture of line, plant fibers are twisted together to form ____________.",opa:"cable",opb:"line",opc:"strands",opd:"yarns",ans:"opd"},{question:"The force acting on a single cargo runner which is vertically lifting or lowering a load is greatest when ____________.",opa:"decelerating when lowering the load",opb:"decelerating when raising the load",opc:"lowering the load at constant speed",opd:"raising the load at constant speed",ans:"opa"},{question:"A predictable result of a vessel nearing a bank or edge of a channel is that the ____________.",opa:"stern is drawn to the bank as the bow sheers off",opb:"bow sheers toward the bank",opc:"vessel continues in a straight line, but with greatly reduced maneuverability",opd:"vessel will be drawn bodily into the bank unless the engines are stopped",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is ALWAYS true?",opa:"Keep clear of any line that is under a strain.",opb:"A line will creak, make snapping sounds, and smoke before it parts.",opc:"Only synthetic lines will snap back after parting.",opd:"Stepping on the bight of a line is safer than stepping in the bight of a line.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The pipe used to connect two separate piping systems on a tank vessel is known as a ____________.",opa:"crossover",opb:"transfer",opc:"connection",opd:"junction",ans:"opa"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to move slowly?",opa:"Use one hand to give any motion signal, and place the other hand motionless in front of the hand giving the motion signal.",opb:"Extend arm with the thumb pointing up, and flex the fingers in and out for as long as the load movement is desired.",opc:"First tap your elbow with one hand and then proceed to use regular signals.",opd:"First tap the top of your head with your fist and then proceed to use regular signals.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When towing astern, chafing gear should NOT be used on a hawser which is ____________.",opa:"attached to an 'H' bitt",opb:"attached to an automatic towing engine",opc:"held amidships by a gob rope",opd:"connected to a swivel",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following statements is/are FALSE concerning cranes being installed on the centerline of vessels?",opa:"One crane is able to work both sides of the ship.",opb:"One crane is able to work one end of two adjacent hatches.",opc:"A centerline crane can never work more than one hatch.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"When underway with a tow, you are required to notify the Coast Guard in which casualty situation?",opa:"Damage to property amounting to$12,500",opb:"Accidental stranding or grounding",opc:"Loss of bridge-to-bridge radio capability",opd:"An injury requiring first aid treatment",ans:"opb"},{question:"The anchor chain should be kept moderately taut during a Mediterranean moor to ____________.",opa:"facilitate speed of recovery during the weighing process",opb:"indicate the anchor's location to passing or mooring ships",opc:"prevent damage to the stern in the event of a headwind",opd:"provide a steady platform for the gangway between the fantail and pier",ans:"opc"},{question:"The purpose of a bilge well is to ____________.",opa:"afford access to the shell through the double bottoms",opb:"collect water to be pumped out",opc:"provide access for the pneumercator",opd:"provide a base line for sounding measurements",ans:"opb"},{question:"The vessel shown has broken down and you are going to take her in tow. The wind is on her starboard beam. She is making more leeway than you. Where should you position your vessel when you start running lines?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opd"},{question:"Floors aboard ship are ____________.",opa:"frames to which the tank top and bottom shell are fastened on a double bottomed ship",opb:"transverse members of the ships frame which support the decks",opc:"longitudinal beams in the extreme bottom of a ship from which the ship's ribs start",opd:"longitudinal angle bars fastened to a surface for strength",ans:"opa"},{question:"When rigging a bosun's chair, a tail block or lizard is used to ____________.",opa:"guide the bosun's chair down a stay when applying a protective coating",opb:"run paint or tools up to a sailor in a chair with a heaving line",opc:"keep a bosun's chair from swinging with the ship's motion",opd:"reeve the gantline through",ans:"opd"},{question:"The label required for magnesium scrap is ____________.",opa:"oxidizer",opb:"yellow",opc:"corrosive",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"If there are any changes in the crew in a foreign port, the changes will be made by ____________.",opa:"the Master on the Certified Crew List",opb:"the Master on the Shipping Articles",opc:"U.S. Consul on the Certified Crew List",opd:"U.S. Consul on the Shipping Articles",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are transporting dangerous cargo on your vessel. The regulations require you to ____________.",opa:"periodically inspect it and make an entry in a log",opb:"keep a warning sign posted nearby",opc:"keep a fire hose run out and ready for use if needed",opd:"allow no chipping or painting in the vicinity of the cargo",ans:"opa"},{question:"The length of a standard 'shot' of chain is ____________.",opa:"12 fathoms",opb:"15 fathoms",opc:"18 fathoms",opd:"20 fathoms",ans:"opb"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to lower the boom?",opa:"With arm extended and fingers closed, point thumb downward.",opb:"With arm extended downwards and forefinger pointing down, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opc:"Extend arm with the palm down, and hold this position rigidly.",opd:"With hands clasped in front of your body.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The garboard strake is the ____________.",opa:"raised flange at the main deck edge",opb:"riveted crack arrester strap on all-welded ships",opc:"riveting pattern most commonly used in ship construction",opd:"row of plating nearest the keel",ans:"opd"},{question:"The number of certificated able seamen and lifeboat men required on a vessel is determined by the ____________.",opa:"International Maritime Organization",opb:"Corps of Engineers",opc:"Coast Guard",opd:"American Bureau of Shipping",ans:"opc"},{question:"On the Great Lakes, the term 'controlling depth' means the ____________.",opa:"designed dredging depth of a channel constructed by the Corps. of Engineers",opb:"minimum amount of tail water available behind a dam",opc:"distance in units of the chart (feet, meters or fathoms) from the reference datum to the bottom",opd:"least depth within the limits of the channel which restricts the navigation",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) when it becomes necessary to send a distress message. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"P (PRIORITY)",opb:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opc:"R (ROUTINE)",opd:"Z (FLASH)",ans:"opb"},{question:"The organization that certifies the safe working load of cargo cranes on a vessel is the ____________.",opa:"classification society",opb:"National Cargo Bureau",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"none of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"'Free pratique' means that ____________.",opa:"clearance requirements for all regulatory bodies have been met",opb:"health requirements have been met and no further quarantine formalities are required",opc:"shipment will be made at no cost",opd:"tonnage taxes are not required to be paid",ans:"opb"},{question:"The fluke is indicated by which letter?",opa:"F",opb:"G",opc:"H",opd:"I",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have orders to load cargoes of carbon disulfide, diisopropylamine and pyridine on your multi-product tankship. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Carbon disulfide may be carried in NOS. 1 and 2 center tanks and diisopropylamine in NOS. 1 and 2 wing tanks.",opb:"Pyridine and diisopropylamine may be carried in tanks having a common header vent.",opc:"Diisopropylamine must be separated from carbon disulfide by two barriers (cofferdams, voids, empty tanks, etc.)",opd:"A tank of carbon disulfide may be used to separate a tank of pyridine from a tank of diisopropylamine.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A seaman about to be discharged has a Continuous Discharge Book. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"A Certificate of Discharge Form should be attached to the book.",opb:"An entry should be made in the book and a Certificate of Discharge Form issued to the seaman.",opc:"If a vessel was on coastwise articles, the record of discharge will be made in the Official Logbook.",opd:"The record of entry in the book must be submitted to the Coast Guard.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The ratio of the height of a vessel's rudder to its width is referred to as the ____________.",opa:"aspect ratio",opb:"constriction ratio",opc:"rudder ratio",opd:"steering ratio",ans:"opa"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to raise the boom?",opa:"Extend arm with the thumb pointing up and flex the fingers in and out.",opb:"Place both fists in front of the body with the thumbs pointing upward.",opc:"With forearm vertical and forefinger pointing up, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opd:"Extend arm with fingers closed and point thumb upward.",ans:"opd"},{question:"On the Great Lakes, short-term fluctuations in water levels may be a result of any of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"strong winds",opb:"sudden changes in barometric pressure",opc:"seiches",opd:"below normal rain fall",ans:"opd"},{question:"During the course of a voyage, a seaman falls on the main deck and injures his ankle. The Master should submit a Report of Marine Accident, Injury or Death if the ____________.",opa:"injured needs first aid",opb:"injured, is unable to perform routine duties",opc:"injury results in loss of life only",opd:"injury is the result of misconduct",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are using an automatic tension winch by yourself. If you get caught in the turns of the line as they lead into the gypsyhead ____________.",opa:"the safety cutout will stop the winch before you're injured",opb:"the line will part and snap back",opc:"you may be pulled into the winch and injured or killed",opd:"None of the above are correct",ans:"opc"},{question:"When evacuating a seaman by helicopter lift, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The vessel should be stopped with the wind dead ahead during the hoisting operation.",opb:"Flags should be flown to provide a visual reference as to the direction of the apparent wind.",opc:"The drop line should be grounded first then secured as close to the hoist point as possible.",opd:"The hoist area should be located as far aft as possible so the pilot will have a visual reference while approaching.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following are considered to be 'road vehicles' that can be carried on Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Semi-trailer",opb:"Train",opc:"Articulated train",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are operator of a towing vessel which collides with a buoy and drags it off station. What should you do if the damage to your vessel is not serious?",opa:"If the buoy is afloat, no action is necessary.",opb:"Wait one week and submit form GG-2692 to the nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety or Inspection Office.",opc:"Immediately notify the nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety or Inspection Office and no further action is necessary.",opd:"Immediately notify the nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety or Inspection Office and then submit form CG-2692.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The best method of protecting that portion of a fiber anchor line nearest the anchor from chafing on the bottom is by ____________.",opa:"using a small scope ratio",opb:"replacing that portion with a short length of chain",opc:"using a hockle to keep that portion of the anchor line off the bottom",opd:"using a synthetic line",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which synthetic rope has the greatest breaking strength?",opa:"Polyethylene",opb:"Polyester",opc:"Polyglycine",opd:"Polypropylene",ans:"opb"},{question:"After casting off moorings at a mooring buoy in calm weather, you should ____________.",opa:"go full ahead on the engine(s)",opb:"back away a few lengths to clear the buoy and then go ahead on the engines",opc:"go half ahead on the engines and put the rudder hard right",opd:"go half ahead on the engines and pass upstream of the buoy",ans:"opb"},{question:"The thickness of a 30.6 pound plate is ____________.",opa:"3/8'",opb:"1/2'",opc:"3/4'",opd:"1'",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are to load a consignment of lumber. Each piece measures 2-inches thick, 10-inches wide and 16-feet long. There are 30,000 pieces in the shipment. How many board feet would be listed on the Bill of Lading?",opa:"800000",opb:"1200000",opc:"1440000",opd:"14400000",ans:"opa"},{question:"A U.S. Coast Guard icebreaker, while escorting ships in ice, may sound four short and one long blasts on the whistle to indicate that the icebreaker ____________.",opa:"has become beset in fast ice",opb:"is increasing speed; watch for broken ice",opc:"has its engines full astern",opd:"is increasing the distance between vessels",ans:"opa"},{question:"When inspecting wire rope before a hoisting operation, one must look for ____________.",opa:"fishhooks",opb:"kinks",opc:"worn spots",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which publication offers information on Great Lakes ice services?",opa:"Light List volume VII",opb:"U.S. Coast Pilot #6",opc:"Marine Weather Log",opd:"National Weather Service, Ice Outlooks",ans:"opb"},{question:"Generally speaking, the most favorable bottom for anchoring is ____________.",opa:"very soft mud",opb:"rocky",opc:"a mixture of mud and clay",opd:"loose sand",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) and wish to send a message concerning an initial enemy contact. Which precedence will you assign this message?",opa:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opb:"P (PRIORITY)",opc:"R (ROUTINE)",opd:"Z (FLASH)",ans:"opd"},{question:"A towline should be fastened to ____________.",opa:"the chocks at the bow of a towed vessel",opb:"the most forward, centermost point of a towed vessel such as a sturdy bow rail",opc:"the mast of a towed sailboat",opd:"a secure fitting near the bow of the towed vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"Cargoes that might leak from containers are known as ____________.",opa:"dirty cargoes",opb:"caustic cargoes",opc:"wet cargoes",opd:"bulk cargoes",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are using tackle number 3 to lift a weight of 120 lbs. If you include 10 percent of the weight for each sheave for friction, what is the pull on the hauling part required to lift the weight?",opa:"52 lbs.",opb:"49 lbs.",opc:"40 lbs.",opd:"27 lbs.",ans:"opa"},{question:"With a given load on the cargo hook, tension in a single span topping lift ____________.",opa:"increases as the boom's angle to the horizontal increases",opb:"is at a maximum when the boom is at a 45\xb0 angle to the horizontal",opc:"increases as the boom's angle to the horizontal decreases",opd:"decreases as the boom's angle to the horizontal decreases",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the period of validity of a Safety Management Certificate?",opa:"60 months",opb:"48 months",opc:"42 months",opd:"36 months",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following actions are stated in the correct order prior to loading or discharging cargo on a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Raise/open stern door, lower the stern ramp, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",opb:"Lower the stern ramp, raise/open stern door, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",opc:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, lower the stern ramp, raise/open stern door",opd:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, raise/open stern door, lower the stern ramp",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 8?",opa:"Parbuckle",opb:"Gun tackle",opc:"Single purchase",opd:"Single luff tackle",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are the licensed operator of a 100 GT towing vessel making coastwise runs. Whenever a crew member is discharged from your vessel you must ____________.",opa:"issue a Certificate of Discharge and make an entry in his Continuous Discharge Book",opb:"issue a Certificate of Discharge or make an entry in his Continuous Discharge Book",opc:"retain the crew member's Continuous Discharge Book onboard",opd:"retain the crew member's Certificate of Discharge onboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"The knot lettered E is a ____________.",opa:"stopper hitch",opb:"blackwall hitch",opc:"timber and half hitch",opd:"bowline on a bight",ans:"opc"},{question:"In determining the scope of cable to be used when anchoring, what would NOT be considered?",opa:"Depth of the water",opb:"Character of the holding ground",opc:"maintenance cost for the chain",opd:"Type of anchor cable",ans:"opc"},{question:"When comparing twin screw tug to single screw tugs, which statement about a twin screw tug is FALSE?",opa:"If one engine fails, you do not lose control of the tow.",opb:"It is more maneuverable.",opc:"It develops more bollard pull for the same horsepower.",opd:"It is generally subject to more propeller damage from debris in the water.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Aboard ship, vertical flat plates running transversely and connecting the vertical keel to the margin plates are called ____________.",opa:"floors",opb:"intercostals",opc:"girders",opd:"stringers",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel is underway with a work stage rigged over the side. A seaman may work on the stage, but only when ____________.",opa:"wearing a life jacket",opb:"wearing a safety harness secured to the stage",opc:"wearing both a life jacket and a safety harness secured to the stage",opd:"the vessel is not making way",ans:"opd"},{question:"The owner or Master of a towing vessel must ensure that each person that directs and controls the movement of the vessel knows all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"the effects of maneuvering on the vessel and its tow",opb:"the speed and direction of any current for the area being transited",opc:"how to apply variation and deviation to readings from a magnetic compass",opd:"the ownership of the vessel(s) being towed",ans:"opd"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability book to determine the hogging numeral.",opa:"98.23 numeral",opb:"95.70 numeral",opc:"84.46 numeral",opd:"81.37 numeral",ans:"opb"},{question:"The effect of wind on exposed areas of the vessel is most noticeable when ____________.",opa:"backing",opb:"going slow ahead",opc:"going full ahead",opd:"turning",ans:"opa"},{question:"The use of an anchor to assist in turning in restricted waters is ____________.",opa:"a last resort",opb:"good seamanship",opc:"the sign of a novice shiphandler",opd:"to be used only with a single-screw vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have orders to load cargoes of carbon disulfide, diisopropylamine and pyridine on your multi-product tankship. Which statement is true?",opa:"Carbon disulfide may be carried in NOS. 1 and 2 center tanks and diisopropylamine in NOS. 1 and 2 wing tanks.",opb:"Pyridine and diisopropylamine may not be carried in tanks having a common header vent.",opc:"Pyridine must be separated from carbon disulfide by two barriers (cofferdams, voids, empty tanks, etc.).",opd:"A tank of diisopropylamine may be used to separate a tank of pyridine from a tank of carbon disulfide.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Cargo transfer operations on a tank vessel need NOT be stopped when ____________.",opa:"a tug comes alongside while the tanker is loading grade D and E cargoes",opb:"a large, fresh oil spill is discovered immediately adjacent to the side of the tanker",opc:"there is an electrical storm in the vicinity",opd:"there is a fire on the dock or on a nearby vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"'Hard right rudder' means ____________.",opa:"put the rudder over to the right all the way",opb:"jam the rudder against the stops",opc:"meet a swing to the right, then return to amidships",opd:"put the rudder over quickly to 15\xb0 right rudder",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is used when securing heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Buckle or ratchet tensioner",opb:"Webbing",opc:"Manila rope",opd:"None of these",ans:"opd"},{question:"Official proof of an American vessel's nationality is contained in the ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Official Log",opc:"Certificate of Documentation",opd:"Shipping Articles",ans:"opc"},{question:"What provides little or no indication that a vessel is dragging anchor?",opa:"Increasing radar range to a fixed object ahead",opb:"Drift lead with the line leading perpendicular to the centerline",opc:"Vibrations felt by placing a hand on the anchor cable",opd:"Changing bearings to distant fixed objects abeam",ans:"opb"},{question:"The term 'overriding' or 'overrunning' when applied to towing, implies that ____________.",opa:"there is more crew on board than required",opb:"the tow has overtaken its tug",opc:"the towing hawser comes out of the water",opd:"the Norman pins are not effective",ans:"opb"},{question:"The locking pin that joins the parts of a detachable link is held in position by ____________.",opa:"a tack weld",opb:"the self-locking characteristics of its taper",opc:"a cotter pin",opd:"a lead plug",ans:"opd"},{question:"When relieving the helm, the new helmsman should find it handy to know the ____________.",opa:"amount of helm carried for a steady course",opb:"variation in the area",opc:"leeway",opd:"deviation on that heading",ans:"opa"},{question:"The distance a vessel moves at right angles to the original course, when a turn of 180\xb0 has been completed, is called the ____________.",opa:"advance",opb:"pivoting point",opc:"tactical diameter",opd:"kick",ans:"opc"},{question:"The forecastle card is a(n) ____________.",opa:"copy of the shipping agreement",opb:"quarters allocation",opc:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opd:"unlicensed shipping card from the union",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which towing equipment can be used to prevent the tripping of a tug?",opa:"Bridles",opb:"Chafing boards",opc:"Gob ropes",opd:"Drogues",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have loaded dangerous cargo on your vessel and must fill out a Dangerous Cargo Manifest. In which publication would you find the requirements to complete this form?",opa:"33 CFR -Navigation and Navigable Waters",opb:"46 CFR -Shipping",opc:"IMCO -Intergovernmental Maritime Consultative Organization",opd:"IMDG -International Maritime Dangerous Goods",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which tool is used to open the strands of fiber lines when making an eye splice?",opa:"Belaying spike",opb:"Fid",opc:"Heaver",opd:"Pricker",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel's Certificate of Documentation ____________.",opa:"may be retained by the owner at the home port OR kept on the vessel",opb:"must be posted under transparent material in the pilothouse",opc:"must be carried on board",opd:"must be kept on file at the corporate offices of the owner or operator",ans:"opc"},{question:"When shoring a damaged bulkhead, effort should be taken to spread the pressure over the ____________.",opa:"maximum possible area",opb:"minimum possible area",opc:"nearest watertight door",opd:"nearest longitudinal girder",ans:"opa"},{question:"A twin-screw vessel with a single rudder is making headway. The engines are full speed ahead. There is no wind or current. Which statement is FALSE?",opa:"If one screw is stopped, the ship will turn toward the side of the stopped screw.",opb:"The principal force which turns the ship is set up by the wake against the forward side of the rudder.",opc:"Turning response by use of the rudder only is greater than on a single-screw vessel.",opd:"With the rudder amidships, the ship will steer a fairly steady course.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Damage to cargo caused by fumes or vapors from liquids, gases, or solids is known as ____________.",opa:"contamination",opb:"oxidation",opc:"tainting",opd:"vaporization",ans:"opc"},{question:"In writing up the logbook at the end of your watch, you make an error in writing an entry. What is the proper means of correcting this error?",opa:"Cross out the error with a single line, and write the correct entry, then initial it.",opb:"Carefully and neatly erase the entry and rewrite it correctly.",opc:"Remove this page of the log book, and rewrite all entries on a clean page.",opd:"Blot out the error completely and rewrite the entry correctly.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The structural member indicated by the letter F is known as a(n) ____________.",opa:"erection",opb:"pillar",opc:"girder",opd:"deck support",ans:"opb"},{question:"A cargo of canned foodstuff is packed in cartons. Each carton is 36 cubic feet and weighs 340 pounds. The stowage factor of the cargo is ____________.",opa:"9.5",opb:"62",opc:"212",opd:"237",ans:"opd"},{question:"Any vehicle to be loaded aboard a Ro-Ro vessel must ____________.",opa:"weigh less than 22 tons",opb:"be provided with an effective braking system",opc:"have securing points with each aperture capable of accepting more than one lashing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A spreader bar is used to ____________.",opa:"increase the lifting capacity",opb:"increase the lifting radius",opc:"protect the slings",opd:"protect the upper part of a load",ans:"opd"},{question:"The piping that routes an oil cargo from the manifold directly to a cargo tank and serves only one tank is known as a ____________.",opa:"cargo fill",opb:"filler line",opc:"tank drop",opd:"branch line",ans:"opc"},{question:"A journal kept by the officer of the watch in which day to day happenings are recorded regarding the deck department is the ____________.",opa:"cargo record book",opb:"deck rough log",opc:"bell book",opd:"Official Logbook",ans:"opb"},{question:"When hugging a bank in a narrow channel, you should take precautions against ____________.",opa:"bank suction, squat and the effects of vessels passing close aboard",opb:"clogged sea chests, plugged sea strainers and overheated machinery",opc:"striking underwater obstructions close to the bank",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"In which casualty case is it UNNECESSARY to notify the local Coast Guard Marine Safety Office?",opa:"Your vessel is backing from a dock and runs aground, but is pulled off by tugs in 30 minutes.",opb:"Your vessel strikes a pier and does $1,500 damage to the pier but no damage to the vessel.",opc:"A nylon mooring line parts while the vessel is tied up and kills a harbor worker who was on the pier.",opd:"A seaman is injured and in the hospital for four days.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which type of towing hawser is preferred for towing astern?",opa:"Manila",opb:"Polypropylene",opc:"Nylon",opd:"Polyester",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a ship's crane, the load chart relates the allowable load to the combination of the boom length and ____________.",opa:"winch speed",opb:"boom strength",opc:"load radius",opd:"cable strength",ans:"opc"},{question:"The 30 ton capacity pedestal cranes shown in the illustration can lift a maximum weight of how many tons when two cranes are married together in twin with the other pair of cranes at the opposite end of the hatch?",opa:"30 tons",opb:"60 tons",opc:"90 tons",opd:"120 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"As a ship moves through the water, it causes a wake, which is also moving forward relative to the sea. In addition to a fore and aft motion, this wake also has a(n) ____________.",opa:"downward and inward flow",opb:"downward and outward flow",opc:"upward and inward flow",opd:"upward and outward flow",ans:"opc"},{question:"Pedestal cranes have limit switches to restrict the movement of which function?",opa:"Slew travel limits",opb:"Turntable limits",opc:"Luff travel limits",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the chief hazard encountered when surging synthetic mooring lines on the gypsyhead during operations?",opa:"If there is sudden strain, the man tending the line may be pulled into the gypsyhead.",opb:"The lines may jam and then jump off the gypsyhead.",opc:"The lines' surging may cause the vessel to surge.",opd:"The heat generated may cause the lines to temporarily fuse to the gypsyhead.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which agency is authorized to assist the Coast Guard in the inspection of vessels for the suitability of loading hazardous materials?",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Environmental Protection Agency",opc:"National Cargo Bureau, Inc.",opd:"U.S. Navy explosive loading details",ans:"opc"},{question:"When paying off seamen in a foreign port, where a United States consul is not available, the release must be executed by the seamen and the ____________.",opa:"representative of the foreign country",opb:"local port authority representative",opc:"Master of the vessel",opd:"ship's union delegate",ans:"opc"},{question:"Another name for the garboard strake is the ____________.",opa:"A strake",opb:"Z strake",opc:"side keel plate",opd:"stringer plate",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which term describes a part of a natural fiber line?",opa:"Yarns",opb:"Twines",opc:"Lacings",opd:"Lays",ans:"opa"},{question:"A well in the uppermost deck of a shelter deck vessel which has only a temporary means of closing for the purpose of gaining an exemption from tonnage measurement is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"exemption space",opb:"tonnage deck",opc:"cofferdam",opd:"tonnage opening",ans:"opd"},{question:"The distance that a vessel travels from the time that the order to put engines full astern until the vessel is dead in the water is known as ____________.",opa:"advance",opb:"head reach",opc:"surge",opd:"transfer",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel is entering port 'A' for the first time and has a Pilot conning the vessel. The Master is unsure that the Pilot is taking sufficient action to prevent a collision. What should the Master do?",opa:"Nothing; The Pilot is required by law and is solely responsible for the safety of the vessel.",opb:"State his concerns to the Pilot but do not interfere with the handling of the vessel.",opc:"Direct the Pilot to stop the vessel and anchor if necessary until the situation clears.",opd:"Recommend an alternative action and if not followed relieve the Pilot.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The floors in a vessel's hull structure are kept from tripping, or folding over, by ____________.",opa:"face plates",opb:"bottom longitudinals",opc:"longitudinal deck beams",opd:"transverse deck beams",ans:"opb"},{question:"The document which shows a vessel's nationality, ownership, and tonnage is the ____________.",opa:"Manifest Certificate",opb:"Bill of Lading Certificate",opc:"Certificate of Documentation",opd:"Official Logbook",ans:"opc"},{question:"The crown of the anchor shown is indicated by which letter?",opa:"K",opb:"J",opc:"H",opd:"G",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) when it becomes necessary to send a distress message. What precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"R (ROUTINE)",opb:"Z (FLASH)",opc:"P (PRIORITY)",opd:"O (IMMEDIATE)",ans:"opd"},{question:"What would NOT require that a detailed report of the release of hazardous cargo be made to the Department of Transportation?",opa:"The valve on an empty portable tank that contained acetone is accidentally opened and some of the residue escapes to the open sea.",opb:"A carboy of nitric acid is broken on deck while loading and is flushed overboard with no injury or damage.",opc:"Part of your deck cargo of five gallon cans of paint is damaged and leaking so you jettison them to eliminate the fire hazard.",opd:"Heavy weather causes damage to packages of a hazardous liquid that is subsequently pumped out at sea through the bilge pumping system.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Generally speaking, the more destructive storms occurring on the Great Lakes usually come from the ____________.",opa:"northeast or east",opb:"southwest or west",opc:"northwest or north",opd:"southeast or south",ans:"opb"},{question:"There are basically three categories of water level fluctuations on the Great Lakes. What is NOT included as one of these?",opa:"Long range fluctuations",opb:"Controlled outflow fluctuations",opc:"Seasonal fluctuations",opd:"Short period fluctuations",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which certificate is NOT issued by the Coast Guard?",opa:"Award of official number",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Classification of Hull and Machinery",opd:"Safety Equipment Certificate",ans:"opc"},{question:"An icebreaker assisting a vessel through an ice field would display a visual signal consisting of the code letter 'M' (Mike) to signify that '__________'.",opa:"I am altering my course to starboard",opb:"I am altering my course to port",opc:"I am operating astern propulsion",opd:"my vessel is stopped and making no way through the water",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of line floats?",opa:"Dacron",opb:"Nylon",opc:"Old manila",opd:"Polypropylene",ans:"opd"},{question:"A seaman you have just discharged has a Continuous Discharge Book. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The record of entry in the continuous discharge book shall agree with the entry made in the Ship's Articles.",opb:"If the vessel was on coastwise articles, the record of discharge will be made in the Official Logbook.",opc:"An entry should be made in the book and a Certificate of Discharge issued to the seaman.",opd:"A Certificate of Discharge form should be attached to the book.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The pitch of a propeller is a measure of the ____________.",opa:"angle that the propeller makes with a free stream of water",opb:"angle that the propeller makes with the surface of the water",opc:"number of feet per revolution the propeller is designed to advance in still water without slip",opd:"positive pressure resulting from the difference of the forces on both sides of the moving propeller in still water without slip",ans:"opc"},{question:"When inspecting wire rope that has been in use for some time, one must look for ____________.",opa:"fishhooks",opb:"kinks",opc:"worn spots",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a single-screw vessel with a left-handed propeller making no way in the water. How will your vessel react when you apply right rudder?",opa:"Bow will kick to starboard",opb:"Bow will kick to port",opc:"Rudder alone has no effect on the vessel",opd:"Stern will kick to port, then slowly swing to starboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have orders to load cargoes of carbon disulfide, diisopropylamine and pyridine on your multi-product tankship. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Carbon disulfide may be carried in NOS. 1 and 2 center tanks and diisopropylamine in NOS. 1 and 2 wing tanks.",opb:"Pyridine and diisopropylamine may be carried in tanks having a common header vent.",opc:"Pyridine need not be separated from carbon disulfide by two barriers (cofferdams, voids, empty tanks, etc.).",opd:"A tank of carbon disulfide may be used to separate a tank of pyridine from a tank of diisopropylamine.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of bottom provides most anchors with the best holding ability?",opa:"Clay and rocks",opb:"Soft mud",opc:"Sandy mud",opd:"Soft sand",ans:"opc"},{question:"While the Pilot is maneuvering the vessel to a dock, what is the PRIMARY responsibility of the watch officer?",opa:"Supervise the signaling and flag etiquette.",opb:"Record the bells and their times in the bell book.",opc:"Insure that helm and throttle orders given by the Pilot are correctly executed.",opd:"Judge the appropriateness of the Pilot's orders and countermand them if necessary.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are lifting a 3 ton weight with a single whip rove on a swinging boom set at an angle of 60\xb0 to the horizontal. Use the formula for the size of a shackle with a safe working load and determine the minimum size shackle that should be used to secure the head block to the boom.",opa:"1 1/8 inch",opb:"1 1/2 inch",opc:"1 3/4 inch",opd:"2 inch",ans:"opb"},{question:"The vessel's 'quarter' is located ____________.",opa:"abeam",opb:"dead astern",opc:"just forward of the beam on either side",opd:"on either side of the stern",ans:"opd"},{question:"A U.S. Coast Guard icebreaker may use all of the following distinctive lights when escorting ships in ice EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"a single amber rotating light",opb:"a single red rotating light",opc:"red aircraft warning lights",opd:"a single blue rotating light",ans:"opd"},{question:"How do the height and location of a tug's towing bitts relate to the danger of tripping?",opa:"The further forward and closer to amidships the more readily the tug will trip.",opb:"Placement further aft permits more effective pulling, better steering and eliminates the danger of tripping.",opc:"Installing the bitts down low lowers the center of gravity.",opd:"The height and position of towing bitts has no significance.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When may foreign licensed or documented personnel be employed on a US-flag towing vessel?",opa:"While on a foreign voyage and outside US jurisdiction, in order to meet manning requirements",opb:"While operating above the US outer continental shelf",opc:"On vessels operating on domestic voyages only",opd:"Never, under any circumstances",ans:"opa"},{question:"A load line certificate is valid for how many years?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"5",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to lower the boom and raise the load?",opa:"Extend arm and point finger in the direction to move the boom.",opb:"Extend arm with thumb pointing downward and flex fingers in and out.",opc:"With forearm vertical and forefinger pointing up, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opd:"With arm extended downwards and forefinger pointing down, move hand in small horizontal circles.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Insulating flanges minimize the dangers arising from ____________.",opa:"smoking on deck",opb:"loading asphalt",opc:"accumulations of electrostatic charges",opd:"tank over-pressurization",ans:"opc"},{question:"Fittings used for towing must be ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard approved",opb:"stamped with maximum working loads",opc:"securely fastened",opd:"positioned exactly at the bow of the towed vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"When oil is discharged overboard, an entry is required in the ____________.",opa:"engine rough log",opb:"Oil Record Book",opc:"Official Logbook",opd:"deck rough log",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are using tackle number 5 to lift a weight of 300 lbs. If you include 10 percent of the weight for each sheave for friction, what is the pull on the hauling part required to lift the weight?",opa:"50 lbs.",opb:"75 lbs.",opc:"90 lbs.",opd:"112 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel has an amidships superstructure. Which location would be most suitable for main deck stowage of vehicles?",opa:"On top of #1 hatch",opb:"Beside the hatches, forward of the midships house",opc:"On top of the aftermost hatch on the vessel",opd:"On top of the hatch immediately aft of the midships house",ans:"opd"},{question:"When the pilot is embarked he or she ____________.",opa:"relieves the officer of the watch",opb:"relieves the Master of his duties",opc:"is solely responsible for the safe navigation of the vessel",opd:"is a specialist hired for his or her local navigational knowledge",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a tankship carrying benzene in bulk. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"No other cargoes may be carried due to the possibility of contamination by a carcinogen.",opb:"The crew quarters must have positive-pressure ventilation to prevent the fumes from entering the living spaces.",opc:"Benzene is not a cancer-causing agent.",opd:"Personnel working in regulated areas must use respirators.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The owner or Master of a towing vessel shall ensure that each person that directs and controls the movement of the vessel can accomplish all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"evaluate the danger of each closing visual or radar contact",opb:"adjust speed with due regard for the weather and visibility",opc:"reduce speed only where local speed limits are posted",opd:"enter all required test and inspection results in the vessel's log or other record carried on board",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a voyage charter, when a vessel is ready to load cargo, the Master should render to the charterer a ____________.",opa:"Notice of Readiness",opb:"Master Certificate of Service",opc:"Shipmasters Declaration",opd:"Vessel Utilization and Performance Report",ans:"opa"},{question:"While anchoring your vessel, the best time to let go the anchor is when the vessel is ____________.",opa:"dead in the water",opb:"moving slowly astern over the ground",opc:"moving fast ahead over the ground",opd:"moving fast astern over the ground",ans:"opb"},{question:"The knot lettered G in the illustration is a ____________.",opa:"round turn and two half hitches",opb:"fisherman's bend",opc:"timber hitch",opd:"barrel hitch",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a two-leg sling is used to lift a load, a sling 40 feet long is better than one of 30 feet because the ____________.",opa:"tension in the sling legs is less",opb:"load can be lifted higher",opc:"sling will be easier to attach",opd:"sling will be easier to remove",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are signing on a deck officer, who will be designated as one of the GMDSS operators, before sailing foreign. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"He/she must have an STCW certificate endorsed as 'Valid for Service on Vessels Operating in the GMDSS System'.",opb:"He/she must present either an FCC-issued license or a Coast Guard-issued license.",opc:"You must consult the 'List of Qualifications' on the reverse of his/her FCC-issued license.",opd:"His/her Merchant Mariners Document must have an added endorsement as 'Radio Electronics Officer'.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the best guide for determining the proper scope of anchor chain to use for anchoring in normal conditions?",opa:"One shot of chain for every ten feet of water",opb:"One shot of chain for every fifteen feet of water",opc:"One shot of chain for every thirty feet of water",opd:"One shot of chain for every ninety feet of water",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are aboard a single-screw vessel (right-hand propeller) going full ahead with good headway. The engine is put astern and the rudder is placed hard left. The stern of the vessel will swing to ____________.",opa:"starboard until headway is lost and then to port",opb:"port",opc:"port until headway is lost and then may possibly swing to starboard",opd:"port slowly at first and then quickly to port",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is used when securing light vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever or turnbuckle",opb:"Chain",opc:"Wire",opd:"None of these",ans:"opd"},{question:"A tug may be in danger of tripping when ____________.",opa:"towed sideways by an overwhelming force on the towline",opb:"her tow moves parallel to and forward on either side of the tug",opc:"the tow is no longer directly astern but moves up on her quarter",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Shell plating that has curvature in two directions and must be heated and hammered to shape over specially prepared forms is called ____________.",opa:"compound plate",opb:"furnaced plate",opc:"flat plate",opd:"rolled plate",ans:"opb"},{question:"The purpose of a devil's claw is to ____________.",opa:"act as a chain stopper",opb:"prevent the windlass from engaging",opc:"prevent the chain from fouling on deck",opd:"control the wildcat",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) when you wish to send a message concerning your ships diversion. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opb:"Z (FLASH)",opc:"R (ROUTINE)",opd:"P (PRIORITY)",ans:"opd"},{question:"The electrical components for each single crane are installed in its ____________.",opa:"crane house",opb:"machinery base",opc:"turntable",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Functions aboard a tanker or tank barge such as connecting, disconnecting, and topping off must be supervised by ____________.",opa:"any certificated tankerman",opb:"the Master of the vessel",opc:"the officer of the watch",opd:"the person designated as 'person in charge'",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following is the stated proper sequence before commencing cargo operations aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Start ventilation, lower the ramp, notify engine room",opb:"Lower the ramp, start ventilation, notify engine room",opc:"Notify engine room, lower the ramp, start ventilation",opd:"Start ventilation, notify engine room, lower the ramp",ans:"opc"},{question:"The metal, teardrop-shaped object sometimes used within an eyesplice is a ____________.",opa:"grommet",opb:"reinforcement",opc:"splice form",opd:"thimble",ans:"opd"},{question:"Strengthening damaged bulkheads by using wood or steel is called ____________.",opa:"bracing",opb:"battening",opc:"blocking",opd:"shoring",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a helmsman receives the command 'Right 15 degrees rudder,' the helmsman's immediate reply should be ____________.",opa:"'Right 15 degrees rudder'",opb:"'Aye Aye Sir'",opc:"'Rudder is right 15 degrees'",opd:"No reply is necessary, just carry out the order.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The oil record book is required to be carried aboard ____________.",opa:"tankers",opb:"passenger vessels",opc:"cargo vessels",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have the 'conn' at the time the helmsman who is steering by hand reports that the rudder is not responding to the wheel. Your FIRST action should be to ____________.",opa:"shift the selector switch to the other steering pump",opb:"signal the engineroom to stop the engines",opc:"call the engineroom",opd:"call the Master",ans:"opa"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the hogging numeral.",opa:"86.72 numeral",opb:"89.98 numeral",opc:"91.40 numeral",opd:"93.18 numeral",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which knot is secure only when there is a strain on the line?",opa:"H",opb:"I",opc:"L",opd:"P",ans:"opc"},{question:"When anchoring a vessel, it is best to release the anchor when ____________.",opa:"going full astern",opb:"going full ahead",opc:"going slow astern",opd:"dead in the water",ans:"opc"},{question:"Cargo that is highly susceptible to damage by tainting from odorous cargo is called ____________.",opa:"clean cargo",opb:"delicate cargo",opc:"dry cargo",opd:"immune cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the minimum size required before a vessel can be documented?",opa:"5 net tons",opb:"100 gross tons",opc:"26 feet length",opd:"65 feet length",ans:"opa"},{question:"When taking a length of new manila rope from the coil, you should ____________.",opa:"mount the coil so it will turn like a spool and unreel from the outside",opb:"roll the coil along the deck and allow the rope to fall off the coil",opc:"lay the coil on end with the inside end down, then pull the inside end up through the middle of the coil",opd:"lay the coil on end with the inside end up then unwind the rope from the outside of the coil",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a tow sinks in shallow water, you should ____________.",opa:"release it immediately",opb:"attempt to beach it before it goes under",opc:"pay out cable until it's on the bottom and place a buoy on the upper end",opd:"shorten cable to keep it off the bottom",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are using tackle number 7 to lift a weight of 100 lbs. If you include 10 percent of the weight for each sheave for friction, what is the pull on the hauling part required to lift the weight?",opa:"200 lbs.",opb:"150 lbs.",opc:"110 lbs.",opd:"55 lbs.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The main underdeck pipeline on a tankship is connected to individual tanks by ____________.",opa:"tank drops",opb:"line drops",opc:"crossovers",opd:"branch lines",ans:"opd"},{question:"Wire rope is used in the towing industry ____________.",opa:"for back up wires and main towing hawsers",opb:"for face wires or jockeys when pushing ahead",opc:"as stern wires when pushing ahead",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The crane manufacturer's operating tables are posted near the ____________.",opa:"crane pedestal",opb:"wire-rope locker",opc:"main deck",opd:"crane controls",ans:"opd"},{question:"The forecastle card is a copy of the ____________.",opa:"quarters allocation",opb:"shipping agreement",opc:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opd:"unlicensed shipping card from the union",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the stowage factor of a commodity whose density is 15 pounds per cubic foot?",opa:"15",opb:"45",opc:"133",opd:"149",ans:"opd"},{question:"The rudders are amidships and both screws are going ahead. What will happen if the starboard screw is stopped?",opa:"The bow will go to port.",opb:"The bow will go to starboard.",opc:"The bow will remain steady.",opd:"The stern will go to starboard.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel is entering port and has a Pilot conning the vessel. The Master is unsure that the Pilot is taking sufficient action to prevent a collision. What should the Master do?",opa:"Nothing; the Pilot is required by law and is solely responsible for the safety of the vessel.",opb:"State his concerns to the Pilot but do not interfere with the handling of the vessel.",opc:"Recommend an alternative action and if not followed relieve the Pilot.",opd:"Direct the Pilot to stop the vessel and anchor if necessary until the situation clears.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What affect does shallow water have on a vessel's stopping distance?",opa:"The stopping distance is shorter.",opb:"The stopping distance is longer.",opc:"There is no difference in the stopping distance.",opd:"The propeller is more effective when going astern in shallow water.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A deep draft VLCC (100,000 DWT+) navigating in a narrow channel or canal ____________.",opa:"draws more water than when underway in deep water",opb:"draws less water with an increase in speed",opc:"requires less power for a given speed",opd:"steers better under full power",ans:"opa"},{question:"Pedestal cranes have limit switches to restrict the movement of which function?",opa:"Luff rate limits",opb:"Slew travel limits",opc:"Swivel power limits",opd:"Slew rate limits",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following is considered auxiliary securing equipment that provides extra reliability to lashing in Ro-Ro transport operations?",opa:"Trailer trestles",opb:"Pedestals",opc:"Wheel chocks",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"In which casualty case is it UNNECESSARY to notify the local Coast Guard Marine Safety Office?",opa:"Your vessel is backing from a dock and runs aground, but is pulled off by tugs in 30 minutes.",opb:"A seaman is injured and in the hospital for four days.",opc:"Your vessel strikes a pier and does $1,500 damage to the pier but no damage to the vessel.",opd:"A nylon mooring line parts while the vessel is tied up and kills a harbor worker who was on the pier.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your ship is dead in the water with the rudder amidships. As the right-handed screw starts to turn ahead, the bow will tend to go ____________.",opa:"to starboard",opb:"to port",opc:"straight ahead",opd:"as influenced by the tide and sea",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the Great Lakes generally has the shortest navigation season?",opa:"Lake Erie",opb:"Lake Huron",opc:"Lake Michigan",opd:"Lake Superior",ans:"opd"},{question:"The master or individual in charge of a vessel prepares a certificate of discharge for each mariner being discharged from the vessel where the original discharge goes to the ____________.",opa:"National Maritime Center",opb:"Officer In Charge, Marine Inspection (OCMI)",opc:"Shipping Company",opd:"Mariner",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which factor would NOT lead to removing a towline from service?",opa:"An excessive number of miles of towing service.",opb:"Failing a tensile strength test that proved the towline was no longer appropriate for expected sea conditions.",opc:"When heavy grease on the towline saturates the core of the wire rope.",opd:"Its surface condition is noted, including its corrosion and discoloration.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT a requirement for a salvage claim?",opa:"The property saved must be 'maritime property.'",opb:"The salvors must save or attempt to save any life in peril.",opc:"The salvage service must be voluntary.",opd:"The property must be in peril.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are moving a gas free tank barge to dry dock for repairs. The barge must have onboard a valid ____________.",opa:"Gas Free Certificate",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Permit to Proceed and Hot Work Permit",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Total responsibility for shipping and discharging the seamen is that of the ____________.",opa:"Master of the vessel",opb:"steamship company",opc:"U.S. Custom Service",opd:"U.S. Coast Guard",ans:"opa"},{question:"The tripping palm is indicated by which letter?",opa:"F",opb:"G",opc:"H",opd:"J",ans:"opb"},{question:"A list signal of one white light indicates that the vessel is ____________.",opa:"on an even keel",opb:"listing about 1\xb0 to the side the light is displayed on",opc:"listing over 5\xb0 with the light displayed on the high side",opd:"listing, and the chutes should be directed to the side where the light is displayed",ans:"opb"},{question:"A man was sighted as he fell overboard. After completing a Williamson turn, the man is not sighted. What type of search should be conducted?",opa:"Expanding circle",opb:"Sector search",opc:"Parallel track pattern",opd:"Datum-drift search",ans:"opb"},{question:"To properly rig the downhaul to your stage for lowering, you must ____________.",opa:"take only figure eights around the horns",opb:"take 2 or 3 round turns around the stage and then belay the downhaul around the horns",opc:"take 2 round turns around the stage and then dip the third turn to form a clove hitch",opd:"pass the downhaul through the bridle formed by the standing part and then take round turns",ans:"opb"},{question:"If the towline parts, you should ____________.",opa:"start pushing ahead",opb:"abandon the towing vessel",opc:"retrieve the tow bridle",opd:"relieve strain on the retrieving line",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to the illustration, which of the figures is the preferred method of forming a temporary eye splice using wire rope clips?",opa:"A.",opb:"B.",opc:"C.",opd:"D.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The official identification of a vessel is found in the ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Classification Certificate",opc:"Load Line Certificate",opd:"Certificate of Documentation",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) and wish to send a message concerning an initial enemy contact. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opb:"P (PRIORITY)",opc:"Z (FLASH)",opd:"R (ROUTINE)",ans:"opc"},{question:"The area indicated by the letter G is known as the ____________.",opa:"entrance",opb:"stringer plate",opc:"turn of the bilge",opd:"garboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"Assume that your vessel has just entered Lake Erie by way of the Welland Canal and is proceeding in a southwesterly direction. Which statement about the aids to navigation you can expect to encounter along the route is TRUE?",opa:"The characteristics of buoys and other aids are as if 'returning from seaward' when proceeding in this direction.",opb:"All aids are maintained by the U.S.. Coast Guard, 9th Coast Guard District, Cleveland, Ohio.",opc:"All red even-numbered buoys should be kept on your port side when proceeding in this direction.",opd:"Lighted aids, fog signals, and radio beacons maintained by Canada are not included in the Great Lakes Light List.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Who is responsible for establishing watches aboard a U.S. vessel?",opa:"The owner of the vessel",opb:"The company that operates the vessel",opc:"The company that charters the vessel",opd:"The Master of the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a vessel designed to carry compressed gasses in bulk with a cargo of butadiene. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The ullage must be padded with compressed air at a minimum pressure of 2 psig.",opb:"Silver and copper are prohibited in the parts of valves and fittings in contact with the cargo.",opc:"The cargo tank may be sampled only when the tank is being filled.",opd:"The shipping document must specify the exact quantity of butadiene being carried.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What type of line melts easiest?",opa:"Wire",opb:"Dacron",opc:"Nylon",opd:"Polypropylene",ans:"opd"},{question:"A disadvantage of using chain lashing on heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels is that ____________.",opa:"it is easily damaged",opb:"it is affected by temperature",opc:"the links lose strength if placed over corners",opd:"it has high initial cost",ans:"opc"},{question:"As the propeller turns, voids are formed on the trailing and leading edges of the propeller blades causing a loss of propulsive efficiency, pitting of the blades, and vibration. These voids are known as ____________.",opa:"advance",opb:"cavitation",opc:"edging",opd:"slip",ans:"opb"},{question:"Where are the test certificates, for wire rope used as cargo runners, and loose gear certificates usually maintained?",opa:"With the Cargo Gear Register on the ship",opb:"In the Official Log",opc:"At the Coast Guard Marine Safety Office with the vessel's inspection records",opd:"At the central records center of the agency testing the cargo gear",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the principal danger in attempting to swing a barge on a hawser in order to slow the barge's speed?",opa:"Dangerous wakes may result from the swinging barge and capsize the tug.",opb:"The barge may swing too quickly and run over the tug.",opc:"Free surface effect of liquid inside the barge may rupture the barge bulkheads if the turn is too quick.",opd:"The barge may pass under the hawser and capsize the tug.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Conventional anchors are least likely to hold in a bottom consisting of ____________.",opa:"soft clay",opb:"hard mud",opc:"very soft mud",opd:"sand",ans:"opc"},{question:"An icebreaker assisting a vessel through an ice field would display a visual signal consisting of the code letter 'I' (India) to signify that '__________'.",opa:"I am altering my course to starboard",opb:"I am altering my course to port",opc:"I am operating astern propulsion",opd:"My vessel is stopped and making no way through the water",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which basic category of water level fluctuations on the Great Lakes is the most regular?",opa:"Seasonal fluctuations",opb:"Outflow fluctuations",opc:"Short-term fluctuations",opd:"Long-term fluctuations",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are stopped with no way upon your vessel at the pilot station. Your vessel is a large twin-screw ship. You must come around 180\xb0 to board your Pilot. How should you use the engines and rudder to turn the ship fastest in the least amount of space?",opa:"Full ahead on the engines and hard over rudder",opb:"Full ahead on one engine, full astern on the other",opc:"Half ahead with hard over rudder, then full astern on inboard engine",opd:"Slow ahead with hard over rudder",ans:"opc"},{question:"When working with wire rope, which must be considered?",opa:"Metal sheaves should be lined with wood or leather.",opb:"It needs better care than hemp or manila.",opc:"It should be lubricated annually.",opd:"The diameter of a sheave over which a rope is worked should be ten times that of the rope.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the sagging numeral.",opa:"29.49 numeral",opb:"31.97 numeral",opc:"33.61 numeral",opd:"35.12 numeral",ans:"opb"},{question:"While on watch at sea you must maintain a proper lookout at all times. On a 700-foot cargo vessel being hand-steered during daylight hours in good visibility and clear of any navigational hazards, the lookout may be ____________.",opa:"the helmsman",opb:"the mate on watch",opc:"Either A or B",opd:"Neither A nor B",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are transporting dangerous cargo on your vessel. You must inspect this cargo ____________.",opa:"daily",opb:"daily, at sea only",opc:"after encountering rough weather",opd:"after loading and prior to arrival in port only",ans:"opa"},{question:"The knot lettered I as shown is a ____________.",opa:"square knot",opb:"round knot",opc:"bowline on a bight",opd:"timber hitch",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are lifting a 5-ton weight with a single whip rove on a swinging boom set at an angle of 20\xb0 to the horizontal. Use the formula for the size of a shackle with a safe working load and determine the minimum size shackle that should be used to secure the head block to the boom.",opa:"1 3/8 inch",opb:"1 1/2 inch",opc:"1 3/4 inch",opd:"1 7/8 inch",ans:"opc"},{question:"Progressive flooding is controlled by securing watertight boundaries and ____________.",opa:"transferring water ballast",opb:"jettisoning cargo",opc:"pumping out flooded compartments",opd:"abandoning ship",ans:"opc"},{question:"What should be given, as a minimum, to personnel who are involved in crane cargo handling?",opa:"Protective head gear, gloves, and steel-toed safety shoes",opb:"A survival suit for work on the stern or side port",opc:"A life preserver for going aloft to work on the crane",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"When stripping a tank, excessive air in the suction line may cause ____________.",opa:"an over pressurized line",opb:"back pressure",opc:"loss of suction",opd:"increase of suction",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the Master of a US-flag towing vessel replaces any crew member with a non-US citizen, he/she must ensure that the ____________.",opa:"replacement holds a license or document equivalent in experience and training to a mariner holding US credentials",opb:"replacement can communicate with other crew members to the extent required by regulations",opc:"vessel is on a foreign voyage, outside US jurisdiction, and not operating above the US outer continental shelf",opd:"all of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which document shows details of a tank vessel, cargoes it may carry, manning and safety equipment required?",opa:"Safety Construction Certificate",opb:"Cargo Gear Certificate",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Declaration of Inspection",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT true regarding a Lloyd's Open Form (LOF) Salvage Agreement?",opa:"The agreement between vessels can be made via VHF",opb:"If salvage is not successful, vessel owes salvor nothing",opc:"There is a bonus to the salvage award if environmental casualty is averted",opd:"The LOF is subject to the law of the country the two parties agree upon",ans:"opd"},{question:"The sprocket teeth on a wildcat are known as the ____________.",opa:"pawls",opb:"devil's claws",opc:"whelps",opd:"pockets",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which term refers to a transverse curvature of the deck?",opa:"Deadrise",opb:"Camber",opc:"Freeboard",opd:"Flare",ans:"opb"},{question:"The 'inner bottom' is the ____________.",opa:"tank top",opb:"compartment between the tank top and shell of the vessel",opc:"inner side of the vessel's shell",opd:"space between two transverse bottom frames",ans:"opa"},{question:"The primary purpose of a load line is to establish required ____________.",opa:"minimum freeboard",opb:"GM",opc:"transverse stability",opd:"fresh water allowances",ans:"opa"},{question:"What may NOT be used when securing heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever",opb:"Turnbuckle",opc:"Webbing",opd:"Chain",ans:"opc"},{question:"The two courses of action if the underwater hull is severely damaged are to plug the openings or to ____________.",opa:"establish and maintain flooding boundaries",opb:"dewater the compartment",opc:"secure power to the compartment",opd:"ballast to maintain even keel",ans:"opa"},{question:"The anchor shackle is indicated by which letter?",opa:"K",opb:"J",opc:"H",opd:"F",ans:"opa"},{question:"A cargo that has a stowage factor over 40 is known as a ____________.",opa:"hygroscopic cargo",opb:"measurement cargo",opc:"stowage cargo",opd:"weight cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are conducting trials to determine the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel. While making a turn, you take ranges and bearings of an isolated light with the results as shown. Based on this information, what is the advance for a turn of 90\xb0?",opa:"820 yards",opb:"870 yards",opc:"930 yards",opd:"975 yards",ans:"opb"},{question:"Following a Serious Marine Incident, a mariner directly involved in the incident is required to submit a urine specimen for drug testing within ____________.",opa:"2 hours",opb:"12 hours",opc:"24 hours",opd:"32 hours",ans:"opd"},{question:"A cargo of canned foodstuffs is packed in cartons. Each carton is 36 cubic feet and weighs 380 pounds. What is the stowage factor of the cargo?",opa:"9.5",opb:"62",opc:"212",opd:"237",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE about placing the eyes of two mooring lines on the same bollard?",opa:"Put one line at the low point and one at the high point of the bollard so they don't touch.",opb:"Take the eye of the second line up through the eye of the first line before putting the second line on the bollard.",opc:"Never put two mooring lines on the same bollard.",opd:"The mooring line forward should be put on the bollard first.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are aboard a right-handed single-screw vessel with headway on. The engine is put full astern and the rudder hard left. What will the bow do?",opa:"It will swing to the left, and will swing left faster as the vessel loses way.",opb:"It will swing to the left, straighten out and then swing to the right as the vessel loses way.",opc:"It will swing to the left without increasing or decreasing its swing.",opd:"The bow will swing to the right.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The securing systems for containers were developed to prevent container movement during which ship motion?",opa:"Surge",opb:"Roll",opc:"Sway",opd:"Yaw",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT required as special safety equipment on a tankship carrying hazardous cargoes in bulk?",opa:"Shower and eyewash fountain",opb:"Equipment to lift an injured person from a pumproom",opc:"Two portable vapor detectors suitable for the cargoes carried",opd:"A safety locker adjacent to the emergency shutdown station",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which knot should be used to secure a line to a spar when the pull is parallel to the spar?",opa:"G",opb:"F",opc:"P",opd:"Q",ans:"opc"},{question:"When weighing anchor in a rough sea, how would you avoid risk of damaging the bow plating?",opa:"Heave it home as fast as you can.",opb:"Heave it home intermittently, between swells.",opc:"Leave the anchor under foot, until the vessel may be brought before the sea.",opd:"Wait for a calm spot between seas, then house it.",ans:"opc"},{question:"In bad weather, what length of chain should be used with a single anchor?",opa:"3 times the depth of water",opb:"6 times the depth of water",opc:"10 times the depth of water",opd:"15 times the depth of water",ans:"opc"},{question:"The load chart of a crane enables the operator to combine the load radius with boom length to determine the ____________.",opa:"maximum counter weight required",opb:"minimum horsepower required",opc:"hoist rope strength",opd:"allowable load",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Master may have his/her license suspended or revoked for ____________.",opa:"carrying stowaways",opb:"sailing shorthanded",opc:"being negligent",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The securing of passenger cars on a Ro-Ro vessel requires ____________.",opa:"simple and lightweight equipment",opb:"low labor intensive equipment",opc:"specially designed equipment to avoid vehicle damage",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is a correct reply to a Pilot's request, 'How's your head'?",opa:"'Passing 040\xb0'",opb:"'Steady'",opc:"'Checked'",opd:"'Eased to 15\xb0 rudder'",ans:"opa"},{question:"A holder of a license as Operator of Uninspected Towing Vessels may work each 24 hours for a period not to exceed ____________.",opa:"24 hours",opb:"18 hours",opc:"12 hours",opd:"6 hours",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on watch and the pilot has just anchored the vessel. The next thing that you should do after the anchor has been let go is to ____________.",opa:"stop the engines",opb:"escort the pilot to the accommodation ladder",opc:"plot the vessel's position on the chart",opd:"make a round of the weather decks",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel proceeding along the bank of a river or channel has the tendency to ____________.",opa:"continue in line with the bank",opb:"hug the bank",opc:"sheer away from the bank",opd:"increase speed",ans:"opc"},{question:"To lay out a towing hawser in a fore-and-aft direction so each bight is clear and can run out freely without snagging describes ____________.",opa:"flemishing",opb:"faking",opc:"spooling",opd:"worming, parceling and serving",ans:"opb"},{question:"You notice that your speed has decreased, the stern of your vessel has settled into the water, and your rudder is sluggish in responding. The MOST likely cause is ____________.",opa:"mechanical problems with the steering gear",opb:"shallow water",opc:"loss of lubricating oil in the engine",opd:"current",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are using tackle number 8 to lift a weight of 100 lbs. If you include 10 percent of the weight for each sheave for friction, what is the pull on the hauling part required to lift the weight?",opa:"120 lbs.",opb:"55 lbs.",opc:"40 lbs.",opd:"37 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The wheel on the windlass with indentations for the anchor chain is the ____________.",opa:"grabber",opb:"wildcat",opc:"locking ring",opd:"pawl",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is another name for the boom of a crane?",opa:"Lift",opb:"Rider",opc:"Jib",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"When should a crane boom-up so high that the boom hits the stops?",opa:"Only if the load has not exceeded the limit at that angle",opb:"Only if the load contains non-hazardous materials",opc:"Only if necessary to perform a given lift",opd:"Never",ans:"opd"},{question:"In the context of shiphandling, what would be the definition of shallow water?",opa:"Water depth of less than twice a vessel's draft",opb:"Water depth of less than 1\xbd times a vessel's draft",opc:"Under keel clearance of twice a vessel's draft",opd:"Under keel clearance of less than 10 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Grade D combustible liquids have a maximum flash point of ____________.",opa:"109\xb0F",opb:"100\xb0F",opc:"149\xb0F",opd:"80\xb0F",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which is NOT required on a tankship carrying hazardous liquid cargoes in bulk?",opa:"A copy of 46 CFR parts 35 and 150",opb:"Certificate of Adequacy for the hazardous cargoes carried",opc:"Certificate of Inspection issued under the Tank Vessel Regulations",opd:"Cargo piping plan showing loading rates for all applicable cargo lines",ans:"opb"},{question:"On which of the Great Lakes would shore ice be the most pronounced?",opa:"Lake Michigan",opb:"Lake Superior",opc:"Lake Huron",opd:"Lake Erie",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a single-screw vessel with a right-handed propeller, and you are making headway. When you enter shallow water, ____________.",opa:"you will have better rudder response",opb:"your speed will increase without a change in your throttle",opc:"your rudder response will become sluggish",opd:"your vessel will tend to ride higher",ans:"opc"},{question:"The maneuver which will return your vessel to a person who has fallen overboard in the shortest time is ____________.",opa:"a Williamson Turn",opb:"engine(s) crash astern, no turn",opc:"a single turn with hard rudder",opd:"two 180\xb0 turns",ans:"opc"},{question:"The strongest way to join the ends of two ropes is with a ____________.",opa:"back splice",opb:"short splice",opc:"square knot",opd:"carrick bend",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which situation requires you to furnish a notice of marine casualty to the Coast Guard?",opa:"Storm damage to the cargo winch motors requires repairs costing $19,000.",opb:"Your vessel is at anchor and grounds at low tide with no apparent damage.",opc:"You collide with a buoy and drag it off station with no apparent damage to the vessel or the buoy.",opd:"A seaman slips on ice on deck and sprains his ankle, requiring an ace bandage.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The part of the anchor indicated by the letter J is the ____________.",opa:"crown",opb:"shank",opc:"bill",opd:"tip",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT a problem when carrying coal?",opa:"The requirement for through-ventilation",opb:"The corrosion some types of coal will cause to the ship",opc:"Spontaneous heating",opd:"Generation of methane gas",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) when you wish to send a message concerning your ships diversion. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"P (PRIORITY)",opb:"Z (FLASH)",opc:"R (ROUTINE)",opd:"O (IMMEDIATE)",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which single-letter signal, when used by icebreakers on the Great Lakes, may be made by using the ship's whistle?",opa:"E",opb:"I",opc:"M",opd:"None",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Shipping Articles shall be signed by each seaman and the ____________.",opa:"Master of the vessel",opb:"Shipping Commissioner",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"U.S. Customs Service",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which factor(s) might indicate that a towline should be removed from service?",opa:"Visible damage to the towline, including fishhooks.",opb:"Measurements showing a decrease in diameter.",opc:"A surface condition of corrosion and discoloration.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A term applied to the bottom shell plating in a double-bottom ship is ____________.",opa:"bottom floor",opb:"outer bottom",opc:"shear plating",opd:"tank top",ans:"opb"},{question:"The disadvantage(s) of using web lashing on light vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels is that it ____________.",opa:"deteriorates in sunlight",opb:"cuts on sharp edges",opc:"is vulnerable to damage and pilferage",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Many dangerous cargoes are stowed on deck because of the ____________.",opa:"danger to crew and cargo",opb:"necessity of periodic inspection",opc:"possible need to jettison",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have been towing astern and have just let go the tow. Your deckhands are pulling in and faking the towline by hand on the stern. The most dangerous action to take is to ____________.",opa:"continue ahead at slow speed",opb:"continue ahead at half speed",opc:"stop your engines",opd:"back down on your engines",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which two Great Lakes are considered hydraulically as one?",opa:"Lakes Superior -Huron",opb:"Lakes Michigan -Huron",opc:"Lakes Erie -St. Clair",opd:"Lakes Erie -Ontario",ans:"opb"},{question:"Cargo securing for Ro-Ro is based on the concept of ____________.",opa:"solid packing",opb:"rapid loading and discharge",opc:"vessel loaded full and down to her marks",opd:"palletized cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Certificate of Inspection for your tankship authorizes the carriage of grade A and lower products. Which chemical may NOT be carried unless it is specifically endorsed on the Certificate of Inspection?",opa:"Amylene",opb:"Diisobutyl Phthalate",opc:"Oleic acid",opd:"Vinyl acetate",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a multiple-product tankship and scheduled to load a cargo classed as an aromatic amine. This cargo is incompatible with cargoes classed as ____________.",opa:"organic anhydrides",opb:"ketones",opc:"phenols",opd:"esters",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are standing watch on entering port and the Master gives a rudder command which conflicts with a rudder command from the Pilot. You should ensure the helmsman ____________.",opa:"obeys the Master",opb:"obeys the Pilot",opc:"brings the rudder to a position midway between the two conflicting positions",opd:"asks the Pilot if he has relinquished control",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel operating 'in class' has met all the requirements of the ____________.",opa:"ABS or similar society",opb:"insurance company",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"U.S. Customs",ans:"opa"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the hogging numeral.",opa:"43.19 numeral",opb:"46.56 numeral",opc:"49.92 numeral",opd:"55.72 numeral",ans:"opa"},{question:"What will NOT increase friction of a liquid flowing in a pipe and cause a loss of suction head?",opa:"Bends in the piping",opb:"Slowing the pumping rate",opc:"Pipeline valves",opd:"Backing rings for pipe welds",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which type of rudder may lose its effectiveness at angles of 10 or more degrees?",opa:"Contra-guide",opb:"Balanced spade",opc:"Unbalanced",opd:"Flat plate",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel which is being assisted by an icebreaker should indicate that she is ready to cast off the towline by ____________.",opa:"displaying code letter 'Y' (Yankee)",opb:"sounding five short blasts on his whistle",opc:"displaying code numeral '5'",opd:"sounding one prolonged blast on his whistle",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about a centrifugal cargo pump is TRUE?",opa:"It is a positive displacement pump.",opb:"It must have a positive suction.",opc:"Increasing rotation speed will decrease discharge pressure.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"In ship construction, keel scantlings should be the greatest ____________.",opa:"at each frame",opb:"amidships",opc:"one-third the distance from the bow",opd:"one-third the distance from the stern",ans:"opb"},{question:"When rigging a stage, the standing part should be fastened to the horns of a stage with which of the following hitches?",opa:"Clove hitch",opb:"Timber hitch",opc:"Marlinespike hitch",opd:"Double blackwall hitch",ans:"opc"},{question:"What must be accurately determined to assess the potential for progressive flooding after a vessel has been damaged?",opa:"The integrity of the water tight boundaries",opb:"The capacity of the water sprinkler systems",opc:"The operation of the machinery space bilge level alarms",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"How are aids to navigation on the Great Lakes arranged geographically?",opa:"In a westerly and northerly direction, except on Lake St. Clair",opb:"In an easterly and southerly direction, except on Lake Erie",opc:"In a westerly and northerly direction, except on Lake Michigan",opd:"In an easterly and southerly direction, except on the New York State Barge Canal",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is being towed and back-up wires have been installed. Back-up wires carry the towing load in the event that the ____________.",opa:"bridle legs part",opb:"towing bitt or pad eye fails",opc:"bight ring fails",opd:"main towing hawser parts",ans:"opb"},{question:"Wages due a seaman may be attached by the court for the ____________.",opa:"payment of monthly bills",opb:"payment of creditors",opc:"support of a minor child",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"A carling is used aboard ship ____________.",opa:"as a connecting strap between the butted ends of plating",opb:"to stiffen areas under points of great stress between beams",opc:"to prevent the anchor from fouling when the brake is released",opd:"to provide an extra heavy fitting in a heavy lift cargo rig",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which type of line is best able to withstand sudden shock loads?",opa:"Polypropylene",opb:"Nylon",opc:"Dacron",opd:"Manila",ans:"opb"},{question:"To determine the number of portable fire extinguishers required on an inspected vessel, you should check the ____________.",opa:"hot work permit",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opd:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who certifies the safe working load of cargo booms on a vessel?",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers",opd:"The Ship's Master",ans:"opb"},{question:"An advantage of using chain lashing on heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels is that it ____________.",opa:"has long life",opb:"is light weight",opc:"absorbs shock",opd:"has fine adjustment",ans:"opa"},{question:"Keeping the draft at or below the load line mark will insure that the vessel has adequate ____________.",opa:"ballast",opb:"reserve buoyancy",opc:"displacement",opd:"rolling periods",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are conducting trials to determine the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel. While making a turn, you take ranges and bearings of an isolated light with the results as shown. Based on this information, what is the transfer for a turn of 90\xb0?",opa:"355 yards",opb:"380 yards",opc:"410 yards",opd:"455 yards",ans:"opb"},{question:"Pedestal cranes have limit switches to restrict movement of which function(s)?",opa:"Hoist upper & lower limits",opb:"Luff travel limits",opc:"Rider block hoist upper & lower limits",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are transporting dangerous cargo on your vessel. The Dangerous Cargo Manifest must be signed by the ____________.",opa:"shipper",opb:"U.S. Coast Guard Marine Inspector",opc:"Master or his authorized representative",opd:"Master only",ans:"opc"},{question:"What statement is true regarding a Contract Salvage Agreement?",opa:"Lloyd's Open Form (LOF) Salvage Agreement is a Contract Salvage Agreement",opb:"There cost of the salvage is set at a fixed price",opc:"The crew is allotted the largest percentage of the salvage award",opd:"There is a 'no cure-no pay' agreement",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the wave period and the apparent rolling period are the same ____________.",opa:"synchronous rolling occurs",opb:"roll period decreases",opc:"roll period increases",opd:"roll amplitude is dampened",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are in a fresh water port loading logs with gear rated at 5 tons, and suspect the weight of the logs exceeds the SWL of the gear. The logs are floating in the water alongside the vessel and have 95% of their volume submerged. The average length of the logs is 15 feet and the average diameter is 4.4 feet. What is the nearest average weight of the logs, based on these average measurements?",opa:"5.5 tons",opb:"6.0 tons",opc:"7.7 tons",opd:"24.1 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Twenty-five hundred (2500) tons of iron ore with a stowage factor of 17 is stowed in a cargo hold. The dimensions of the hold are 55 feet long and 45 feet wide and 35 feet high. What is the height of the center of gravity of the ore above the bottom of the hold?",opa:"7.8 feet",opb:"8.6 feet",opc:"17.1 feet",opd:"34.6 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"When anyone voluntarily deposits his/her license or document with a Coast Guard investigating officer ____________.",opa:"he/she permanently gives up rights to the license or document",opb:"it may be for reasons of mental or physical incompetence",opc:"it must be for reason of addiction to narcotics",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which mooring line has the least elasticity?",opa:"Dacron",opb:"Nylon",opc:"Esterlene",opd:"Polypropylene",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your ship is in a neutral port when full Naval Control of Shipping is established. You may expect to be boarded and instructed by a(n) ____________.",opa:"U.S. Naval Control of Shipping Officer",opb:"allied Naval Control of Shipping Officer",opc:"Consular Shipping Advisors (CONSA)",opd:"Any of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT a requirement for the preparation of used, gasoline-propelled cars if they are to be carried as ordinary cargo and not as hazardous cargo?",opa:"The engine must be run until it dies from lack of fuel.",opb:"The fuel tank must be inerted with CO2.",opc:"The ignition key may not be in the ignition.",opd:"The vehicle must be inspected for fuel leaks.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Nonflammable gases should have what kind of label?",opa:"Skull and crossbones",opb:"White",opc:"Green",opd:"Red",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which term describes goods having a stowage factor below 40?",opa:"'Deadweight' cargo",opb:"'Full-and-down' cargo",opc:"'Heavy-lift' cargo",opd:"'Measurement' cargo",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is/are the advantage(s) of cranes over conventional cargo booms?",opa:"Cranes are able to pick up and drop loads over a greater spotting area",opb:"Increased safety because the deck is clear of running and standing rigging",opc:"Simplicity of operation of the crane by its operator",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The MAIN use of the knot lettered M is to ____________.",opa:"marry two hawsers",opb:"form a temporary eye in the end of a line",opc:"secure a heaving line to a hawser",opd:"provide a seat for a man to work over the side",ans:"opa"},{question:"You must load as much of a large shipment of case goods as possible into a hold which has 24,400 cubic feet of space. Each case measures 2 feet by 2 feet by 4 feet and weighs 448 pounds. If you allow for broken stowage of 15%, how many long tons can be loaded?",opa:"54",opb:"207",opc:"259",opd:"351",ans:"opc"},{question:"Argon is classified as a ____________.",opa:"corrosive",opb:"flammable gas",opc:"flammable liquid",opd:"nonflammable gas",ans:"opd"},{question:"You want to double the strength of a mooring line by using two lines. To accomplish this, the second line must ____________.",opa:"be 1 1/2 times the diameter of the first",opb:"be married to the first",opc:"not cross the first",opd:"be of the same length",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE with respect to shiphandling procedures in ice?",opa:"Never go 'full astern' at any time while in ice.",opb:"Go astern in ice with extreme care -always with rudder amidships.",opc:"Enter ice at medium speeds to reduce impact.",opd:"The presence of a snow cover on the ice assists a vessel's progress through an ice field.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Where is a surge line placed in the towing hookup?",opa:"Connected between the main towing hawser and the towing bridle",opb:"Connected between the 'H' towing bitts and the main towing hawser",opc:"End of line fastened directly to the drum of the towing winch",opd:"As both legs of the towing bridle",ans:"opa"},{question:"What does a jib refer to on a crane?",opa:"Boom",opb:"Topping lift",opc:"Control cab",opd:"Liftline",ans:"opa"},{question:"Allied Naval Control of Shipping (NCS) has been established. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The Naval Control of Shipping Organization of each nation will serve their own ships only.",opb:"Allied ships, which are at sea when an emergency is declared, will all be controlled by a central authority.",opc:"The conduct of US-flag ships in an allied port will be controlled by US NCS authorities.",opd:"After Naval Control of Shipping has been established, permission to sail must come from local naval authorities or consular officers.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The tension on an anchor cable increases so that the angle of the catenary to the seabed at the anchor reaches 10\xb0. How will this affect the anchor in sandy soil?",opa:"It will have no effect.",opb:"It will increase the holding power.",opc:"It will reduce the holding power.",opd:"It will cause the anchor to snag.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Before a tank is to be crude oil washed, the oxygen content in the tank must be measured at a position ____________.",opa:"immediately above the level of the oil",opb:"at the top of the tank",opc:"in the vent riser",opd:"one meter from the deck",ans:"opd"},{question:"The strake on each side of the keel is called a ____________.",opa:"sheer strake",opb:"gatewood strake",opc:"insulation strake",opd:"garboard strake",ans:"opd"},{question:"The knot shown lettered W is a ____________.",opa:"clove hitch",opb:"square knot",opc:"barrel hitch",opd:"stopper knot",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the meaning of a flag hoist consisting of the code letters 'WM' (Whiskey Mike) when displayed by an icebreaker?",opa:"'I am going ahead; follow me.'",opb:"'You should stop your vessel instantly.'",opc:"'Icebreaker support is now commencing.'",opd:"'Icebreaker support is finished.'",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a containership. Which statement about the stowage of hazardous materials in containers is TRUE?",opa:"The containers provide automatic segregation of hazardous materials except for class A explosives.",opb:"All packages within a container must be marked 'This End Up' to indicate the correct stowage.",opc:"A refrigerated container with a fuel tank containing a flammable liquid must be stowed on deck.",opd:"Packages of liquids within a container should be stowed on top of packages of solids to prevent crushing.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The horizontal flat surfaces where the upper stock joins the rudder are the ____________.",opa:"rudder keys",opb:"rudder palms",opc:"lifting flanges",opd:"shoes of the rudder",ans:"opb"},{question:"A lookout can leave his station ____________.",opa:"only when properly relieved",opb:"at the end of the watch",opc:"15 minutes before the end of the watch",opd:"at any time",ans:"opa"},{question:"Galvanizing would not be suitable for protecting wire rope which is used for ____________.",opa:"cargo runners",opb:"mooring wires",opc:"shrouds",opd:"stays",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are aboard vessel 'A' in a narrow channel and the pilot is approaching vessel 'B' as shown. The reason he has not previously changed course to the starboard side of the channel is ____________.",opa:"to avoid vessel squat in the shallower water near the bank",opb:"to avoid the effects of bank cushion and bank suction",opc:"because there is less chance of striking submerged objects in mid-channel",opd:"because the current has less eddies in mid-channel",ans:"opb"},{question:"Shipping articles are a contract of agreement between the members of the crew and the ____________.",opa:"charterers",opb:"Coast Guard",opc:"Master",opd:"vessel's owner",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are towing a large barge on a hawser. Your main engine suddenly fails. What is the greatest danger?",opa:"The tug and the tow will go aground.",opb:"The tow will endanger other traffic.",opc:"The tow will overrun tug.",opd:"The tow will block the channel.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which lashing material is preferred when securing new cars aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever or turnbuckle",opb:"Webbing",opc:"Wire",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A band or collar on the top end of a boom to which the topping lift, midships guy, and outboard guys are secured, is called the ____________.",opa:"collar band",opb:"guy band",opc:"pad eye collar",opd:"spider band",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a tug is 'in irons', she ____________.",opa:"is made fast to the dock with engines secured",opb:"is in dry dock",opc:"may be in danger of being overrun by her tow",opd:"should pay out more towline",ans:"opc"},{question:"Repairing damage to the hull at or above the waterline reduces the threat of ____________.",opa:"free surface effects",opb:"capsizing",opc:"continued progressive flooding",opd:"wind heel",ans:"opc"},{question:"The bow thruster generally is ineffective at ____________.",opa:"over 3 knots headway",opb:"at any speed astern",opc:"at any speed ahead",opd:"over 1 knot sternway",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are the credentialed Master of a 199 GT uninspected towing vessel making a 500 mile coastwise trip. You carry a deck crew of six (6). Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"There must be 3 separate watches stood.",opb:"There must be at least 5 able seamen among the deck crew.",opc:"Only the able seamen require Merchant Mariner Credentials.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following lashing materials would be used in securing heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever or turnbuckle",opb:"Webbing",opc:"Buckle or ratchet tensioner",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The single turn method of returning to a man overboard should be used ONLY if ____________.",opa:"the man is reported missing rather than immediately seen as he falls overboard",opb:"the vessel is very maneuverable",opc:"the conning officer is inexperienced",opd:"a boat will be used to recover the man",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are using tackle number 12 to lift a weight of 300 lbs. If you include 10 percent of the weight for each sheave for friction, what is the pull on the hauling part required to lift the weight?",opa:"80 lbs.",opb:"69 lbs.",opc:"55 lbs.",opd:"50 lbs.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The boom stops on a pedestal crane prevent the boom from ____________.",opa:"being raised too high",opb:"swinging at sea",opc:"overloading when not in use",opd:"being lowered too low",ans:"opa"},{question:"A common occurrence when a vessel is running into shallow water is that ____________.",opa:"the wake is less pronounced",opb:"the vessel is more responsive to the rudder",opc:"'squat' will cause a decrease in bottom clearance and an increase in draft",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"When attempting to free an anchor jammed in the hawsepipe, the simplest method of freeing it may be ____________.",opa:"starting the disengaged windlass at high speed",opb:"rigging a bull rope to pull it out",opc:"to grease the hawsepipe",opd:"to pry it loose with a short piece of pipe",ans:"opa"},{question:"Anyone voluntarily surrendering their license to a U.S. Coast Guard investigating officer signs a statement indicating that ____________.",opa:"all title to the license is given up for 5 years",opb:"their rights to a hearing are waived",opc:"they may be issued a new license in 5 years after passing another written examination",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Insufficient space between the hull and bottom in shallow water will prevent normal screw currents resulting in ____________.",opa:"waste of power",opb:"sudden sheering to either side",opc:"sluggish rudder response",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When lowering manropes alongside a stage rigged over the side of a vessel, they should be allowed to trail in the water ____________.",opa:"to easily remove the kinks that form in the lines",opb:"to allow the seamen on the stage to know the direction and strength of the current",opc:"to provide the seaman something to hold onto if he or she falls from the stage into the water",opd:"only for short periods of time since they will become waterlogged and be very heavy to pull up",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel has been ordered to proceed to the United Grain Growers Wharf at Thunder Bay, Lake Superior, for the purpose of taking on a load of wheat. Which publication(s) would you consult for such information as the length of the wharf, the depth of the water alongside, and the loading capacity at the facility?",opa:"The Navigational Chart and Light List Vol. VII",opb:"The International Guide to Canadian Ports and Facilities",opc:"The Lake Carriers Association Facilities Directory",opd:"The United States Coast Pilot #6",ans:"opd"},{question:"The owners of the S.S. Short Haul agree to a charter with the Longsplice Steamship Company. The owners stipulate in the charter party that they must approve the Master of the vessel for the entire life of the contract. Which charter has been affected?",opa:"Bareboat",opb:"Lease",opc:"Time",opd:"Voyage",ans:"opa"},{question:"How does a vessel's rate of turn change when entering shallow water?",opa:"It is faster.",opb:"It is slower.",opc:"There is no change.",opd:"It remains constant for varying propeller revolutions.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your tank vessel is loading a hazardous cargo. The allowance for expansion is based on ambient temperatures of what maximum range?",opa:"0\xb0C to 100\xb0C",opb:"-10\xb0C to 90\xb0C",opc:"-18\xb0C to 46\xb0C",opd:"-40\xb0C to 50\xb0C",ans:"opc"},{question:"While loading a cargo of grain, your vessel develops a list to starboard. This will be corrected by ____________.",opa:"the compensating tanks on the high side",opb:"the list man changing the discharge location of the chutes",opc:"allowing the grain to level itself as the hold fills to the spar deck level",opd:"trimming the final loading cone by hand",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on watch and the Pilot has the conn. The Master has temporarily gone below. The Pilot orders a course change which you are certain will put the vessel into imminent danger. Your first action should be to ____________.",opa:"countermand the order and immediately notify the Master",opb:"make an appropriate entry in the deck log concerning the Pilot's order",opc:"immediately call the Master and await further orders from him",opd:"immediately sound a short ring on the general alarm",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which type of line will stretch the most when under strain?",opa:"Polypropylene",opb:"Dacron",opc:"Nylon",opd:"Manila",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which bend or knot is used to tie a small line to a larger one?",opa:"Becket bend",opb:"Bowline",opc:"Clove hitch",opd:"Lark's head",ans:"opa"},{question:"Assume that your vessel has just entered Lake Michigan via the Straits of Mackinac and is proceeding south to Chicago. Which statement is TRUE with respect to the aids to navigation you will encounter along this route?",opa:"Aids to navigation are serviced jointly by the U.S. and Canadian Coast Guard.",opb:"Red buoys should be passed down your starboard side.",opc:"Green buoys mark the location of wrecks or obstructions which must be passed by keeping the buoy on the right hand.",opd:"All solid colored buoys are numbered, the red buoys bearing odd numbers and green buoys bearing even numbers.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which measure should NOT be taken to reduce the pounding of a vessel in a head sea?",opa:"Add ballast in the after peak.",opb:"Add ballast forward.",opc:"Alter course.",opd:"Reduce speed.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Distances on the Great Lakes System are generally expressed in ____________.",opa:"miles above the entrance to the St. Lawrence Seaway (MASLW)",opb:"miles above the head of the passes (AHP)",opc:"nautical miles",opd:"statute miles",ans:"opd"},{question:"While towing, what is the principal danger in attempting to swing a barge on a hawser in order to slow the barge's speed?",opa:"The barge may swing too quickly and run over the tug.",opb:"The barge may pass under the hawser and capsize the tug.",opc:"Free surface affect of liquid inside the barge may rupture the barge bulkheads when turning too quickly.",opd:"Dangerous wakes may result from the swinging barge and capsize the tug.",ans:"opb"},{question:"When must the owner or Master of a towing vessel retest a towline or remove it from service?",opa:"When the record of its material condition lapses for 3 months or more.",opb:"After it jams on the towing winch.",opc:"After it drags on the bottom.",opd:"When it has not been used for over 60 days.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Flammable liquids should have what kind of label?",opa:"Skull and crossbones",opb:"Yellow",opc:"Red",opd:"White",ans:"opc"},{question:"One shot of anchor chain is equal to how many feet (meters)?",opa:"6 (1.8 meters)",opb:"15 (4.6 meters)",opc:"45 (13.7 meters)",opd:"90 (27.4 meters)",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a multiple-product chemical tanker with orders to load diethylamine. What is NOT a requirement for transporting this cargo?",opa:"You must have two toxic vapor detectors or the pumproom must meet special requirements.",opb:"Each crew member must be provided with an emergency escape breathing apparatus.",opc:"You must have a containment system made out of stainless steel other than types 416 and 422.",opd:"If you are also carrying allyl alcohol, the venting systems don't have to be segregated.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The result of two forces acting in opposite directions and along parallel lines, is an example of what type of stress?",opa:"Tensile",opb:"Compression",opc:"Shear",opd:"Strain",ans:"opc"},{question:"While assigned to a 106 GRT vessel, you are required to sign 'foreign' articles on a voyage from San Francisco to which port?",opa:"Mazatlan, Mexico (west coast)",opb:"Vera Cruz, Mexico (east coast)",opc:"New York, NY",opd:"Vancouver, Canada (west coast)",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your containership has a container displaying a hazardous cargo placard. The placard has the number 2282 on it. This indicates that it is carrying what cargo?",opa:"Isoheptene",opb:"Phosphine",opc:"Furan",opd:"Hexanols",ans:"opd"},{question:"A chain bridle is used when towing astern because it ____________.",opa:"is easy to connect",opb:"provides an effective catenary and absorbs shock due to its weight",opc:"makes rigging a swivel unnecessary",opd:"prevents the tow from yawing by the drag of the chains in a seaway",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE of centrifugal pumps aboard tank vessels?",opa:"They are positive displacement pumps.",opb:"They are gravity-fed.",opc:"They produce a pulsating flow.",opd:"They require more maintenance than a reciprocating pump.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A crew has signed on for a 3-month voyage. Fourteen days into the voyage a seaman is improperly discharged at the first port of call. How much pay is he entitled to receive?",opa:"14 days",opb:"1 month's",opc:"14 days and one month's extra",opd:"double wages (28 days)",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is/are the advantage(s) of using web lashing on light vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Good working life",opb:"Light and easy to handle",opc:"Flexible",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The force exerted by a propeller which tends to throw the stern right or left is called ____________.",opa:"slip",opb:"sidewise force",opc:"rotational force",opd:"thrust",ans:"opb"},{question:"What will NOT be found on the Certificate of Inspection of an ocean going tankship?",opa:"Manning requirements",opb:"Minimum freeboard permitted",opc:"Grade(s) of cargoes that the vessel may carry",opd:"Waters upon which the vessel may be operated",ans:"opb"},{question:"While being assisted by an icebreaker on Lake Superior, you receive a single letter code instructing you to slow your vessel. Which signal could you use to signify that you are complying with the request?",opa:"Three blasts of the whistle",opb:"The code flag 'A' (Alpha) displayed from a halyard",opc:"Four blasts of the whistle, namely 1short 2 long and 1 short",opd:"The code flag 'L' (Lima) displayed from a halyard",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following is an inherent advantage possessed by a twin-screw vessel in opposition to a single-screw vessel?",opa:"The correct trim will be obtained more easily",opb:"The drag effect will be cancelled out",opc:"The side forces will be cancelled out",opd:"The vessel's speed will be increased",ans:"opc"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'F' is called a ____________.",opa:"bow line",opb:"breast line",opc:"forward spring line",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on watch while your vessel is entering port with a pilot conning. The pilot gives a steering command to the helmsman who fails to acknowledge it by repeating the command. You should immediately ____________.",opa:"notify the Master",opb:"ask the Pilot to repeat the command since the helmsman failed to hear it",opc:"tell the helmsman to ask the Pilot to repeat any command that he fails to hear or understand",opd:"repeat the Pilot's command and ensure that the helmsman repeats it exactly",ans:"opd"},{question:"When relieving the helm, the new helmsman should know the ____________.",opa:"course per magnetic steering compass",opb:"gyro error",opc:"variation",opd:"maximum rudder angle previously used",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which effect does speed through the water have on a vessel which is underway in shallow water?",opa:"A decrease in the speed results in a decrease in steering response and maneuverability.",opb:"An increase in speed results in the stern sucking down lower than the bow.",opc:"An increase in speed results in the vessel rising on an even plane.",opd:"A decrease in speed results in the vessel sucking down on an even plane.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What requires a Report of Marine Accident, Injury or Death?",opa:"Collision with a bridge",opb:"Injury beyond first aid",opc:"loss of life",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Control of flooding should be addressed ____________.",opa:"first",opb:"following control of fire",opc:"following restoration of vital services",opd:"only if a threat exists",ans:"opb"},{question:"Under Naval Control of Shipping who is responsible for routing and diverting ships and convoys?",opa:"The Maritime Defense Zone Sector",opb:"The Operational Control Authority",opc:"The National Shipping Authority",opd:"Any Navy Command",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following statements is TRUE regarding crane operations?",opa:"Radio communications allow the crane operator to disregard the use of hand signals.",opb:"The crane operators and signalman must be familiar with the correct hand signals.",opc:"The forward cranes can be operated from the bridge.",opd:"The aft cranes can be operated from the aft steering station.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The maximum draft to which a vessel can legally be submerged is indicated by the ____________.",opa:"load line mark",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opd:"tonnage mark",ans:"opa"},{question:"A disadvantage of using chain lashing on heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels is that it ____________.",opa:"can wrap around cargo",opb:"is easily damaged",opc:"is affected by temperature",opd:"does not absorb shock",ans:"opd"},{question:"A sling is a device used in ____________.",opa:"hoisting cargo aboard a vessel",opb:"hoisting personnel aboard a vessel",opc:"securing a small boat to a large vessel",opd:"hoisting the anchor",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using a safety factor of five, determine what is the safe working load for 3-1/2 inch manila line with a breaking stress of 4.9 tons.",opa:"0.82 ton",opb:"0.98 ton",opc:"2.45 tons",opd:"12.25 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The line with the most stretch is ____________.",opa:"manila",opb:"nylon",opc:"polypropylene",opd:"dacron",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are planning the stowage of two incompatible products on your multiple-product tankship. What will NOT provide the minimum required segregation?",opa:"Empty tank",opb:"Solid (non-intercostal) bulkhead",opc:"Diagonally adjacent tanks",opd:"Tank containing a third cargo compatible with the other two",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is in a foreign port and you find that one of the crew members has been incarcerated for drunkenness. The Official Logbook shows that the seaman doesn't have funds to cover the costs of the fine. Which action should the Master take?",opa:"Inventory his gear and send it and a pay voucher ashore with the agent.",opb:"Leave the seaman in jail and log him as a fail to join after the vessel sails.",opc:"Leave the seaman in jail and log him as a deserter after the vessel sails.",opd:"Pay the seaman's fine.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which lien against a vessel would be settled FIRST?",opa:"Maintenance and cure",opb:"Vessel mortgage",opc:"Salvage lien",opd:"Ship repairer's lien",ans:"opc"},{question:"As look-out, you spot an object 45\xb0 off your port bow. You should report the object as ____________.",opa:"broad on the port bow",opb:"3 points on the port bow",opc:"3 points forward of the port beam",opd:"on the port beam",ans:"opa"},{question:"In time of war Naval Control of Shipping Authorities may give orders concerning the ____________.",opa:"cargo to be loaded",opb:"final destination",opc:"ship's route",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"When improperly tied, which knot shown is called a granny or thief's knot?",opa:"F",opb:"M",opc:"R",opd:"W",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Oil Record Book for all U.S. ships is the property of the ____________.",opa:"U.S. government",opb:"master of the vessel",opc:"vessel's owner",opd:"charterer of the vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"In vessel construction, the garboard strake is ____________.",opa:"located next to and parallel to the keel",opb:"located next to and parallel to the gunwale",opc:"another term for the bilge keel",opd:"another term for the rub rail",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a large vessel fitted with a right-handed controllable-pitch propeller set at maximum forward pitch. Which statement about reversing is TRUE?",opa:"When the pitch is reversed, the stern will slew to port even with headway.",opb:"The vessel will respond to the rudder until sternway is developed, then the stern will slew to starboard.",opc:"There will probably be a loss of steering control.",opd:"The vessel will have full rudder control throughout the speed change from ahead to astern.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The projecting lugs of the rudderpost which furnish support to the rudder are called ____________.",opa:"bases",opb:"gudgeons",opc:"pintles",opd:"rudder lugs",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Certificate of Inspection of a damaged tank barge has expired. What certificate authorizes the barge to move to a repair facility for repair and inspection?",opa:"Application for Inspection",opb:"Change of Employment",opc:"Permit to Proceed",opd:"Temporary Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the Great Lakes is most affected by short-term Lake level fluctuations?",opa:"Lake Superior",opb:"Lake Michigan",opc:"Lake Huron",opd:"Lake Erie",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which method of adjusting mooring lines is MOST useful for leaving a boat free to rise and fall with the tide?",opa:"Crossing the spring lines",opb:"Slacking all forward running lines while keeping all after running lines taut",opc:"Doubling up on spring or breast lines",opd:"Slacking bow and stern lines",ans:"opa"},{question:"The explosive range of a fuel lies between the lower explosive limit and the ____________.",opa:"flash point",opb:"ignition temperature",opc:"upper explosive limit",opd:"fire point",ans:"opc"},{question:"Before letting the anchor go, you should check that the ____________.",opa:"chain is clear",opb:"anchor is clear of obstructions",opc:"wildcat is disengaged",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Adequate horsepower is of great importance when a ship is navigating independently in ice. Adequate horsepower is generally considered to exist when the horsepower to length ratio is at least ____________.",opa:"4 to 1 or better",opb:"5 to 1 or better",opc:"6 to 1 or better",opd:"8 to 1 or better",ans:"opc"},{question:"By law, a user of marijuana shall be subject to ____________.",opa:"loss of pay during the period of such use",opb:"reprimand by the US Coast Guard",opc:"revocation of license or certificate",opd:"termination of employment",ans:"opc"},{question:"To safely anchor a vessel there must be sufficient 'scope' in the anchor cable. Scope is the ratio of ____________.",opa:"weight of cable to weight of vessel",opb:"weight of cable to weight of anchor",opc:"length of anchor to depth of water",opd:"length of cable to depth of water",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which method should be used to warm up the pump turbines prior to discharge?",opa:"Lock the turbine rotor and slowly bleed in steam until operating temperature is reached",opb:"Run the pump at high speed with the discharge valves closed",opc:"Run the turbine at slow speed with the pump disconnected",opd:"Shut the discharge valve and run the pump at slow speed",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement concerning an automatic towing engine is FALSE?",opa:"It automatically maintains tow line tension.",opb:"It prolongs the life of the hawser by distributing chafing as the hawser is paid out and taken in.",opc:"As tension on the hawser increases, more line is taken in by the automatic towing engine.",opd:"As tension on the hawser decreases, more line is taken in by the automatic towing engine.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is used to power modern pedestal cranes?",opa:"Steam",opb:"Water",opc:"Hydraulics",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Grade E combustible liquids have a flash point of ____________.",opa:"80\xb0F to 150\xb0F",opb:"150\xb0F or above",opc:"60\xb0F to 100\xb0F",opd:"90\xb0F to 120\xb0F",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which action(s) is/are included in crane operations?",opa:"Pre-operation checks and start-up",opb:"Removing booms from stowage",opc:"Luff, slew, and hoist operations",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your ship is in shallow water and the bow rides up on its bow wave while the stern sinks into a depression of its transverse wave system. What is this called?",opa:"Broaching",opb:"Fish tailing",opc:"Squatting",opd:"Parallel sinkage",ans:"opc"},{question:"For any given pedestal crane, when the boom is lengthened, the lifting capacity is ____________.",opa:"unchanged",opb:"increased",opc:"eliminated",opd:"decreased",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a containership. The cargo includes a container of small arms ammunition, a container of lead-acid storage batteries and a container of methyl acetylene bottles. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The storage batteries must be stowed on deck away from the ammunition.",opb:"The storage batteries must be at least ten horizontal feet away from the methyl acetylene.",opc:"The ammunition must be separated from the methyl acetylene by at least one hold.",opd:"No separation is required because freight containers are exempted.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are approaching a pier and intend to use the port anchor to assist in docking port side to ____________. You would NOT use the anchor if ____________.",opa:"the current was setting you on the pier",opb:"another vessel is berthed ahead of your position",opc:"the wind was blowing from the starboard side",opd:"there is shallow water enroute to the berth",ans:"opd"},{question:"Deckhands onboard towing vessels shall be divided into 3 watches when on a trip exceeding ____________.",opa:"600 miles",opb:"700 miles",opc:"800 miles",opd:"1000 miles",ans:"opa"},{question:"Progressive flooding may be indicated by ____________.",opa:"ballast control alarms",opb:"excessive draft",opc:"excessive list or trim",opd:"a continual worsening of list or trim",ans:"opd"},{question:"While towing, sudden shock-loading caused during heavy weather can be reduced by ____________.",opa:"using a short tow hawser",opb:"using a nonelastic type hawser",opc:"using a heavier hawser",opd:"decreasing the catenary in the hawser",ans:"opc"},{question:"When you 'end for end' a wire rope, you ____________.",opa:"cut off the free end and bitter end of the rope",opb:"splice two wire ropes together",opc:"remove the wire rope from the drum and reverse it so that the free end becomes the bitter end",opd:"remove the wire rope from the drum and turn it over, so the wire bends in the opposite direction",ans:"opc"},{question:"Water may boil up around the stern of a vessel in a channel due to ____________.",opa:"slack water when upbound",opb:"shallow water",opc:"a cross current",opd:"a head current",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Scharnow turn should be used in a man overboard situation only when ____________.",opa:"the man can be kept in sight from the bridge while maneuvering",opb:"the turn is started immediately when the man goes over",opc:"there has been sufficient time elapsed since the man went over to complete the maneuver",opd:"the vessel has twin screws to assist in making the turn",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are using tackle number 4 to lift a weight. The hauling part of this tackle is bent to the weight hook (w) of tackle number 10. What is the mechanical advantage of this rig?",opa:"4",opb:"5",opc:"9",opd:"20",ans:"opd"},{question:"Advection fog, a common occurrence on the Great Lakes, forms when ____________.",opa:"air comes in contact with a rapidly cooling land surface",opb:"frigid arctic air moves across the lakes and becomes saturated",opc:"relatively warm air flows over cooler water",opd:"cool air contacts warm river currents",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statement(s) is/are TRUE regarding lashing requirements to secure vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"It is imperative that the securing of cargo on flats and trailers and in containers be adequate for both road and sea motions.",opb:"The movements experienced by road borne cargo differ significantly from the roll and sway movements of a ship at sea.",opc:"It is necessary for adequate number and strength of securing points on the vehicles themselves in order that lashings may be properly and safely utilized.",opd:"All the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which picture represents a stopper hitch?",opa:"M",opb:"N",opc:"R",opd:"L",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are proceeding along the right bank of a narrow channel aboard a right-handed single-screw vessel. The vessel starts to sheer due to bank suction/cushion effect. You should ____________.",opa:"stop engines and put the rudder left full",opb:"back full with rudder amidships",opc:"decrease speed and put the rudder right full",opd:"increase speed and put the rudder right full",ans:"opd"},{question:"The shank is indicated by which letter?",opa:"K",opb:"J",opc:"H",opd:"F",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are the Master of an uninspected diesel towing vessel of 190 GT operating on a regular run from New York to the Gulf of Mexico. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Able Seamen are not required in the deck crew.",opb:"Sailors may stand watch for 6 hours on and 6 hours off.",opc:"A licensed Chief Engineer is required.",opd:"All crew members must have Merchant Mariner Credentials.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is chartered under a time charter party. Under this type of charter party, your responsibility is ____________.",opa:"solely to the charterer for all matters pertaining to cargo and ship administration",opb:"solely to the cargo shippers and consignees",opc:"solely to the owner, as under normal conditions",opd:"to the owner for vessel administration and to the charterer for cargo operations and schedule",ans:"opd"},{question:"What describes a tandem crane lift?",opa:"Single crane hoisting 30 tons",opb:"Two cranes on a single pedestal hoisting 60 tons",opc:"Two sets of twin cranes hoisting 120 tons",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your tankship is carrying a cargo of styrene. Which of the following is NOT a requirement for carriage of this cargo?",opa:"P/V valves with galvanized parts must be replaced.",opb:"Authorization to carry styrene must be endorsed on the Certificate of Inspection.",opc:"You must have a 'Certificate of Inhibition' provided by the shipper.",opd:"The cargo tank heating coils must be blanked off.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Advection fog holds longest over which portions of the lakes?",opa:"Northwest",opb:"Southeast",opc:"Northeast",opd:"Southwest",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your ship is carrying hazardous cargo. During a daily inspection, you notice that some of the cargo has shifted and several cases are broken. You should FIRST ____________.",opa:"call out the deck gang to jettison the cargo",opb:"log the facts in the rough log and inform the Chief Mate later",opc:"make a determination of the seriousness of the breakage, and do what you think best",opd:"report the facts immediately to the Master, who will make a decision",ans:"opd"},{question:"While steering by autopilot you notice that the vessel is deviating from the given course and there is no follow up with corrective rudder action to return to the proper heading. The emergency operating procedure should require you to immediately change operation from ____________.",opa:"'gyro' to 'hand'",opb:"'hand' to 'gyro'",opc:"'gyro' to 'control'",opd:"'control' to 'hand'",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel will 'squat' when it proceeds underway ____________.",opa:"only in deep water",opb:"only in shallow water",opc:"in all depths of water",opd:"only in narrow channels",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many feet are there in 2 shots of anchor chain?",opa:"50",opb:"60",opc:"180",opd:"360",ans:"opc"},{question:"Atmospheres laden with coal dust or grain dust caused by loading these cargoes ____________.",opa:"require loading operations to be shut down until the atmosphere clears",opb:"are toxic to human life",opc:"are subject to spontaneous combustion",opd:"may be explosive in some concentrations",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is required to be stenciled at the heel of a cargo boom?",opa:"Maximum angle of elevation permitted",opb:"Date of the last quadrennial test",opc:"Safe working load",opd:"Maximum load when doubled up",ans:"opc"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference to determine the sagging numeral.",opa:"71.07 numeral",opb:"74.95 numeral",opc:"77.56 numeral",opd:"78.29 numeral",ans:"opd"},{question:"The beam of a vessel refers to the ____________.",opa:"depth between decks",opb:"internal cubic capacity",opc:"molded depth of the vessel",opd:"width of the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"When your tug reduces speed to shorten tow, the ____________.",opa:"length of the tow gets shorter as the strain is reduced",opb:"tow may continue its momentum and overtake the tug",opc:"towing hawser may drag the bottom and put the tug in irons",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"In twin-screw engine installations while going ahead, maneuvering qualities are most effective when the tops of the propeller blades both turn ____________.",opa:"to starboard",opb:"outboard from the center",opc:"to port",opd:"inboard toward the center",ans:"opb"},{question:"An icebreaker assisting a vessel through an ice field would display a visual signal consisting of the code letter 'S' (Sierra) to signify that '__________'.",opa:"I am altering my course to starboard",opb:"I am altering my course to port",opc:"I am operating astern propulsion",opd:"My vessel is stopped and making no way through the water",ans:"opc"},{question:"The advantage(s) of using wire rope lashing on vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels is that it ____________.",opa:"is Lighter than chain",opb:"has a good working life",opc:"is not affected by temperature",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A new coil of nylon line should be opened by ____________.",opa:"pulling the end up through the eye of the coil",opb:"uncoiling from the outside with the coil standing on end",opc:"taking a strain on both ends",opd:"unreeling from a spool",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Lake Carriers Association and the Canadian Ship-owners Association prescribe separation routes for upbound and downbound vessels on the Great Lakes. The recommended courses for these routes are shown on the Great Lakes Charts in the form of ____________.",opa:"red or magenta figures over a segmented course line track",opb:"red figures over a solid course line track",opc:"black figures over a segmented course line track",opd:"green figures over a solid course line track",ans:"opa"},{question:"When caring for natural-fiber line, you should NEVER ____________.",opa:"dry the line before stowing it",opb:"lubricate the line",opc:"protect the line from weather",opd:"slack off taut lines when it rains",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT an advantage of centrifugal pumps over reciprocating pumps?",opa:"They pump more cargo in less time.",opb:"They are smaller for equivalent pumping ability.",opc:"They are less expensive.",opd:"They require priming for stripping.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has completed an inspection for certification and is issued a temporary certificate. This ____________.",opa:"expires six months after it is issued",opb:"must be exchanged for a regular Certificate of Inspection before going foreign or out of state",opc:"has the full force of a regular Certificate of Inspection",opd:"must be posted in the vicinity of the officers' licenses",ans:"opc"},{question:"Seeing that all hands are familiar with their duties, as specified in the muster list, is the responsibility of the ____________.",opa:"Master",opb:"Chief Mate",opc:"safety officer",opd:"department heads",ans:"opa"},{question:"Marline is ____________.",opa:"four-stranded sisal line",opb:"three-stranded cotton line",opc:"sail twine",opd:"two-stranded hemp cord",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which situation requires you to furnish a notice of marine casualty to the Coast Guard?",opa:"A seaman slips on ice on deck and sprains his ankle, requiring an ace bandage.",opb:"You collide with a buoy and drag it off station with no apparent damage to the vessel or the buoy.",opc:"Storm damage to the cargo winch motors requires repairs costing $19,000.",opd:"Your vessel is at anchor and grounds at low tide with no apparent damage.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Under defense plans, operation of electronic aids may be temporarily suspended with ____________.",opa:"thirty (30) day's notice",opb:"a week's notice",opc:"one day's notice",opd:"no notice",ans:"opd"},{question:"With a following sea, a vessel will tend to ____________.",opa:"heave to",opb:"pound",opc:"reduce speed",opd:"yaw",ans:"opd"},{question:"A maritime lien may be placed against ____________.",opa:"any assets that a ship's owner may have",opb:"a vessel, cargo, or freight",opc:"objects that are fixed and immovable, such as wharves",opd:"the vessel only",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel has a deadweight carrying capacity of 10,500 tons. Fuel, water, and stores require 1500 tons. The cubic capacity is 500,000 cubic feet. Which cargo will put her full and down?",opa:"Slabs of zinc, SF 7.1",opb:"Rolls of barbed wire, SF 55.5",opc:"Barrels of tallow, SF 66.8",opd:"Bundles of rubber, SF 140.2",ans:"opb"},{question:"The load line certificate is issued by ____________.",opa:"the American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"the National Cargo Bureau",opc:"the United States Coast Guard",opd:"United States Customs",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which entry on a dangerous cargo manifest concerning the classification of a cargo is correct?",opa:"Class 8",opb:"Class 3 -flammable liquid",opc:"Division 2.2 -nonflammable gas",opd:"All of the above are correct",ans:"opa"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'G' is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"inshore bow line",opb:"offshore bow line",opc:"forward breast line",opd:"forward spring line",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are approaching a ship that is broken down and are preparing to take her in tow. BEFORE positioning your vessel to pass the towline, you must ____________.",opa:"compare the rate of drift between the ships",opb:"install chafing gear on the towline",opc:"secure the bitter end of the towing hawser to prevent loss if the tow is slipped",opd:"have traveling lizards rigged to guide the towline while it is paid-out",ans:"opa"},{question:"The circular steel structure installed around the propeller of a towboat is the ____________.",opa:"nozzle",opb:"shroud",opc:"strut",opd:"hood",ans:"opa"},{question:"A twin-screw vessel can clear the inboard propeller and maneuver off a pier best by holding a(n) ____________.",opa:"forward spring line and going slow ahead on the inboard engine",opb:"after spring line and going slow astern on the outboard engine",opc:"forward spring line and going slow ahead on both engines",opd:"forward spring line and going slow ahead on the outboard engine",ans:"opd"},{question:"A majority of the crew requests a survey from the American Consul to determine a vessel's seaworthiness. The vessel is found unfit to continue her intended voyage. The Consul allows the vessel to sail to another port where deficiencies can be corrected. The crew must ____________.",opa:"be discharged and given first class passage back to the original port of signing on in lieu of one month's wages",opb:"be discharged by the American Consul with additional one month's wages until repairs are made",opc:"be furnished employment on another vessel returning to the United States which is satisfactory to that crew",opd:"comply with the judgment",ans:"opd"},{question:"The extension of the after part of the keel in a single-screw vessel upon which the stern post rests is called the ____________.",opa:"boss",opb:"knuckle",opc:"skeg",opd:"strut",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which act would be considered barratry?",opa:"A criminal act committed by a crew member ashore in a foreign port",opb:"A criminal act committed by the ship Master in violation of his duty to the ship-owner",opc:"Theft of cargo by longshoremen",opd:"Smuggling with the connivance of the ship-owner",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which safety precaution(s) should be observed during crane operations?",opa:"Checking for proper lifting from beneath the load during cargo operations",opb:"Using the proper slings or other lifting devices during cargo operations",opc:"Relaying communications to port agents on the pier during cargo hoists",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Using a safety factor of 6, determine the safe working load of a line with a breaking strain of 30,000 pounds.",opa:"4,000 lbs.",opb:"5,000 lbs.",opc:"20,000 lbs.",opd:"100,000 lbs.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is to dock bow in at a pier without the assistance of tugboats. Which line will be the most useful when maneuvering the vessel alongside the pier?",opa:"Bow breast line",opb:"Stern breast line",opc:"Bow spring line",opd:"Inshore head line",ans:"opc"},{question:"When loading containers into the cell guides in the hold of a container ship, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"No further securing is usually required.",opb:"Containers must have vertical lashings if they do not have twist lock securing.",opc:"All containers must have vertical and horizontal lashings.",opd:"The container must be locked into the cell guide.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A continual worsening of the list or trim indicates ____________.",opa:"negative GM",opb:"progressive flooding",opc:"structural failure",opd:"an immediate need to ballast",ans:"opb"},{question:"An advantage of the modified Christmas Tree towing method is to ____________.",opa:"increase the towing hawser's catenary and provide more spring",opb:"reduce catenary, allow operation in shallower water, and to release one barge without breaking up the entire tow",opc:"enable one tug and its crew without any outside assistance to make up or break down the tow",opd:"provide rapid delivery of logs from the northwestern United States to Hawaiian sawmills",ans:"opb"},{question:"At the outbreak of war your ship is caught in an enemy port. Which statement is FALSE?",opa:"You should attempt to contact U.S. Consular officials.",opb:"You should attempt to clear for sea before your ship is interned.",opc:"You should resist boarding by local officials.",opd:"You should try to send a Ship Hostile Action Report to the NGA (formerly NIMA).",ans:"opc"},{question:"The part of the anchor indicated by the letter I is the ____________.",opa:"tripping palm",opb:"fluke",opc:"bill",opd:"stock",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel spotted at 45\xb0 relative can be reported as ____________.",opa:"on the starboard beam",opb:"broad on the starboard bow",opc:"4 points forward of starboard bow",opd:"4 points abaft the starboard beam",ans:"opb"},{question:"After each operation involving the transfer of oil or oily mixture, an entry shall be recorded in the Oil Record Book ____________.",opa:"without delay",opb:"within 1 hour of completion of the inspection",opc:"within 6 hours of completion of the operation",opd:"as the operation permits",ans:"opa"},{question:"All entries in the Official Logbook must be signed by the Master and ____________.",opa:"the Chief Engineer",opb:"the person about whom the entry concerns",opc:"one other crew member",opd:"No other signature is required.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which lashing device(s) would be used in securing heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Buckle or ratchet tensioner",opb:"Webbing",opc:"Chain",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a multiple-product chemical tanker. The loading plan includes cargoes of diethylenetriamine and formamide. Which statement concerning the stowage of these cargoes is TRUE?",opa:"They must be separated by a void space or empty tank.",opb:"The cargoes must have individual venting systems.",opc:"The valves in common piping systems must be chained closed and locked.",opd:"The minimum segregation required is a single bulkhead.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the Great Lakes experiences the least amount of water level fluctuation between seasonal high and low water marks?",opa:"Lake Huron",opb:"Lake Erie",opc:"Lake Superior",opd:"Lake Michigan",ans:"opc"}],this.data1=[{question:"The (auto)ignition temperature is that temperature at which ____________.",opa:"no spark or flame is required to ignite gas or vapor",opb:"a fuel begins to give off explosive vapors",opc:"a fuel if ignited will continue to burn",opd:"a 1% mixture of the fuel with air will explode",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of the relief valve of a cargo pump?",opa:"Provides for the removal of vapors",opb:"Allows two or more tanks to be filled at the same time",opc:"Provides for the emergency shutdown of the pump",opd:"Permits the return of cargo to the suction side of the pump",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is docking, but not yet alongside. Which line will be the most useful when maneuvering the vessel alongside the pier?",opa:"Bow breast line",opb:"Bow spring line",opc:"Inshore head line",opd:"Offshore head line",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are the Master of a single-screw vessel. You are docking at a port which has no tugs available. You decide to drop the offshore anchor to help in docking. The amount of chain you should pay out is ____________.",opa:"5 to 7 times the depth of the water",opb:"1 1/2 to 2 times the depth of the water",opc:"equal to the depth of the water",opd:"you should NEVER use the anchor to help in docking",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are to load styrene in bulk, which is subject to self-polymerization. In accordance with 46 CFR Table 153 what are you required to do?",opa:"not carry any cargo in the tanks surrounding the tank loaded with styrene",opb:"inject nitrogen to pad any ullage above the styrene to prevent contact with oxygen",opc:"be furnished with a Certificate of Inhibition to be maintained on the bridge",opd:"use heating coils to maintain the styrene within the temperatures specified by the shipper",ans:"opc"},{question:"The knot used to join two lines or two large hawsers for towing is called a ____________.",opa:"square knot",opb:"carrick bend",opc:"sheet bend",opd:"bowline",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tug is 'in irons' when held in a fixed position by ____________.",opa:"the weight of its tow, its being anchored, or grounded",opb:"the towing hawser snagged on the bottom",opc:"an adverse current",opd:"lack of power or an engine breakdown",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the advantage of the tandem working arrangement of pedestal cranes when operating cargo?",opa:"The cranes enable the handling of heavy cargos without shoreside assistance",opb:"The cargo discharge can be accomplished with controlled pendulation",opc:"The cargo discharge can be performed in port or at anchor",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When paying out nylon line from around the bitts ____________.",opa:"stand clear of the bitts and use two or more round turns under your figure eights",opb:"you can surge the line even with a single turn",opc:"no extra turns are necessary since nylon has a high coefficient of friction",opd:"stand in the bight of the line",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which method is used to detect rot in manila lines?",opa:"Feeling the surface of the line for broken fibers",opb:"Measuring the reduction in circumference of the line",opc:"Observing for the appearance of mildew on the outer surface",opd:"Opening the strands and examining the inner fibers",ans:"opd"},{question:"All wire rope used in shipboard cargo gear must be identified and described in a certificate. The certificate shall certify all of the following EXCEPT the ____________.",opa:"date of the test",opb:"load at which a test sample broke",opc:"name of the vessel",opd:"number of strands and of wires in each strand",ans:"opc"},{question:"A license issued by the U.S. Coast Guard for Master of Towing Vessels is valid for ____________.",opa:"2 years and must be renewed",opb:"3 years and must be renewed",opc:"5 years and must be renewed",opd:"life and need not be renewed",ans:"opc"},{question:"The major components which determine the length of a catenary in a deployed anchor cable are water depth, cable weight, and ____________.",opa:"cable tension",opb:"water temperature",opc:"bottom conditions",opd:"water density",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which action(s) is/are included in crane operations?",opa:"Normal boom stowage and shutdown operations",opb:"Emergency shutdown operation",opc:"Removing booms from stowage",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The boom indicator on a crane will indicate the ____________.",opa:"length of the boom",opb:"angle of the boom",opc:"lifting capacity of the boom",opd:"direction of the boom",ans:"opb"},{question:"The knot lettered Q as shown is a ____________.",opa:"square knot",opb:"clove hitch",opc:"bowline",opd:"round knot",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which picture represents a timber hitch?",opa:"E",opb:"F",opc:"N",opd:"U",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are using tackle number 4, as shown, to lift a weight. The hauling part of this tackle is bent to the weight hook of tackle number 11. What is the mechanical advantage of this rig?",opa:"4",opb:"6",opc:"10",opd:"24",ans:"opd"},{question:"The 'Mode' selector switch can be positioned and select all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"weather adjustments",opb:"hand-electric steering",opc:"automatic gyro",opd:"non-follow-up control",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a container vessel. Which of the following is true concerning the handling and stowage of containerized hazardous materials?",opa:"Open-bed containers may be used to transport hazardous materials if the cargo is properly secured.",opb:"A portable cargo tank of a flammable, cryogenic liquid may not be in transit for a period exceeding its marked rated holding time unless the liquid is inhibited.",opc:"A portable cargo tank containing a cryogenic liquid must be shipped on deck unless forced ventilation is provided to the tween-decks.",opd:"A container loaded with packages of tear gas would display a placard reading 'Irritant.'",ans:"opa"},{question:"A condition where two currents meet at the downstream end of a middle bar can be determined by a ____________.",opa:"small whirlpool",opb:"smooth patch of water",opc:"V-shaped ripple with the point of the V pointing downstream",opd:"V-shaped ripple with the point of the V pointing upstream",ans:"opc"},{question:"While you are on watch, you learn that a crewman has not been seen on board for the past three hours. Which type of turn is best in this man-overboard situation?",opa:"Round",opb:"Scharnow",opc:"Racetrack",opd:"Single turn of 180\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which molten substance is poured into the basket of a wire rope socket being fitted to the end of a wire rope?",opa:"Babbitt",opb:"Bronze",opc:"Lead",opd:"Zinc",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of carrier accepts without discrimination all legal cargoes of a shipper?",opa:"Common",opb:"Industrial",opc:"Private",opd:"Tramp",ans:"opa"},{question:"When turning a vessel in shallow water, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The rate of turn is increased.",opb:"The rate of turn is decreased.",opc:"The turning diameter increases.",opd:"The turning diameter remains the same.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of fog is the most dense and widely spread of those that occur on the Great Lakes?",opa:"Steam fog",opb:"Advection fog",opc:"Radiation fog",opd:"Lake effect fog",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel operating on the Great Lakes, and whose position is south of an approaching eastward-moving storm center, would NOT experience ____________.",opa:"a falling barometer",opb:"lowering clouds and drizzle",opc:"a southwest to west wind",opd:"rain or snow",ans:"opc"},{question:"What describes a twin crane lift?",opa:"Single crane hoisting 30 tons",opb:"Two cranes on a single pedestal hoisting 60 tons",opc:"Two sets of twin cranes hoisting 120 tons",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which vessel is required by regulations to have an Official Logbook?",opa:"A 100-gross ton tug on a trip between Baltimore, Maryland, and San Pedro, California.",opb:"A 199-gross ton tug on a coastwise trip of 610 miles.",opc:"A 66-gross ton tug operating between states.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What should you be concerned with when loading and securing vehicles on a Ro-Ro?",opa:"Number, position and angle of lashes",opb:"Number of axles",opc:"Disconnecting the battery cables to prevent fire hazard",opd:"Minor air pressure changes in the tires",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is meant by veering the anchor chain?",opa:"Bringing the anchor to short stay",opb:"Heaving in all the chain",opc:"Locking the windlass to prevent more chain from running out",opd:"Paying out more chain",ans:"opd"},{question:"The term 'strake' is used in reference to ____________.",opa:"rudder mountings",opb:"anchor gear",opc:"hull plating",opd:"vessel framing",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which characteristic is an advantage of a butterfly valve as compared to a gate valve?",opa:"Precise control over cargo flow",opb:"Quick operation",opc:"No resistance to cargo flow when open",opd:"Less maintenance required",ans:"opb"},{question:"A normal safe working load for used nylon rope in good condition is ____________.",opa:"10% of its breaking strain",opb:"25% of its breaking strain",opc:"33% of its breaking strain",opd:"50% of its breaking strain",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master of a vessel may tender a Notice of Readiness to the charterer when the vessel ____________.",opa:"has completed the terms of the charter party",opb:"is in all respects ready to load",opc:"is in all respects ready to sail",opd:"is safely moored or at a suitable anchorage",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tow can override its tug as a result of ____________.",opa:"a mechanical breakdown on the tug",opb:"adverse tidal current conditions",opc:"the tug reducing its speed",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A wire rope rove through two single blocks with two parts at the moving block is used for a boat fall. The weight of the 100-person boat is 5 tons. Compute the required breaking strain. Safety Factor -6, weight per person -165 lbs., 10% friction per sheave (2 sheaves).",opa:"18.30 tons B.S.",opb:"20.29 tons B.S.",opc:"22.27 tons B.S.",opd:"24.31 tons B.S.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which variable factor affects the initial lashing requirements aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Number, position and angle of lashings",opb:"Vessel's draft",opc:"Port of origin",opd:"ABS requirements",ans:"opa"},{question:"An Official Logbook is required on which vessel?",opa:"A 150-G.T. tug going from Boston to New Orleans.",opb:"A 100-G.T. tug going from New York to San Pedro, California.",opc:"A 50-G.T. tug going from Miami to Seattle.",opd:"A 199-G.T. tug on a coastwise trip of 650 miles.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE?",opa:"Your stern is sucked down and your draft increases when going from deep to shallow water.",opb:"Excessive speed while passing moored vessels may cause them to surge and break their moorings.",opc:"Excessive speed while passing a tow being pushed ahead or pushing a tow into an eddy too fast may break up the tow.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which tensioning device is used with wire rope lashing to secure vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever",opb:"Buckle tensioner",opc:"Adjust-a-matic tensioner",opd:"Ratchet tensioner",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel which is being assisted by an icebreaker should indicate that he is ready to cast off the towline (if one is used) by ____________.",opa:"displaying code letter 'Y' (Yankee)",opb:"sounding five short blasts of his whistle",opc:"displaying code numeral '5'",opd:"sounding one prolonged blast of his whistle",ans:"opa"},{question:"By definition, a 'spar deck' is the ____________.",opa:"lower most continuous deck not broken by water tight bulkheads",opb:"after most weather deck above the main strength deck",opc:"upper or weather deck above the main strength deck",opd:"deck of light construction below the main or strength deck",ans:"opc"},{question:"The 'carrick bend' is used to ____________.",opa:"add strength to a weak spot in a line",opb:"join two hawsers",opc:"be a stopper to transfer a line under strain",opd:"join lines of different sizes",ans:"opb"},{question:"While the Pilot is maneuvering the vessel to a dock, what is the PRIMARY responsibility of the watch officer?",opa:"Supervise the signaling and flag etiquette.",opb:"Record the bells and their times in the bell book.",opc:"Judge the appropriateness of the Pilot's orders and countermand them if necessary.",opd:"Insure that helm and throttle orders given by the Pilot are correctly executed.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Using a scope of 6, how much cable would have to be used in order to anchor in 24 feet of water?",opa:"4 feet",opb:"18 feet",opc:"30 feet",opd:"144 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is an advantage of having wire rope with a fiber core over that of a wire rope of the same size with a wire core?",opa:"Fiber core rope offers greater strength.",opb:"Fiber core rope offers greater flexibility.",opc:"Fiber core rope can be used at higher operating temperatures.",opd:"Fiber core rope is the only type authorized for cargo runners.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which type of ice is the most difficult to combat and presents the greatest hazard to shipping on the Great Lakes during the winter months?",opa:"Icebergs",opb:"Fast ice",opc:"Slow ice",opd:"Pack slush ice",ans:"opd"},{question:"The muster list must be posted in conspicuous locations and signed by the ____________.",opa:"safety officer",opb:"Coast Guard Officer approving the bill",opc:"owner",opd:"Master",ans:"opd"},{question:"Temporary Certificates of Inspection are effective until the ____________.",opa:"Solas Certificate is issued",opb:"Load Line Certificate is renewed",opc:"classification society approval is issued",opd:"permanent Certificate of Inspection is issued",ans:"opd"},{question:"The implied condition(s) with respect to the doctrine of deviation in a marine insurance policy is(are) ____________.",opa:"that the cargo be discharged from the vessel with customary dispatch",opb:"that the voyage be commenced in a reasonable time",opc:"that the voyage be pursued over the usual and direct route",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Load lines for U.S. vessels are assigned by ____________.",opa:"the U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"the American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"Lloyd's Register of Shipping",opd:"the National Cargo Bureau",ans:"opb"},{question:"When steering on autopilot which of the following input conditions may NOT have an effect on the control of the steering gear?",opa:"Non-follow-up",opb:"Rudder adjustment",opc:"Weather adjustment",opd:"All the above may be activated",ans:"opa"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'E' is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"after spring line",opb:"bow spring line",opc:"forward breast line",opd:"bow line",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel sailing from Liverpool to New York puts into Boston, Mass. for emergency repairs. If no inward foreign cargo is to be discharged at that port, which of the following documents is required?",opa:"Customs Manifest",opb:"Inward Foreign Manifest",opc:"Pro Forma Manifest",opd:"Traveling Manifest",ans:"opc"},{question:"A tanker is loaded with 5,000 barrels of petroleum. The cargo was loaded at a temperature of 70\xb0F, and the coefficient of expansion is .0004. What is the net amount in barrels of cargo loaded?",opa:"4800",opb:"4980",opc:"5020",opd:"5200",ans:"opb"},{question:"Nautical charts published by the Canadian Hydrographic service which are referenced in the United States Coast Pilot are identified by ____________.",opa:"the abbreviation 'can' preceding the chart number",opb:"the letter 'C' in parentheses following the chart number",opc:"an asterisk preceding the chart number",opd:"a footnote number",ans:"opc"},{question:"The owner, agent, Master or person-in-charge of a 'T-Boat' involved in a marine casualty causing injury that requires professional medical treatment must ____________.",opa:"immediately notify the nearest USCG MSO, MIO, or Group Office",opb:"keep all voyage records and make them available to Coast Guard investigators",opc:"file a written report (CG2692) of the casualty within five days",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are attempting to take a dead ship in tow. All lines have been passed and secured. How should you get underway?",opa:"Order minimum turns until the towing hawser is just clear of the water, then reduce speed to that necessary to keep the line clear of the water.",opb:"If the towline is properly adjusted and weighted you can order slow or dead slow and the towline will act as a spring to absorb the initial shock.",opc:"Order minimum turns until the towing hawser is taut and then continue at that speed until towing speed is attained.",opd:"Gradually apply power until catenary almost breaks the water, but keep the catenary in the water.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A 'wet cargo' refers to ____________.",opa:"a cargo that will be damaged if it gets wet",opb:"bulk liquids",opc:"cargoes that will cause condensation",opd:"liquids in containers",ans:"opd"},{question:"When piloting a vessel, how are visual references used to establish a constant rate of turn?",opa:"Fixed objects that stay on the same relative bearing when the ship is turning indicate a constant rate of turn.",opb:"Visual references cannot be used to maintain a constant rate of turn.",opc:"Begin the turn when the fixed object is on the beam.",opd:"Keep the fixed object's relative bearing opening, for a constant rate of turn.",ans:"opa"},{question:"In which casualty case is it UNNECESSARY to notify the local Coast Guard Marine Safety Office?",opa:"Your vessel strikes a pier and does $1,500 damage to the pier but none to the vessel.",opb:"A nylon mooring line parts while the vessel is tied up and kills a harbor worker who was on the pier.",opc:"A seaman is injured and in the hospital for four days.",opd:"Your vessel is backing from a dock and runs aground, but is pulled off by tugs in 30 minutes.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Combustible liquid is defined as any liquid having a flash point above ____________.",opa:"40\xb0F ( 4\xb0C)",opb:"80\xb0F (27\xb0C)",opc:"110\xb0F (43\xb0C)",opd:"150\xb0F (66\xb0C)",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master of a passenger vessel which is not required to maintain an Official Logbook must keep a record of the number of passengers received and delivered from day to day. This record must be available for a period of ____________.",opa:"6 months",opb:"12 months",opc:"24 months",opd:"36 months",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a 165 foot (50.3 meters) long vessel with a draft of 9 feet (2.7 meters) and twin screws. Which statement about rescuing a survivor in the water with ship pickup is TRUE?",opa:"You should stop to windward of the man and drift down on him.",opb:"You should stop with the man on your weather beam and twist the ship up to him.",opc:"A pickup off the weather bow gives maximum maneuverability with the least possibility of injury to the man.",opd:"Ship pick up should never be used with a shallow draft vessel.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are standing the wheel watch on entering port and the Master gives you a rudder command which conflicts with a rudder command from the Pilot. What should you do?",opa:"Ask the Pilot if he relinquishes control.",opb:"Obey the Pilot.",opc:"Obey the Master.",opd:"Bring the rudder to a position midway between the two conflicting positions.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are conning a twin-screw vessel going ahead with rudders amidships. If the port screw stops turning the bow will ____________.",opa:"go to port",opb:"go to starboard",opc:"not veer to either side",opd:"go first to port and then to starboard",ans:"opa"},{question:"The part of the anchor indicated by the letter H is the ____________.",opa:"fluke",opb:"shank",opc:"tripping palm",opd:"crown",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT an advantage of containership operations over conventional break-bulk operations?",opa:"Flexibility of operation",opb:"Greater operational safety",opc:"Lower stevedoring costs",opd:"Reduction of cargo damage",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are docking a vessel. If possible, you should ____________.",opa:"go in with the current",opb:"go in against the current",opc:"approach the dock at a 90\xb0 angle and swing to",opd:"pass a mooring line to the dock with a heaving line and let the crew pull the vessel in",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE regarding certificates of discharge?",opa:"The mariner receives the original copy of the discharge",opb:"The mariner only signs the original copy of the discharge",opc:"Computer generated signatures are not authorized",opd:"Copies of the certificate of discharge are furnished by the shipping company",ans:"opb"},{question:"Operators of Uninspected Passenger Vessels are required to keep their Coast Guard License aboard ____________.",opa:"only when operating more than one mile from shore",opb:"only when operating at night",opc:"only when carrying passengers for hire",opd:"At all times",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which action will take place if a crew member is replaced in a U.S. port after foreign articles have been signed, and the ship proceeds foreign?",opa:"The Master will remove the replaced man's name from the Certified Crew List but not from the articles.",opb:"The name of the new man is added to the articles but not to the Certified Crew List.",opc:"The U.S. Consul will remove the replaced man's name from the Certified Crew List.",opd:"The U.S. Consul will add the new man's name to the Certified Crew List.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the Great Lakes is generally the last to reach its seasonal low and seasonal high water marks?",opa:"Lake Superior",opb:"Lake Michigan",opc:"Lake Huron",opd:"Lake Ontario",ans:"opa"},{question:"The horizontal fore-and-aft movement of a vessel is called ____________.",opa:"yaw",opb:"sway",opc:"heave",opd:"surge",ans:"opd"},{question:"Reid vapor pressure is ____________.",opa:"exerted by liquid cargo on the sides of a tank",opb:"exerted by liquid cargo on a cargo hose body",opc:"the lowest temperature and pressure that will cause a flammable liquid to give off vapors",opd:"a measurement of the amount of flammable vapors given off by a liquid at a certain temperature",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Master of any vessel bound on a voyage must apply to a district court when an allegation of unseaworthiness has been made to the Master by ____________.",opa:"any member of the crew of the vessel",opb:"any two officers of the vessel and a majority of the crew",opc:"the First and Second Officers of the vessel or a majority of the crew",opd:"the First Officer of the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are carrying cargoes of crotonaldehyde, phosphoric acid, and morpholine on your multiple-product tankship. Which of the following statements is TRUE?",opa:"Each of the cargoes must be segregated from the other by at least two barriers.",opb:"The minimum protective clothing required for taking samples of phosphoric acid is goggles or a face shield.",opc:"Aluminum, copper, and zinc are prohibited in all valve parts in contact with these cargoes.",opd:"The required warning sign must have the legend 'cancer hazard' added to it.",ans:"opa"},{question:"For the deepest water when rounding a bend in a river, you should navigate your vessel ____________.",opa:"toward the inside of the bend",opb:"toward the outside of the bend",opc:"toward the center of the river just before the bend, then change course for the river's center after the bend",opd:"in the river's center",ans:"opb"},{question:"A deep well pump is a type of ____________.",opa:"screw pump",opb:"centrifugal pump",opc:"eductor",opd:"gear pump",ans:"opb"},{question:"A natural fiber rope can be ruined by dampness because it may ____________.",opa:"rot",opb:"shrink",opc:"stretch",opd:"unlay",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a hydraulic pump on a winch accidentally stops while hoisting, the load will stay suspended because ____________.",opa:"a check valve will close and prevent reverse circulation",opb:"a centrifugal counterweight counteracts the force of gravity.",opc:"the electric pump motor will cut out",opd:"the control lever will move to the stop position",ans:"opa"},{question:"A wooden plug fitted tightly in the vent of a damaged tank may prevent the tank from ____________.",opa:"filling completely",opb:"developing free surface",opc:"developing free surface moment",opd:"collapsing",ans:"opa"},{question:"Under defense plans, operation of electronic aids may be temporarily suspended with ____________.",opa:"one day's notice",opb:"no notice",opc:"thirty (30) day's notice",opd:"a week's notice",ans:"opb"},{question:"What term indicates the line drawn at the top of the flat plate keel?",opa:"Base line",opb:"Molded line",opc:"Designer's waterline",opd:"Keel line",ans:"opa"},{question:"The major components which determine the length of catenary in a deployed anchor cable are water depth, cable tension, and ____________.",opa:"environmental forces",opb:"bottom conditions",opc:"cable weight",opd:"water density",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your ship is navigating independently in heavy ice when it becomes beset. Which statement is FALSE?",opa:"The vessel will most likely require an icebreaker to free her.",opb:"The vessel may be able to free herself by pumping ballast from side to side.",opc:"The propeller is more susceptible to ice damage when turning slowly than when stopped.",opd:"It is advisable to clear the rudder area of ice by using ahead turns before backing down.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Close link chain of not less the 3/4' (or the wire rope equivalent) is required for lashing deck cargoes of timber. What size flexible wire rope would provide the strength equivalent to 3/4' chain, using a safety factor of 5?",opa:"9/16'",opb:"1'",opc:"1 1/4'",opd:"1 3/8'",ans:"opb"},{question:"The knot lettered U is a ____________.",opa:"half hitch",opb:"round knot",opc:"becket bend",opd:"plain whipping",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following statement(s) is/are TRUE regarding twin pedestal cranes?",opa:"Each single boom is of the partial-level luffing type and is capable of limited rotation.",opb:"A slew drive system provides for rotation of each crane.",opc:"An independent slew drive system rotates the turntable.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"On the fully containerized ship, approximately one-third or more of the cargo is on deck above the rolling center. Top stowed containers are subject to ____________.",opa:"accelerations greater than on conventional vessels",opb:"accelerations less than on conventional vessels",opc:"accelerations the same as on conventional vessels",opd:"no accelerations",ans:"opa"},{question:"The boom indicator tells the operator at what angle the boom is compared to the ____________.",opa:"horizontal position of the boom",opb:"vertical position of the boom",opc:"horizontal position of the load being lifted",opd:"vertical position of the load being lifted",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which knot represents a single becket bend?",opa:"E",opb:"F",opc:"G",opd:"H",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the MOST irritating to the skin?",opa:"Carbon disulfide",opb:"Ethyl alcohol",opc:"Isoprene",opd:"Oleum",ans:"opd"},{question:"The terms 'ceiling' and 'margin plate' are associated with the ____________.",opa:"crew's quarters",opb:"engine room",opc:"main deck",opd:"tank top",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are using tackle number 5 to lift a weight. The hauling part of this tackle is bent to the weight hook of tackle number 9. What is the mechanical advantage of this rig?",opa:"20",opb:"9",opc:"5",opd:"4",ans:"opa"},{question:"What material may be substituted for zinc when making a poured metal socket ending to a wire rope?",opa:"Lead",opb:"Babbitt",opc:"Solder",opd:"Nothing",ans:"opd"},{question:"Coiling new rope against the lay, bringing the lower end up through the center of the coil, then coiling with the lay, in order to remove the kinks, is known as ____________.",opa:"coiling",opb:"faking",opc:"flemishing",opd:"thoroughfooting",ans:"opd"},{question:"The S.S. Microwave has been chartered to the Longline Steamship Company. The Longline Steamship Company agrees to pay all expenses and employ and pay the crew. Which type of contract is involved?",opa:"Bareboat Charter Party",opb:"Lease Charter Party",opc:"Time Charter Party",opd:"Voyage Charter Party",ans:"opa"},{question:"Combustible liquids are divided into how many grades?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are making a sharp turn in a channel and using a buoy four points on the bow to gauge your rate of turn. If you observe the buoy moving aft relative to you, what should you do?",opa:"Increase the rate of turn",opb:"Decrease the rate of turn",opc:"Maintain a constant rate of turn",opd:"Decrease speed",ans:"opa"},{question:"When making a Scharnow turn, the ____________.",opa:"rudder must be put over towards the side the man went over",opb:"initial turn direction is away from the side the man went over",opc:"rudder is put hard over and the initial turn is maintained until about 240\xb0 from the original course",opd:"man overboard must be not more than 300 feet astern when starting the turn",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the period of beam seas equals the natural rolling period of a vessel, what will most likely occur?",opa:"Excessive pitching",opb:"Excessive yawing",opc:"Excessive rolling",opd:"No change should be evident",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is another description for a tandem crane lift?",opa:"Single crane hoisting 30 tons",opb:"Twin cranes hoisting 60 tons",opc:"Quad lift hoisting 120 tons",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is an advantage of a gate valve over a butterfly valve?",opa:"Less frequent maintenance",opb:"Faster operation",opc:"Cheaper",opd:"More compact",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your enrolled vessel is bound from Baltimore, MD, to Norfolk, VA, via Chesapeake Bay. Which statement about the required Pilot is TRUE?",opa:"The Pilot must be licensed by Virginia and Maryland.",opb:"The Pilot must be licensed by either Virginia or Maryland.",opc:"The Pilot need only be licensed by the Coast Guard.",opd:"The Pilot must be licensed by Virginia, Maryland and the Coast Guard.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are ordering a new block to use with a 3-inch circumference manila line. Which represents a proper size block for this line?",opa:"6-inch cheek, 4-inch sheave",opb:"8-inch cheek, any size sheave",opc:"9-inch cheek, 6-inch sheave",opd:"At least a 12-inch sheave",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning lighting requirements for Great Lakes vessels?",opa:"The showing of a forward masthead light is optional for vessels under 150 meters.",opb:"An all-round white light may be carried in lieu of the second masthead light and stern light.",opc:"Sidelights for vessels over 50 meters are required to have only a two-mile range of visibility.",opd:"Great Lakes vessels are exempted from the requirement to show yellow towing lights.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The ultimate or maximum strength of a wire rope is referred to as the ____________.",opa:"operating strength",opb:"working load",opc:"breaking strength",opd:"lifting load",ans:"opc"},{question:"Forty-five fathoms is marked on the anchor chain by ____________.",opa:"one turn of wire on the first stud from each side of the detachable link",opb:"two turns of wire on the second stud from each side of the detachable link",opc:"three turns of wire on the third stud from each side of the detachable link",opd:"four turns of wire on the fourth stud from each side of the detachable link",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your containership has a container displaying a hazardous cargo placard. The placard has the number 2206 on it. This indicates that it is carrying what cargo?",opa:"Isocyanates, n.o.s.",opb:"Propadiene, inhibited",opc:"Xylenol",opd:"Hexanols",ans:"opa"},{question:"To reduce the number of strakes at the bow, two strakes are tapered and joined at their ends by a single plate. This plate is known as a ____________.",opa:"cover plate",opb:"joiner",opc:"lap strake",opd:"stealer plate",ans:"opd"},{question:"When plugging holes below the waterline you should ____________.",opa:"eliminate all water entering the hole",opb:"only plug holes in machinery or other vital spaces",opc:"reduce the entry of water as much as possible",opd:"plug the largest holes first",ans:"opc"},{question:"Form 2692 (Notice of Marine Casualty), when required, must be filed to the U.S. Coast Guard within how many days?",opa:"1 day",opb:"3 days",opc:"5 days",opd:"7 days",ans:"opc"},{question:"A Contract of Affreightment covering the movement of a particular cargo from one designated port to another at a specified rate for each ton of goods loaded is called a ____________.",opa:"bareboat charter party",opb:"demise charter party",opc:"time charter party",opd:"voyage charter party",ans:"opd"},{question:"How many wire clips must be used to make a temporary repair to a tow wire?",opa:"3",opb:"4",opc:"5",opd:"Wire clips are never, under any circumstances, permitted",ans:"opc"},{question:"Nylon line can be dangerous because it ____________.",opa:"breaks down when wet",opb:"kinks when wet",opc:"is not elastic",opd:"stretches",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a single-screw vessel the stern frame ____________.",opa:"furnishes support to the rudder, propeller shaft, and transom frame",opb:"provides foundations for after mooring winches",opc:"provides foundations for the main propulsion engines",opd:"transfers the driving force of the propeller to the hull",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which tensioning device is used with chain to secure heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever",opb:"Buckle tensioner",opc:"Adjust-a-matic tensioner",opd:"Ratchet tensioner",ans:"opa"},{question:"When underway and proceeding ahead, as the speed increases, the pivot point tends to ____________.",opa:"move aft",opb:"move forward",opc:"move lower",opd:"remain stationary",ans:"opb"},{question:"Using a scope of 6, determine how many feet of anchor cable you should put out to anchor in 12 feet (3.7 meters) of water.",opa:"2 feet (0.6 meters)",opb:"18 feet (5.5 meters)",opc:"48 feet (14.6 meters)",opd:"72 feet (21.9 meters)",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement concerning storm surges on the Great Lakes is FALSE?",opa:"They are common along the deeper areas of the lakes.",opb:"They cause rapid differences in levels between one end of the lake and the other.",opc:"The greatest water level difference occurs when the wind is blowing along the axis of the lake.",opd:"If the wind subsides rapidly, a seiche effect will most likely occur.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The agency which assigns load lines and issues Load Line Certificates is the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Secretary of Commerce",opc:"U.S. Customs",opd:"U.S. Coast Guard",ans:"opa"},{question:"A seaman signed on articles on 16 January 1987 and signed off on 2 March 1987. How should you enter this under the Time of Service column in the articles?",opa:"1 Month 18 Days",opb:"1 Month 16 Days",opc:"2 Months",opd:"46 Days",ans:"opd"},{question:"Particular average is ____________.",opa:"the average distance steamed per day over the duration of the voyage",opb:"charges against all parties in a marine venture to pay for damages",opc:"loss sustained by only one party",opd:"claimed after all liens against the vessel are settled",ans:"opc"},{question:"Good seamanship while towing in heavy weather requires all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"reducing speed to reduce surging on the towline",opb:"lashing down or stowing all loose gear",opc:"dogging all hatches and watertight doors",opd:"streaming all of your towing hawser",ans:"opd"},{question:"A 'bowline' is used to ____________.",opa:"join lines of equal size",opb:"form a temporary eye (loop) at the end of a line",opc:"be a stopper",opd:"keep a line from fraying",ans:"opb"},{question:"Most pedestal crane power is provided by ____________.",opa:"Electro-hydraulic units",opb:"Steam units",opc:"Independent internal combustion power units",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following responsibilities should you assume once you have agreed to assist a disabled vessel?",opa:"All personnel on the disabled vessel don life jackets",opb:"All passengers move to the highest point on the disabled vessel to remain clear of towing gear",opc:"Operator of disabled vessel on the bow with a lifejacket and emergency tow disconnect equipment",opd:"Operator of disabled vessel to dump fuel and ballast to improve disabled vessel's towing movement",ans:"opa"},{question:"The proper way to correct a mistake in the logbook is to ____________.",opa:"erase the entry and rewrite",opb:"draw a line through the entry, rewrite, and initial the correction",opc:"draw several lines through the entry, rewrite, and initial the correction",opd:"completely black out the entry, rewrite, and initial the correction",ans:"opb"},{question:"The document that the Master uses to attest to the truth of the manifest of cargo is called ____________.",opa:"Master's Protest",opb:"Oath of Entry",opc:"Owner's Oath",opd:"Shipper's Certification",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is a wet cargo?",opa:"A liquid cargo carried in the deep tanks",opb:"A canned or bottled liquid such as beer",opc:"A cargo that contains hygroscopic moisture",opd:"A cargo particularly susceptible to damage by moisture",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel that tows astern must have a/an ____________.",opa:"towing winch",opb:"method to easily release the towline",opc:"oxy-acetylene cutting torch",opd:"ax or knife mounted near the towing bitts",ans:"opb"},{question:"When towing a small trailer-able boat, the sturdiest fitting available to attach a tow rig is the ____________.",opa:"towing cleat on the bow",opb:"most forward handrail stanchion",opc:"trailer eye",opd:"chock",ans:"opc"},{question:"How long is the standard container used to measure equivalent units?",opa:"10 feet (3 meters)",opb:"20 feet (6 meters)",opc:"35 feet (11 meters)",opd:"40 feet (12 meters)",ans:"opb"},{question:"The part of the anchor indicated by the letter G is the ____________.",opa:"fluke",opb:"shank",opc:"tripping palm",opd:"crown",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are backing on twin engines with rudders amidships, when your port engine stalls. To continue backing on course, you should ____________.",opa:"apply left rudder",opb:"apply right rudder",opc:"increase engine speed",opd:"keep your rudder amidships",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which information MUST be entered on the muster list?",opa:"Names of all crew members",opb:"Use and application of special equipment",opc:"Listing of approved emergency equipment",opd:"Duties and station of each person during emergencies",ans:"opd"},{question:"A tank is loaded with 9,000 barrels of gasoline. The temperature of the product is 90\xb0F (32\xb0C), and it has a coefficient of expansion of .0008. What is the net amount of cargo loaded?",opa:"8856 bbls",opb:"8784 bbls",opc:"8820 bbls",opd:"9216 bbls",ans:"opb"},{question:"Under normal weather and sea conditions when securing a stack of containers with twist locks, lashings are required when the tier exceeds what height?",opa:"Lashings are always required",opb:"One container",opc:"Two containers",opd:"Three containers",ans:"opc"},{question:"In a foreign port with a consulate, the U.S. Consul may excuse the Master from personally appearing before him to consent to the mutual release of an injured seaman, when the ____________.",opa:"injury requires immediate inpatient hospitalization of the seaman",opb:"Master authorizes the agent to act in his place",opc:"ship is still in port and the seaman can appear before the Consul after medical treatment",opd:"seaman also consents to the absence, and there is no dispute as to the wages due",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have a large, broken-down vessel in tow with a wire rope and anchor cable towline. Both vessels have made provision for slipping the tow in an emergency; however, unless there are special circumstances ____________.",opa:"the towing vessel should slip first",opb:"the vessel towed should slip first",opc:"they should slip simultaneously",opd:"either vessel may slip first",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following statement(s) is/are FALSE regarding a twin pedestal crane set?",opa:"The cranes may be operated independently.",opb:"The cranes may be interconnected for twin operation.",opc:"The cranes are powered by independent internal combustion power units.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is meant by the term 'two-blocked'?",opa:"The bottom block touches the top block.",opb:"The line has jumped the sheaves.",opc:"There are turns in the fall.",opd:"You have two blocks.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the Great Lakes lies entirely within the United States?",opa:"Lake Ontario",opb:"Lake St. Clair",opc:"Lake Michigan",opd:"Lake Superior",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which factor(s) should be considered when loading vehicles or trailers aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Layout of decks",opb:"Vertical clearances",opc:"Tie-down and lashing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the main reason to slush a wire rope?",opa:"Keep the wire soft and manageable",opb:"Lubricate the inner wires and prevent wear",opc:"Prevent kinking",opd:"Prevent rotting",ans:"opb"},{question:"The distance between the surface of the liquid and the tank top in a cargo tank is called ____________.",opa:"thievage",opb:"innage",opc:"ullage",opd:"tankage",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which picture in illustration D030DG represents a half hitch?",opa:"U",opb:"S",opc:"K",opd:"H",ans:"opa"},{question:"In order to help protect a natural fiber rope from rotting, the line must be ____________.",opa:"dried, and stowed in a place with adequate ventilation",opb:"stowed in a hot, moist compartment",opc:"stowed on deck at all times",opd:"stowed in any compartment",ans:"opa"},{question:"The horizontal port or starboard movement of a vessel is called ____________.",opa:"yaw",opb:"sway",opc:"surge",opd:"heave",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning deep well self-priming pumps?",opa:"When loading oil cargo, it is always loaded via the discharge line through to the pump until the tank is topped off.",opb:"Stripping systems are generally eliminated for the purposes of cargo handling.",opc:"In recent years deep well pumps have become increasingly unpopular in product tankers and medium size crude ships.",opd:"There is no danger of damaging the pump from overheating.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Under defense plans, operation of electronic aids to navigation may be temporarily suspended with ____________.",opa:"one day's notice",opb:"thirty (30) days notice",opc:"no notice",opd:"a week's notice",ans:"opc"},{question:"After having been pulled aloft in a bosn's chair on a mast, you must now make yourself fast in the chair prior to painting the mast. You should first ____________.",opa:"have the sailor on deck make the hauling part fast to a cleat on the mast",opb:"make the tail of the line leading from the becket bend fast to a padeye on the mast",opc:"seize the hauling part and the standing part firmly in one hand to support your weight",opd:"frap yourself to the mast to take the strain off the hauling part",ans:"opc"},{question:"A pelican hook ____________.",opa:"can be released while under strain",opb:"is used for boat falls",opc:"is used for extra heavy loads",opd:"is used for light loads only",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the breaking strain of steel wire rope with a 5/8' diameter?",opa:"1.0 tons",opb:"6.6 tons",opc:"9.6 tons",opd:"15.6 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statement(s) is/are TRUE regarding a twin pedestal crane set?",opa:"The cranes may be operated independently.",opb:"The cranes may be interconnected for twin operation.",opc:"When twinned, the crane rotation on the foundation assembly is unlimited.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which letter represents a bowline on a bight?",opa:"H",opb:"I",opc:"M",opd:"W",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is a proper size block to use with a 3-inch circumference Manila line?",opa:"At least a 12-inch sheave",opb:"9-inch cheek, 6-inch sheave",opc:"8-inch cheek, any size sheave",opd:"6-inch cheek, 4-inch sheave",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following statements is FALSE concerning cranes being installed on the centerline of vessels?",opa:"A centerline crane can never be operated in tandem.",opb:"One crane is able to work one end of two adjacent hatches.",opc:"These cranes are more economical and weigh less than outboard-mounted cranes.",opd:"One crane is able to work both sides of the ship.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a man who is conscious has fallen overboard is being picked up by a lifeboat, the boat should approach with the wind ____________.",opa:"astern and the victim just off the bow",opb:"ahead and the victim just off the bow",opc:"just off the bow and the victim to windward",opd:"just off the bow and the victim to leeward",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a multiple product tankship and carrying methyl acrylate, diethanolamine, and triethylamine. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Methyl acrylate may be loaded in a tank adjacent to diethanolamine but not triethylamine.",opb:"The heating coils to the cargo tank loaded with methyl acrylate must be blanked off.",opc:"Valve components made of aluminum, copper, or zinc may not be in contact with the cargoes.",opd:"Each crew member working on deck must have an emergency escape breathing apparatus.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is an explosion hazard when exposed to flame?",opa:"Formic acid",opb:"Nitrous oxide",opc:"Tallow",opd:"Toluene",ans:"opd"},{question:"What would have the greatest affect on a vessel's longitudinal strength?",opa:"Collision damage to the bow, forward of the collision bulkhead",opb:"Grounding damage to the bilge strake, just aft of midships",opc:"Extensive corrosion to the centerline deck plating",opd:"Damage to the side shell, midway between the bilge and the stringer plate",ans:"opb"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'C' is called a ____________.",opa:"breast line",opb:"shore line",opc:"spring line",opd:"stern line",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which is an advantage of using watertight longitudinal divisions in double bottom tanks?",opa:"Cuts down free surface effect",opb:"Increases the rolling period",opc:"Decreases weight because extra stiffeners are unneeded",opd:"Lowers the center of buoyancy without decreasing GM",ans:"opa"},{question:"On which vessels are the officers and deck crew allowed to operate under a two-watch system on voyages of less than 600 miles?",opa:"Towing vessels",opb:"Offshore supply vessels",opc:"Barges, when manned",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"In plugging submerged holes; rags, wedges, and other materials should be used in conjunction with plugs to ____________.",opa:"reduce the water pressure on the hull",opb:"reduce the possibility of stress fractures",opc:"prevent progressive flooding",opd:"reduce the water leaking around the plugs",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is meant by the term 'broaching to'?",opa:"Having the vessel head toward the sea",opb:"Running before a sea",opc:"Being turned broadside to the sea",opd:"Having the vessel filled with water",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is LEAST likely to be used to strip a cargo tank?",opa:"Centrifugal pump",opb:"Eductor",opc:"Rotary pump",opd:"Reciprocating pump",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is a step in attaching a poured metal socket to a wire rope?",opa:"Etch the wire with acid.",opb:"Install a wire seizing on the wire that will be inside the socket.",opc:"Ensure the fiber core is well lubricated.",opd:"Pour molten babbitt metal into the socket.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fire fighting equipment requirements for a particular vessel may be found on the ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Certificate of Seaworthiness",opc:"Classification Certificate",opd:"Certificate of Registry",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following statement(s) is/are TRUE regarding twin pedestal cranes?",opa:"A slew drive system provides for rotation of each crane.",opb:"An independent slew drive system rotates the turntable.",opc:"Each crane is supplied with luff, hoist, and slew functions for crane load handling.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"In stopping distances of vessels, 'head reach' can best be described as the ____________.",opa:"difference between the vessel's speed through the water at any instant and the new speed ordered on the telegraph",opb:"distance the vessel has actually run through the water since a change of speed was ordered",opc:"distance the vessel will run between taking action to stop her and being stationary in the water",opd:"speed at which a vessel should proceed to ensure that she will run a predetermined distance, once her engines have been stopped",ans:"opc"},{question:"In relation to the turning circle of a ship, the term 'advance' means the distance ____________.",opa:"gained at right angles to the original course",opb:"gained in the direction of the original course",opc:"moved sidewise from the original course when the rudder is first put over",opd:"around the circumference of the turning circle",ans:"opb"},{question:"Lifting the anchor from the bottom is called ____________.",opa:"broaching the anchor",opb:"shifting the anchor",opc:"walking the anchor",opd:"weighing the anchor",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a power-driven vessel proceeding down a channel, with the current, on a river on the Great Lakes System. If you meet another power-driven vessel who is upbound, your responsibilities include ____________.",opa:"backing down to get out of the way of the other vessel",opb:"waiting for the other vessel to signal her intentions, and then answering promptly",opc:"proposing a safe way to pass",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which tensioning device is used with webbing to secure light vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever",opb:"Turnbuckle",opc:"Adjust-a-matic tensioner",opd:"Ratchet tensioner",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Great Lakes Edition of the Notice to Mariners is published ____________.",opa:"weekly by the 9th Coast Guard District",opb:"monthly by the Army Corps of Engineers",opc:"monthly by the Naval Oceanographic office",opd:"biweekly by the Commandant, U.S. Coast Guard",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a large merchant vessel entering a U.S. port. There is a Pilot on board and he has the conn. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The Pilot is solely responsible for the safe maneuvering of the ship only if he is required to be on board by law.",opb:"The Master is responsible for the safe navigation of the ship and the Pilot is employed for his local knowledge.",opc:"The Pilot is solely responsible for the internal working of the ship.",opd:"The Pilot becomes solely responsible for the safe navigation of the vessel only if the Master relinquishes the conn.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is being assisted through an ice field in Thunder Bay by the Canadian Coast Guard icebreaker Alexander Henry. The starboard lookout reports that the icebreaker has run up the code flag 'N' (November). What action should you take?",opa:"Reduce speed",opb:"Stop your engines",opc:"Reverse your engines",opd:"Stop your vessel instantly",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage, neglecting friction, of tackle number 4?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has grounded on a bar. What should you do?",opa:"If you cannot get clear immediately, lighten the ship by pumping all ballast overboard.",opb:"Run the engine full astern to keep from being set further onto the bar.",opc:"Switch to the high suction for condenser circulating water, if it is submerged.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are landing a single-screw vessel with a left-handed propeller, starboard side to the dock. As you approach the dock you back your engine with your rudder amidships. You would expect the vessel to ____________.",opa:"lose headway without swinging",opb:"turn its bow towards the dock",opc:"turn its stern towards the dock",opd:"drift away from the dock",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many board feet of dunnage would you estimate to be in a pile 5 feet wide, 1 foot high and 14 feet long?",opa:"70",opb:"840",opc:"960",opd:"1080",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are proceeding against the current on a river in the Great Lakes System. You are meeting a down bound vessel. Both vessels are power-driven. The other vessel sounds one short blast. You must ____________.",opa:"change course to port",opb:"hold course and speed",opc:"sound three short blasts",opd:"sound one short blast",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE regarding the operation of a crane?",opa:"The crane jib is raised and lowered by the luffing winch.",opb:"The cargo block is raised and lowered by the hoisting winch.",opc:"The cargo block is raised and lowered by the luffing winch.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"What purpose does a bridge fitting serve when lashing containers?",opa:"Ties a container stack to the deck",opb:"Ties a container to the container below it",opc:"Restrains racking loads",opd:"Restrains the container against horizontal motion",ans:"opd"},{question:"To reeve a right-angle threefold purchase start with the ____________.",opa:"left sheave bottom block",opb:"left sheave top block",opc:"middle sheave top block",opd:"right sheave bottom block",ans:"opc"},{question:"The term 'pintle' and 'gudgeon' are associated with the ____________.",opa:"anchor windlass",opb:"jumbo boom",opc:"rudder",opd:"steering engine",ans:"opc"},{question:"The pivoting point of a fully loaded vessel with normal trim proceeding ahead at sea speed is ____________.",opa:"right at the bow",opb:"one-third the length of the vessel from the bow",opc:"one-half the length of the vessel from the bow",opd:"two-thirds the length of the vessel from the bow",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which variable factor affects the initial lashing requirements aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Age of vehicle or cargo unit",opb:"Size and weight of vehicle/cargo unit",opc:"Reputation of shipper concerning condition of cargo",opd:"Air pressure in the vehicles tires",ans:"opb"},{question:"When underway with a tow, you are required to notify the Coast Guard in which casualty situation?",opa:"An injury requiring first aid treatment",opb:"Damage of bridge-to-bridge radio capability",opc:"Accidental stranding or grounding",opd:"Damage to property amounting to$12,500",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a course of 000\xb0T and put the rudder right 30\xb0. In which direction will the transfer be measured?",opa:"000\xb0T",opb:"090\xb0T",opc:"180\xb0T",opd:"270\xb0T",ans:"opb"},{question:"Round line is a ____________.",opa:"four-stranded, left-or right-handed line",opb:"three-stranded, right-handed line",opc:"three-stranded, left-handed line",opd:"small tarred hemp line of three strands laid left-handed",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel brought alongside should be fended off the towing vessel by ____________.",opa:"crew members using their arms",opb:"a boat hook",opc:"fenders",opd:"No fending is necessary due to the rugged construction of most towing vessels.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which knot represents a double blackwall hitch?",opa:"F",opb:"G",opc:"L",opd:"R",ans:"opc"},{question:"At the required fire drill, all persons must report to their stations and demonstrate their ability to perform the duties assigned to them ____________.",opa:"by the Coast Guard regulations",opb:"in the Muster List ('Station Bill')",opc:"by the person conducting the drill",opd:"at the previous safety meeting",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your containership has a container displaying a hazardous cargo placard. The placard has the number 2199 on it. This indicates that it is carrying what cargo?",opa:"Furan",opb:"Phosphine",opc:"Adiponitrile",opd:"Xylenol",ans:"opb"},{question:"The part of the anchor indicated by the letter F is the ____________.",opa:"shank",opb:"bar",opc:"stock",opd:"shot",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is approaching the International Bridge on the St. Marys River. If the gage on the bridge, read from top to bottom, indicates 124 ft. and the IGLD (1955) is 600 ft., determine the actual vertical clearances between the existing water level and the lowest point of the bridge over the channel.",opa:"124 feet",opb:"476 feet",opc:"724 feet",opd:"840 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is loaded with nonhygroscopic cargoes and is going from a cold to a warm climate. You should ____________.",opa:"start the exhaust blowers",opb:"start the intake blowers",opc:"not ventilate the cargo holds",opd:"ventilate the cargo holds",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which entry is NOT required in the Official Logbook?",opa:"Steering gear tests",opb:"Position of the load line and freeboard upon sailing",opc:"Commencement and termination of cargo operations",opd:"Closure of hatches and sideports upon sailing",ans:"opc"},{question:"You receive a package, for shipment aboard your vessel, containing Class 1 explosives. The package is damp, moldy and stained. You must ____________.",opa:"have the U.S.C.G. Captain of the Port approve the shipment",opb:"note an exception on the Bill of Lading",opc:"repair or replace the packaging before stowage",opd:"seek the shipper's advice with regard to withdrawal, repair, or replacement",ans:"opd"},{question:"Tonnage tax is officially based upon the figures obtained from the ____________.",opa:"Admeasurement Certificate",opb:"deadweight scale",opc:"displacement scale",opd:"Load Line Certificate",ans:"opa"},{question:"You should conduct a sector search under which of the following circumstances?",opa:"The search target is sighted and then lost.",opb:"More than one vessel is available for a search.",opc:"The search object is a target that will be readily detected by radar.",opd:"An aircraft is available to assist a surface vessel.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A twin screw vessel, making headway with both engines turning ahead, will turn more readily to starboard if you ____________.",opa:"reverse port engine, apply right rudder",opb:"reverse port engine, rudder amidships",opc:"reverse starboard engine, apply right rudder",opd:"reverse starboard engine, rudder amidships",ans:"opc"},{question:"The basic shipping paper that forms an agreement between a ship-owner and a charterer is a ____________.",opa:"Cargo Declaration",opb:"Charter Commission",opc:"Charter Party",opd:"Letter of Intent",ans:"opc"},{question:"A partial deck in a hold is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"weather deck",opb:"orlop deck",opc:"shelter deck",opd:"main deck",ans:"opb"},{question:"The lashings on a stack of containers with interlocking fittings restrain the forces that cause ____________.",opa:"toppling",opb:"racking",opc:"buckling",opd:"crushing",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which line is two-stranded, left-handed small stuff?",opa:"Houseline",opb:"Marline",opc:"Ratline",opd:"Lagline",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has run aground and is touching bottom for the first one-quarter of its length. What is the LEAST desirable method from the standpoint of stability to decrease the bottom pressure?",opa:"Discharge forward deck cargo.",opb:"Pump out the forepeak tank.",opc:"Shift deck cargo aft.",opd:"Flood an after double bottom tank.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel having continuous closely spaced transverse strength members is ____________.",opa:"longitudinally framed",opb:"transversely framed",opc:"cellular framed",opd:"web framed",ans:"opb"},{question:"Wages due a seaman may be attached by the court for the ____________.",opa:"payment of any fines imposed by the court",opb:"payment of back taxes to the IRS",opc:"support of a spouse",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a large merchant vessel entering a U.S. port. There is a Pilot on board and he has the conn. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The Pilot becomes solely responsible for the safe navigation of the vessel only if the Master relinquishes the conn.",opb:"The Pilot is solely responsible for the internal working of the ship.",opc:"The Pilot is solely responsible for the safe maneuvering of the ship only if he is required to be on board by law.",opd:"The Master is responsible for the safe navigation of the ship and the Pilot is employed for his local knowledge.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A rope ladder with wooden rungs is a ____________.",opa:"drop ladder",opb:"life ladder",opc:"Jacob's ladder",opd:"jury ladder",ans:"opc"},{question:"The anchors on the bow are known as ____________.",opa:"bower anchors",opb:"kedge anchors",opc:"spare anchors",opd:"stream anchors",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which element(s) should be taken into account in the preparation of the 'Cargo Securing Manual'?",opa:"Weight of the vehicles",opb:"Geographical area of the voyage",opc:"Dynamic forces under adverse weather conditions",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A tank is loaded with 9,000 barrels of gasoline. The temperature of the product is 80\xb0F (27\xb0C), and it has a coefficient of expansion of .0008. The net amount of cargo loaded is ____________.",opa:"8,856 barrels",opb:"8,944 barrels",opc:"9,072 barrels",opd:"9,144 barrels",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning weather conditions on the Great Lakes?",opa:"When a vessel is south of an eastward-moving storm center, the approach of the low is evidenced by winds from the north to northeast.",opb:"When a vessel is north of an eastward-moving storm center, changes in the weather are less distinctive than when sailing south of the center.",opc:"The most destructive storms usually come from the northwest or north.",opd:"Thunderstorms are most likely to develop from November through April.",ans:"opb"},{question:"When you have a tow alongside, your stern should extend aft of the tow in order to ____________.",opa:"avoid obscuring your stern light",opb:"provide a better lead for your lines",opc:"obtain better steering control",opd:"let the barge deflect floating objects from your propeller",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement concerning solid floors is TRUE?",opa:"They must be watertight.",opb:"They may have lightening, limber, or air holes cut into them.",opc:"They are built of structural frames connected by angle struts and stiffeners, with flanged plate brackets at each end.",opd:"They are lighter than open floors.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The owner or Master of a towing vessel shall ensure that each person that directs and controls the movement of the vessel can accurately fix the vessel's position using all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"installed navigational equipment",opb:"buoys alone",opc:"all available aids to navigation",opd:"depths soundings and hydrographic contour lines",ans:"opb"},{question:"The angular movement of a vessel about a horizontal line drawn from its bow to its stern is ____________.",opa:"pitching",opb:"rolling",opc:"heaving",opd:"swaying",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is required to be posted in the pilothouse of a vessel?",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Officer's licenses",opc:"Company Mission Statement",opd:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which form of navigation may be suspended without notice under defense planning?",opa:"electronic",opb:"celestial",opc:"piloting",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which refers to the depth of a petroleum product in a tank?",opa:"Outage",opb:"Ullage",opc:"Thievage",opd:"Innage",ans:"opd"},{question:"You must shore up the collision bulkhead due to solid flooding forward. The bulkhead approximates an inverted triangle. The center of pressure of the shores on the bulkhead should be located ____________.",opa:"evenly over the surface of the bulkhead",opb:"approximately two-thirds of the way up the bulkhead",opc:"approximately halfway up the bulkhead",opd:"at the bottom of the bulkhead",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE regarding the operation of a crane?",opa:"The crane jib is raised and lowered by the luffing winch.",opb:"The crane jib is raised and lowered by the hoisting winch.",opc:"The cargo block is raised and lowered by the luffing winch.",opd:"The crane jib is raised and lowered by a jibing winch.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The safe working load (SWL) of wire rope with a safety factor of 6 is what percent of its strength?",opa:"0.1",opb:"0.17",opc:"0.5",opd:"0.8",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have been pulled aloft in a bosun's chair rigged to a mast that you intend to paint. You are now supporting your weight by seizing the hauling part and the standing part of the gantline in one hand. Your next procedure in securing the bosun's chair is to ____________.",opa:"secure the tail of the standing part leading from the becket bend to the mast",opb:"dip the bight of the hauling part around your back and up in front of you to form the hitch",opc:"take a strain on the hauling part by having it led to the gypsy head on a winch",opd:"secure the standing part of the gantline to the hauling part by taking turns of marlin and tying off",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT a primary function of the freight forwarder?",opa:"To book cargo space in advance",opb:"To execute, approve, and submit all shipping documents necessary to the particular shipment",opc:"To provide financial assistance to the shipper when required",opd:"Clear the goods through customs",ans:"opc"},{question:"Sulfuric acid is a ____________.",opa:"clear syrupy liquid with no odor",opb:"colorless-to-brown liquid with a choking odor when hot",opc:"colorless liquid with a pleasant fruity odor",opd:"whitish liquid with a faint, pleasant odor",ans:"opb"},{question:"All of the following steps are taken in starting a centrifugal pump, EXCEPT to ____________.",opa:"set the relief valve",opb:"check the lubrication system",opc:"vent the pump casing",opd:"open the pump suction and discharge valves",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which tackle arrangement has the LEAST mechanical advantage?",opa:"Single whip",opb:"Gun tackle",opc:"Luff tackle",opd:"Twofold purchase",ans:"opa"},{question:"The 'square knot' is used for ____________.",opa:"forming temporary eyes in lines",opb:"joining two lines of equal size",opc:"keeping line from unlaying or fraying",opd:"joining two lines of different size",ans:"opb"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'D' is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"after spring line",opb:"forward spring line",opc:"waist breast line",opd:"stern line",ans:"opa"},{question:"The number or name of a tank barge shall be ____________.",opa:"displayed in at least 4 different positions on the barge",opb:"carved on a wooden board and attached to the barge's hull",opc:"displayed as close to the navigation lights as possible",opd:"displayed at the highest point of the barge's hull such that it can be seen from either side",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is an advantage of the 6X19 class of wire rope over the 6X37 class of wire rope of the same diameter?",opa:"Greater holding power",opb:"Better for towing",opc:"More resistance to elongation",opd:"More resistance to corrosion",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which piece(s) of equipment is/are required to 'twin-up' 30-ton pedestal cranes aboard a crane vessel?",opa:"Equalizing beam",opb:"Portable power swivel",opc:"20-foot container spreader",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Before a Master relieves a Pilot of the conn, the ____________.",opa:"Master should foresee any danger to the vessel on the present course",opb:"vessel must be in extremis",opc:"Master should agree to sign a release of liability form",opd:"Master must first request the Pilot to take corrective action",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which factor does NOT affect the required freeboard of a cargo vessel?",opa:"Season of the year",opb:"Geographic zone of operation",opc:"Density of the water",opd:"Condition of trim in normal operation",ans:"opd"},{question:"How many fathoms are in a shot of anchor cable?",opa:"6",opb:"15",opc:"20",opd:"30",ans:"opb"},{question:"Preparation of muster lists and signing of same is the responsibility of the ____________.",opa:"Chief Officer of the vessel",opb:"owner of the vessel",opc:"Master of the vessel",opd:"United States Coast Guard",ans:"opc"},{question:"A tow of 9 barges is made up three abreast and three long. The towboat is faced up to the center string which is known as the ____________.",opa:"main string",opb:"push string",opc:"power string",opd:"face string",ans:"opb"},{question:"If you were to pass a stopper on a wire rope, what should the stopper be made of?",opa:"Wire",opb:"Manila",opc:"Nylon",opd:"Chain",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel is tide rode when it is ____________.",opa:"carrying extra rudder to compensate for the current",opb:"necessary to adjust the course steered to allow for the current",opc:"at anchor and stemming the current",opd:"being forced off of a pier by the hydraulic effect of the current",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the period of validity of a Cargo Ship Safety Equipment Certificate?",opa:"72 months",opb:"60 months",opc:"48 months",opd:"42 months",ans:"opb"},{question:"In order to reduce the accumulation of static electricity while loading petroleum products, you should ____________.",opa:"start to load at maximum pressure",opb:"start to load slowly",opc:"increase the air flow into the tank",opd:"use the overall method of loading only",ans:"opb"},{question:"To coil a right-laid rope, you should coil the line in ____________.",opa:"a clockwise direction",opb:"a counterclockwise direction",opc:"alternating clockwise and counterclockwise directions",opd:"either a clockwise or counterclockwise directions",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a multiple-product chemical tanker and will carry cargoes of ethanolamine, methyl acrylate, and glycerine. Which statement is true?",opa:"All of these cargoes are mutually incompatible.",opb:"Glycerine may be stowed adjacent to methyl acrylate but must be segregated from ethanolamine.",opc:"Methyl acrylate and ethanolamine are compatible but both must be segregated from glycerine.",opd:"Glycerine is compatible with both of the other cargoes.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which illustration represents a carrick bend?",opa:"H",opb:"J",opc:"L",opd:"M",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a small boat, if someone fell overboard and you did not know over which side the person fell, you should ____________.",opa:"immediately reverse the engines",opb:"stop the propellers from turning and throw a ring buoy over the side",opc:"increase speed to full to get the vessel away from the person",opd:"first put the rudder hard over in either direction",ans:"opb"},{question:"One function of a bulwark is to ____________.",opa:"help keep the deck dry",opb:"prevent stress concentrations on the stringer plate",opc:"protect against twisting forces exerted on the frame of the vessel",opd:"reinforce the side stringers",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 7?",opa:"0",opb:"0.5",opc:"1",opd:"2",ans:"opd"},{question:"For operations in pack ice, a vessel should ____________.",opa:"be on an even keel",opb:"be trimmed slightly by the head",opc:"have a drag of not more than 2 to 3 feet",opd:"be ballasted so the forefoot is near the surface",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following tensioning devices is used with webbing to secure light vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever",opb:"Buckle tensioner",opc:"Adjust-a-matic tensioner",opd:"Turnbuckle",ans:"opb"},{question:"What shape barge offers the least resistance in river towing?",opa:"A square ended barge",opb:"Barges with raked shaped bows",opc:"Ship-shaped barges",opd:"Hopper barges",ans:"opb"},{question:"What term indicates a curvature of the decks in a longitudinal direction?",opa:"Deadrise",opb:"Camber",opc:"Sheer",opd:"Flare",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are docking a ship with a single-screw tug assisting on your starboard bow. How should the tug be tied up if you are anticipating that she will have to hold your bow off while you stem the current?",opa:"One head line would be sufficient.",opb:"The tug would need at least two head lines.",opc:"The tug should put a spring line up, leading astern on the ship.",opd:"The tug should put a stern line up, leading ahead on the ship.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A ballasted vessel sinks enroute to a dry dock. Under these circumstances, the vessel's owner can claim ____________.",opa:"actual total loss",opb:"constructive total loss",opc:"general average",opd:"particular average",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which publication would give detailed information on the commercial vessel traffic reporting system for connecting waters from Lake Erie to Lake Huron?",opa:"United States Coast Pilot -Great Lakes#6",opb:"U.S. Coast Guard Light List -Vol. VII",opc:"Code of Federal Regulations -Title 33",opd:"The appropriate Great Lakes Navigation Chart",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel has a deadweight capacity of 5000 tons and a cubic capacity of 300,000 cu. ft. You are to load lead, with a stowage factor of 18, and cotton, with a stowage factor of 80. If you load full and down, how much cotton should you load?",opa:"1613 tons",opb:"2190 tons",opc:"2810 tons",opd:"3387 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The single line located directly above the diamond is the ____________.",opa:"load line",opb:"water line",opc:"freeboard line",opd:"deck line",ans:"opd"},{question:"Onboard a Ro-Ro vessel many decks are used for the carriage of both rolling and container cargoes, as such it is most useful if a deck socket accepts both ____________.",opa:"twist-Locks and lashing hooks",opb:"container locks and bridge fittings",opc:"bridge fittings and lashing hooks",opd:"twist-locks and container locks",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT a securing system used on a containership?",opa:"Lashing system",opb:"Stacking system",opc:"Locking system",opd:"Buttress system",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many board feet of dunnage are in a draft 4 feet wide, 1-1/2 feet high and 13 feet long?",opa:"84",opb:"756",opc:"936",opd:"1021",ans:"opc"},{question:"Transverse frames are more widely spaced on a ship that is designed with the ____________.",opa:"centerline system of framing",opb:"isometric system of framing",opc:"longitudinal system of framing",opd:"transverse system of framing",ans:"opc"},{question:"Dead freight is the charge for the ____________.",opa:"carriage of demise cargo",opb:"cost of transshipment of over-carried cargo",opc:"difference in the amount of cargo loaded and the amount of cargo discharged",opd:"difference in the amount of cargo loaded and the amount of cargo booked, through no fault of the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"A 150-meter vessel is proceeding down the course of a narrow channel in the Great Lakes System. A 60-meter vessel is starting to cross the channel. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"If the smaller vessel is engaged in fishing, he shall not impede the passage of the other vessel.",opb:"The crossing vessel has the right of way.",opc:"The vessel in the channel must slow to her steerageway.",opd:"The larger vessel is considered to be a vessel restricted in her ability to maneuver.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about ships operating in ice is FALSE?",opa:"Light and partly loaded ships should be ballasted as deeply as possible.",opb:"In brash-filled channels, operating with a shallow draft forward is most effective.",opc:"Traditionally, operating ships light in the ice has been effective in the spring.",opd:"Good searchlights should be available in the event of night navigation with or without icebreaker escort.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel puts into the port of Kobe, Japan, to discharge cargo. The vessel contracts a local shipyard to have the hull chipped and scaled. If the vessel provides the primer and paint, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You need NOT declare the cost of labor, since no duty is involved.",opb:"You need NOT declare the cost of labor, since this is considered ship's personnel work.",opc:"You MUST declare the cost of labor and pay duty.",opd:"You MUST declare the cost of labor, but no duty is charged since labor is involved.",ans:"opc"},{question:"If you are guilty of failure to properly perform your duties as Master of Uninspected Towing Vessels, which of the following actions may NOT be taken?",opa:"Issuance of a letter of warning",opb:"Suspension of your license",opc:"Revocation of your license",opd:"A fine placed against your license",ans:"opd"},{question:"The vertical reference for all water levels and bench marks on the Great Lakes -St. Lawrence River System is known as ____________.",opa:"Mean Sea Level Datum",opb:"International Great Lakes Datum",opc:"Great Lakes Low Water Datum",opd:"North Central Reference Datum",ans:"opb"},{question:"When backing down with sternway, the pivot point of a vessel is ____________.",opa:"at the bow",opb:"about one-third of the vessel's length from the bow",opc:"aft of the propellers",opd:"about one-quarter of the vessel's length from the stern",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are signing on your crew. Which is NOT authorized?",opa:"A man presenting his Chief Mate's license to sign on as able seaman",opb:"An engineer presenting an MMD endorsed 'QMED -any rating' to sign on as an Electrician",opc:"A man presenting an MMD endorsed as 'Able Seaman' to sign on as Bosun",opd:"A man presenting an MMD endorsed 'Steward's Department (F.H.)' to sign on as Chief Cook",ans:"opa"},{question:"You must medevac a critically injured seaman by helicopter hoist. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The ship's relative wind should be from dead ahead at 10 to 30 knots.",opb:"The deck crew at the hoist point should not wear baseball hats.",opc:"The helicopter's drop line should be secured to the ship not more than 15 feet from the hoist position.",opd:"When using a 'horse collar', the bight of the loop should be around the chest of the injured seaman.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Fire and abandon ship stations and duties may be found on the ____________.",opa:"crewman's duty list",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"shipping articles",opd:"muster list",ans:"opd"},{question:"Nearly half of all storms that enter the Great Lakes Basin during the period from October through May come from ____________.",opa:"highs which originate in the east and east central USA",opb:"lows which originate in north central and western Canada",opc:"highs which originate in north eastern and eastern Canada",opd:"lows which originate in the central and western USA",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your containership has a container displaying a hazardous cargo placard. The placard has the number 2224 on it. This indicates that it is carrying what cargo?",opa:"Hexanol",opb:"Acrylic acid",opc:"Benzonitrile",opd:"Propadiene, inhibited",ans:"opc"},{question:"The part of the anchor indicated by the letter K is the ____________.",opa:"crown",opb:"ring",opc:"shank",opd:"bending shot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which item must be entered in the official log?",opa:"All engine orders",opb:"Drafts upon leaving port",opc:"Names of night mates and engineers",opd:"Number of cargo gangs on board",ans:"opb"},{question:"You receive a package, for shipment aboard your vessel, containing Class 1 explosives. The package is damp, moldy and stained. You must ____________.",opa:"refuse to accept the package",opb:"note the exception(s) on the Bill of Lading",opc:"replace the packaging material before stowage",opd:"seek the approval of the USCG Captain of the Port",ans:"opa"},{question:"Under normal weather and sea conditions when securing a stack of containers with non-locking fittings, lashings are required when the tier exceeds what height?",opa:"Lashings are always required",opb:"One container",opc:"Two containers",opd:"Three containers",ans:"opa"},{question:"A clause in the charter party requires a vessel's owner to pay dispatch money when the vessel ____________.",opa:"changes berths to expedite loading or discharging",opb:"does not load and discharge its cargo in the time specified",opc:"is not ready to load or discharge cargo",opd:"loads and discharges its cargo in less time than specified",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning insulating flanges?",opa:"They should be inspected and tested periodically to ensure that the insulation is clean and in good condition.",opb:"Switching off a cathodic protection system may be substituted for using an insulating flange",opc:"The measured resistance value after installation should be less than 1,000 ohms.",opd:"After the insulating flange is installed, hot work may be performed on deck.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A sheave is a ____________.",opa:"grooved wheel in a block",opb:"line to hold a lifeboat next to the embarkation deck",opc:"partial load of grain",opd:"seaman's knife",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are preparing to slush a stay on your vessel by lowering yourself down the stay in a bosun's chair. The proper way to do this is to ride down the stay on a riding shackle ____________.",opa:"with the pin of the shackle riding on the stay",opb:"with the pin of the shackle through the chair's bridle eye",opc:"with a hook attaching the chair to the riding shackle",opd:"connected to a second shackle on the chair",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who should be notified prior to starting up a crane?",opa:"The pumpman",opb:"The stevedore foreman",opc:"The engine room",opd:"All the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"A petroleum liquid has a flash point of 85\xb0F. This is a grade ____________.",opa:"B flammable liquid",opb:"C flammable liquid",opc:"D combustible liquid",opd:"E combustible liquid",ans:"opc"},{question:"A Permit to Proceed is issued by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"National Cargo Bureau",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"U.S. Department of Labor",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which space(s) is(are) exempt when measuring gross tonnage?",opa:"Auxiliary machinery spaces above the uppermost continuous deck",opb:"Steering gear room",opc:"Part of the wheelhouse used to control vessel",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The vertical motion of a floating vessel in which the entire hull is lifted by the force of the sea is known as ____________.",opa:"surge",opb:"sway",opc:"heave",opd:"pitch",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of link is generally used to connect shots of anchor chain?",opa:"Detachable",opb:"Open",opc:"Pear shaped",opd:"Stud link",ans:"opa"},{question:"The sheave diameter to be used with a 3-inch manila rope is ____________.",opa:"3 inches",opb:"6 inches",opc:"9 inches",opd:"12 inches",ans:"opb"},{question:"While the Pilot is maneuvering the vessel to a dock, what is the primary responsibility of the watch officer?",opa:"Judge the appropriateness of the Pilot's orders and countermand them if necessary",opb:"Insure that helm and throttle orders given by the Pilot are correctly executed",opc:"Record the bells and their times in the bell book",opd:"Supervise the signaling and flag etiquette",ans:"opb"},{question:"The term 'scantlings' refers to the ____________.",opa:"draft of a vessel",opb:"measurements of structural members",opc:"requirements for ship's gear",opd:"placement of a vessel's load line",ans:"opb"},{question:"Flame screens are used to ____________.",opa:"contain flammable fumes",opb:"protect firefighters from flames",opc:"prevent flames from entering tanks",opd:"keep flames and sparks from getting out of an engine's exhaust system",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which picture represents a barrel hitch?",opa:"O",opb:"U",opc:"E",opd:"P",ans:"opa"},{question:"In securing a towing cable, consideration must be given to letting go in an emergency. The possible whip of towlines when released can be overcome by ____________.",opa:"increasing the shaft RPM prior to release",opb:"using a pelican hook for quick release",opc:"using preventers",opd:"using a short chain for the lead through the stern chock",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to the IMO Code, what are the minimum number of securing points that should be on each side of a 'road vehicle', whose gross vehicle mass is between 3.5 Tons and 20 Tons, when carried on Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opb"},{question:"Usually the most gentle way of riding out a severe storm on a larger vessel is ____________.",opa:"head on at slow speeds",opb:"hove to",opc:"running before the seas",opd:"to rig a sea anchor",ans:"opc"},{question:"The type of joint formed when an edge of one plate is laid over the edge of the plate to which it is riveted is a ____________.",opa:"grip joint",opb:"strap joint",opc:"thread joint",opd:"lap joint",ans:"opd"},{question:"The size of wire rope is determined by the ____________.",opa:"number of strands",opb:"number of wires in each strand",opc:"circumference",opd:"diameter",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement, concerning offshore supply vessel operations, correctly defines the length of a voyage?",opa:"The distance from the point of departure to the vessel's first stop",opb:"The distance from the point of departure to the most distant point offshore",opc:"The total distance from the port of departure to the port of arrival, not including stops at offshore points",opd:"The shortest measurable distance from the port of departure to the port of arrival",ans:"opc"},{question:"When cutting wire rope, seizing's are put on each side of the cut. The seizing's prevent the wire from unlaying and also ____________.",opa:"maintain the original balance of the tension in the wires and strands",opb:"prevent moisture from entering between the wires at the cut end",opc:"forces lubricant from the core to protect the raw, cut end",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated ROUTINE will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"6 hours",opb:"3 hours",opc:"30 minutes",opd:"10 minutes or less",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning toluene?",opa:"Its Reid Vapor Pressure is 9.4.",opb:"The boiling point is 174\xb0F.",opc:"It is an aromatic hydrocarbon.",opd:"It is classified as a grade A flammable liquid.",ans:"opc"},{question:"During the manufacture of line, yarns are twisted together in the ____________.",opa:"opposite direction from which the fibers are twisted together to form strands",opb:"same direction the fibers are twisted to form strands",opc:"opposite direction from which the fibers are twisted together to form the line",opd:"opposite direction from which the fibers are twisted together forming cables",ans:"opa"},{question:"The responsibility for maintaining the Official Logbook on voyages between the Atlantic and Pacific coasts of the United States rests with the ____________.",opa:"Chief Mate of the vessel",opb:"Master of the vessel",opc:"Deck Officer of the watch at the time of the occurrence",opd:"Purser of the vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement(s) is/are TRUE concerning crane cargo operations?",opa:"Lifting points on all equipment need not be checked prior to commencing a lift.",opb:"Cargo loaded into vehicles and/or containers prior to lifting need not be secured.",opc:"Never exceed crane manufacturer\u2019s limits concerning the safe working loads of cargo jibs.",opd:"All the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the longitudinal strength members of a vessel are continuous and closely spaced, the vessel is ____________.",opa:"transversely framed",opb:"longitudinally framed",opc:"intermittently framed",opd:"web framed",ans:"opb"},{question:"Temporary seizing's on wire rope are made with ____________.",opa:"marline",opb:"sail twine",opc:"tape",opd:"wire",ans:"opd"},{question:"Ice concentration is measured in tenths. What concentration range of ice corresponds to 'Open Pack'?",opa:"< 1 tenth",opb:"1 -3 tenths",opc:"4 -6 tenths",opd:"7 -8 tenths",ans:"opc"},{question:"A copy of the Articles of Agreement, less the signatures, is required to be posted. This document is called the ____________.",opa:"Fo'c'sle Card",opb:"Articles Copy",opc:"Voyage Agreement",opd:"Shipping Articles",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are lifting a 3-ton weight with a single whip rove on a swinging boom set at an angle 20\xb0 to the horizontal. Use the formula for the size of a shackle with a safe working load and determine the minimum size shackle that should be used to secure the head block to the boom.",opa:"1 3/8 inch",opb:"1 1/2 inch",opc:"1 5/8 inch",opd:"1 3/4 inch",ans:"opa"},{question:"You will load class 1.2 commercial explosives and need to construct a portable magazine. The magazine MUST ____________.",opa:"be made of metal",opb:"be elevated with skids 10cm (3.9 inches) above the deck",opc:"have a hinged cover",opd:"be fastened with nails or screws",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are going to load bales of wool having a stowage factor of 110 in #3 lower hold which has a bale cubic of 72,000. If broken stowage is figured at 15%, how many tons of the wool can be stowed?",opa:"556",opb:"654",opc:"752",opd:"770",ans:"opa"},{question:"Galvanizing would be suitable for protecting wire rope which is used for ____________.",opa:"cargo runners",opb:"stays",opc:"topping lifts",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A disk with a horizontal line through its center, equivalent to the summer load line, is called the ____________.",opa:"deadrise mark",opb:"maximum allowable draft mark",opc:"Plimsoll mark",opd:"tonnage mark",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the purpose of the equalizing beam aboard a crane vessel?",opa:"It allows for rotation of the hook in the single mode.",opb:"It is required to 'twin-up' 30-ton pedestal cranes.",opc:"It is used to pick up light loads.",opd:"It is used to rigidly connect two cranes.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The marking on an anchor chain for 30 fathoms is ____________.",opa:"two links on each side of the 30 fathom detachable link are painted white",opb:"one link on each side of the 30 fathom detachable link is painted white",opc:"three links on each side of the 30 fathom detachable link are painted white",opd:"only the detachable link is painted red",ans:"opa"},{question:"The strongest of the natural fibers is ____________.",opa:"cotton",opb:"hemp",opc:"manila",opd:"sisal",ans:"opc"},{question:"A towing winch, that handles a wire towline, must have all of the following EXCEPT a ____________.",opa:"device that evenly spools and tightly winds the towline",opb:"brake with holding power appropriate for the vessel's horsepower or bollard pull",opc:"brake that can be operated when there is no power available to drive the winch",opd:"source of emergency power to operate the winch",ans:"opd"},{question:"What would be prima facie evidence of unseaworthiness?",opa:"Overloading",opb:"Overstowage",opc:"Overbooking",opd:"Overcarriage",ans:"opa"},{question:"In general, an un-reinforced vessel can safely navigate in ice provided the concentration does not exceed how many tenths?",opa:"9 -10 tenths",opb:"6 -8 tenths",opc:"4 -6 tenths",opd:"1 -3 tenths",ans:"opd"},{question:"The operator of an uninspected vessel MUST assist people affected by an accident if he or she can do so without ____________.",opa:"serious danger to his or her own vessel",opb:"further damaging the other vessel",opc:"harming persons onboard",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"On U.S. flag vessels, which certificate is always issued by the Coast Guard?",opa:"Load Line Certificate",opb:"Safety Equipment Certificate",opc:"Safety Construction Certificate",opd:"Register of cargo gear",ans:"opb"},{question:"A 'skiff hook' is a device used to ____________.",opa:"shorten the length of catenary in the towline",opb:"attach a towline to the eye bolt to the bow of a trailer-able boat",opc:"to create a temporary fairlead",opd:"join a towline to a pair of towing bridles",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is TRUE of pressure/vacuum valves?",opa:"They are designed to provide for the flow of small volumes of tank atmospheres caused by thermal variations in a cargo tank.",opb:"They should operate in advance of the pressure/vacuum breakers.",opc:"They should be kept in good working order by regular inspection and cleaning.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement(s) is/are TRUE concerning crane cargo operations?",opa:"Do not exceed rated load capacity of crane and container spreader or slings.",opb:"During any cargo handling operation, the safety of personnel is paramount.",opc:"Cargo handlers must be outfitted with adequate protection from personal injury.",opd:"All the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is on a voyage from Ogdensburg, NY, to Chicago, IL, via the Great Lakes. The date is October 3 of the current year. If your vessel is subject to the load line requirements, to which of her marks should she be loaded?",opa:"Fresh water -Winter",opb:"Salt water -Intermediate",opc:"Fresh water -Intermediate",opd:"Salt water -Winter",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which tensioning device is used with wire rope lashing to secure vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever.",opb:"Adjust-a-matic tensioner",opc:"Buckle tensioner",opd:"Ratchet tensioner",ans:"opb"},{question:"The upward slope of a vessels bottom from the keel to the bilge is called ____________.",opa:"camber",opb:"sheer",opc:"rake",opd:"rise of bottom",ans:"opd"},{question:"The knot used to form the bridle at the standing part of a gantline rigged to a stage is a ____________.",opa:"sheet bend",opb:"carrick bend",opc:"fisherman's bend",opd:"bowline",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement(s) is/are TRUE concerning crane cargo operations?",opa:"Lifting points on all equipment must be safely checked prior to commencing a lift.",opb:"Cargo loaded into vehicles and/or containers prior to lifting needs to be properly secured so as to prevent shifting during transport.",opc:"Never exceed crane manufacturer\u2019s limits concerning the safe working loads of cargo jibs.",opd:"All the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A new crewman reports on board. He must be trained in the use of the ship's lifesaving appliances within what time period?",opa:"2 months",opb:"1 month",opc:"2 weeks",opd:"Before sailing",ans:"opc"},{question:"Who publishes the 'Canadian List of Lights, Buoys and Fog Signals'?",opa:"The U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"The Canadian Coast Guard",opc:"The U.S. Hydrographic Service",opd:"The Canadian Hydrographic Service",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tow of 9 barges is made up three abreast by three long. The towboat is faced up to the last barge of the center string. The outer two strings of barges are the ____________.",opa:"port and starboard strings",opb:"outer strings",opc:"drag strings",opd:"side strings",ans:"opc"},{question:"When evacuating a seaman by helicopter lift, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Evacuation should be from an area forward of the bridge.",opb:"The vessel should be slowed to bare steerageway.",opc:"If the hoist is at the stern, booms extending aft at the stern should be cradled with the topping lifts hove taut.",opd:"The litter should not be touched until it has been grounded.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The grooved wheel inside a block is called a ____________.",opa:"cheek",opb:"gypsy",opc:"sheave",opd:"drum",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT a requirement for the safe and effective use of a crude oil washing system?",opa:"Strip all tanks and remove the bottom residue.",opb:"Use an inert gas system while washing tanks.",opc:"Use portable washing machines to reach areas obscured by structural members in the tanks.",opd:"Decant one meter from the source tank for the tank cleaning machines.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A person who sees someone fall overboard should ____________.",opa:"call for help and keep the individual in sight",opb:"run to the radio room to send an emergency message",opc:"immediately jump in the water to assist the individual",opd:"go to the bridge for the distress flares",ans:"opa"},{question:"If there is a discrepancy in the cargo totals, between the cargo onboard the vessel and the cargo listed in the cargo manifest, the more accurate account of cargo totals can be found in the ____________.",opa:"Notice of Readiness",opb:"Charter Party",opc:"Bill of Lading",opd:"Portage Bill",ans:"opc"},{question:"When towing astern, each towline must meet all of these requirements, EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"being suitable for use as soon as it is removed from its normal stowage location",opb:"having wire clips for other than a temporary repair",opc:"having the end either spliced with a thimble or fitted with a poured socket",opd:"being free of knots",ans:"opa"},{question:"What provides the majority of strength to an aluminum-sided container?",opa:"Corner fittings",opb:"Framework, primarily the corner posts",opc:"Framework and siding acting as a girder",opd:"Aluminum side and end panels",ans:"opb"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated PRIORITY will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"6 hours",opb:"3 hours",opc:"30 minutes",opd:"10 minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"When towing, the least amount of tension will be on each bridle leg when the two legs ____________.",opa:"form a large angle with each other",opb:"form a small angle with each other",opc:"are of unequal length",opd:"are joined by a fishplate",ans:"opb"},{question:"The structural member indicated by the letter I is the ____________.",opa:"garboard strake",opb:"center pillar",opc:"keel",opd:"girder",ans:"opc"},{question:"The normal and safest way for a sailor to be lowered in a bosun's chair when descending vertically is ____________.",opa:"for that sailor to feed the hauling part through a bosun's chair hitch",opb:"to lead the hauling part to a cleat on the mast and slacking the sailor down",opc:"by taking several turns of the gantline on a winch drum and then lower the sailor by backing off on the winch",opd:"by leading the bight of the hauling part to a rail and taking several turns, then slacking away with the bight",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement(s) is/are FALSE concerning crane cargo operations?",opa:"Lifting points on all equipment must be safely checked prior to commencing a lift.",opb:"Cargo loaded into vehicles and/or containers prior to lifting need not be secured.",opc:"Never exceed crane manufacturer\u2019s limits concerning the safe working loads of cargo jibs.",opd:"All the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A grapnel is a ____________.",opa:"device for securing a chain topping lift",opb:"hook to prevent the anchor cable from slipping",opc:"device used to drag for a submerged cable or line",opd:"type of clam bucket used for discharging bulk cargo",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Articles of Agreement ____________.",opa:"is also known as a Merchant Mariner's Document",opb:"designates the quarters a seaman will occupy during a voyage",opc:"advises the crew of the conditions of employment",opd:"are signed by each crewmember at the end of the voyage",ans:"opc"},{question:"In a Williamson turn, the rudder is put over full until the ____________.",opa:"vessel has turned 90\xb0From her original course",opb:"vessel has turned 60\xb0From her original course",opc:"vessel is on a reciprocal course",opd:"emergency turn signal sounds",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT a basic shiphandling rule for navigating in ice concentrations on the Great Lakes?",opa:"Keep moving -even very slowly, but keep moving.",opb:"Work with the ice movement, not against.",opc:"Transit ice along pressure ridges when possible.",opd:"Excessive speed means ice damage.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A cargo of oil has a coefficient of expansion of .0005 per degree F. If this cargo is loaded at 70\xb0F, and a cargo temperature of 90\xb0F is expected at the discharge port, how many barrels would you expect to unload if you loaded 10,000 barrels?",opa:"9900",opb:"9990",opc:"10010",opd:"10100",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following is/are the component(s) of a twin crane set as shown?",opa:"Boom assembly",opb:"Hook block assembly",opc:"Operator's cab",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Most crude oils are classified as grade ____________.",opa:"A or B",opb:"B",opc:"C or D",opd:"E",ans:"opc"},{question:"The hitch used to secure the standing part of a gantline to the horns of a stage is a ____________.",opa:"marlinespike hitch",opb:"clove hitch",opc:"blackwall hitch",opd:"Killick hitch",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on watch while your vessel is entering port with a pilot conning. The pilot gave a steering command to the helmsman who failed to acknowledge it by repeating the order. You have now enunciated the pilot's order to the helmsman and there is still no response. If the helmsman continues on the original course, you should immediately ____________.",opa:"take the helm and expedite the maneuver that the pilot ordered",opb:"ask the Pilot to repeat the command since the helmsman failed to hear it",opc:"tell the helmsman to ask the Pilot to repeat any command that he fails to hear or understand",opd:"repeat the Pilot's command a second time and notify the Master",ans:"opa"},{question:"Wire rope should be renewed when the ____________.",opa:"outer wires are rusted",opb:"outer wires are worn to half their original diameter",opc:"inner core appears dry",opd:"certification period expires",ans:"opb"},{question:"The turning circle of a vessel is the path followed by the ____________.",opa:"tipping center",opb:"bow",opc:"outermost part of the ship while making the circle",opd:"center of gravity",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of anchor is depicted?",opa:"Stock",opb:"Danforth",opc:"Patent",opd:"Old-fashioned",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning the tandem working arrangement of pedestal cranes when completing a quad lift?",opa:"The cranes require shoreside assistance to handle heavy cargos.",opb:"The cargo discharge cannot be accomplished without pendulation.",opc:"The cargo discharge cannot be performed at anchor.",opd:"The discharge is slow due to the size of the cargo and all the cranes working together.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A hygroscopic cargo is defined as a cargo ____________.",opa:"capable of absorbing moisture in the form of a gas",opb:"capable of giving off moisture in the form of a liquid",opc:"that is shipped in a liquid state",opd:"that will ignite in contact with water",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you intend to land tulip bulbs from Holland in a U.S. port, they must be inspected by the ____________.",opa:"Animal and Plant Health Service Inspector",opb:"Captain of the Port personnel",opc:"Quarantine Officer",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"During which condition should the operator of a pedestal crane shutdown operations?",opa:"Bunkering barge alongside",opb:"Potable water spill on deck",opc:"Crane hydraulic hose bursts",opd:"Trim greater than 4 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A Deratization Exemption Certificate is valid for a period of ____________.",opa:"no time limit so long as Certificate of Sanitation is valid",opb:"no time limit so long as no evidence of rodents aboard",opc:"1 year",opd:"6 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"Storms that enter the Great Lakes Basin from the west and northwest at a peak in October are the products of pressure systems known as ____________.",opa:"Northwesters",opb:"Alberta lows",opc:"Fata morgana",opd:"Polar highs",ans:"opb"},{question:"A small light tackle with blocks of steel or wood that is used for miscellaneous small jobs is called a ____________.",opa:"snatch block",opb:"threefold purchase",opc:"handy-billy",opd:"chockablock",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement concerning sweat damage in containers is TRUE?",opa:"Sweat damage in containers is unusual due to the small enclosed volume of air.",opb:"In general, containerized hygroscopic cargoes are the only ones subject to sweat damage.",opc:"Containers should be ventilated, dehumidified, or the contents physically protected against sweat damage.",opd:"Sweat damage is not a problem except in insulated and refrigerated containers.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The normal and safest way for a sailor in a bosun's chair to be raised aloft is ____________.",opa:"for the sailor to pull himself aloft and then make fast with a bosun's chair hitch",opb:"manually by two or three sailors heaving away on deck",opc:"by taking the gantline to a winch drum and heaving away with the winch",opd:"by fairleading the gantline with a snatch block and pulling with a cargo runner",ans:"opb"},{question:"The wooden planking that protects the tank top from cargo loading is called ____________.",opa:"ceiling",opb:"shores",opc:"frames",opd:"toms",ans:"opa"},{question:"A tug would NOT assist a ship to steer if the tug is made up to the large vessel ____________.",opa:"by a tow line ahead of the vessel",opb:"forward on either bow of the vessel",opc:"approximately amidships of the vessel",opd:"on the vessel's quarter",ans:"opc"},{question:"The time allowed for loading and discharging cargo in a charter party is referred to as ____________.",opa:"charter hire",opb:"demurrage",opc:"dispatch",opd:"lay days",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is NOT a part of an anchor?",opa:"Bill",opb:"Devil's claw",opc:"Palm",opd:"Crown",ans:"opb"},{question:"A twin-screw vessel is easier to maneuver than a single-screw vessel because the twin-screw vessel ____________.",opa:"permits the rudder to move faster",opb:"generates more power",opc:"can turn without using her rudder",opd:"can suck the water away from the rudder",ans:"opc"},{question:"While you are on watch entering port, the Master gives the helmsman a rudder command which conflicts with a rudder command from the Pilot. You should make sure the helmsman ____________.",opa:"brings the rudder to a point midway between the two conflicting positions",opb:"obeys the Pilot",opc:"asks you for instructions",opd:"obeys the Master",ans:"opd"},{question:"The group of markings shown is called a ____________.",opa:"loft mark",opb:"load line mark",opc:"test mark",opd:"water mark",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is used to prevent accidental flooding of a double bottom or peak tanks in the event of a pipe rupture due to collision?",opa:"Separate lines are provided for filling and pumping these tanks.",opb:"Pipe lines must run vertically from the tank to a point above the margin line before turning fore or aft towards the pump.",opc:"All tanks must be served by the fewest possible number of pipes to reduce the possibility of rupture.",opd:"Suction lines are fitted with a non-return valve",ans:"opd"},{question:"Yawing is angular motion of the vessel about what axis?",opa:"Longitudinal",opb:"Transverse",opc:"Vertical",opd:"Centerline",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's available bale cubic capacity is 625,000 and her available cargo capacity is 10,000 deadweight tons. Disregarding broken stowage, how many tons of pyrite (stowage factor -13) and how many tons of cork (s.f. -150) must be loaded to be full and down?",opa:"6387 tons pyrite,3613 tons cork",opb:"6721 tons pyrite,3279 tons cork",opc:"7500 tons pyrite,2500 tons cork",opd:"9133 tons pyrite, 867 tons cork",ans:"opa"},{question:"In which situation could a vessel most easily capsize?",opa:"Running into head seas",opb:"Running in the trough",opc:"Running with following seas",opd:"Anchored with your bow into the seas",ans:"opb"},{question:"The order of importance in addressing damage control is ____________.",opa:"control flooding, control fire, repair structural damage",opb:"restore vital services, control fire, control flooding",opc:"control fire, restore vital services, control flooding",opd:"control fire, control flooding, repair structural damage",ans:"opd"},{question:"The effect of ocean current is usually more evident on a tug and tow than on a tug navigating independently because the ____________.",opa:"speed of the tug and tow is less",opb:"towline catches the current",opc:"current causes yawing",opd:"current will offset the tow",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a drill required by regulations is not completed, the Master or person in charge must ____________.",opa:"report this immediately to the Commandant of the Coast Guard",opb:"log the reason for not completing the drill",opc:"conduct two of the required drills at the next opportunity",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The use of liners in riveted construction is eliminated by using ____________.",opa:"lapped construction",opb:"strapped construction",opc:"joggled construction",opd:"belted construction",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which term indicates the rise in height of the bottom plating from the plane of the base line?",opa:"Deadrise",opb:"Camber",opc:"Molded height",opd:"Sheer",ans:"opa"},{question:"During which condition should the operator of a pedestal crane shutdown operations?",opa:"Lightning in the vicinity",opb:"An approaching squall line",opc:"A fire on the pier",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which term describes a part of a natural fiber line?",opa:"Twines",opb:"Fibers",opc:"Lays",opd:"Lacings",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are in a tropical port. The refrigeration machinery on a container loaded with air-cooled fruit fails. It cannot be repaired for 18 to 24 hours. Which step should you take to reduce the temperature rise and spoilage of the fruit?",opa:"Discharge a cylinder of nitrogen into the container",opb:"Shade the container and periodically hose it down",opc:"Seal any ventilation openings and add dry ice",opd:"Spread ice over the top layer and in any voids within the container",ans:"opb"},{question:"A deck beam does NOT ____________.",opa:"act as a beam to support vertical deck loads",opb:"lessen the longitudinal stiffness of the vessel",opc:"act as a tie to keep the sides of the ship in place",opd:"act as a web to prevent plate wrinkling due to twisting action on the vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"What should look-outs report?",opa:"Discolored water",opb:"Shoals",opc:"Floating objects",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Owing to the greater girth of a ship amidships than at the ends, certain strakes are dropped as they approach the bow and stern to reduce the amount of plating at the ends. These strakes are called ____________.",opa:"drop strakes",opb:"stealers",opc:"throughs",opd:"voids",ans:"opa"},{question:"The designations A, B, C, D, and E grades of cargo refer to the ____________.",opa:"degrees of quality of petroleum products",opb:"flash point range and Reid vapor pressure index of petroleum products",opc:"grades of crude oil",opd:"pour point, color, and viscosity index of petroleum products",ans:"opb"},{question:"A hook that will release quickly is a ____________.",opa:"longshore hook",opb:"margin hook",opc:"marginal hook",opd:"pelican hook",ans:"opd"},{question:"Ice concentration is measured in tenths. What concentration range of ice corresponds to 'Close Pack'?",opa:"9 -10 tenths",opb:"7 -8 tenths",opc:"4 -6 tenths",opd:"1 -3 tenths",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are lifting a one-ton weight with a swinging boom. When comparing the stresses on the rig with the boom at 20\xb0 to the horizontal to the stresses when the boom is at 60\xb0 to the horizontal, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The angle of elevation does not change the stresses in the masthead fairlead for the topping lift.",opb:"The stress on the head block is greater at 60\xb0.",opc:"The stress on the heel block is greater at 60\xb0.",opd:"The thrust on the boom is greater at 20\xb0.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A towing hawser should be stowed ____________.",opa:"in a sealed locker with adequate air circulation",opb:"by spooling it on the winch",opc:"by faking on a rack",opd:"by hanging it in the engineroom",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 3?",opa:"1-2 purchase",opb:"Gun tackle",opc:"Single luff tackle",opd:"Double whip",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which knot is suitable for hoisting an unconscious person?",opa:"Bowline in a bight",opb:"French bowline",opc:"Fisherman's loop",opd:"Spider hitch",ans:"opb"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated IMMEDIATE will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"3 hours to start of business the following day",opb:"1 to 6 hours",opc:"30 minutes to 1 hour",opd:"10 minutes if possible",ans:"opc"},{question:"A design modification of an anchor chain which prevents kinking is the ____________.",opa:"detachable link",opb:"stud link",opc:"Kenter link",opd:"connecting link",ans:"opb"},{question:"A wire rope that has been overstrained will show ____________.",opa:"a bulge in the wire where the strain occurred",opb:"a decrease in diameter where the strain occurred",opc:"a kink in the wire where the strain occurred",opd:"no visible effects of an overstrain",ans:"opb"},{question:"There is a large shipment of case goods available to be loaded on your vessel. You are to load as many tons as possible in a hold which has 32,300 cubic feet left unfilled by cargo. Each case measures 2-feet high by 2-feet wide by 4-feet long and weighs 500 pounds. If you allow a broken stowage allowance of 10% of the 32,300 feet, what is the nearest whole number of tons which may be loaded?",opa:"324 tons",opb:"360 tons",opc:"363 tons",opd:"406 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel is involved in a casualty. The cost of property damage includes the ____________.",opa:"damage claims awarded to individuals or companies involved in the casualty, up to a maximum of$50,000",opb:"loss of revenue while the vessel is being repaired, up to a maximum of $50,000",opc:"cost of labor and material to restore the vessel to the service condition which existed before the casualty",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The label required on containers carrying barium oxide in an international shipment must read ____________.",opa:"'Poison'",opb:"'Spontaneously Combustible'",opc:"'Radioactive'",opd:"'Infectious Substance'",ans:"opa"},{question:"The fo'c'sle card ____________.",opa:"is posted in the crews quarters and lists the emergency stations",opb:"advises the crew of the conditions of employment",opc:"is also known as a Merchant Mariner's Document",opd:"designates the quarters a seaman will occupy during a voyage",ans:"opb"},{question:"When clearing a vessel for a foreign voyage, the original crew list is duly certified by proper authority. In a U.S. port, this authority is the U.S. ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard",opb:"Customs",opc:"Immigration Service",opd:"Public Health Service",ans:"opb"},{question:"When towing, what is the main reason for using a chain bridle on a wire hawser?",opa:"It makes for an easy connection.",opb:"It gives a spring effect to cushion the shock.",opc:"It eliminates the necessity of a swivel.",opd:"It does not chafe.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A chain bridle is preferable to a wire rope towing bridle on a long ocean tow because chain ____________.",opa:"is more flexible and has the ability to absorb shock because of its weight",opb:"is less subject to wear and damage from abrasion",opc:"requires little maintenance",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"During which condition should the operator of a pedestal crane shutdown operations?",opa:"Bunkering",opb:"High winds",opc:"Potable water spill on deck",opd:"More than 3\xb0 list",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Safety Equipment Certificate shows that the vessel conforms to the standards of the ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"American Salvage Association",opd:"S.O.L.A.S. Convention",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which log includes a statement of the conduct, ability, and character of each crew member on the completion of a voyage?",opa:"Official Logbook",opb:"Department Logbook",opc:"Crew Logbook",opd:"Smooth Logbook",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a vessel is entering or leaving a port, a record of engine speeds is kept in the ____________.",opa:"bell book",opb:"deck rough log",opc:"Official Logbook",opd:"engine rough log",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is NOT true concerning the stowage of class 1 explosives?",opa:"Class 1.1 explosives may be stowed with class 9 dangerous substances",opb:"Class 1.4 explosives must be 'separated from' a stow of class5.1 oxidizing materials.",opc:"Class 1.4 explosives may not be stowed in the same hold with class 6.1 poisons.",opd:"Class 1.4 explosives must be 'separated from' a stow of class 8 corrosive materials.",ans:"opc"},{question:"'Herringbone' is a term associated with ____________.",opa:"anchoring",opb:"mooring",opc:"sewing",opd:"splicing",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which tensioning device is used with chain to secure heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Ratchet tensioner",opb:"Buckle tensioner",opc:"Adjust-a-matic tensioner",opd:"Turnbuckle",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which effects listed below does NOT influence stability of a towing vessel?",opa:"Free surface",opb:"Load heights",opc:"Towline length",opd:"Ice",ans:"opc"},{question:"What term indicates the immersed body of the vessel forward of the parallel mid-body?",opa:"Run",opb:"Flare",opc:"Entrance",opd:"Sheer",ans:"opc"},{question:"Cargo pump relief valves are piped to the ____________.",opa:"cargo pump pressure gauges",opb:"crossover lines interconnecting two pumps",opc:"suction side of pumps",opd:"atmosphere through pump vents",ans:"opc"},{question:"The last shot of an anchor cable is usually painted ____________.",opa:"white",opb:"international orange",opc:"yellow",opd:"red",ans:"opd"},{question:"The larger sizes of manila line are measured by their ____________.",opa:"radius",opb:"diameter",opc:"circumference",opd:"weight per foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE with regards to the Great Lakes Light List?",opa:"The Light List does not contain information on any of the navigational aids maintained by Canada.",opb:"Volume VII does not include information on Class III private aids to navigation.",opc:"The Light List does not include Coast Guard mooring buoys, special purpose buoys, or buoys marking fish net areas.",opd:"The Light List should be corrected each week from the appropriate Notice to Mariners.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The key to rescuing a man overboard is ____________.",opa:"good equipment",opb:"a dedicated crew",opc:"well-conducted drills",opd:"good communication",ans:"opc"},{question:"The rope which is rove from the truck to be used with a bos'n's chair is called a ____________.",opa:"gantline",opb:"life line",opc:"strop",opd:"whip",ans:"opa"},{question:"The period of roll is the time difference between ____________.",opa:"zero inclination to full inclination on one side",opb:"full inclination on one side to full inclination on the other side",opc:"full inclination on one side to the next full inclination on the same side",opd:"zero inclination to the next zero inclination",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is in Charleston, S.C. You need not clear Customs if ____________.",opa:"all the cargo on board is of U.S. origin and destined for New York",opb:"you took on no new cargo in Charleston, S.C.. and are bound for Puerto Rico and thence foreign",opc:"you did not discharge any cargo in Charleston and are bound for Panama",opd:"you did not load any cargo in Charleston and are bound for Halifax",ans:"opa"},{question:"A piece of small stuff (small line) secured to an object to prevent it from going adrift is a ____________.",opa:"lanyard",opb:"keeper",opc:"noose",opd:"stopper",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement concerning the lashings of containers with solid bar or wire rope lashings is TRUE?",opa:"Stack weights should be less when using a solid bar lashing as compared to a wire lashing.",opb:"Stack heights may be increased when using a solid bar lashing.",opc:"Stack heights should be reduced when using a solid bar lashing.",opd:"Solid bars should be used for lashing the first tier only, with wire lashings on the higher tier(s).",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a light tow, what could you substitute for a fishplate?",opa:"heart-shaped shackle",opb:"pelican hook",opc:"swivel",opd:"ring",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are planning to use a crude oil washing system. What precaution must be taken with the source tank for the washing machines?",opa:"At least one meter must be decanted from the source tank.",opb:"The oil in the source tank must be sampled for compatibility.",opc:"The source tank must have been crude oil washed at least once in the past 150 days.",opd:"The inert gas system must lower the oxygen content in the source tank to a maximum of 12%.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A combustible liquid with a flash point of 90\xb0F would be grade ____________.",opa:"B",opb:"C",opc:"D",opd:"E",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE with respect to the load line markings shown.",opa:"A vessel displaying these marks may load in the salt waters of the St. Lawrence River.",opb:"Vessels engaged solely on Great Lakes voyages are not required to show these marks.",opc:"U.S. flag vessels less than 100 feet in length and less than 200 gross tons are not required to show these marks.",opd:"U.S. flag vessels of 100 gross tons and upward must show these marks.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the meaning of the term tare weight?",opa:"Pounds of force necessary to damage a container",opb:"Total weight of a container and contents",opc:"Weight of a container",opd:"Weight of the contents of a container",ans:"opc"},{question:"Sluicing or slushing wire rope ____________.",opa:"prevents internal and external rust and corrosion",opb:"reduces chafing and increases its useful service life",opc:"reduces internal friction within the wire",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to 33 CFR, on board which type of vessel described below is required to maintain Part II (Cargo/Ballast Operations) of the Oil Record Book?",opa:"A ship of 150 gross tons and above, other than an oil tanker.",opb:"A non-tanker that carries more than 200 cubic meters of oil in bulk.",opc:"Any oil tanker of 100 gross tons and above.",opd:"An oil tanker of 150 gross tons and above on domestic voyages only.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are taking the bow line from the port bow of a large vessel that is underway when the stern of your tug comes in contact with the vessel. The forward motion of both vessels causes your tug to be turned toward the other vessel and contact the stem thereby being 'stemmed'. You should immediately ____________.",opa:"stop engines and the vessel's wake will push you clear of the bow",opb:"go full astern with rudder amidships",opc:"go full ahead with the rudder hard over to starboard",opd:"go full ahead with the rudder amidships",ans:"opb"},{question:"If the winch should fail while you are hauling in the anchor, what prevents the anchor cable from running out?",opa:"Chain stopper",opb:"Devil's claw",opc:"Hawse ratchet",opd:"Riding pawl",ans:"opd"},{question:"The number of able seamen required on board is stated in the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping code",opb:"Solas Certificate",opc:"Classification Certificate",opd:"Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"The letter I indicates the keel. Which of the following plates is NOT part of the keel?",opa:"Center vertical keel",opb:"Rider plate",opc:"Longitudinal girder",opd:"Flat plate keel",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are doing a Williamson turn. Your vessel has swung about 60\xb0 from the original course heading. You should ____________.",opa:"put the rudder amidships and check the swing",opb:"stop the engines and prepare to maneuver to pick up the man in the water",opc:"shift your rudder",opd:"increase to maximum speed",ans:"opc"},{question:"The turning circle of a vessel making a turn over 360 degrees is the path followed by the ____________.",opa:"center of gravity",opb:"bow",opc:"bridge",opd:"centerline",ans:"opa"},{question:"A stage should only be rigged ____________.",opa:"over the bow or stern of a vessel",opb:"over the flat sides of a vessel",opc:"over the open water",opd:"over the dockside",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel loads 5000 tons of manganese ore. The railroad cars that brought the ore to the vessel were previously loaded with iron ore so the ore is contaminated. The agent requests the Master to sign a Clean Bill of Lading and in return the shipper will give him a Letter of Indemnity. What is the best procedure to follow?",opa:"Sign a Clean Bill of Lading and accept the Letter of Indemnity.",opb:"Refuse to sign a Clean Bill of Lading.",opc:"Sign the Clean Bill of Lading and have the agent countersign it.",opd:"Sign a Clean Bill of lading under protest.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which type of anchor is illustrated?",opa:"Stockless",opb:"Danforth",opc:"Old-fashioned",opd:"Kedge",ans:"opa"},{question:"When towing another vessel, the length of the towing line should be ____________.",opa:"as long as possible",opb:"as short as possible under the circumstances and not over two wave lengths",opc:"such that one vessel will be on a crest while the other is in a trough",opd:"such that the vessels will be in step",ans:"opd"},{question:"When towing astern what equipment should be stowed ready for use near the towline?",opa:"First aid kit",opb:"Axe or cutting torch",opc:"Fire extinguisher",opd:"Chafing gear",ans:"opb"},{question:"The upward slope of a ships bottom from the keel to the bilge is known as ____________.",opa:"camber",opb:"slope",opc:"deadrise",opd:"keel height",ans:"opc"},{question:"A block and tackle is 'rove to advantage'. This means that the ____________.",opa:"blocks have been overhauled",opb:"hauling parts of two tackles are attached",opc:"hauling part leads through the movable block",opd:"hauling part leads through the standing block",ans:"opc"},{question:"Shell plating is ____________.",opa:"the galvanizing on steel",opb:"a hatch cover",opc:"the outer plating of a vessel",opd:"synonymous with decking",ans:"opc"},{question:"To lead the towing hawser over the center of the stern when not under a strain you could ____________.",opa:"fairlead it through a stern roller chock",opb:"lead it through the Norman pins",opc:"hold it in the median position by a gob rope",opd:"All of the above when so equipped",ans:"opd"},{question:"A cargo of fuel oil is loaded whose temperature is 66\xb0F. API gravity is 36\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. A cargo temperature of 80\xb0F is expected at the discharge port. If 9,000 barrels were loaded, how many barrels would you expect to unload?",opa:"8910",opb:"8937",opc:"9063",opd:"9090",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a vessel proceeding from a very cold to a warm climate with a cargo of a nonhygroscopic nature in the holds, which is TRUE?",opa:"Danger of heavy ship sweat exists; constant and vigorous ventilation is required.",opb:"There is danger of heavy cargo sweat if outside air is introduced by ventilation.",opc:"There is little danger of ship's sweat, slight possibility of cargo sweat; moderate ventilation is needed.",opd:"The possibility of any sweat problem, either cargo or ship, is remote.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The agency most concerned with a stowaway is ____________.",opa:"Customs",opb:"Immigration",opc:"Public Health",opd:"U.S.D.A.",ans:"opb"},{question:"On an anchor windlass, the wheel over which the anchor chain passes is called a ____________.",opa:"brake compressor wheel",opb:"devil's claw",opc:"wildcat",opd:"winchhead",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is true concerning repairs on the hull of a vessel which is to be riveted and welded?",opa:"Riveting must be completed before welding begins.",opb:"Riveting and welding should be done alternately.",opc:"Welding must be completed before the riveting begins.",opd:"It does not matter in what order the operations are done.",ans:"opc"},{question:"All U.S. Flag vessels engaged in foreign trade are required to have a(n) ____________.",opa:"enrollment",opb:"license",opc:"registry",opd:"sea letter",ans:"opc"},{question:"Why are most break bulk vessels built with the transverse framing system rather than the longitudinal system?",opa:"The transverse system is more resistant to hog and sag stresses.",opb:"The numerous longitudinal frames cause excessive broken stowage.",opc:"The transverse system provides better support to the varying cargo densities on a break bulk vessel.",opd:"The deep web frames interfere with the stowage of break bulk cargo.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The charterer has completed loading the vessel in 3 days instead of the 5 days agreed to in the charter party. As a result of this, the ____________.",opa:"ship-owner may charge for two lay days",opb:"charterer may receive dispatch money",opc:"stevedore may collect demurrage",opd:"consignee may be required to pay a ceaser fee",ans:"opb"},{question:"A high cube container would most likely be used to stow ____________.",opa:"dense bulk cargoes",opb:"household appliances",opc:"fragile cargoes",opd:"heavy industrial machinery",ans:"opb"},{question:"Instructions to the crew in the use of all the ship's lifesaving equipment shall be completed ____________.",opa:"before sailing",opb:"within one week of sailing",opc:"in one month and repeated quarterly",opd:"within any two month period",ans:"opd"},{question:"On the Great Lakes, winter storms compound the ice threat by bringing a variety of wind, wave, and weather problems on an average of every ____________.",opa:"two days",opb:"three days",opc:"four days",opd:"five days",ans:"opc"},{question:"Deckhands onboard towing vessels shall be divided into 3 watches when the trip exceeds ____________.",opa:"1000 miles",opb:"800 miles",opc:"700 miles",opd:"600 miles",ans:"opd"},{question:"During which condition should the operator of a pedestal crane shutdown operations?",opa:"Lightning",opb:"High winds",opc:"Fire aboard",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is broken down and rolling in heavy seas. You can reduce the danger of capsizing by ____________.",opa:"constantly shifting the rudder",opb:"moving all passengers to one side of the boat",opc:"rigging a sea anchor",opd:"moving all passengers to the stern",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT an indication that pack ice may be nearby?",opa:"The presence of icebergs",opb:"Ice blink",opc:"Absence of wave motion",opd:"Sighting a walrus in the Arctic",ans:"opa"},{question:"When making up a tow connection, you should use ____________.",opa:"safety hooks",opb:"plain eye hooks",opc:"round pin shackles",opd:"screw pin shackles",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a line is spirally coiled about its end and lying flat on deck, it is said to be ____________.",opa:"coiled",opb:"faked",opc:"flemished",opd:"seized",ans:"opc"},{question:"When towing astern, you notice that another vessel is about to pass between the towing vessel and the tow. You should immediately ____________.",opa:"turn away from the approaching vessel",opb:"shine a spotlight in the direction of the approaching vessel",opc:"sever the towline",opd:"slow down and pay out the main tow hawser",ans:"opd"},{question:"Mousing a cargo hook with marline or small line ____________.",opa:"increases the lifting capacity of the hook",opb:"protects the hook from the sling ring",opc:"prevents the sling ring from coming out of the hook",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is a characteristic of all centrifugal cargo pumps?",opa:"They are self-priming.",opb:"Decreasing the speed of rotation will decrease the discharge pressure.",opc:"Opening the discharge valve wider will increase the discharge pressure.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated PRIORITY will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"6 hours",opb:"30 minutes",opc:"3 hours",opd:"10 minutes",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a tug makes up to a large vessel, the spring line should lead from the forward most part of the tug so that ____________.",opa:"friction on the spring line is minimized",opb:"the length of the spring line is minimized",opc:"the head line and spring line can be worked simultaneously",opd:"the tug can pivot freely",ans:"opd"},{question:"The BEST way to steer a twin-screw vessel if you lose your rudder is by using ____________.",opa:"one engine and a steering oar",opb:"both engines at the same speed",opc:"one engine at a time",opd:"one engine running at reduced speed and controlling the vessel with the other",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the name of the mark indicated by the letter A?",opa:"Winter North Atlantic load line",opb:"Fresh Water load line",opc:"Deck line",opd:"Plimsoll line",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statements concerning the rigging of bosn's' chairs and their use is TRUE?",opa:"Always secure the gantline to the chair with a bowline.",opb:"Always have the chair hoisted with at least three turns on a winch drum.",opc:"Any tools, paint pots etc. should be secured by lanyards.",opd:"When riding a stay, make sure that the bow of the shackle passes through the becket of the bridle.",ans:"opc"},{question:"When natural fiber rope gets wet, the ____________.",opa:"overall strength of the line will decrease",opb:"line shrinks in length",opc:"line will become more elastic",opd:"line will be easier to handle",ans:"opb"},{question:"A towing hawser is readied for service by ____________.",opa:"spooling it on a winch cathead",opb:"coiling it in a counterclockwise direction on the fantail",opc:"faking it on deck in a fore and aft direction",opd:"spooling it on a reel lying on its side to prevent rolling",ans:"opc"},{question:"The turning circle of a vessel making a turn of over 360 degrees is the path followed by the ____________.",opa:"bow",opb:"bridge",opc:"center of gravity",opd:"centerline",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lower hold of your vessel has a bale cubic of 52,000 cu. ft. You will load a cargo of cases, each weighing 380 lbs. and measuring 3 ft. x 2 ft. x 2 ft. The estimated broken stowage is 15%. How many tons of cases can be loaded?",opa:"137 tons",opb:"161 tons",opc:"625 tons",opd:"969 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a manned vessel carrying packaged hazardous cargo, the hazardous materials shall be inspected ____________.",opa:"every 24 hours unless equipped with a fire detecting system",opb:"prior to entry into a U.S.. port",opc:"after stowage is complete",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Unless extremely flexible wire rope is used, the sheave diameter should always be as large as possible, but should never be less than ____________.",opa:"20 times the rope diameter",opb:"10 times the rope diameter",opc:"2 times the rope diameter",opd:"the rope diameter",ans:"opa"},{question:"A stream of water immediately surrounding a moving vessel's hull, flowing in the same direction as the vessel is known as ____________.",opa:"directional current",opb:"forward current",opc:"propeller current",opd:"wake current",ans:"opd"},{question:"In the manufacture of wire rope, if the wires are shaped to conform to the curvature of the finished rope before they are laid up, the rope is called ____________.",opa:"composite",opb:"left-lay",opc:"improved",opd:"preformed",ans:"opd"},{question:"As a rule, ships of most configurations, when drifting in calm water with negligible current, will lie ____________.",opa:"bow to the wind",opb:"beam to the wind",opc:"stern to the wind",opd:"with the wind on the quarter",ans:"opb"},{question:"A declaration made by the Master before a U.S. Consul, giving particulars regarding heavy weather or other incidents which may have caused damage to the vessel or cargo, through no fault of the vessel, her officers, or crew is a(n) ____________.",opa:"cargo addendum",opb:"exception report",opc:"Master's declaration",opd:"note of protest",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about the fo'c'sle card is TRUE?",opa:"The fo'c'sle card is a blank sample of the articles.",opb:"It contains copies of the crew's signatures from the articles.",opc:"Is an exact copy of shipping articles.",opd:"Each crewmember is given a copy of the fo'c'sle card.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which is supplied to the vessel by the U.S. Coast Guard?",opa:"Bell book",opb:"Cargo gear register",opc:"Official Logbook",opd:"Rough Logbook",ans:"opc"},{question:"Due to the nature of a vessel's construction for a particular trade, it does not fully comply with the provisions of SOLAS. Where will this be indicated?",opa:"On the Exemption Certificate",opb:"On the reverse of the particular SOLAS certificate affected",opc:"On the face of the Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Nowhere; the vessel must comply to engage in international trade.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are conducting trials to determine the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel. While making a turn, you take ranges and bearings of an isolated light with the results as shown. Based on this information, what is the advance for a turn of 75\xb0?",opa:"825 yards (754 meters)",opb:"860 yards (774 meters)",opc:"910 yards (819 meters)",opd:"955 yards (860 meters)",ans:"opa"},{question:"You need to make a fixed loop at the end of a line in order to use the line as a mooring line. You have insufficient time to make a splice. Which knot should you use?",opa:"Clove Hitch",opb:"Fisherman's Bend",opc:"Bowline",opd:"Round-turn and two half hitches",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statements is TRUE regarding lashing requirements to secure vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"The securing of cargo on flats and trailers must be adequate to withstand road motions only.",opb:"The movements experienced by road borne cargo are the same as the movements of a ship at sea.",opc:"The generally recommended lash angle is no greater than 45 degrees relative to the deck in any direction.",opd:"It is not necessary for an adequate number of securing points on the vehicles themselves since setting the brakes is sufficient.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A relief valve for a cargo pump is generally installed ____________.",opa:"after the discharge valve",opb:"between the pump and discharge valve",opc:"after the suction valve",opd:"between the pump and suction valve",ans:"opb"},{question:"The key to rescuing a man overboard is ____________.",opa:"good communication",opb:"a dedicated crew",opc:"good equipment",opd:"well-conducted drills",ans:"opd"},{question:"The pillar shape that gives the greatest strength for the least weight is the ____________.",opa:"octagonal pillar",opb:"'H' Beam pillar",opc:"'I' Beam pillar",opd:"circular type pillar",ans:"opd"},{question:"A package contains nitric acid solution and is radioactive. The radiation level at the package surface is .36 millirems per hour. How should this package be labeled?",opa:"Radioactive II and oxidizer",opb:"Radioactive II and poison",opc:"Radioactive I and corrosive",opd:"Fissile class I",ans:"opc"},{question:"The two factors which make underwater hull repair difficult are accessibility and the ____________.",opa:"availability of tools",opb:"shape of the hull",opc:"pressure exerted by the water",opd:"threat of progressive flooding",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are lifting a one-ton weight with a swinging boom. When comparing the stresses on the rig with the boom at 20\xb0 to the horizontal to the stresses when the boom is at 60\xb0 to the horizontal, which statement is true?",opa:"The thrust on the boom is greater at 20\xb0.",opb:"The stress on the topping lift is greater at 60\xb0.",opc:"The stress on the heel block is less at 60\xb0.",opd:"The change in angle of elevation has no effect on the stresses in the head block.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Fracture damage to the end links of the anchor cable, or to the Jews' harp may be eliminated by ____________.",opa:"using a small diameter connecting shackle",opb:"ensuring the swivel is well lubricated and free to turn",opc:"installing the connecting shackle with the bow towards the anchor",opd:"securing a piece of wood to the Jews' harp",ans:"opd"}],this.data3=[{question:"A set of interior steps on a ship leading up to a deck from below is know as ____________.",opa:"a companion way",opb:"tween-decks",opc:"stairs",opd:"All of the above are acceptable",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are loading a cargo of canned goods with a stowage factor of 65. If you allow 15% for broken stowage, how many tons can be loaded in a space of 55,000 cubic feet?",opa:"687",opb:"719",opc:"846",opd:"973",ans:"opb"},{question:"The point that is halfway between the forward and after perpendicular and is a reference point for vessel construction is the ____________.",opa:"half length",opb:"mid-body",opc:"center line",opd:"amidships",ans:"opd"},{question:"A VLCC (100,000 DWT+) with a 30,000 Shaft Horsepower Steam Turbine is slow to respond to engine movements and has less stopping power than normal ships because it has a ____________.",opa:"bigger propeller",opb:"smaller power to weight ratio",opc:"smaller propeller",opd:"larger power to weight ratio",ans:"opb"},{question:"U.S. Customs, upon boarding a vessel desiring entry into a U.S. port, would inspect which document?",opa:"Cargo Manifest",opb:"Certified Crew List",opc:"Stores List",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which knot should be used to secure a line to a spar when the pull is perpendicular to the spar?",opa:"E",opb:"F",opc:"N",opd:"P",ans:"opb"},{question:"'Seiche' is defined as a(n) ____________.",opa:"unusually strong storm system which approaches the Great Lakes System generally from the Northeast",opb:"lake current which is predominant during the spring and fall navigation season on the Great Lakes",opc:"oscillation caused by the diminishing of forces which cause lake level fluctuations",opd:"higher than normal high water or lower than normal low water",ans:"opc"},{question:"The greatest horizontal stress between the heads of the booms in the yard and stay rig occurs when the load is in such a position that the ____________.",opa:"falls are at an equal angle to the horizontal",opb:"stay fall is vertical",opc:"stay fall is at a greater angle to the horizontal than the yard fall",opd:"yard fall is at a greater angle to the horizontal than the stay fall",ans:"opa"},{question:"What does 'level-luffing' accomplish during crane operations?",opa:"It prevents the load from swinging when the boom level is adjusted.",opb:"Less power is needed when topping the boom with a load on the hook.",opc:"It maintains the height of the load above the deck.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"After a seaman is discharged, at the end of the voyage, the final payment of wages due must be made, whichever is earliest, either within 24 hours after the cargo has been discharged, or ____________.",opa:"within 4 days after the seaman's discharge",opb:"prior to the vessel's departure on the next voyage",opc:"prior to loading any out-bound cargo",opd:"prior to any change of Master",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which is part of the ground tackle?",opa:"Charlie noble",opb:"Devil's claw",opc:"Gooseneck",opd:"Rat's tail",ans:"opb"},{question:"The effect known as 'bank cushion' acts in which of the following ways on a single-screw vessel proceeding along a narrow channel?",opa:"It forces the bow away from the bank.",opb:"It forces the stern away from the bank.",opc:"It forces the entire vessel away from the bank.",opd:"It heels the vessel toward the bank.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are planning to use the crude oil washing system on your tankship. What is required to prevent electrostatic buildup in the tanks?",opa:"The portable machines must be set at the proper drop for the first wash before the fixed machines are used.",opb:"The source tank for the tank cleaning machines must have least one meter decanted from it.",opc:"The inert gas system must reduce the oxygen content in the tanks to a maximum of 18%.",opd:"The fixed machines must be operated simultaneously with the portable machines to equalize the electrostatic potential.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A flammable liquid having a Reid vapor pressure of 8\xbd P.S.I.A. or less and a flash point of 80\xb0F or below is grade ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opc"},{question:"What does the line labeled 'MS' denote on the Great Lakes load line model shown?",opa:"Mean sea level",opb:"Midseason",opc:"Maximum submergence",opd:"Midsummer",ans:"opd"},{question:"A wildcat is a ____________.",opa:"deeply-grooved drum on the windlass with sprockets which engage the links of the anchor chain",opb:"winch that is running out of control due to a failure of the overspeed trips",opc:"line that has jumped off the gypsyhead while under strain",opd:"nylon line that parts under strain and whips back in a hazardous manner",ans:"opa"},{question:"The official number of a documented vessel is ____________.",opa:"not required to be marked anywhere on the vessel",opb:"required to be permanently marked on the vessel's structure",opc:"required to be painted on the vessel's stern",opd:"required to be painted on the vessel's bow",ans:"opb"},{question:"A lot of special cargo of similar cartons, as shown, is to be loaded. What is the weight of the consignment?",opa:"50 pounds",opb:"1100 pounds",opc:"1200 pounds",opd:"1250 pounds",ans:"opd"},{question:"If kinking results while wire rope is being coiled clockwise, you should ____________.",opa:"coil it counterclockwise",opb:"not coil it",opc:"take a turn under",opd:"twist out the kinks under a strain",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which is NOT a potential hazard of approaching close to an iceberg?",opa:"The brash ice in the vicinity may clog sea intakes.",opb:"The berg may calve with the bergy bit hitting the vessel.",opc:"There may be underwater rams extending out from the berg.",opd:"The berg may suddenly tilt or capsize due to uneven melting and hit the vessel.",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a passenger vessel over 400 gross tons, routine entries for the Oil Record Book are recorded in ____________.",opa:"Oil Record Book is not required",opb:"Part I (Machinery Space Operations)",opc:"Part II (Cargo Oil/Ballast Operations)",opd:"Part III (Emergency Discharge/Spillage)",ans:"opb"},{question:"A cargo of fuel oil is loaded whose temperature is 66\xb0F. API gravity is 36\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. A cargo temperature of 80\xb0F is expected at the discharge port. If 9,000 barrels were loaded, how many gallons would you expect to unload?",opa:"375354",opb:"380646",opc:"491535",opd:"498465",ans:"opb"},{question:"What does 'in step' refer to in regards to towing?",opa:"The towed vessel follows exactly in the wake of the towing vessel.",opb:"There is no catenary in the towing hawser.",opc:"When turning, both the towed and towing vessels turn at the same time.",opd:"Both the towed and towing vessels reach a wave crest or trough at the same time.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The strictest load line regulations apply to ____________.",opa:"gas carriers",opb:"freighters (break-bulk)",opc:"passenger ships",opd:"tankers",ans:"opc"},{question:"A common class of wire rope is the 6X37 class. What does the 37 represent?",opa:"Number of wires in the inner core",opb:"Number of strands per wire rope",opc:"Tensile strength of the wire",opd:"Number of wires per strand",ans:"opd"},{question:"A chock ____________.",opa:"is a deck fitting used to shackle gear to the deck",opb:"permits easy jettisoning of deck cargo in an emergency",opc:"prevents stress concentration in the bulwark",opd:"provides openings through the bulwark for mooring lines",ans:"opd"},{question:"With the buttress securing system, containers of different heights must be stowed ____________.",opa:"on the bottom tier on deck",opb:"in the hold",opc:"next to the buttress tower",opd:"on the top tier",ans:"opd"},{question:"It is the responsibility of the crane operator to, at all times, be aware of the location of the ____________.",opa:"load",opb:"hook",opc:"boom",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about the Williamson turn is FALSE?",opa:"It requires the highest degree of shiphandling skills to accomplish.",opb:"It is the slowest of the methods used in turning the vessel.",opc:"It is the best turn to use when the victim is not in sight due to reduced visibility.",opd:"It returns the vessel to the original track-line on a reciprocal course.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The term used in levying customs duties when such are fixed at rates proportioned to estimated value of goods concerned is ____________.",opa:"ad valorem",opb:"infinite",opc:"secure",opd:"specific",ans:"opa"},{question:"A high cube container is designed specifically to ____________.",opa:"carry low density cargoes",opb:"protect fragile cargoes",opc:"stow cargoes with concentrated weights such as machinery",opd:"carry cargoes of very low stowage factors",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which is normally used to hold wire rope for splicing?",opa:"Come along",opb:"Jigger",opc:"Rigger's screw",opd:"Sealing clamp",ans:"opc"},{question:"Under the Carriage of Goods by Sea Act of 1936, a vessel will be liable for damage to cargo when the damage arises out of ____________.",opa:"poor stowage of cargo in a container",opb:"fire caused by lightning",opc:"overloading",opd:"inherent vice",ans:"opc"},{question:"Sweat damage in a hatch full of canned goods in cartons will occur when the ____________.",opa:"air temperature is higher than the temperature of the cargo",opb:"air temperature is lower than the temperature of the cargo",opc:"dew point is higher than the temperature of the cargo",opd:"dew point is lower than the temperature of the cargo",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lead of a tow bridle is usually redirected with a ____________.",opa:"bollard",opb:"chock",opc:"pad eye",opd:"devil's claw",ans:"opb"},{question:"One advantage of chain over wire rope for a tow bridle is that chain ____________.",opa:"is better suited for inland towing",opb:"resists damage from chafing",opc:"handles more easily",opd:"equalizes towing forces better",ans:"opb"},{question:"A charterer is unable to complete the loading of a vessel during the lay days specified in the charter party. Under these circumstances, the ____________.",opa:"vessel operator can collect demurrage",opb:"ship is authorized extra time to discharge the cargo",opc:"charterer must pay dispatch money",opd:"effective period of the charter is extended",ans:"opa"},{question:"When using the term 'limber system' one is referring to a ____________.",opa:"cleaning system",opb:"drainage system",opc:"strengthening system",opd:"weight reduction system",ans:"opb"},{question:"Fog can form in any season on the Great Lakes, but it is most likely to occur over open waters in ____________.",opa:"summer and early autumn",opb:"autumn and early winter",opc:"winter and early spring",opd:"spring and early summer",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is meant by the term 'level-luffing' a crane?",opa:"Luffing while the load remains at a constant height",opb:"Maintaining the boom at a constant height",opc:"Slewing the boom left or right in a level plane",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"A lookout can leave his station ____________.",opa:"at the end of the watch",opb:"at any time",opc:"ONLY when properly relieved",opd:"15 minutes before the end of the watch",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a line is laid down in loose, looping figure-eights, it is said to be ____________.",opa:"faked",opb:"flemished",opc:"coiled",opd:"chined",ans:"opa"},{question:"When being towed, a fairlead is a ____________.",opa:"fabricated shape used to change the direction of a flexible member of the tow hookup",opb:"fabricated shape used to secure the tow hookup to the towed vessel",opc:"line connecting the fishplate to the bridle legs",opd:"line connecting the tow bridle to the towed vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"While your vessel is docked port side to a wharf, a sudden gale force wind causes the vessel's bow lines to part. The bow begins to fall away from the dock, and no tugs are immediately available. Which measure(s) should you take FIRST?",opa:"Call the Master and the deck gang.",opb:"Slip the stern lines, let the vessel drift into the river, and then anchor.",opc:"Let go the starboard anchor.",opd:"Obtain assistance and attempt to put some new bow lines out.",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to the IMO Code, what are the minimum number of securing points that should be on each side of a 'road vehicle', whose gross vehicle mass is between 30 tons and 40 tons, when carried on Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opd"},{question:"You must shore up a bulkhead due to solid flooding forward. The bulkhead approximates a rectangle. The center of pressure of the shores on the bulkhead should be located ____________.",opa:"evenly over the surface of the bulkhead",opb:"approximately one-third of the way up the bulkhead",opc:"approximately halfway up the bulkhead",opd:"at the bottom of the bulkhead",ans:"opb"},{question:"What equipment is NOT used to protect a towing hawser?",opa:"Hawser boards and chafing gear",opb:"Halyards and snaphooks",opc:"Seizing wire, rope yarn and marline",opd:"Norman pins and tow spans",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the purpose of pressure-vacuum relief valves?",opa:"Regulation of discharge pressure from cargo pumps",opb:"Maintaining constant velocity in cargo lines",opc:"Regulation of suction head on cargo pumps",opd:"Automatic regulation of pressure or vacuum in enclosed spaces",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about shipping coal is TRUE?",opa:"Anthracite will generate more methane than bituminous coal.",opb:"Coal should not be shipped while wet.",opc:"Coal should be surface ventilated to remove methane gas.",opd:"The methane gas generated by coal will react with moisture on the ship's structure and accelerate corrosion.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are proceeding to the area of reported distress. When you arrive at the reported position, the vessel in distress is not sighted. What type of search should be conducted?",opa:"Sector search",opb:"Expanding square",opc:"Track crawl",opd:"Parallel track search",ans:"opb"},{question:"While towing, bridle legs of unequal lengths may cause ____________.",opa:"the bridle to foul",opb:"the shorter leg to fail",opc:"chafing on the fairlead or bitts",opd:"a bent swivel",ans:"opb"},{question:"When an azimuth of the Sun has been taken and the deviation of the standard magnetic compass computed, the watch officer should record the results ____________.",opa:"in the vessel's Official Logbook",opb:"on the compass deviation card",opc:"in the compass deviation log",opd:"on a Napier diagram",ans:"opc"},{question:"In order to correctly open a new coil of manila line, you should ____________.",opa:"pull the tagged end from the top of the coil",opb:"pull the tagged end through the eye of the coil",opc:"secure the outside end and unroll the coil",opd:"unreel the coil from a spool",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the cargo manifest, the total weight of a box containing cargo is the ____________.",opa:"tare weight",opb:"net weight",opc:"gross weight",opd:"cargo weight",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lower hold of your vessel has a bale capacity of 45,000 cubic feet. How many cases of a cargo weighing 450 lbs. and measuring 2.5 feet by 3 feet by 3 feet could be stowed in the hold, assuming a broken stowage factor of 15 percent?",opa:"300",opb:"675",opc:"1325",opd:"1700",ans:"opd"},{question:"The distance a vessel moves parallel to the original course from the point where the rudder is put over to any point on the turning circle is called the ____________.",opa:"advance",opb:"drift angle",opc:"pivoting point",opd:"transfer",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the name of the mark indicated by the letter B in the diagram?",opa:"Timber summer load line",opb:"Tropical fresh water load line",opc:"Tropical load line",opd:"Summer load line",ans:"opb"},{question:"How does the effect known as 'bank suction' act on a single-screw vessel proceeding along a narrow channel?",opa:"It pulls the bow toward the bank.",opb:"It heels the vessel toward the bank.",opc:"It pushes the entire vessel away from the bank.",opd:"It pulls the stern toward the bank.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The primary purpose of the stud is to prevent the anchor chain from ____________.",opa:"kinking",opb:"distorting",opc:"elongating",opd:"breaking",ans:"opa"},{question:"A seaman lost his continuous discharge book during the voyage. Upon discharge from Articles, he should be issued a ____________.",opa:"letter of service on company letterhead signed and sealed by the master",opb:"Record of Entry in a Continuous Discharge Book for use in applying for a duplicate book",opc:"Certificate of Discharge with the white copy forwarded to the Commandant",opd:"Mutual Release (CG-2119), and the articles should be annotated as to the loss",ans:"opc"},{question:"As a ship moves through the water, it drags with it a body of water called the wake. The ratio of the wake speed to the ship's speed is called ____________.",opa:"propeller velocity",opb:"speed of advance",opc:"wake distribution",opd:"wake fraction",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are Master of a vessel that is sold in a foreign country after discharge of cargo. What is your responsibility to the crew in regards to return to the United States?",opa:"You must provide air transportation to the nearest port of entry in the United States.",opb:"You must provide passage to the port of original engagement.",opc:"There is no requirement for return to the United States provided the voyage has exceeded 4 weeks duration.",opd:"The crew can be employed on another United States vessel, but only if it is returning to the port of original engagement.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Once a vessel has loaded packaged hazardous cargo, the cargo spaces shall be inspected. The spaces shall also be inspected at least once in every 24 hours. The only exception to daily inspection is when ____________.",opa:"a vessel is equipped with an automatic smoke or fire detecting system",opb:"the cargo hatches are of steel construction",opc:"the cargo is of a nonflammable type",opd:"there is sufficient fire protection located on the main deck adjacent to the cargo hatch",ans:"opa"},{question:"A serving mallet is used in ____________.",opa:"covering wire or fiber rope",opb:"forcing fids into a line",opc:"dogging hatches",opd:"splicing lines",ans:"opa"},{question:"Container vessels are required to maintain an Oil Record Book when the vessel is?",opa:"150 gross tons and above",opb:"200 gross tons and above",opc:"300 gross tons above",opd:"400 gross tons and above",ans:"opd"},{question:"If a passenger vessel navigating the Great Lakes is required to carry 8 life buoys, what is the allowable minimum number of these buoys that must have self-igniting lights attached?",opa:"8",opb:"6",opc:"4",opd:"2",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel arrives in the port of Los Angeles from a foreign port and discharges some of its inward foreign cargo. What additional manifest is required?",opa:"Discharge Manifest",opb:"Inward Foreign Manifest",opc:"Pro Forma Manifest",opd:"Traveling Manifest",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on watch and see a man fall overboard. Which man overboard turn should NOT be used in this situation?",opa:"Scharnow",opb:"Single turn",opc:"Racetrack",opd:"Williamson",ans:"opa"},{question:"Panting frames are located in the ____________.",opa:"after double bottoms",opb:"centerline tanks on tankships",opc:"fore and after peaks",opd:"forward double bottoms",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statement(s) is/are TRUE regarding twin pedestal cranes?",opa:"Each single boom is of the partial-level luffing type and is capable of limited rotation.",opb:"A slew drive system provides for rotation of each crane.",opc:"Maintenance logs and records are to be kept for each crane.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are drifting in a locale where there is no current. As a rule, your vessel will lie ____________.",opa:"bow to the wind",opb:"beam to the wind",opc:"stern to the wind",opd:"with the wind on the quarter",ans:"opb"},{question:"The strength of a deck will be increased by adding ____________.",opa:"camber",opb:"deck beam brackets",opc:"hatch beams",opd:"sheer",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which wire rope purchases may be used with a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Hoist",opb:"Luff",opc:"Rider block",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The type of carrier required to file a copy of freight tariffs would be the ____________.",opa:"common carrier",opb:"tramp",opc:"public vessel",opd:"bulk carrier",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the penalty for desertion?",opa:"Fine of not more than 2000 dollars and forfeiture of wages",opb:"Imprisonment for not more than 2 years and/or a fine of not more than 2000 dollars",opc:"Revocation of Merchant Mariner's Document (and license if applicable) and forfeiture of wages due",opd:"Forfeiture of money and property left on the vessel, and wages due",ans:"opd"},{question:"The trim and stability booklet must be approved by the ____________.",opa:"International Maritime Organization",opb:"National Cargo Bureau",opc:"Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers",opd:"United States Coast Guard",ans:"opd"},{question:"In handling break bulk hazardous materials, it is forbidden to use ____________.",opa:"cargo nets",opb:"metal bale hooks",opc:"pallets",opd:"slings",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are going to load bales of wool having a stowage factor of 100 in #3 lower hold which has a bale cubic of 72,000. How many tons of the wool can be stowed in the compartment, assuming 10% broken stowage?",opa:"493",opb:"577",opc:"602",opd:"648",ans:"opd"},{question:"The knot lettered N as shown is a ____________.",opa:"timber hitch",opb:"rolling bowline",opc:"stopper",opd:"heaving line hitch",ans:"opc"},{question:"What could be used as fairleads on a towed vessel?",opa:"Chocks",opb:"Double bitts",opc:"Roller chocks",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which best describes a 'fishplate' used in towing?",opa:"A triangular-shaped heavy steel plate with a round hole inset from each corner",opb:"A steel plate in the shape of a flat fish",opc:"A rectangular-shaped piece of heavy steel plate with four holes",opd:"A circular piece of heavy steel with three holes forming an equilateral triangle",ans:"opa"},{question:"When running before a heavy sea, moving weights aft will affect the handling of a vessel by ____________.",opa:"reducing rolling",opb:"increasing rolling",opc:"reducing yawing",opd:"increasing yawing",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are proceeding to a distress site. The survivors are in liferafts. What will make your ship more visible to the survivors?",opa:"Steering a sinuous course",opb:"Steering a zig-zag course",opc:"Turning on all available deck lights at night",opd:"Dumping debris over the side to make a trail to your vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Snow has obliterated surface features and the sky is covered with uniform, altostratus clouds. There are no shadows and the horizon has disappeared. What is this condition called?",opa:"Ice blink",opb:"Whiteout",opc:"Water sky",opd:"Aurora reflection",ans:"opb"},{question:"The fore and aft run of deck plating which strengthens the connection between the beams and the frames and keeps the beams square to the shell is called the ____________.",opa:"garboard strake",opb:"limber strake",opc:"sheer strake",opd:"stringer strake",ans:"opd"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated IMMEDIATE will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"6 hours",opb:"3 hours",opc:"10 minutes",opd:"30 minutes",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which part of the patent anchor performs the same function as the stock of an old fashioned anchor; that is, forces the flukes to dig in?",opa:"Bill or pea",opb:"Arm",opc:"Shank",opd:"Tripping Palm",ans:"opd"},{question:"A 'chock' is a ____________.",opa:"deck fitting used to secure mooring lines",opb:"casting fitted at the side of a weather deck, used as a fairlead",opc:"sharp block of wood used to support hygroscopic cargo",opd:"smoke pipe for the galley stove",ans:"opb"},{question:"While standing look-out at night, a dim light on the horizon will be seen quickest by looking ____________.",opa:"a little above the horizon",opb:"directly towards the light",opc:"a little below the horizon",opd:"quickly above then quickly below the horizon",ans:"opa"},{question:"The phenomenon known as a 'seiche' is most likely to occur on Lake Erie ____________.",opa:"during the passage of a rapidly moving warm front",opb:"when strong winds from the Northeast suddenly diminish",opc:"during the months of May through August",opd:"when the Moon and Sun are in alignment",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the penalty for willfully damaging cargo?",opa:"Forfeiture of wages equal to the value of the damage and, if ordered by the court, imprisonment for not more than 12 months",opb:"Fine equal to the value of the damage plus a 1000 dollar penalty and/or imprisonment not to exceed 2 years",opc:"Fine not to exceed the value of the damage and/or imprisonment not to exceed 18 months",opd:"Revocation of Merchant Mariner's Document (and license if applicable), fine equal to the value of the damage or imprisonment for not more than 2 years",ans:"opa"},{question:"The structural member indicated by the letter K was fitted in segments between continuous longitudinals. It is known as which type of floor?",opa:"Intercostal",opb:"Open",opc:"Lightened",opd:"Non-watertight",ans:"opa"},{question:"The main function of the core of a wire rope is to ____________.",opa:"give flexibility",opb:"support the strands laid around it",opc:"allow some circulation around the strands",opd:"allow lubrication inside the rope",ans:"opb"},{question:"When using two tugs to assist in mooring a large, deeply laden ship, the most powerful tug is usually placed ____________.",opa:"forward to control the bow",opb:"amidships to move the entire vessel evenly",opc:"aft to assist the ship's rudder and propeller",opd:"anywhere, since the maneuverability of the tug governs the placement not the power",ans:"opa"},{question:"A seaman may have all or part of his wages deposited by allotment to a bank or savings institution. Which of the following is NOT a requirement for this type of allotment?",opa:"The account must be either a checking or savings account.",opb:"The institution must be insured by the FSLIC or FDIC.",opc:"The account must be opened by the seaman and maintained in the seaman's name.",opd:"All of the above are requirements.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are as shown. Based on this data what is the advance for a turn of 60\xb0?",opa:"665 yards",opb:"710 yards",opc:"745 yards",opd:"780 yards",ans:"opa"},{question:"The complete details of a crude oil washing system aboard your vessel, including the operating sequences and procedures, design characteristics, a description of the system, and required personnel will be found in the ____________.",opa:"Oil Transfer Procedures Manual",opb:"Crude Oil Washing Operations and Equipment Manual",opc:"Code of Federal Regulations",opd:"Crude Oil Washing addendum to the Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are lifting a one-ton weight with a swinging boom. When comparing the stresses in the rig with the boom at 20\xb0 to the horizontal to the stresses when the boom is at 60\xb0 to the horizontal, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The stress on the topping lift is greater at 60\xb0.",opb:"The thrust on the boom is greater at 20\xb0.",opc:"The stress on the heel block is less at 20\xb0.",opd:"The stress on the masthead fairlead for the topping lift is greater at 20\xb0.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A towing vessel is tripped when ____________.",opa:"it is overtaken by the tow",opb:"it is pulled sideways by the tow",opc:"the weight of the towing hawser causes loss of maneuverability",opd:"the propeller is fouled by the towing hawser",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement(s) is(are) TRUE concerning wire rope?",opa:"Wire rope should be condemned if the outside wires are worn to one-half their original diameter.",opb:"Wire rope should be condemned if the fiber core appears moist.",opc:"Wire rope which is right-hand laid should be coiled counterclockwise to prevent kinking.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What should you inspect to be sure that it is safe to go aloft in a bosun's chair?",opa:"The gantline",opb:"The tail block",opc:"The chair and bridle",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The vapor pressure of a substance ____________.",opa:"decreases as temperature increases",opb:"increases with the temperature",opc:"is not affected by temperature",opd:"may increase or decrease as the temperature rises",ans:"opb"},{question:"Camber, in a ship, is usually measured in ____________.",opa:"feet per feet of breadth",opb:"feet per feet of length",opc:"inches per feet of breadth",opd:"inches per feet of length",ans:"opc"},{question:"In towing it is desirable for the tug and the tow to ride wave crests simultaneously because ____________.",opa:"shock loading on the tow line is reduced",opb:"towing speed is improved",opc:"the tow is more visible from the tug",opd:"the catenary of the towline is reduced",ans:"opa"},{question:"A lot of special cargo of similar cartons is to be loaded aboard your vessel. You examine one of the cartons of the lot shown. What is the total cubic space the consignment will occupy? (Assume no broken stowage.)",opa:"51 cubic feet (1.5 cubic meters)",opb:"58 cubic feet (1.7 cubic meters)",opc:"336 cubic feet (10 cubic meters)",opd:"700 cubic feet (21 cubic meters)",ans:"opb"},{question:"A post on a dock or wharf used to secure mooring lines or hawsers is called a ____________.",opa:"bitt",opb:"bollard",opc:"cleat",opd:"capstan",ans:"opb"},{question:"All of the following records are usually maintained by the watch-standing officers aboard a vessel EXCEPT the ____________.",opa:"deck logbook",opb:"official logbook",opc:"compass record book",opd:"chronometer error book",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has been loaded in a sagging condition. Enroute you encounter heavy weather and notice buckling in the midships deck plating of your vessel. To relieve the strain you could ____________.",opa:"pump fuel oil from midships to the ends of the vessel",opb:"reduce speed",opc:"take a course which most eases the vessel",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You suspect that a crewmember has fallen overboard during the night and immediately execute a Williamson turn. What is the primary advantage of this maneuver under these circumstances?",opa:"You will be on a reciprocal course and nearly on the track-line run during the night.",opb:"The turn provides the maximum coverage of the area to be searched.",opc:"The turn enables you to reverse course in the shortest possible time.",opd:"You have extra time to maneuver in attempting to close in on the man for rescue.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The correct way to make an eye in a wire rope with clips is to place the clips with the ____________.",opa:"first and third U-bolts on the bitter end and the second U-bolt on the standing part",opb:"first and third U-bolts on the standing part and the second U-bolt on the bitter end",opc:"U-bolts of all clips on the bitter end",opd:"U-bolts of all clips on the standing part",ans:"opc"},{question:"A half-height container is used ____________.",opa:"to carry cargoes of low density",opb:"when stowage space is limited",opc:"to carry cargoes such as steel products or drums",opd:"to double the stowage capacity of the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Holes in the bulwark, which allow deck water to drain into the sea, are ____________.",opa:"doggers",opb:"fidleys",opc:"freeing ports",opd:"swash ports",ans:"opc"},{question:"As you hold a piece of manila line vertically in front of you, the strands run from the lower right to the upper left. Which type of line is this?",opa:"Plain-laid",opb:"Shroud-laid",opc:"Left-hand laid",opd:"Water-laid",ans:"opc"},{question:"Under the Carriage of Goods by Sea Act of 1936, a vessel will be liable for damage to cargo when the damage arises from ____________.",opa:"an act of war",opb:"lack of ventilation in transit",opc:"perils of the sea",opd:"an error in navigation",ans:"opb"},{question:"The ceiling is ____________.",opa:"the overhead in berthing compartments",opb:"a wooden protection placed over the tank top",opc:"material driven into seams or cracks to prevent leaking",opd:"None of the above are correct",ans:"opb"},{question:"When using natural-fiber rope, you should NEVER ____________.",opa:"dry the line before stowing it",opb:"reverse turns on winches periodically to keep out kinks",opc:"try to lubricate the line",opd:"use chafing gear",ans:"opc"},{question:"A 6x12, two-inch wire rope has ____________.",opa:"12 strands and a two-inch diameter",opb:"12 strands and a two-inch circumference",opc:"6 strands and a two-inch diameter",opd:"6 strands and a two-inch circumference",ans:"opc"},{question:"On Great Lakes vessels, midsummer load lines apply ____________.",opa:"April 16 through April 30 and September16 through September 30",opb:"May 1 through September 15",opc:"July 16 through August 30",opd:"June 16 through September 16",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is a negotiated charter?",opa:"Fixture",opb:"Bill of Lading",opc:"Conference agreement",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"'Limber' is a term associated with ____________.",opa:"emergency gear",opb:"drainage",opc:"deck cargo storage",opd:"securing gear",ans:"opb"},{question:"The piping that routes an oil cargo from the manifold to underdeck pipelines is known as a ____________.",opa:"cargo fill",opb:"line drop",opc:"transfer",opd:"branch line",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning the vessel's slipstream?",opa:"It has no effect on the steering of the vessel.",opb:"It has no effect on the rudder when the helm is amidships.",opc:"Its velocity is the same as that of the wake.",opd:"The propeller gives it a helical motion.",ans:"opd"},{question:"In a tow made up astern, the fishplate ____________.",opa:"connects the hawser to the bridle",opb:"connects the bridle to the tow",opc:"keeps the hawser amidships on the tug",opd:"is the capping piece on the 'H' bitt",ans:"opa"},{question:"A heated bulkhead has the effect on a hygroscopic commodity of ____________.",opa:"causing moisture to accumulate against the bulkhead",opb:"lowering the vapor pressure of the commodity",opc:"lowering the dew point of the air",opd:"raising the vapor pressure of the commodity",ans:"opd"},{question:"You would be most likely to use a fishplate ____________.",opa:"when towing alongside",opb:"on a hawser tow",opc:"when pushing ahead or in the notch",opd:"when running 'light boat'",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the IMO Code, what are the minimum number of securing points that should be on each side of a 'road vehicle', whose gross vehicle mass is between 3.5 tons and 20 tons, when carried on Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The knot lettered J is a ____________.",opa:"plain whipping",opb:"bowline",opc:"marline hitch",opd:"becket bend",ans:"opa"},{question:"The moisture equilibrium chart can be used to determine the ____________.",opa:"absolute moisture content of the air surrounding a hygroscopic cargo when moisture equilibrium exists",opb:"dew point temperature that the air surrounding a hygroscopic commodity will have when in moisture equilibrium with that commodity",opc:"enthalpy of the air surrounding a hydroscopic cargo which is in moisture equilibrium with the cargo",opd:"temperature at which moisture equilibrium will occur in a cargo hold containing a hygroscopic cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"Manila lines in which the strands are right-hand laid ____________.",opa:"should be coiled in a clockwise direction",opb:"should be coiled in a counterclockwise direction",opc:"may be coiled either clockwise or counterclockwise",opd:"should never be coiled",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using a scope of five, determine how many feet of chain you should put out to anchor in 12 fathoms of water.",opa:"60 feet (18 meters)",opb:"72 feet (22 meters)",opc:"360 feet (110 meters)",opd:"450 feet (137 meters)",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are loading a cargo of cases into a hold which has a bale cubic of 44,000. The cargo consists of cases measuring 4 ft. by 2 ft. by 1.5 ft. Estimated broken stowage is 15%. What is the maximum number of cases which can be stowed in the hold?",opa:"3096",opb:"3116",opc:"3136",opd:"3156",ans:"opb"},{question:"A large basin cut into the shore, closed off by a caisson, and used for dry docking of ships is known as a ____________.",opa:"slipway",opb:"graving dock",opc:"ground warp",opd:"caisson dock",ans:"opb"},{question:"The riding pawl is ____________.",opa:"a safety interlock in a cargo winch that prevents the runner from overspeeding",opb:"a stopper that prevents the anchor cable from running free if the cable jumps the wildcat",opc:"the device that locks the deck lashings of the Peck and Hale system",opd:"the lug that rides on the eccentric rib and engages the locking ring on the windlass",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 6,000 barrels of gasoline, at a cargo temperature of 50\xb0F, departing New Jersey bound for Florida. API gravity is 55\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0006. How many gallons would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 90\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"337920",opb:"322080",opc:"295952",opd:"258048",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel proceeding to London, England, from New York makes an unscheduled call at the port of Hamilton, Bermuda. What term is used to denote the voluntary departure from the usual course?",opa:"Alteration",opb:"Deviation",opc:"Liberty",opd:"Unscheduled stop",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the name of the mark indicated by the letter C?",opa:"Fresh water line",opb:"Tropical water line",opc:"Summer water line",opd:"Winter North Atlantic water line",ans:"opa"},{question:"Prior to getting underway in fresh or brackish water, the Master must ____________.",opa:"log the density of the water",opb:"secure all overboard discharges",opc:"take on fresh water ballast",opd:"clean the sides with fresh water",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a merchant vessel is under the Naval Control of Shipping Organization in wartime, naval authorities may give orders pertaining to ____________.",opa:"minimum manning standards",opb:"regulations about darkening ship",opc:"the stowage of explosives",opd:"the types of cargoes permitted on board",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is off a lee shore in heavy weather and laboring. Which action should you take?",opa:"Put the sea and wind about two points on either bow and reduce speed.",opb:"Heave to in the trough of the sea.",opc:"Put the sea and wind on either quarter and proceed at increased speed.",opd:"Put the bow directly into the sea and proceed at full speed.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Because of the arrangement of the cell guides, the MOST important factor while loading containers is the ____________.",opa:"contents of the container",opb:"list of the vessel",opc:"size of the shoreside crane",opd:"weight of the container",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are using the anchor to steady the bow while maneuvering. You have the proper scope of anchor cable when the ____________.",opa:"bow is held in position with the engines coming slowly ahead",opb:"anchor is just touching the bottom",opc:"scope is not more than 5 times the depth of the water",opd:"cable enters the water at an angle between 60\xb0 and 85\xb0 from the horizontal",ans:"opa"},{question:"The term 'inland waters', as defined in the Rules of the Road, includes ____________.",opa:"the Great Lakes in their entirety",opb:"the Mississippi River System",opc:"U.S. waters out to three miles offshore",opd:"the St. Lawrence River to Anticosti Island",ans:"opb"},{question:"Great Lakes vessels, using liferafts, must have sufficient liferaft capacity on each side of the vessel to accommodate at least ____________.",opa:"50% of the persons on board",opb:"100% of the persons on board",opc:"100% of the persons normally assigned to those spaces",opd:"150% of the crew",ans:"opb"},{question:"The pivot pin at the base of a sheath-screw boom davit must be ____________.",opa:"inserted each time before the booms are cranked out",opb:"periodically removed for inspection and lubricated",opc:"replaced at each inspection for certification",opd:"in the locked position after the boat is cradled and griped down",ans:"opb"},{question:"After splicing an eye in a piece of wire rope, the splice should be parceled and served to ____________.",opa:"strengthen the line",opb:"increase its efficiency",opc:"prevent hand injury by covering loose ends",opd:"make the line more flexible",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the minimum size required before a vessel can be documented?",opa:"26 feet; end-to-end over the deck excluding sheer",opb:"100 gross tons",opc:"5 net tons",opd:"26 feet between perpendiculars",ans:"opc"},{question:"In towing, chocks are used to ____________.",opa:"protect the towline from chafing",opb:"secure the end of the towline on the tug",opc:"stop off the towline while retrieving it",opd:"absorb shock loading on the towline",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning a tagline as used with a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Taglines are wire rope purchases that raise and lower the jib.",opb:"Taglines are wire ropes payed-out or taken-in for horizontal positioning of the rider block.",opc:"Taglines can be can be fastened to the corners of the jib when lifting containers.",opd:"The taglines are wire rope purchases that raise and lower the topping lift.",ans:"opb"},{question:"When stowing hazardous materials on deck, lashing of such cargo is permitted if ____________.",opa:"a wooden bin is constructed of at least 2-inch dunnage and bolted together",opb:"the cargo is lashed to the adjacent guard rails",opc:"the lashings are secured to deck pad eyes",opd:"there is at least 3 inches of dunnage on deck",ans:"opc"},{question:"The document which acknowledges that the cargo has been received and is in the carrier's custody is called the ____________.",opa:"Dock Receipt",opb:"Hatch Report and Recapitulation",opc:"Cargo Manifest",opd:"Stowage Plan",ans:"opa"},{question:"Leeway is the ____________.",opa:"difference between the true course and the compass course",opb:"momentum of a vessel after her engines have been stopped",opc:"lateral movement of a vessel downwind of her intended course",opd:"displacement of a vessel multiplied by her speed",ans:"opc"},{question:"The number of certificated lifeboat men required for a vessel is found on the ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opc:"lifeboats",opd:"Register or Enrollment",ans:"opa"},{question:"The safety stopper that prevents the anchor cable from running free if the cable jumps the wildcat is the ____________.",opa:"riding pawl",opb:"devil's claw",opc:"buckler plate",opd:"spill pipe",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are signing on a crew. Which person is presenting a Merchant Mariner's Document (MMD) that you should suspect as being invalid?",opa:"An AB with an endorsement of 'Any unlicensed rating in the deck department including Able Seaman'",opb:"A seaman with an MMD only endorsed as 'Bosun'",opc:"A Purser with an MMD only endorsed 'See certificate of registry'",opd:"A Chief Steward with an MMD only endorsed as 'Steward's Dept. (FH)'",ans:"opb"},{question:"How do you determine the weight of the vessel that is supported by the ground when a vessel has run aground?",opa:"This requires extensive calculation and is usually performed only by a naval architect not by a ship's officer.",opb:"Determine the point where aground and the draft at that point, then calculate it using the grounding formula.",opc:"Use the hydrostatic tables and enter with the mean draft before grounding and the mean draft after grounding.",opd:"Use the inclining experiment formula and substitute the change of trim for the angle of list.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement about Naval Control of Shipping in wartime is TRUE?",opa:"It is mandatory in wartime.",opb:"It is mandatory in hazardous areas and voluntary in other areas.",opc:"It is mandatory only for vessels sailing in convoy.",opd:"It is mandatory for vessels bound foreign and voluntary for vessels in the coastwise trade.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A towing vessel should be on the crest of a wave at the same time as its tow and in the trough at the same time. The term used to describe this is ____________.",opa:"tow strain",opb:"catenary length",opc:"being in step",opd:"Williamson's Tow",ans:"opc"},{question:"Multi-year ice is the hardest sea ice and should be avoided if possible. It is recognizable because of what tone to its surface color?",opa:"Greenish",opb:"Bluish",opc:"Grey",opd:"Grey-white",ans:"opb"},{question:"The angle at which the fluke penetrates the soil is called the ____________.",opa:"fluke angle",opb:"tripping angle",opc:"penetration angle",opd:"holding angle",ans:"opa"},{question:"When cutting regular-lay wire rope, what is the minimum number of seizing's to be placed on each side of the cut?",opa:"One",opb:"Two, and three on rope diameters over 1 inch",opc:"Three, and more on larger diameter wire ropes",opd:"Four",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which step is NOT generally taken when gas-freeing a tank?",opa:"Washing the tank interior with sea water",opb:"Application of degreasing solvents",opc:"Removal of corrosion products and sludge",opd:"Fresh air ventilation",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are going to load bales of wool having a stowage factor of 96 in #3 lower hold which has a bale cubic of 84,000. How many tons of wool can be stowed in the compartment?",opa:"577",opb:"602",opc:"654",opd:"875",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Safety of Life at Sea Convention was developed by the ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"International Maritime Organization",opd:"American Institute of Maritime Shipping",ans:"opc"},{question:"The maneuver which will return your vessel in the shortest time to a person who has fallen overboard is ____________.",opa:"engine(s) crash astern, no turn",opb:"a single turn with hard rudder",opc:"a Williamson Turn",opd:"two 180\xb0 turns",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on watch at sea at night when a fire breaks out in #3 hold just forward of the bridge. You would NOT ____________.",opa:"call the Master",opb:"proceed to the space and inspect the extent of the fire",opc:"shut down the cargo hold ventilation",opd:"sound the fire alarm signal to roust out all hands",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many board feet of dunnage are there in a draft 3 feet wide, 1-1/2 feet high, and 14 feet long?",opa:"526",opb:"756",opc:"876",opd:"906",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a transpacific voyage, you receive a message from your vessel's operators saying that your vessel has been consigned to voluntary Naval Control of Shipping. Further information is contained in ____________.",opa:"the Light List",opb:"Radio Aids to Navigation (PUB 117)",opc:"the International Code of Signals (PUB 102)",opd:"the Coast Pilot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is required to have a slop chest. Which of the following articles is NOT required by law to be carried in the slop chest?",opa:"Foul weather clothing",opb:"Candy",opc:"Tobacco products",opd:"Blankets",ans:"opb"},{question:"The structural member indicated by the letter K is a ____________.",opa:"longitudinal frame",opb:"stringer",opc:"girder",opd:"floor",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Certificate of Inspection for a containership ____________.",opa:"must be posted under transparent material in a conspicuous place",opb:"is issued by the Coast Guard and is usually valid for 2 years.",opc:"lists all of the stability limitations and conditions imposed on the vessel",opd:"shows the due date of the quadrennial test of the cargo gear",ans:"opa"},{question:"Sidewise force of the propeller tends to throw a vessel's stern to the right or left, depending on rotation. This force is caused by ____________.",opa:"back current from the rudder",opb:"greater pressure on the right or left side of the propeller, depending on rotation",opc:"lower pressure on the right or left side of the propeller, depending on rotation",opd:"torque from the velocity and angle at which the surrounding water impinges upon the propeller blades",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are rigging a stage over the ship's side to serve as a working platform. For stability of the stage, the downhaul to one end of the stage and the downhaul to the other end, which are used for lowering the stage, should be led ____________.",opa:"both to the inboard side of the stage",opb:"both to the outboard side of the stage",opc:"one to the inboard and the other to the outboard",opd:"either both to the inboard or both to the outboard side of the stage",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are in charge of a U.S. documented vessel. Under title 46 of the United States Code, if you fail to report a complaint of a sexual offense, you may be ____________.",opa:"held personally liable by the victim and sued",opb:"criminally charged and jailed",opc:"civilly charged and fined",opd:"All of the above are correct.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the greatest danger of an overriding tow?",opa:"Fouling of the towing hawser",opb:"Loss of steering",opc:"Tripping",opd:"Collision between the tow and the stern of the towing vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which document shows the minimum required crew a vessel must have to navigate from one port in the United States to another?",opa:"Articles",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Crew List",opd:"Register",ans:"opb"},{question:"Chafing gear should be placed ____________.",opa:"at all wearing points of mooring lines",opb:"at the bitter ends of all standing rigging",opc:"around running rigging",opd:"on wire rope only",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE concerning a tagline as used with a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Taglines are wire rope purchases that raise and lower the jib.",opb:"Taglines are wire ropes for horizontal positioning of the rider block.",opc:"Taglines can be fastened to corners of vehicles or containers.",opd:"The crane might not have taglines installed in its rigging system.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement concerning castor oil is TRUE?",opa:"It has a Reid vapor pressure of 9.5.",opb:"It has a specific gravity of 1.3.",opc:"The boiling point is 215\xb0F (102\xb0C).",opd:"It is a grade E combustible liquid.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The part of an anchor which takes hold on the bottom is the ____________.",opa:"arm",opb:"base",opc:"fluke",opd:"stock",ans:"opc"},{question:"'Ease the rudder' means to ____________.",opa:"move the rudder slowly in the direction of the most recent rudder command",opb:"bring the rudder amidships",opc:"decrease the rudder angle",opd:"steer the course which is your present heading",ans:"opc"},{question:"The dangerous cargo manifest does NOT indicate ____________.",opa:"the stowage location of hazardous material aboard the vessel",opb:"a description of the packaging (drums, boxes, etc.)",opc:"UN identification numbers",opd:"the net weight of each hazardous cargo",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a boat turns broadside to heavy seas and winds, thus exposing the boat to the danger of capsizing, the boat has ____________.",opa:"broached",opb:"pitchpoled",opc:"trimmed",opd:"yawed",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following lashing gear used aboard Ro-Ro vessels should be maintained when not in use?",opa:"Chain",opb:"Wire rope",opc:"Webbing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Coordinator Surface Search in a SAR situation should display by day ____________.",opa:"the code flags FR",opb:"a black ball over a black diamond shape",opc:"code flag Quebec over a black ball",opd:"two black diamond shapes in a vertical line",ans:"opa"},{question:"A mooring line is described as being 6x24, 1-3/4 inch wire rope. What do the above numbers refer to?",opa:"Strands, yarns, circumference",opb:"Strands, wires, diameter",opc:"Wires, yarns, diameter",opd:"Strands, circumference, wires",ans:"opb"},{question:"A long ton is ____________.",opa:"1,000 pounds",opb:"2,000 pounds",opc:"2,240 pounds",opd:"2,400 pounds",ans:"opc"},{question:"A lot of special cargo of similar cartons as shown is to be loaded. What is the total cubic capacity the consignment will occupy if you assume 10% broken stowage?",opa:"51 cubic feet (1.5 cubic meters)",opb:"58 cubic feet (1.7 cubic meters)",opc:"65 cubic feet (2.0 cubic meters)",opd:"336 cubic feet (10 cubic meters)",ans:"opc"},{question:"The weight of the container and its contents is supported on deck by what part(s)?",opa:"Four lower corner castings",opb:"Bottom, side, and end rails",opc:"Bottom flooring, side, and end rails",opd:"Bottom flooring only",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel's 'quarter' is that section which is ____________.",opa:"abeam",opb:"dead astern",opc:"just aft of the bow",opd:"on either side of the stern",ans:"opd"},{question:"If, after examination by the Quarantine Officer, your vessel is found to have a specific deficiency, you may be issued ____________.",opa:"Bill of health",opb:"Free Pratique",opc:"Notice to Comply",opd:"Controlled Free Pratique",ans:"opd"},{question:"Under the Carriage of Goods by Sea Act of 1936, a vessel will be liable for damage to a cargo when the damage arises from ____________.",opa:"unseaworthiness when sailing",opb:"insufficient packing",opc:"quarantine delays",opd:"mismanagement of the vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"When towing astern, increased catenary will ____________.",opa:"increase control of the tow",opb:"prevent the towing vessel from going in irons",opc:"make the towing vessel less maneuverable",opd:"reduce shock stress on the towing hawser",ans:"opd"},{question:"The catenary ____________.",opa:"acts as a reserve length of towing hawser when the tug applies more power, and it dampens the surge effect of the tow",opb:"gives an approximation of the amount of strain on the towing hawser",opc:"is the dip in the towing hawser between the tug and the tow",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are as shown. Based on this data what is the advance for a turn of 90\xb0?",opa:"490 yards",opb:"350 yards",opc:"790 yards",opd:"885 yards",ans:"opc"},{question:"When securing a hook to the end of a wire rope you should use ____________.",opa:"a bowline knot",opb:"a long splice",opc:"an overhand knot with a wire rope clip",opd:"wire rope clips with a thimble eye",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on watch at sea at night and a fire breaks out in #3 hold. What should be done IMMEDIATELY?",opa:"Shut down the cargo hold ventilation.",opb:"Proceed to the space and determine the extent of the fire.",opc:"Flood the space with C02 from the fixed fire fighting system.",opd:"Cool the deck to contain the fire.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A 6x19 wire rope would be ____________.",opa:"6 inches in diameter and 19 fathoms long",opb:"6 inches in circumference with 19 strands",opc:"6 strands with 19 wires in each strand",opd:"19 strands with 6 wires in each strand",ans:"opc"},{question:"A single fitting installed in a pipeline that either blanks off the pipe or allows a full flow passage of a liquid through the pipe is referred to as a ____________.",opa:"blind flange",opb:"pivot coupling",opc:"quick-release coupling",opd:"spectacle flange",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about the dangerous cargo manifest, carried on a ship, is TRUE?",opa:"The manifest must be made up by the Master or other designated ship's officer.",opb:"Shipments of hazardous and non-hazardous cargo may be listed on the manifest if they are destined for the same consignee.",opc:"The manifest must be kept in a designated holder on or near the bridge.",opd:"The type of label(s) required for each cargo must be indicated.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE, concerning the Williamson turn?",opa:"In a large vessel (VLCC) much of the headway will be lost thereby requiring little astern maneuvering.",opb:"When the turn is completed, the vessel will be on a reciprocal course and nearly on the original track line.",opc:"The initial actions are taken at well defined points and reduce the need for individual judgment.",opd:"The turn will return the vessel to the man's location in the shortest possible time.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Uncoiling manila line improperly can result in a(n) ____________.",opa:"number of fishhooks",opb:"kink in the line",opc:"50% loss of efficiency of the line",opd:"increase in deterioration of the line",ans:"opb"},{question:"The next-to-last shot of an anchor cable is usually painted ____________.",opa:"white",opb:"international orange",opc:"yellow",opd:"red",ans:"opc"},{question:"Ten triangular piles of piping on the pier are to be loaded -each pile has a 20 foot base, is 15 feet high and 30 feet long. If the breadth of the hold is 60 feet and the piping is to be stowed fore and aft in a 30 foot space, how high will it stow?",opa:"16.6 feet",opb:"25.0 feet",opc:"50.0 feet",opd:"75.0 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the name of the mark indicated by the letter E?",opa:"Fresh water line",opb:"Winter water line",opc:"Tropical water line",opd:"Summer water line",ans:"opd"},{question:"When anchored, increasing the scope of the anchor chain normally serves to ____________.",opa:"prevent fouling of the anchor",opb:"decrease swing of the vessel",opc:"prevent dragging of the anchor",opd:"reduce strain on the windlass",ans:"opc"},{question:"An ocean towing bridle should ____________.",opa:"have equal legs of sufficient length",opb:"have a large angle between the legs",opc:"be formed on a bight of cable through a ring",opd:"never be made up of chain",ans:"opa"},{question:"Most of your vessel's superstructure is forward. How will the vessel lie when drifting with no way on?",opa:"With the wind from ahead",opb:"With the wind off the port beam",opc:"With the wind off the starboard beam",opd:"With the wind from abaft the beam",ans:"opd"},{question:"When loading a cargo of taconite, proper sequencing of loading by hatch number is necessary to ____________.",opa:"provide the proper trim",opb:"prevent negative stability from developing",opc:"prevent excessive longitudinal stresses",opd:"control list",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 8,000 barrels of gasoline at a cargo temperature of 85\xb0F, departing Aruba bound for New Jersey. API gravity is 55\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0006. How many barrels would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 50\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"7880",opb:"7832",opc:"8168",opd:"8120",ans:"opb"},{question:"A six-strand composite rope made up of alternate fiber and wire strands around a fiber core is called ____________.",opa:"spring lay",opb:"lang lay",opc:"cable lay",opd:"alternate lay",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are signing on crew members. The minimum number of people required aboard, and the qualifications of each, is listed on the ____________.",opa:"fo'c'sle card",opb:"Crew list",opc:"Articles of Agreement",opd:"Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which data can NOT be found on a moisture equilibrium chart?",opa:"Dry bulb temperature",opb:"Moisture content",opc:"Vapor pressure",opd:"Wet bulb temperature",ans:"opd"},{question:"Maritime Administration personnel may be allowed in the pilothouse upon the responsibility of the ____________.",opa:"Chief Officer",opb:"Navigator",opc:"most senior person present from the Maritime Administration",opd:"officer in charge of the watch",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of hull damage should be repaired FIRST?",opa:"Damage below the waterline",opb:"Damage to interior watertight boundaries",opc:"Damage in way of machinery rooms",opd:"Damage at or just above the waterline",ans:"opd"},{question:"Besides saving distance along the track line, another advantage of the Scharnow Turn over the Williamson Turn in a man overboard situation is because ____________.",opa:"it is faster",opb:"it can be used in both the immediate action and the delayed action situations",opc:"in fog, if the turn is started as soon as the man goes over, the vessel will be at the point where he went over when the turn is completed",opd:"it returns the vessel to the original track line on a reciprocal course",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are rigging a stage over the vessel's side and are securing the downhaul with lowering turns at your end of the stage. When finished, the remainder of the line should be ____________.",opa:"lowered down into the water",opb:"coiled on the stage with the bitter end on the bottom",opc:"coiled on the stage with the bitter end on top",opd:"coiled on deck to be slacked down by a seaman as needed",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning vessels over 1600 gross tons certificated for service solely on the Great Lakes?",opa:"They must have magnetic compasses.",opb:"They must have gyro compasses.",opc:"They must carry a deep-sea hand lead.",opd:"All of the above statements are TRUE.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The condition of a towline must be monitored by ____________.",opa:"keeping record of the towline's initial minimum breaking strength",opb:"keeping record of each retest of the towline's minimum breaking strength",opc:"conducting routine visual inspections of the towline",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which knot is used to attach two different sized lines together?",opa:"Granny knot",opb:"Sheet bend",opc:"Square knot",opd:"Thief knot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 77\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 69\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.67",opb:"0.7",opc:"0.77",opd:"0.81",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is crossing a river on the Great Lakes System. A power-driven vessel is ascending the river, crossing your course from port to starboard. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The vessel ascending the river has the right of way.",opb:"Your vessel has the right of way, but you are directed not to impede the other vessel.",opc:"The other vessel must hold as necessary to allow you to pass.",opd:"You are required to propose the manner of passage.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The catenary in a towline is ____________.",opa:"a short bridle",opb:"the downward curvature of the hawser",opc:"another name for a pelican hook",opd:"used to hold it amidships",ans:"opb"},{question:"Serving is ____________.",opa:"marline or ratline wound along the grooves of a rope",opb:"narrow strips of light canvas or cotton cloth spiral-wrapped along the rope",opc:"marline tightly wound on the rope by means of a board or mallet",opd:"a splice made by laying the strand of one rope into the vacated grooves of another rope",ans:"opc"},{question:"Great Lakes cargo vessels, having a liferaft stowed more than 100 meters from the bow or stern, must have at least how many liferafts?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement describes a cofferdam?",opa:"any deck below the main deck and above the lowest deck",opb:"a member that gives fore-and-aft strength",opc:"it's constructed by placing two bulkheads a few feet apart",opd:"a heavy fore-and-aft beam under the deck",ans:"opc"},{question:"The knot lettered R is a ____________.",opa:"double becket bend",opb:"bowline",opc:"fisherman's bend",opd:"round turn and two half hitches",ans:"opa"},{question:"The 'grip' of a joint represents the ____________.",opa:"thickness of the connected members",opb:"diameter of the head",opc:"entire length of the rivet",opd:"diameter of the shank",ans:"opa"},{question:"A complaint of unseaworthiness by a majority of crew members to the American Consul is found to be justified after a survey is completed. Who must pay the cost of the survey?",opa:"Crew members requesting the survey",opb:"American Consul",opc:"Master",opd:"Vessel's owners",ans:"opc"},{question:"When commencing cargo operations on a container ship, one cell at a hatch is generally discharged completely (to the bottom of the ship) before removing any containers from the adjoining cells to ____________.",opa:"remove an existing list that would slow down cargo operations",opb:"initiate loading in conjunction with unloading at the hatch",opc:"improve stability during cargo operations",opd:"allow longshoremen easy access to the hatch",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on anchor watch. As an aid to preventing thievery on the vessel you should ____________.",opa:"show running lights, anchor lights and deck lights",opb:"only show the required anchor lights and keep the rest of the vessel darkened",opc:"maintain water on deck with fire hoses led out and all-purpose nozzles attached",opd:"show anchor lights, deck lights and cargo lights hung over the vessel's side",ans:"opd"},{question:"When tank cleaning with a portable machine, the weight of the machine is suspended from ____________.",opa:"solid iron bars clamped to the Butterworth opening",opb:"the supply hose",opc:"the suspension line, usually manila or natural fiber line",opd:"a wire rope suspension line",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are lifting a 5-ton weight with a single whip rove on a swinging boom set at an angle of 60\xb0 to the horizontal. Use the formula for the size of a shackle with a safe working load and determine the minimum size shackle that should be used to secure the head block to the boom?",opa:"1 inch",opb:"1 3/8 inch",opc:"1 1/2 inch",opd:"1 7/8 inch",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT a form used by ice support services to disseminate information?",opa:"Ice Analyses",opb:"Ice Forecasts",opc:"Ice Outlooks",opd:"Ice Bulletins",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are loading a cargo that includes cylinders of acetylene aboard your break bulk vessel. Which statement is true?",opa:"The cylinders must be stowed at least 10 horizontal feet from corrosive materials in the same space.",opb:"Stowage in the upper deck-deck is considered to be the equivalent of 'on deck' stowage for this cargo.",opc:"The cylinders must have a red label for flammability and a green label for compressed gas.",opd:"The cylinders may be protected from the radiant heat of the Sun by laying a tarp on them.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which cargo would require a dangerous cargo manifest?",opa:"Cotton",opb:"Wheat",opc:"Sugar",opd:"Lumber",ans:"opa"},{question:"Before arriving at the first U.S. port from foreign, you must fill out a Crewman's Landing Permit for each ____________.",opa:"alien crewmember",opb:"crew member",opc:"nonresident alien crewmember",opd:"unlicensed crew member",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are signing on a crew. When they present their Merchant Mariner Credential, you should suspect a fraudulent document if it has a single endorsement that says ____________.",opa:"see Certificate of Registry",opb:"any unlicensed rating in the deck department including AB",opc:"Steward's Department (F.H.)",opd:"Bosun",ans:"opd"},{question:"If the towing bridle legs are not of equal length ____________.",opa:"excessive strain is placed on the shorter leg",opb:"the shorter leg may fail",opc:"the longer leg is slack",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When referring to dry bulk cargoes, the term 'flow state' ____________.",opa:"designates the state of a commodity when the ship is heeled past the angle of repose",opb:"relates to the suitability of loading a cargo by flowing down inclined chutes",opc:"refers to the saturation of a dry bulk product with water to the point where it acts as a liquid",opd:"relates to the minimum granule size of a particular product where it will flow like a liquid at an angle of 30\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is an advantage of the 6X37 class of wire rope over the 6X19 class of wire rope of the same diameter?",opa:"Greater flexibility",opb:"More resistance to corrosion",opc:"More resistance to elongation",opd:"Lower weight per foot",ans:"opa"},{question:"A tonnage tax is levied according to the ____________.",opa:"deadweight cargo tonnage aboard",opb:"displacement tonnage of vessel",opc:"gross tonnage of vessel",opd:"net tonnage of vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"A short ton is a unit of weight consisting of ____________.",opa:"1,000 pounds",opb:"2,000 pounds",opc:"2,205 pounds",opd:"2,240 pounds",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are going to load bales of wool having a stowage factor of 100 in #3 lower hold which has a bale cubic of 62,000. How many tons of the wool can be stowed in the compartment, assuming 10% broken stowage?",opa:"520",opb:"558",opc:"620",opd:"654",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is required to be entered into the Official Logbook?",opa:"Opening a sideport at sea to renew a gasket",opb:"The annual required stripping and cleaning of the lifeboats",opc:"The biennial weight test of the lifeboats and falls",opd:"The drafts on entering port",ans:"opa"},{question:"The shearing stresses on a ship's structure are usually greatest at ____________.",opa:"the bow",opb:"the stern",opc:"midships",opd:"the ship's quarter-length points",ans:"opd"},{question:"Once a towline is connected between the towing vessel and the disabled vessel, the towing vessel should ____________.",opa:"not exceed bare steerageway during the transit",opb:"take a strain as soon as you can to control the tow",opc:"come up to speed very slowly and maintain a 'safe speed'",opd:"come up to speed quickly, then cut back power considerably to ease the strain",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which Naval Control of Shipping publication should be aboard your vessel?",opa:"ATP-2 Vol. II -Allied Control of Shipping Manual",opb:"NWP-II -Underway Replenishment Guide",opc:"Warship Recognition Cards",opd:"ATP-1 -Allied Tactical Signals",ans:"opa"},{question:"How does an icebreaker normally free a ship which has become beset while navigating independently?",opa:"By backing down the track and cutting out ice on either bow",opb:"By approaching from the stern and crossing ahead at an angle of 20\xb0 to 30\xb0 to the beset ship's course",opc:"By overtaking the beset ship, running ahead and then backing down the track to the beset vessel",opd:"By approaching the vessel from astern and towing the beset vessel stern first",ans:"opb"},{question:"Under the Carriage of Goods by Sea Act of 1936, a vessel will be liable for damage to a cargo when the damage arises out of ____________.",opa:"delays due to seizure of the vessel",opb:"fire caused by fault of the carrier",opc:"strikes or lockouts",opd:"improper stowage",ans:"opd"},{question:"Generally, you can best keep a vessel under steering control when the vessel has ____________.",opa:"headway",opb:"sternway",opc:"no way on, with engines stopped",opd:"no way on, with engines full ahead",ans:"opa"},{question:"Containers of flammable solids should be conspicuously labeled by the shipper with a ____________.",opa:"green label",opb:"red and white label",opc:"orange label",opd:"yellow label",ans:"opb"},{question:"What term indicates the midships portion of a vessel that has a constant cross section?",opa:"Half length",opb:"Amidships",opc:"Middle body",opd:"Molded length",ans:"opc"},{question:"The structural member indicated by the letter L is a ____________.",opa:"web frame",opb:"bilge keel",opc:"side keel",opd:"longitudinal",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT suitable for use in making up the towing rig for a heavy, long ocean tow?",opa:"Chain",opb:"Ring",opc:"Solid thimble",opd:"A fishplate",ans:"opb"},{question:"A seaman is reported missing in the morning and was last seen after coming off the mid-watch. Which type of turn would you use to return to the track-line steamed during the night?",opa:"Williamson",opb:"Racetrack",opc:"180\xb0 turn",opd:"Anderson",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's operators send a message that your vessel has been consigned to Voluntary Naval Control of Shipping. The message will refer you to ____________.",opa:"the Light List",opb:"the International Code of Signals (PUB 102)",opc:"Radio Aids to Navigation (PUB 117)",opd:"the Coast Pilot",ans:"opc"},{question:"'White Line' is made from ____________.",opa:"cotton",opb:"hemp",opc:"manila",opd:"sisal",ans:"opa"},{question:"A 'whipping' is ____________.",opa:"a messenger",opb:"a stopper for nylon line",opc:"a U-bolt for securing a cargo whip to the winch drum",opd:"turns of twine around a rope end",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning a tagline as used with a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Taglines are wire rope purchases that raise and lower the jib.",opb:"Taglines are wire ropes payed-out or taken-in for positioning the crane pedestal.",opc:"Taglines can be fastened to the corners of vehicles or containers during cargo operations.",opd:"Taglines are wire rope purchases that raise and lower the topping lift.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which will NOT reduce yawing of a tow?",opa:"Increasing the length of the towing hawser",opb:"Trimming the tow by the bow",opc:"Trimming the tow by the stern",opd:"Drogues put over the stern",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are a watch standing mate and have come to the bridge to relieve the watch while underway at sea. The watch should not be transferred ____________.",opa:"during an engine speed change",opb:"during a navigational course change",opc:"unless the helm is in the 'hand' mode",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tank holds 400 tons of sea water when filled. How many tons of liquid of specific gravity 0.9300 will it hold when filled to 90% capacity?",opa:"326.6",opb:"343.2",opc:"377.6",opd:"390.2",ans:"opa"},{question:"You operate a harbor craft on inland waters exclusively. If you regularly service or contact foreign flag vessels in the course of business, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Your vessel must be inspected.",opb:"Your crew must have identification credentials.",opc:"A customs official must be on board when contacting a foreign flag vessel.",opd:"All contacts with a foreign flag vessel must be reported to the U.S. Coast Guard.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Chafing gear is used to ____________.",opa:"increase mechanical advantage on a towing recovery wheel",opb:"eliminate yawing of disabled tow",opc:"protect towlines from wearing down against edges of vessel",opd:"connects towline to trailer eye of disabled tow",ans:"opc"},{question:"When making way in heavy seas you notice that your vessel's screw is being lifted clear of the water and racing. One way to correct this would be to ____________.",opa:"increase speed",opb:"decrease speed",opc:"move more weight forward",opd:"shift the rudder back and forth several times",ans:"opb"},{question:"Tugs sometimes shackle a length of chain in the towline in order to ____________.",opa:"take the wear should the towline drag bottom",opb:"assure that if the towline is overstressed it will part close to the bridle",opc:"prevent the towline from whipping should it part",opd:"put spring in the towline",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement(s) is/are TRUE regarding the operation of a crane?",opa:"The load is handled by the hoisting winch and cargo block.",opb:"The crane jib is raised and lowered by the hoisting winch.",opc:"The cargo block is raised and lowered by the luffing winch.",opd:"All the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following lashing gear used aboard Ro-Ro vessels should be stowed when not in use?",opa:"Chain",opb:"Wire rope",opc:"Webbing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The most probable position of the object of a search at any given time is the ____________.",opa:"datum position",opb:"incident position",opc:"reported position",opd:"dead-reckoning position",ans:"opa"},{question:"All inspected vessels on unrestricted ocean routes must have equipment on board for testing an individual's ____________.",opa:"blood",opb:"breath",opc:"urine",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"In relation to the turning circle of a ship, the term 'transfer' means the distance ____________.",opa:"gained in the direction of the original course",opb:"gained at right angles to the original course",opc:"the ship moves sidewise from the original course away from the direction of the turn after the rudder is first put over",opd:"around the circumference of the turning circle",ans:"opb"},{question:"At least one reinspection shall be made on each vessel holding a Certificate of Inspection valid for two years. This inspection shall be held between the tenth and fourteenth months of the duration period of the certificate and shall be ____________.",opa:"at the discretion of the inspector, but in no greater detail than required for original certification",opb:"at the discretion of the inspector, but in no lesser detail than required for original certification",opc:"generally similar in scope to the inspection required for certification, but in less detail",opd:"equivalent to the inspection required for certification",ans:"opc"},{question:"A single-screw vessel going ahead tends to turn more rapidly to port because of propeller ____________.",opa:"discharge current",opb:"suction current",opc:"sidewise force",opd:"thrust",ans:"opc"},{question:"The shipping papers for the products being carried in your tankship are NOT required to contain the ____________.",opa:"exact quantity of the cargoes",opb:"grades of the cargoes",opc:"location of the delivery point(s)",opd:"name of the consignee(s)",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which document is NOT required by law to be posted aboard a vessel?",opa:"Official Crew List",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Officer's licenses",opd:"Muster List",ans:"opa"},{question:"A case received for shipment is marked as shown. The portion of the symbol indicated by the letter A is ____________.",opa:"a stowage sequence marking",opb:"the consignee's marking",opc:"a stowage mark, showing the top of the case",opd:"the symbol for toxic contents",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are aboard a single-screw vessel with a right-handed propeller. The vessel is dead in the water and the rudder is amidships. If you reverse your engine you would expect your vessel to ____________.",opa:"kick its stern to port",opb:"kick its stern to starboard",opc:"move astern without swinging",opd:"swing its stern to starboard, then to port",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which product is most likely to accumulate static electricity?",opa:"Crude oil",opb:"Hard asphalt",opc:"Lubricating oil",opd:"Residual fuel oil",ans:"opc"},{question:"A towing hook may be released from the ____________.",opa:"tug's engineroom or the bow",opb:"pilot house or aft steering station",opc:"forecastle",opd:"towing bitts by reaching over and releasing a lever",ans:"opb"},{question:"Another name for coal naphtha that would appear on a dangerous cargo manifest is ____________.",opa:"benzene",opb:"tar",opc:"middle oil",opd:"toluene",ans:"opa"},{question:"The 'margin plate' is the ____________.",opa:"outboard strake of plating on each side of an inner bottom",opb:"outer strake of plating on each side of the main deck of a vessel",opc:"plate which sits atop the center vertical keel",opd:"uppermost continuous strake of plating on the shell of a vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"An example of a modern anchor which has a stock is a(n) ____________.",opa:"articulated anchor",opb:"Flipper Delta anchor",opc:"Baldt anchor",opd:"Danforth anchor",ans:"opd"},{question:"The main function of a stripping system is to ____________.",opa:"maintain the temperature of the cargo throughout the vessel",opb:"dispose of dangerous vapors within the cargo tanks",opc:"increase the loading rate of the shoreside pumps",opd:"discharge liquid left in the cargo tanks after the main pumps have discharged the bulk",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your ship is steaming at night with the gyro-pilot engaged when you notice that the vessel's course is slowly changing to the right. What action should you take FIRST?",opa:"switch to hand steering",opb:"shift steering to the emergency steering station",opc:"call the Master",opd:"notify the engineroom",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which picture shown represents a square knot?",opa:"W",opb:"R",opc:"P",opd:"H",ans:"opa"},{question:"As you hold a piece of manila line vertically in front of you, the strands run from the lower left to the upper right. Which type of line is this?",opa:"Right-hand laid",opb:"Cable-laid",opc:"Sennet-laid",opd:"Water-laid",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are signing on the Purser. He should present a Merchant Mariner Credential with which endorsement?",opa:"See Certificate of Registry",opb:"Steward's Department",opc:"Purser",opd:"Staff Officer",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT characteristic of the conditions which would be experienced by a vessel located southeast of an approaching eastward-moving storm center on the Great Lakes?",opa:"Falling barometer",opb:"A westerly wind",opc:"Lowering clouds",opd:"Rain or snow",ans:"opa"},{question:"A heavy steel curved arch constructed athwartships and above the after deck on a towing vessel is sometimes called a ____________.",opa:"chafing bar",opb:"Dutch tow bar",opc:"carling",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the dew point of the outside air is higher than the dew point of the air in the cargo hold, you should ____________.",opa:"energize the exhaust blowers",opb:"energize the intake blowers",opc:"not ventilate the cargo holds",opd:"ventilate the cargo holds",ans:"opc"},{question:"A list man would expect to see any of the following light signals EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"two red lights",opb:"one green light",opc:"one white light",opd:"one amber light",ans:"opd"},{question:"In relation to cargo gear, what does 'SWL' mean?",opa:"Safe working load",opb:"Ship's working lift",opc:"Starboard wing lift",opd:"Stress, weight, load",ans:"opa"},{question:"When turning a ship in restricted space with a strong wind, it is normally best to ____________.",opa:"go ahead on both engines with the rudder hard to one side, if on a twin-screw vessel",opb:"back down with the rudder hard to one side, if on a single-screw vessel",opc:"take advantage of the tendency to back to port, if on a twin-screw vessel",opd:"turn so that the tendency to back into the wind can be used, if on a single-screw vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the name of the mark indicated by the letter D?",opa:"Tropical load line",opb:"Summer load line",opc:"Fresh load line",opd:"Winter load line",ans:"opa"},{question:"When talking about wire rope, the lay of the wire is the ____________.",opa:"direction wires and strands are twisted together",opb:"number of strands in the wire",opc:"direction the core is twisted",opd:"material used in the core",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are lifting a one-ton weight with a swinging boom. When comparing the stresses on the rig with the boom at 20\xb0 to the horizontal to the stresses when the boom is at 60\xb0 to the horizontal, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The thrust on the boom is greater at 60\xb0.",opb:"The stress on the topping lift is greater at 60\xb0.",opc:"The stress on the heel block is less at 20\xb0.",opd:"The stress on the head block is less at 60\xb0.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The deck load capacity of a compartment into which you intend to load a cargo of soft brick is 380 lbs. per sq. ft. The stowage factor of the brick is 21.3. Disregarding broken stowage, what is the maximum height the brick may be stacked without endangering the structure?",opa:"1.7 feet",opb:"3.6 feet",opc:"5.0 feet",opd:"7.1 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A 750 foot passenger vessel operating on the Great Lakes, not subject to SOLAS regulations, is required to carry how many ring life buoys?",opa:"24",opb:"18",opc:"12",opd:"6",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is equipped with mechanical davits. When stowing the lifeboat after a drill while underway, you should ____________.",opa:"leave the tricing pendants slack",opb:"ensure the falls are taut",opc:"leave the outboard part of the cradle in the down position",opd:"secure the inboard gripes only",ans:"opb"},{question:"With a large ocean tow in heavy weather, you should NOT ____________.",opa:"keep the stern of the tug well down in the water",opb:"adjust the towline so the tug is on the crest when the tow is in the trough",opc:"keep the low point of the catenary in the water",opd:"use a long towing hawser",ans:"opb"},{question:"The knot used to join two lines of different diameter is a ____________.",opa:"square knot",opb:"carrick bend",opc:"becket bend",opd:"sheepshank",ans:"opc"},{question:"While towing, what is the principal danger in attempting to swing a barge on a short hawser in order to slow the barge's speed?",opa:"The barge may capsize from the sharp turn.",opb:"The barge may swing too quickly and run over the tug.",opc:"Free surface effect of liquid inside the barge may rupture the barge bulkheads when turning too quickly.",opd:"Dangerous wakes may result from the swinging barge and capsize the tug.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which document lists all the lifesaving equipment required for a vessel?",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping Classification Certificate",opc:"International Convention for the Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opd:"Certificate of Registry",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a wedge of water builds up between the head of the barge and the bank it is referred to as ____________.",opa:"bank cushion",opb:"bank suction",opc:"bow wave",opd:"veering cushion",ans:"opa"},{question:"On your vessel, a wire rope for the cargo gear shows signs of excessive wear and must be replaced. In ordering a new wire for this 10-ton boom, what safety factor should you use?",opa:"Three",opb:"Five",opc:"Six",opd:"Seven",ans:"opb"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 76\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 59\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.35",opb:"0.47",opc:"0.76",opd:"0.79",ans:"opa"},{question:"The term 'Great Lakes', as defined by the Inland Rules of the Road, does NOT include ____________.",opa:"portions of the Chicago River",opb:"portions of the Calumet River",opc:"the St. Lawrence River to Trois Rivieres",opd:"Saginaw Bay",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are going astern (single-screw, right-handed propeller) with the anchor down at a scope of twice the depth of the water. As the anchor dredges, you should expect the ____________.",opa:"stern to walk to the same side as the anchor being used",opb:"vessel to back in a straight line",opc:"stern to walk to port but at a reduced rate",opd:"stern to walk to port at a faster rate than normal",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of chemical testing is NOT required of merchant marine personnel?",opa:"Pre-employment",opb:"Periodic",opc:"Random",opd:"Annual",ans:"opd"},{question:"The biggest problem you generally encounter while towing a single tow astern is ____________.",opa:"the catenary dragging on the bottom",opb:"swamping of the tow",opc:"the tow tending to dive",opd:"yaw",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT considered 'jewelry'?",opa:"Steamboat ratchets",opb:"Manila lines",opc:"Buttons",opd:"Shackles",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 92\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 85\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.75",opb:"0.81",opc:"0.84",opd:"0.88",ans:"opa"},{question:"An IOPP Certificate on an inspected vessel is valid for what period of time?",opa:"6 months",opb:"12 months",opc:"18 months",opd:"5 years",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Tonnage Certificate indicates ____________.",opa:"deadweight tons",opb:"displacement tons",opc:"net tons",opd:"light displacement tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The internal volume of a cargo hold measured from the inside faces of the cargo battens, the lower side of the deck beams, and the top of the tank top ceiling is known as the ____________.",opa:"gross tonnage",opb:"deadweight space",opc:"bale cubic",opd:"stowage area",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your 199 GT tugboat is on a 675 mile coastwise voyage. What percentage of the deck crew must be Able Bodied Seamen?",opa:"0",opb:"0.25",opc:"0.5",opd:"0.65",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a containership carrying a tank container that had been filled with sodium hydroxide solution. The container is empty but has not been cleaned. Which, if any, placard is required?",opa:"No placard is required; the tank openings must be sealed",opb:"Empty placard with corrosive placard",opc:"Residue label with the UN number",opd:"Black and white corrosive placard",ans:"opd"},{question:"To reduce stress on the towing hawser when towing astern (ocean tow), the hawser should be ____________.",opa:"secured to the aftermost fitting on the towing vessel",opb:"just touching the water",opc:"underwater",opd:"as short as possible",ans:"opc"},{question:"Why is 6X19 class wire rope more commonly used for cargo runners than the more flexible 6X37 wire rope?",opa:"It resists abrasion better.",opb:"It is longer.",opc:"It hugs the winch drum better.",opd:"It is less expensive.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What should be readily available on deck while seamen are working over the side on a stage?",opa:"Ring buoy",opb:"Fire extinguisher",opc:"First aid kit",opd:"Stokes basket",ans:"opa"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the sagging numeral.",opa:"72.42 numeral",opb:"78.98 numeral",opc:"83.46 numeral",opd:"91.48 numeral",ans:"opb"},{question:"Vertical structural members attached to the floors that add strength to the floors are called ____________.",opa:"boss plates",opb:"buckler plates",opc:"stiffeners",opd:"breast hooks",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your ship departed Venezuela for New York, loaded with 10,000 barrels of crude oil, whose average cargo temperature was 30\xb0C (86\xb0F). API is 25\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .00045. If this cargo is heated to 100\xb0F prior to discharge, how many barrels will you offload?",opa:"10315",opb:"10063",opc:"9937",opd:"9685",ans:"opb"},{question:"The National Cargo Bureau represents the ____________.",opa:"agent",opb:"operator",opc:"shipper",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is meant by the term 'luffing the boom' of a crane?",opa:"Stopping the boom",opb:"Topping or lowering the boom",opc:"Moving the boom left or right",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the purpose of cant frames in steel vessels?",opa:"To support the overhang of the stern",opb:"To provide strength to shell plating at the stern",opc:"To add strength to the deck beams which support the weather decks",opd:"To support the plating of a cylindrical tank",ans:"opb"},{question:"When loading a container vessel, the operation is basically that of vertical loading. The important factors to be considered when loading containers are port of discharge, ____________.",opa:"available dunnage, and chocking",opb:"crushability, and inherent vice",opc:"sweat, and weight",opd:"weight, and refrigeration",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel's Classification Certificate is issued by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"National Cargo Bureau",opc:"United States Coast Guard",opd:"United States Customs",ans:"opa"},{question:"What term indicates the immersed body of the vessel aft of the parallel mid-body?",opa:"Run",opb:"Stern",opc:"Counter",opd:"Flow",ans:"opa"},{question:"The letter M indicates a(n) ____________.",opa:"web frame",opb:"intercostal",opc:"stringer",opd:"cant frame",ans:"opa"},{question:"Static electricity may be built up by the ____________.",opa:"spraying or splashing of petroleum",opb:"settling of solids or water in petroleum",opc:"flow of petroleum through pipes",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A Danforth lightweight anchor does NOT hold well in which type of bottom?",opa:"Mud",opb:"Grass",opc:"Sand",opd:"Clay",ans:"opb"},{question:"A mooring line leading at nearly right angles to the keel is a ____________.",opa:"bow line",opb:"breast line",opc:"spring line",opd:"stern line",ans:"opb"},{question:"Naval authorities would NOT give orders about which of the following, when the vessel is under control of the Naval Control of Shipping Organization?",opa:"Visual communication at sea",opb:"Rescue operations",opc:"Diversions",opd:"Schedules for loading cargo",ans:"opd"},{question:"In a racetrack turn, to recover a man overboard, the vessel is steadied for the SECOND time after a turn of how many degrees from the original heading?",opa:"60\xb0",opb:"135\xb0",opc:"180\xb0",opd:"360\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"As Chief Officer of a vessel underway, it comes to your attention that the vessel is, in some manner, unseaworthy. Under such circumstances the Master is required to take action upon receiving ____________.",opa:"information of such condition from yourself",opb:"notification of such condition from yourself and the Second Officer",opc:"notification of such condition from yourself and any other member of the crew",opd:"notification of such condition from yourself or the Second Officer",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which space(s) is (are) deducted from gross tonnage to derive net tonnage?",opa:"Boatswain's stores",opb:"Companions and booby hatches",opc:"Passenger spaces",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"You must evacuate a seaman by helicopter lift. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The ship should be stopped with the wind off the beam while the helicopter is hovering overhead.",opb:"The basket or stretcher must not be allowed to touch the deck.",opc:"The tending line of the litter basket should be secured to the ship beyond the radius of the helicopter blades.",opd:"The hoist line should be slack before the basket or stretcher is hooked on.",ans:"opd"},{question:"After inventorying the Naval Control of Shipping publications you find there is no copy of ATP-2, Volume II 'Allied Control of Shipping Manual -Bridge Supplement'. You should ask for a replacement from the ____________.",opa:"Maritime Administration",opb:"Coast Guard",opc:"Chief of Naval Operations",opd:"local Operational Control Authority",ans:"opa"},{question:"How could lashing gear used aboard Ro Ro vessels be stowed when not in use?",opa:"Drape along brackets",opb:"Hang vertically in a sheltered area",opc:"Stow in bins at hatch coming side",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Laying out a line in successive circles flat on deck with the bitter end in the center is known as ____________.",opa:"coiling",opb:"faking",opc:"flemishing",opd:"lining",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which knot represents a double sheet bend?",opa:"F",opb:"L",opc:"R",opd:"T",ans:"opc"},{question:"If your propeller is racing in rough weather, you should ____________.",opa:"decrease your engine speed",opb:"ignore it",opc:"increase your engine speed",opd:"stop your engine until the rough weather passes",ans:"opa"},{question:"The distance that a ship moves forward with each revolution of its propeller, if there is no slip, is called ____________.",opa:"advance",opb:"head reach",opc:"pitch",opd:"transfer",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which structural members improve a towing vessel's chance of surviving punctured shell plating?",opa:"Stringers",opb:"Longitudinals",opc:"Transverse watertight bulkheads",opd:"The rake",ans:"opc"},{question:"The strongest method of forming an eye in wire rope is using ____________.",opa:"three wire rope clamps",opb:"an eye splice with four or five tucks",opc:"a thimble fastened with four or five tucks",opd:"a wire rope socket attached with zinc",ans:"opd"},{question:"Who is responsible for providing urine specimen collection kits to be used following a serious marine incident?",opa:"Qualified medical personnel",opb:"The marine employer",opc:"The U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"The local police department",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning the carriage of containers is TRUE?",opa:"The Chief Mate and Master of a container ship should have the proposed stowage plan ready for the stevedore upon arrival in port.",opb:"When stowed on deck of a break bulk ship, the bottom of the container must be evenly supported throughout.",opc:"With tiered containers, a 40-foot container may be stowed on top of two 20-foot containers.",opd:"Deck load calculations must take into account the square footage of the entire container bottom.",ans:"opc"},{question:"After an explosion, repair of emergency machinery and services should be accomplished ____________.",opa:"after control of fire, flooding, and structural repairs",opb:"immediately, before the emergency is under control",opc:"after control of fire, but before control of flooding",opd:"after stability is restored",ans:"opa"},{question:"When anchoring in calm water, it is best to ____________.",opa:"maintain slight headway when letting go the anchor",opb:"wait until the vessel is dead in the water before letting go the anchor",opc:"have slight sternway on the vessel while letting go the anchor",opd:"let the anchor go from the stern with the anchor cable leading from the bow",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which term describes a part of a natural fiber line?",opa:"Lacings",opb:"Lays",opc:"Strands",opd:"Twines",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel is found to be seaworthy after a complaint in writing to the American Consul by the Chief and Second Mates. The cost of the survey is to be paid by the ____________.",opa:"American Consul",opb:"Chief and Second Mates",opc:"Vessel's agent",opd:"vessel's owners",ans:"opb"},{question:"In small craft terminology, all of the anchor gear between a boat and her anchor is called the ____________.",opa:"stock",opb:"chock",opc:"scope",opd:"rode",ans:"opd"},{question:"The welds used to attach stiffeners to a plate are known as ____________.",opa:"butt welds",opb:"seam welds",opc:"fillet welds",opd:"plate welds",ans:"opc"},{question:"While assigned to a 90 GRT vessel, you are required to sign 'foreign' articles on a voyage from Philadelphia to which port?",opa:"San Francisco, CA",opb:"Baltimore, MD",opc:"Tampico, Mexico",opd:"Montreal, Canada",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Certificate of Inspection on a passenger vessel of over 100 gross tons must be posted ____________.",opa:"in the Master's office",opb:"on the bridge",opc:"in a conspicuous place where observation by the passengers is likely",opd:"in the passengers' dining room or, where there is no dining room, in the lounge area",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are a watch standing mate and have come to the bridge to relieve the watch. After reviewing the chart and having been briefed by the off-going mate, you are now ready to effect the relief. The watch is officially transferred to you after ____________.",opa:"you state the vessel's charted position, present course and port of destination",opb:"the mate being relieved tells you the vessel's course and speed and states that you have the watch",opc:"you say, 'I relieve you' and you state the course per gyro and magnetic compasses",opd:"the mate being relieved says, 'You have the conn' and you state the ship's course",ans:"opc"},{question:"The fitting at the end of a cargo line in a tank that allows suction to be taken close to the bottom of a tank is a ____________.",opa:"suction end",opb:"strainer",opc:"bell-mouth",opd:"vacuum valve",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which kind of hitch should you use to secure a spar?",opa:"Blackwall hitch",opb:"Stage hitch",opc:"Timber hitch",opd:"Two half hitches",ans:"opc"},{question:"A case received for shipment has the markings shown. Each carton measures 13' X 15' X 23'. What is the total cubic capacity the entire consignment will occupy if you assume 10% broken stowage?",opa:"779 cubic feet (22 cubic meters)",opb:"857 cubic feet (24 cubic meters)",opc:"1047 cubic feet (30 cubic meters)",opd:"112,125 cubic feet(3173 cubic meters)",ans:"opb"},{question:"It is the responsibility of the Master to ensure that ____________.",opa:"the muster list is posted in each compartment",opb:"temporary personnel and visitors are advised of emergency stations",opc:"names of crew members are listed on the muster list",opd:"no changes are made to the muster list",ans:"opb"},{question:"Litmus paste is used in order to determine ____________.",opa:"innage",opb:"thievage",opc:"ullage",opd:"the tank's datum point",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are docking a vessel. Wind and current are most favorable when they are ____________.",opa:"crossing your course in the same direction",opb:"crossing your course in opposite directions",opc:"parallel to the pier from ahead",opd:"setting you on the pier",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the name of the mark indicated by the letter F?",opa:"Fresh water load line",opb:"Summer load line",opc:"Winter load line",opd:"Tropical load line",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the dew point of the outside air is lower than or equal to the dew point of the air in the cargo hold, you should ____________.",opa:"secure all ventilation",opb:"shut down the exhaust blowers",opc:"shut down the intake blowers",opd:"ventilate the cargo holds",ans:"opd"},{question:"A weight of 1,000 short tons is equivalent to ____________.",opa:"1,500 foot-pounds",opb:"2,240 long tons",opc:"2,000 pounds",opd:"2,000 kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"A 'loose' tow may cause all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"loss of maneuverability",opb:"lines to part",opc:"damage to the towing vessel and tow",opd:"a saving in the transit time",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are signing on a crew. You can determine the minimum number and qualifications of the crew that you are required to carry by consulting which document?",opa:"Crew list",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Articles of Agreement",opd:"fo'c'sle card",ans:"opb"},{question:"While cranking out a quadrantal davit, slippage of the quadrant due to excessive wear or failure of the teeth in the quadrant will cause the ____________.",opa:"davit arm to pivot on the traveling nut and the head to fall outboard",opb:"traveling nut to lock up in place on the worm gear",opc:"limit switch to engage and hold the traveling nut in position",opd:"winch brake to lock in position and prevent lowering the boat",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about stopping a vessel is TRUE?",opa:"A lightly laden vessel requires as much stopping distance as a fully laden vessel when the current is from astern.",opb:"A vessel is dead in the water when the back wash from astern operation reaches the bow.",opc:"A tunnel bow thruster can be used in an emergency to reduce the stopping distance.",opd:"When a vessel is dead in the water any speed displayed by Doppler log reflects the current.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which line would be least likely to kink?",opa:"Braided",opb:"Left-handed laid",opc:"Right-handed laid",opd:"Straight laid",ans:"opa"},{question:"Disregarding friction, a twofold purchase when rove to disadvantage has a mechanical advantage of ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"5",ans:"opc"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'H' is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"forward breast line",opb:"offshore spring line",opc:"offshore bow line",opd:"onshore bow line",ans:"opc"},{question:"A Great Lakes vessel bound for Anticosti Island is exempt from the IMO Grain Regulations if the vessel meets all of the following standards EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"the metacentric height corrected for free surface must meet regulatory minimums throughout the voyage",opb:"slack surfaces should be in a mound",opc:"the longitudinal strength of the vessel must not be imperiled",opd:"the Master must ascertain the expected weather conditions enroute",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is used to prevent wear on towlines that bear on hard surfaces?",opa:"Chafing gear",opb:"Chocks",opc:"Grease",opd:"Boots",ans:"opa"},{question:"While steering by autopilot you notice that the vessel has deviated 15 degrees from course and there is no corrective rudder being applied. As a standard operating procedure you should first ____________.",opa:"check the setting of the rudder adjustment",opb:"check the setting of the weather adjustment",opc:"switch to hand steering",opd:"immediately engage the trick wheel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Following a Serious Marine Incident, a mariner involved in the incident is prohibited from consuming alcohol until after being tested or ____________.",opa:"2 hours following the incident",opb:"4 hours following the incident",opc:"8 hours following the incident",opd:"12 hours following the incident",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which publication is NOT carried on board U.S. merchant vessels operating under Naval Control of Shipping?",opa:"Allied Control of Shipping Manual -Guide to Masters",opb:"Communications Supplement",opc:"Tactical Control and Routing of Merchant Vessels",opd:"All of the above are carried on board",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many cubic feet of space is required to stow 775 tons of a cargo with a stowage factor of 25? (estimated broken stowage is 15%)",opa:"12916",opb:"22794",opc:"25833",opd:"29397",ans:"opb"},{question:"The main reason a long towline is used during an ocean tow is that ____________.",opa:"a margin of safety is provided should the line part",opb:"the towline will wear more evenly",opc:"there will be less stress on the towline",opd:"a slight increase in speed will be realized",ans:"opc"},{question:"The wooden plug inserted in the vent of a damaged tank should be removed if you are going to ____________.",opa:"pump from the damaged tank",opb:"fight a fire",opc:"abandon ship",opd:"use the crossover system",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 91\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 87\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.79",opb:"0.85",opc:"0.91",opd:"0.98",ans:"opb"},{question:"An icebreaker displaying a flag hoist which consists of the code letters 'WO' (Whiskey Oscar) is indicating that ____________.",opa:"icebreaker support is finished",opb:"icebreaker support is commencing",opc:"the icebreaker is icebound",opd:"the icebreaker is beset",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel's light displacement is 12,000 tons. Its heavy displacement is 28,000 tons. When fully loaded it carries 200 tons of fuel and 100 tons of water and stores. What is the cargo carrying capacity in tons?",opa:"11,700 tons",opb:"15,700 tons",opc:"16,000 tons",opd:"27,700 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"When towing astern, one way to reduce yawing of the tow is to ____________.",opa:"trim the tow by the stern",opb:"trim the tow by the head",opc:"have the tow on an even keel",opd:"list the tow on the side it is yawing",ans:"opa"},{question:"The term 'Great Lakes', as defined by the Inland Rules of the Road, includes part of the ____________.",opa:"Calumet River",opb:"Chicago River",opc:"St. Lawrence River",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are signing on crew members. The minimum number of people required aboard, and the qualifications of each, is listed on the ____________.",opa:"Crew list",opb:"fo'c'sle card",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Articles of Agreement",ans:"opc"},{question:"While assigned to a 150 GRT vessel, you are required to sign 'foreign' articles on a voyage from New Orleans to which port?",opa:"Houston, Texas",opb:"Veracruz, Mexico",opc:"Kingston, Jamaica",opd:"Cristobal Colon, Panama",ans:"opd"},{question:"After an IOPP Certificate is issued to an inspected vessel, how many other surveys of the vessel's pollution prevention equipment are conducted during the period of validity of the certificate?",opa:"None",opb:"One",opc:"Two",opd:"Three",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following requires the vessel to be dry-docked?",opa:"Verification of load line measurements",opb:"Inspection of the double bottoms",opc:"Inspection of tail shaft liner",opd:"Cleaning of the hull",ans:"opc"},{question:"A tug is best positioned for towing and maneuvering on rivers and other restricted waters where wave action is limited when ____________.",opa:"directly astern and pushing the tow",opb:"towing on a hawser",opc:"towing alongside and parallel to the vessel it is towing",opd:"towing on the hip",ans:"opa"},{question:"When anchoring, it is a common rule of thumb to use a length of chain ____________.",opa:"five to seven times the depth of water",opb:"seven to ten times the depth of water",opc:"twice the depth of water",opd:"twice the depth of water plus the range of tide",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which picture represents a blackwall hitch?",opa:"F",opb:"H",opc:"P",opd:"S",ans:"opd"},{question:"A texas bar ____________.",opa:"prevents the towing hawser from snagging any equipment or gear on deck",opb:"may be equipped with a greased, free sliding spool to fairlead the towing hawser",opc:"allows the crew access to the fantail",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 68\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 65\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.66",opb:"0.74",opc:"0.85",opd:"0.9",ans:"opc"},{question:"What equipment is customarily used when seamen are working on a stage rigged over the side of a vessel?",opa:"Jacob's ladder",opb:"Manropes",opc:"Heaving lines",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"In nautical terminology a 'dog' is a ____________.",opa:"crow bar",opb:"device to force a water tight door against the frame",opc:"heavy steel beam",opd:"wedge",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) when you wish to send a message concerning your ships diversion. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opb:"P (PRIORITY)",opc:"R (ROUTINE)",opd:"Z (FLASH)",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a coastwise tugboat of 199 GT, on a voyage over 600 miles, what percentage of the deck crew (excluding licensed officers) must hold a document of able seaman?",opa:"0.65",opb:"0.5",opc:"0.25",opd:"0",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT an advantage of double bottom ships?",opa:"The tank top forms a second skin for the vessel.",opb:"The center of gravity of a loaded bulk cargo ship may be raised to produce a more comfortable roll.",opc:"The floors and longitudinals distribute the upward push of the water on the ship's bottom.",opd:"They are less expensive to construct because of increased access space.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your ship departed Venezuela for New York, loaded with 10,000 barrels of crude oil, whose average cargo temperature was 30\xb0C (86\xb0F). API is 25\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .00045. If this cargo is heated to 100\xb0F prior to discharge, how many gallons will you offload?",opa:"417354",opb:"422646",opc:"546535",opd:"553465",ans:"opb"},{question:"The BEST information on the nature and extent of damage to the vessel is obtained from ____________.",opa:"alarms and monitoring devices",opb:"the engineroom watch",opc:"personnel at the scene of the damage",opd:"the bridge watch",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a Master must jettison a container loaded with hazardous material, he must, as soon as possible, notify the ____________.",opa:"National Cargo Bureau",opb:"Environmental Protection Agency",opc:"National Hazardous Chemical Response Center",opd:"nearest Captain of the Port",ans:"opd"},{question:"What term indicates the outward curvature of the hull above the waterline?",opa:"sheer",opb:"tumble home",opc:"deadrise",opd:"flare",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Honolulu (Christmas tree) tow was devised to ____________.",opa:"keep the catenary to a minimum",opb:"allow easy removal of a center tow",opc:"reduce hawser length",opd:"increase the catenary",ans:"opa"},{question:"The garboard strake is indicated by which letter?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"G",opd:"H",ans:"opd"},{question:"Ullage measurements are taken from the top of the liquid to ____________.",opa:"the base of the expansion trunk",opb:"the base of the ullage port",opc:"a line scribed within the ullage port",opd:"an above-deck datum, usually the top of the ullage hole",ans:"opd"},{question:"In order to back a right-handed, single-screw vessel in a straight line, you will probably need to use ____________.",opa:"very little rudder",opb:"some left rudder",opc:"some right rudder",opd:"full left rudder",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which mooring line prevents sideways motion of a vessel moored to a pier?",opa:"A line led forward from the bow",opb:"A line led aft from the bow",opc:"A line led in the same direction as the keel",opd:"A line led at a right angle to the keel",ans:"opd"},{question:"In a following sea, a wave has overtaken your vessel and thrown the stern to starboard. To continue along your original course, you should ____________.",opa:"use more right rudder",opb:"use more left rudder",opc:"increase speed",opd:"decrease speed",ans:"opa"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the sagging numeral.",opa:"89.75 numeral",opb:"40.18 numeral",opc:"28.62 numeral",opd:"22.44 numeral",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of bridle is the most effective for a heavy ocean tow?",opa:"Nylon because of its strength",opb:"Polypropylene because it floats and is easier to handle",opc:"Stud link anchor chain for chafe resistance and strength",opd:"Wire rope for flexibility and strength",ans:"opc"},{question:"The knot at the end of the heaving line used to pass the towing hawser is called a ____________.",opa:"monkey's fist",opb:"ball or baseball knot",opc:"heaving knot",opd:"three strand Turk's head",ans:"opa"},{question:"For a given weight of cargo, the stress on the heel block of a cargo boom ____________.",opa:"increases as the cargo closes the head while hoisting",opb:"increases if the cargo runner is doubled up",opc:"decreases as the boom is topped to a greater angle",opd:"is determined by the thrust stresses on the boom",ans:"opc"},{question:"Tripping defects in anchors frequently occur in ____________.",opa:"deep water",opb:"shallow water",opc:"stiff soils",opd:"soft soils",ans:"opd"},{question:"River currents tend to ____________.",opa:"pick up speed where the channel widens",opb:"run slower in the center of the channel",opc:"hug the inside of a bend",opd:"cause the greatest depth of water to be along the outside of a bend",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are using a racetrack turn to recover a man overboard. The vessel is first steadied when how many degrees away from the original heading?",opa:"60\xb0 to 70\xb0",opb:"90\xb0",opc:"135\xb0",opd:"180\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"Mooring lines should be turned end-for-end occasionally. This is because ____________.",opa:"a line is weakened by constantly pulling on it in one direction",opb:"normal wear on the line is thus distributed to different areas",opc:"it prevents the line from kinking or unlaying",opd:"it prevents permanent misalignment of the line's internal strands",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on watch at sea on course 090\xb0T. A man falls overboard on your starboard side. You immediately start a Williamson Turn. Which action is NOT a part of a Williamson Turn?",opa:"Stop the engines until clear of the man.",opb:"Come right full rudder until the vessel heads 150\xb0T.",opc:"Shift the helm to left full rudder.",opd:"Continue with left rudder until on course 270\xb0T.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which condition would NOT entitle a vessel to carry goods on deck?",opa:"The shipper agrees to deck stowage",opb:"The cargo will damage other cargoes by tainting or contamination",opc:"Deck stowage is required by law or regulation",opd:"Deck stowage is customary in the trade (i.e. timber cargoes)",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which space(s) is(are) deducted from gross tonnage to derive net tonnage?",opa:"Companions and booby hatches",opb:"Chart room",opc:"Open structures",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning a short splice is TRUE?",opa:"It is used to temporarily join two lines together.",opb:"A short splice is stronger than two lines joined by a knot.",opc:"A short splice decreases the diameter of the line.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the cargo manifest, the total weight of an empty cargo box is the ____________.",opa:"tare weight",opb:"net weight",opc:"gross weight",opd:"cargo weight",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT an advantage of filler cargo?",opa:"Overcarriage is reduced or eliminated.",opb:"Dunnage costs are reduced.",opc:"Voids in the cargo stow are filled.",opd:"The hold space has maximum utilization.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Safety equipment on board vessels must be approved by the ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"Safety Standards Bureau",opc:"Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA)",opd:"National Safety Council",ans:"opa"},{question:"A rolling hitch can be used to ____________.",opa:"make a temporary eye",opb:"mouse a hook",opc:"secure a line around a spar",opd:"shorten a line",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which is NOT a type of seizing?",opa:"Flat seizing",opb:"Racking seizing",opc:"Throat seizing",opd:"Tube seizing",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are preparing to lubricate standing rigging on your vessel. When rigging a bosun's chair on a stay with a shackle, ____________.",opa:"connect the shackle to the bosun's chair with a hook",opb:"never allow the shackle pin to ride on the stay",opc:"run the gantline through the shackle and then make fast to the bosun's chair",opd:"tie the bitter end of the gantline to the shackle before shackling it to the bosun's chair",ans:"opb"},{question:"Following a Serious Marine Incident, a mariner directly involved in the incident is required to submit to alcohol testing within ____________.",opa:"1 hour",opb:"2 hours",opc:"6 hours",opd:"12 hours",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have completed a crude oil wash. What action should be taken with the oil in the lines running to the washing machines?",opa:"Open a COW nozzle forward and one aft and drain the line into the after tank by gravity",opb:"Blow the line out using compressed air",opc:"Pull a suction using the supply line pump",opd:"Close off all valves in the system and leave the oil in the line primed for the next crude oil wash",ans:"opa"},{question:"Towing a structure using two tugs approximately side by side, each using one hawser, is referred to as a ____________.",opa:"tandem tow",opb:"Honolulu tow",opc:"breasted tug tow",opd:"tandem tug tow",ans:"opc"},{question:"When should you conduct a visual inspection of your towline?",opa:"Whenever its serviceability is in doubt.",opb:"In accordance with the manufacturer's recommendation.",opc:"At least once a month.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a transpacific voyage, you receive a message from your vessel's operators saying that your vessel has been consigned to Naval Control of Shipping. Further information is contained in ____________.",opa:"the Light List",opb:"the International Code of Signals (PUB 102)",opc:"Radio Navigational Aids (PUB 117)",opd:"the Coast Pilot",ans:"opc"},{question:"A rescue helicopter's hoist area should have a radius of at least ____________.",opa:"6 feet of clear deck",opb:"10 feet of clear deck",opc:"25 feet of clear deck",opd:"50 feet of clear deck",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel is to make a voyage between New York and San Juan, Puerto Rico, and return. The crew should be signed on ____________.",opa:"Coastwise Articles",opb:"Foreign Articles",opc:"Intercoastal Articles",opd:"no articles",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are a watch standing mate and have come to the bridge to relieve the watch. After reviewing the chart and having been briefed by the off-going mate, you are now ready to effect the relief. Which of the following is exemplary of the statement that would officially transfer the watch?",opa:"You say to the mate going off watch, 'Destination New York, course 283\xb0,speed 16 knots.'",opb:"The mate being relieved says, 'You now have the watch, course 147\xb0, speed15 knots.'",opc:"The mate being relieved says, 'All in apparent good order, course 068\xb0 per gyro, 075\xb0 per standard.'",opd:"You say to the mate going off watch, 'I relieve you, course 321\xb0 per gyro, 316\xb0 per standard.'",ans:"opd"},{question:"Oil product samples should be taken from the ____________.",opa:"dock riser",opb:"ship's cargo tanks",opc:"shore tank discharge",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which action reduces the yawing of a vessel in a following sea?",opa:"Increasing GM",opb:"Pumping out tanks aft",opc:"Shifting weights to the bow",opd:"Shifting weights to the stern",ans:"opd"},{question:"Faking a line means to ____________.",opa:"arrange it on deck in long bights",opb:"coil it down on deck",opc:"put a whipping on it",opd:"stow it below",ans:"opa"},{question:"A spring line leads ____________.",opa:"fore and aft from the ship's side",opb:"to the dock at a right angle to the vessel",opc:"through the bull nose or chock at the bow",opd:"through the chock at the stern",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel must have one approved ring life buoy on board if its length is over how many feet?",opa:"6 feet",opb:"16 feet",opc:"26 feet",opd:"36 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a vessel with a single right-hand propeller backs to port the ____________.",opa:"bow falls off to starboard",opb:"vessel moves to port without changing heading",opc:"bow swings to port",opd:"vessel moves to starboard without changing heading",ans:"opa"},{question:"Frames to which the tank top and bottom shell are fastened are called ____________.",opa:"floors",opb:"intercostals",opc:"stringers",opd:"tank top supports",ans:"opa"},{question:"A heavy steel curved arch constructed athwartships and above the after deck on a towing vessel is sometimes called a ____________.",opa:"main brace",opb:"texas bar",opc:"jockey bar",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A case received for shipment has the markings shown. Each carton measures 13' X 15' X 23'. What is the total cubic capacity the entire consignment will occupy? (Ignore broken stowage.)",opa:"779 cubic feet (22 cubic meters)",opb:"992 cubic feet (28 cubic meters)",opc:"1,047 cubic feet (30 cubic meters)",opd:"112,125 cubic feet(3173 cubic meters)",ans:"opa"},{question:"Sometimes it is desirable to connect a member both by riveting and welding. Which statement is TRUE concerning this procedure?",opa:"Tearing through the member is more likely in this type connection.",opb:"The weld may be broken by the stresses caused by riveting.",opc:"The weld increases the tensile stress on the rivet heads.",opd:"The welding must be completed before the riveting commences.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which factor is MOST important in preventing sweat damage within a cargo hold?",opa:"Dew point of the cargo hold",opb:"Dew point of the outside atmosphere",opc:"Outside air temperature",opd:"Temperature of the cargo",ans:"opa"},{question:"The effect of excessive catenary in shallow water may be ____________.",opa:"dragging the towing hawser along the bottom and chafing it",opb:"snagging sunken or submerged objects",opc:"slowing, stopping or endangering the towing operation by placing the tug in irons",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What will cause wire rope to fail?",opa:"Operating the winch too fast",opb:"Using a sheave 9 times the wire's diameter",opc:"Kinking",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which action(s) should the operator of a pedestal crane take if crane control is lost?",opa:"Let go of both control levers and return to neutral position.",opb:"Press the emergency stop.",opc:"Notify the mate on watch.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is going from a warm climate to a cold climate with a hygroscopic cargo. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You must ventilate constantly and vigorously to combat ship sweat.",opb:"You should ventilate; there is little danger of ship sweat, but a possibility of cargo sweat.",opc:"There is danger of heavy cargo sweat if you ventilate.",opd:"There is little danger of any sweat problem.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Besides the chemical testing of a mariner\u2019s breath for alcohol, what other specimen testing for alcohol is acceptable to be taken onboard the vessel after a Serious Marine Incident?",opa:"Saliva",opb:"Blood",opc:"Hair",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 98\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 87\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.87",opb:"0.84",opc:"0.79",opd:"0.64",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is required to launch a boat stowed in a crescent davit?",opa:"Hoist the boat clear of the cradle.",opb:"Release the outboard part of the cradle.",opc:"Rig the tricing lines.",opd:"Crank the crescent out.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is on an extended foreign voyage. Several vacancies have occurred in your unlicensed crew through sickness and repatriation. Which statement is correct?",opa:"Aliens may be employed except that all U.S. flag vessels must maintain no less than 90% U.S. citizens in the crew.",opb:"Qualified aliens may be employed to fill the vacancies.",opc:"Seamen to fill vacancies must be flown from U.S. to join the vessel in the foreign port.",opd:"Vacancies can only be filled by U.S. citizens with valid Merchant Mariner's Documents.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) and wish to send a message warning of a hurricane. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"R (ROUTINE)",opb:"Z (FLASH)",opc:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opd:"P (PRIORITY)",ans:"opc"},{question:"The opening in the deck beneath the anchor windlass that leads to the chain locker is the ____________.",opa:"hawsepipe",opb:"fallpipe",opc:"drop-pipe",opd:"spill pipe",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel reduces speed without backing. The rate that her speed through the water decreases depends primarily on the ____________.",opa:"vessel's horsepower",opb:"sea state",opc:"number of propellers",opd:"vessel's displacement",ans:"opd"},{question:"A bridle for an ocean tow consists of ____________.",opa:"two chains of equal length",opb:"a single nylon pendant rove through a heavy ring free to move on the pendant",opc:"two long legs of wire rope shackled to a fishplate",opd:"a single length of heavy chain with both ends secured on deck to welded pad eyes",ans:"opa"},{question:"The best time to work a boat into a slip is ____________.",opa:"when the wind is against you",opb:"with the current setting against you",opc:"at slack water",opd:"with a cross current",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's operators send a message that your vessel has been consigned to Naval Control of Shipping. The message will refer you to ____________.",opa:"the Light List",opb:"Radio Aids to Navigation (PUB 117)",opc:"the International Code of Signals (PUB 102)",opd:"the Coast Pilot",ans:"opb"},{question:"When anchoring in a current, you should ____________.",opa:"drop the anchor with the bow headed downstream",opb:"back your vessel into the current",opc:"anchor while stemming the current",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The tow makeup that is designed to keep the catenary of the tow hawser to a minimum is called the ____________.",opa:"Christmas tree tow",opb:"tandem tow",opc:"British tow",opd:"tandem tug tow",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel loads 100 tons of glass jars. The mate on watch discovers that some of the cartons have been damaged and has an exception made on the Bill of Lading. What is this document called?",opa:"Damage Bill of Lading",opb:"Letter of Indemnity",opc:"Non-negotiable Bill of Lading",opd:"Unclean Bill of Lading",ans:"opd"},{question:"In which case is the IOPP Certificate of an inspected vessel NOT invalidated?",opa:"The required oily-water separator malfunctions.",opb:"The ship is transferred to Liberian registry.",opc:"An annual survey is conducted fifteen months after the date of certificate issuance.",opd:"A 15 ppm oily-water separator is replaced by a 100 ppm oily-water separator.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are loading 530,000 barrels of cargo oil. At 0945 on 13 April, you find that you have loaded 202,000 barrels. At 1130, you find that you have loaded 223,000 barrels. If you continue at the same rate, you will finish at ____________.",opa:"1322, 13 April",opb:"1920, 13 April",opc:"1120, 14 April",opd:"1305, 14 April",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 6,000 barrels of gasoline, at a cargo temperature of 50\xb0F, departing New Jersey bound for Florida. API gravity is 55\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0006. How many barrels would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 90\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"5856",opb:"5982",opc:"6018",opd:"6144",ans:"opd"},{question:"The S.S. Sheet Bend arrives in New York after encountering heavy weather on a voyage from Cape Town. Who will note the maritime protest for the Master?",opa:"Collector of Customs",opb:"Notary Public",opc:"Officer in Charge Marine Inspection",opd:"U.S. Shipping Commissioner",ans:"opb"},{question:"When anchoring, good practice requires 5 to 7 fathoms of chain for each fathom of depth. In deep water you should use ____________.",opa:"the same ratio",opb:"more chain for each fathom of depth",opc:"less chain for each fathom of depth",opd:"two anchors with the same ratio of chain",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement about the carriage of solid hazardous materials in bulk is TRUE?",opa:"A special permit issued by the Coast Guard is required before bulk solid materials that require special handling are loaded.",opb:"Hazzardous materials that require separation must not be handled at the same time.",opc:"A certificate issued by ABS will be accepted as evidence that the vessel complies with all applicable loading regulations.",opd:"The shipping papers can be used in lieu of a Dangerous Cargo Manifest for a vessel carrying solid hazardous materials in bulk.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The distance between rivets in a row is known as the ____________.",opa:"arm",opb:"pitch",opc:"gage",opd:"rivet distance",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who would normally certify that all preparations have been made and all regulations observed prior to loading a cargo of bulk grain?",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"U.S. Coast Guard",opc:"National Cargo Bureau",opd:"Master of the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel is loaded to her summer marks for a voyage from Montreal, Canada to Duluth, MN via the Great Lakes System. The voyage has been estimated to take nine (9) days. If the vessel departs Montreal on September 28th, which of the following statements is TRUE?",opa:"The vessel must be at her summer marks when she arrives at Duluth.",opb:"The vessel is in violation of the load line requirements.",opc:"The vessel's intermediate load line marks may not be submerged after September 30.",opd:"The vessel must be at her winter marks by the evening of the third day.",ans:"opc"},{question:"It is NOT advisable to use nylon for alongside towing because it ____________.",opa:"stretches too much",opb:"is too difficult to make fast",opc:"parts too readily",opd:"is too susceptible to mildew",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which knot shown is a French bowline?",opa:"L",opb:"T",opc:"Q",opd:"W",ans:"opb"},{question:"The strake of shell plating indicated by letter H is known as the ____________.",opa:"sheer strake",opb:"outboard keel plate",opc:"garboard strake",opd:"bilge strake",ans:"opc"},{question:"Uncleared crew curios remaining on board during a domestic coastwise voyage after returning from foreign should be ____________.",opa:"listed in the Official Logbook",opb:"cleared prior to the next foreign voyage",opc:"noted in the Traveling Curio Manifest",opd:"retained under locked security by the owner",ans:"opc"},{question:"The 'Port-Off-Stbd' selector switch on an autopilot steering stand is used to ____________.",opa:"change from hand electric steering to automatic gyro",opb:"change over one steering system to the other",opc:"change over hand electric steering to non-follow-up",opd:"change over the port to the starboard bow thruster",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tow that veers to the side on the end of the towline is said to ____________.",opa:"yaw",opb:"surge",opc:"sway",opd:"swing",ans:"opa"},{question:"What term indicates an inward curvature of the ship's hull above the waterline?",opa:"Camber",opb:"Tumble home",opc:"Deadrise",opd:"Flare",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many turns of wire normally mark either side of the detachable link 45 fathoms from the anchor?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the difference between net tonnage and gross tonnage?",opa:"Net tonnage is the gross tonnage less certain deductions for machinery and other areas.",opb:"Net tonnage is tonnage of cargo compared to tonnage of whole ship.",opc:"Net tonnage is the net weight of the ship.",opd:"There is no difference.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 76\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 58\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.31",opb:"0.47",opc:"0.61",opd:"0.76",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of a threefold purchase when rove to disadvantage and neglecting friction?",opa:"3",opb:"4",opc:"5",opd:"6",ans:"opd"},{question:"When may a seaman on a vessel engaged in foreign trade be paid before earning the wages?",opa:"The seaman may only draw an advance on earned wages.",opb:"Wages up to fifty percent of the seaman's base wage maybe advanced upon proof of serious family illness.",opc:"Wages equivalent to three days base wage may be advanced upon arrival in a foreign port.",opd:"The advance of wages is at the discretion of the master; however, a seaman cannot be in an overpaid status at signoff.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When evacuating a seaman by helicopter lift, which course should the ship take?",opa:"Downwind so that the apparent wind is close to nil.",opb:"A course that will keep a free flow of air, clear of smoke, over the hoist area.",opc:"A course that will have the hoist area in the lee of the superstructure.",opd:"With the wind dead ahead because the helicopter is more maneuverable when going into the wind.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who cannot commit the crime of barratry?",opa:"Master",opb:"Ship's officer(s)",opc:"Ship's unlicensed crewmember(s)",opd:"Ship owner",ans:"opd"},{question:"A safety shackle is identified by its ____________.",opa:"shape",opb:"pin",opc:"certification stamp",opd:"color code",ans:"opb"},{question:"After your vessel has been involved in a casualty, you are required to make your logbooks, bell books, etc., available to ____________.",opa:"attorneys for opposition parties",opb:"marine surveyors",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard officials",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which splice should you use in order to make a permanent loop in a line?",opa:"Back splice",opb:"Eye splice",opc:"Long splice",opd:"Short splice",ans:"opb"},{question:"A snag or other underwater obstruction may form a ____________.",opa:"V-shaped ripple with the point of the V pointing upstream",opb:"V-shaped ripple with the point of the V pointing downstream",opc:"small patch of smooth water on a windy day",opd:"smoothing out of the vessel's wake",ans:"opa"},{question:"The boat is stowed on the davit rather than on a cradle with which type of davit?",opa:"Crescent",opb:"Sheath-screw boom",opc:"Quadrantal",opd:"Radial",ans:"opa"},{question:"Whipping the bitter end of a fiber rope ____________.",opa:"increases the circumference of the rope",opb:"makes for easier handling",opc:"prevents fraying of the bitter end",opd:"prevents moisture from entering the bitter end",ans:"opc"},{question:"The best method to stop a vessel from dragging anchor in a sand bottom is to ____________.",opa:"reduce the length of the cable",opb:"pay out more anchor cable",opc:"back the engines",opd:"swing the rudder several times to work the anchor into the bottom",ans:"opb"},{question:"The internal volume of a cargo hold measured from the inside of the side shell, the underside of the deck, and the tank top is known as the ____________.",opa:"gross tonnage",opb:"deadweight space",opc:"measurement space",opd:"grain cubic",ans:"opd"},{question:"A tow bridle is attached to the main tow hawser at the ____________.",opa:"bight ring",opb:"tow hook",opc:"fishplate",opd:"swivel",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is meant by 'thieving' a petroleum cargo?",opa:"Siphoning off a few barrels of petroleum for shipboard use",opb:"Determining the amount of water (if any) in each cargo tank",opc:"Adjusting the cargo figures to coincide with the draft",opd:"Reducing the gross cargo calculations to net amounts",ans:"opb"},{question:"What welding pattern is NOT used to permanently attach a stiffener to a plate?",opa:"Chain intermittent",opb:"Tack",opc:"Continuous",opd:"Staggered intermittent",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is NOT an advantage of the flush method of welded shell plating?",opa:"Reduces weight",opb:"Reduces frictional resistance",opc:"Keeps practically 100% of tensile strength at the joints",opd:"Reduces plate stress",ans:"opd"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the hogging numeral.",opa:"101.02 numeral",opb:"91.36 numeral",opc:"72.43 numeral",opd:"52.79 numeral",ans:"opd"}],this.data4=[{question:"What does item 'E' refer to in this illustration of a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Tagline",opb:"Electric cable",opc:"Cargo snaking wire",opd:"Hook release cable",ans:"opa"},{question:"A 'sheepshank' is used to ____________.",opa:"keep a line from fraying",opb:"join lines of unequal size",opc:"stop off a line",opd:"shorten a line",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT required to be approved or certified by the U.S. Coast Guard before being used on inspected vessels?",opa:"Lifesaving equipment that is in excess of the regulatory minimum",opb:"Ship's stores that are Class A poisons or Class A explosives",opc:"Steel plate used in hull construction",opd:"EPIRBs",ans:"opc"},{question:"To determine the weight capacity of a deck in a cargo hold, you would refer to the ____________.",opa:"deadweight scale",opb:"deck capacity plan",opc:"cubic capacity tables",opd:"general arrangement plan",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has been damaged and is partially flooded. The first step to be taken in attempting to save the vessel is to ____________.",opa:"establish flooding boundaries and prevent further spread of flood water",opb:"plug the hole(s) in the outer shell",opc:"pump out the water inside the vessel",opd:"calculate the free surface effect and lost buoyancy to determine the vessel's stability",ans:"opa"},{question:"What type of stopper would you use on a nylon mooring line?",opa:"Chain",opb:"Nylon",opc:"Manila",opd:"Wire",ans:"opb"},{question:"The number of certificated able seamen and lifeboat men required on board is listed in the ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping code",opc:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opd:"Safety of Life at Sea Convention",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) and wish to send a message concerning an initial enemy contact. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"Z (FLASH)",opb:"P (PRIORITY)",opc:"R (ROUTINE)",opd:"O (IMMEDIATE)",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel is equipped with twin propellers, both turning outboard with the engines half ahead. If there is no wind or current and the rudders are amidships, what will happen?",opa:"The bow will swing to starboard.",opb:"The bow will swing to port.",opc:"The vessel will steer a zigzag course.",opd:"The vessel will steer a fairly straight course.",ans:"opd"},{question:"What would you use to adjust the height of a cargo boom?",opa:"Lizard",opb:"Spanner guy",opc:"Topping lift",opd:"Working guy",ans:"opc"},{question:"While underway in thick fog you are on watch and hear the cry 'man overboard'. Which type of maneuver should you make?",opa:"figure eight turn",opb:"Round turn",opc:"Racetrack turn",opd:"Williamson turn",ans:"opd"},{question:"In ship construction, frame spacing is ____________.",opa:"greater at the bow and stern",opb:"reduced at the bow and stern",opc:"uniform over the length of the vessel",opd:"uniform over the length of the vessel, with the exception of the machinery spaces, where it is reduced due to increased stresses",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on an ice-reinforced vessel about to enter pack ice. You should ____________.",opa:"enter the pack on the windward side where there is a well defined ice edge",opb:"trim to an even keel or slightly down by the bow to take maximum benefit of the ice reinforcement",opc:"take maximum advantage of coastal leads caused by offshore winds",opd:"look for areas of rotten ice and enter perpendicular to the ice edge",ans:"opd"},{question:"When cleaning a tank by the Butterworth process, you should begin to pump out the slops ____________.",opa:"at the end of the drop schedule",opb:"when the process is started",opc:"when the process is finished",opd:"when the tank is clean",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are trying to rescue survivors from a wrecked vessel on fire. You should approach ____________.",opa:"to leeward of the wrecked vessel",opb:"at a speed of at most one-half that of the wrecked vessel",opc:"at a speed of at least that of the wrecked vessel",opd:"to windward of the wrecked vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the difference between net tonnage and gross tonnage?",opa:"Net tonnage is the gross tonnage less certain deductible spaces.",opb:"Net tonnage is tonnage of cargo compared to tonnage of whole ship.",opc:"Net tonnage is gross tonnage minus engine and bunker spaces.",opd:"Net tonnage is the net weight of the ship.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is correct concerning the carriage of coal in bulk?",opa:"Coal should be vented with surface ventilation only.",opb:"Because of its inherent vice, coal should not be loaded wet.",opc:"Dunnage should be placed against ship's sides and around stanchions.",opd:"Through ventilation, as well as surface ventilation, should be provided whenever possible.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are making a sharp turn in a channel and using a buoy four points on the bow to gauge your rate of turn. If you observe the buoy moving forward relative to you, what should you do?",opa:"Increase the rate of turn",opb:"Decrease the rate of turn",opc:"Maintain a constant rate of turn",opd:"Increase speed",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel is not required to carry urine specimen collecting kits onboard the vessel only if the individuals directly involved in a Serious Marine Incident can be tested ashore within?",opa:"12 hours",opb:"24 hours",opc:"32 hours",opd:"48 hours",ans:"opc"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the sagging numeral.",opa:"29.70 numeral",opb:"33.63 numeral",opc:"49.82 numeral",opd:"58.33 numeral",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a small passenger vessel the collision bulkhead is ____________.",opa:"amidships forward of the engine room",opb:"just forward of the steering compartment",opc:"in the engine room",opd:"A distance of 5% to 15% of the waterline length abaft the stem measured at the load waterline",ans:"opd"},{question:"The equipment used to control, protect and connect a towline is called ____________.",opa:"cat head",opb:"terminal gear",opc:"level wind",opd:"poured socket",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT an advantage of ship construction methods using welded butt joints in the shell plating?",opa:"Keeps practically 100% of tensile strength at the joints",opb:"Reduces frictional resistance",opc:"Reduces plate stress",opd:"Reduces weight",ans:"opc"},{question:"When maneuvering from pull towing to breasted (alongside) towing, a twin-screw vessel is more likely than a single-screw vessel of equal horsepower to ____________.",opa:"trip or capsize",opb:"foul the towline",opc:"go into irons",opd:"part the towing strap",ans:"opb"},{question:"Oil may NOT be transferred unless ____________.",opa:"there are two certificated tankermen on each vessel",opb:"the vessel is equipped with constant-tension winches",opc:"discharge containment equipment (i.e. drip pans) are in place",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"A metal object on the pier resembling a tree stump and made to receive mooring lines is a ____________.",opa:"bight",opb:"bollard",opc:"chock",opd:"camel",ans:"opb"},{question:"A monkey fist is found on a ____________.",opa:"heaving line",opb:"lead line",opc:"manrope",opd:"mooring line",ans:"opa"},{question:"Hygroscopic cargoes should be ventilated when ____________.",opa:"going from a warm to a cold climate",opb:"the dew point of the outside air is greater than the dew point of the air in the hold",opc:"the dew point of the air in the hold is very low",opd:"the outside dew point is 60\xb0F (16\xb0C) and the cargo temperature is 54\xb0F (12\xb0C)",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT accepted as the required shipping papers on a manned and loaded tank barge?",opa:"Bill of Lading",opb:"Manifest",opc:"Shipping document",opd:"Logbook entry",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the accepted standard for wire rope falls used in connection with the lifeboat gear?",opa:"Six by seven galvanized wire rope",opb:"Six by twenty-four improved plow steel wire rope",opc:"Six by thirty-seven preformed fiber-core wire rope",opd:"Six by nineteen regular-lay filler wire rope",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is a spill pipe?",opa:"A drainage pipe that carries rain or spray from an upper deck to a lower deck",opb:"A pipe under the anchor windlass leading to the chain locker",opc:"A chute, usually over the stern, to lead dumped garbage clear of the hull",opd:"An opening in the deck leading outside the hull",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which knot reduces the strength of a line by the LEAST amount?",opa:"Carrick bend",opb:"Square knot",opc:"Sheet bend",opd:"Bowline",ans:"opd"},{question:"An icebreaker assisting a vessel through an ice field would display a visual signal consisting of the code letter 'E' (Echo) to signify that '__________'.",opa:"I am altering my course to starboard",opb:"I am altering my course to port",opc:"I am operating astern propulsion",opd:"My vessel is stopped and making no way through the water",ans:"opa"},{question:"The major components which determine the length of catenary in a deployed anchor cable are cable tension, cable weight, and ____________.",opa:"water density",opb:"bottom conditions",opc:"environmental forces",opd:"water depth",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are backing on twin engines with rudders amidships. Your starboard engine stalls. To continue backing on course, you should ____________.",opa:"apply left rudder",opb:"apply right rudder",opc:"increase your engine speed",opd:"keep your rudder amidships",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a transpacific voyage, you receive a message from your vessel's operators saying that your vessel has been consigned to Naval Control of Shipping. Further information is contained in ____________.",opa:"Radio Aids to Navigation (PUB 117)",opb:"the Coast Pilot",opc:"the International Code of Signals (PUB 102)",opd:"the Light List",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which item is rigged to transmit the thrust from one barge to another when backing down?",opa:"I",opb:"H",opc:"C",opd:"B",ans:"opc"},{question:"When passing a hawser to the dock you would first use what line?",opa:"Gantline",opb:"Heaving line",opc:"Preventer",opd:"Warp",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which wire rope purchase(s) is/are optional with a 30-Ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Hoist",opb:"Luff",opc:"Rider block",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 58\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 53\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.56",opb:"0.61",opc:"0.66",opd:"0.72",ans:"opd"},{question:"A situation has occurred in which your vessel must be towed. When the towing vessel passes the towing line to you, you should secure the line ____________.",opa:"to the base of the foremast",opb:"to the forward-most bitts",opc:"to the forward part of the deckhouse",opd:"at the stern",ans:"opb"},{question:"Rivets are usually made of ____________.",opa:"wrought-iron",opb:"aluminum",opc:"high-tensile steel",opd:"mild steel",ans:"opd"},{question:"A shipper of cargo aboard your vessel offers a letter of indemnity for the cargo. This is done in order to obtain a(n) ____________.",opa:"Clean Bill of Lading",opb:"Order Bill of Lading",opc:"Straight Bill of Lading",opd:"Through Bill of Lading",ans:"opa"},{question:"You can safely step in the bight of a line ____________.",opa:"when it is not under strain",opb:"if both ends are made fast",opc:"in an emergency",opd:"at no time",ans:"opd"},{question:"Sour crude oil ____________.",opa:"contains high quantities of hydrogen sulfide",opb:"is diluted with other products for carriage",opc:"is lighter than other crudes",opd:"is less hazardous to load than other crudes",ans:"opa"},{question:"A short splice in a line ____________.",opa:"decreases the size of the line",opb:"should be used if the line is going through a block",opc:"should only be used in wire rope",opd:"doubles the size of the line",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a single-screw vessel with a right-handed propeller. The vessel is going full speed astern with full right rudder. The bow will swing ____________.",opa:"quickly to port, then more slowly to port",opb:"probably to port",opc:"slowly to port, then quickly to starboard",opd:"probably to starboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which position shown is the most dangerous when tying up?",opa:"I",opb:"II",opc:"III",opd:"IV",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a small boat, which knot is best suited for attaching a line to the ring of an anchor?",opa:"Clove hitch",opb:"Figure-eight knot",opc:"Fisherman's bend",opd:"Overhand knot",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are proceeding to a distress site and expect large numbers of people in the water. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You should stop to windward of the survivors in the water and only use the ship's boats to recover the survivors.",opb:"If the survivors are in inflatable rafts you should approach from windward to create a lee for the survivors.",opc:"An inflatable liferaft secured alongside can be an effective boarding station for transfer of survivors from the boats.",opd:"Survivors in the water should never be permitted alongside due to the possibility of injury from the vessel.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Yawing can be described as ____________.",opa:"jumping on the towline as the tow pitches",opb:"jumping on the towline as the tow slams into waves",opc:"veering from side to side on the end of the towline",opd:"corkscrew motion of the tow due to wave action",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement about a tunnel bow thruster is TRUE?",opa:"It provides lateral control without affecting headway.",opb:"It is fully effective at speeds up to about six knots.",opc:"It can be used to slow the ship in addition to backing down.",opd:"It will allow you to hold a position when the current is from astern.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is meant by the term 'topping the boom'?",opa:"Lowering the boom",opb:"Raising the boom",opc:"Spotting the boom over the deck",opd:"Swinging the boom athwartships",ans:"opb"},{question:"What imminent danger results from tripping?",opa:"The barge(s) collide with the stern",opb:"Capsizing your tug",opc:"Your tug being pulled backwards by your tow",opd:"The stern of the tug submerges causing flooding into engine room",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel is constructed with a steel hull and an aluminum superstructure. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The aluminum will provide greater resistance to the spread of fire by conduction.",opb:"The aluminum structure is usually attached to a steel coaming by a method that insulates the two metals.",opc:"If the superstructure is stressed, an aluminum structure requires additional expansion joints to prevent fracture.",opd:"The steel at the area of the aluminum-to-steel connection must be closely checked for galvanic corrosion.",ans:"opb"},{question:"It is not advisable to use nylon for alongside towing because it ____________.",opa:"stretches too much",opb:"is too expensive for everyday towing usage",opc:"binds on the cleats",opd:"parts too readily",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's operators send a message that your vessel has been consigned to Naval Control of Shipping. The message will refer you to ____________.",opa:"Radio Aids to Navigation (PUB 117)",opb:"the Coast Pilot",opc:"the International Code of Signals (PUB 102)",opd:"the Light List",ans:"opa"},{question:"On stud-link anchor chain the addition of the stud increases the strength of the link by about ____________.",opa:"0.1",opb:"0.15",opc:"0.2",opd:"0.5",ans:"opb"},{question:"In moderate wind and current what should be the length of chain with a single anchor?",opa:"5 times the depth of the water in good holding ground",opb:"10 times the depth of the water in shallow water",opc:"2 times the depth of the water in poor holding ground",opd:"8 times the depth of the water in deep water",ans:"opa"},{question:"The supplement to the IOPP Certificate contains what type of data?",opa:"The grades of cargo that an oil tanker is permitted to carry.",opb:"A checklist of the equipment installed for controlling the discharge of oil.",opc:"The trade routes upon which the vessel may operate.",opd:"A list of the underwriters who will assume financial responsibility in the event of an oil spill.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A seam is indicated by which letter in illustration D033DG?",opa:"E",opb:"H",opc:"L",opd:"M",ans:"opa"},{question:"Considering the manning requirements for U.S. vessels, your three watch cargo vessel has a deck crew of 20 people, exclusive of the officers. How many of these people do the manning regulations require to be Able Seamen?",opa:"13",opb:"10",opc:"7",opd:"5",ans:"opa"},{question:"You will load and carry a bulk cargo of sulfur at ambient temperature. Which statement is true?",opa:"Wooden covers must be laid over the bilge wells to prevent the sulfur from entering the bilges.",opb:"Bulk sulfur may be carried without a special permit providing the vessel complies with all applicable regulations.",opc:"The major characteristic of this cargo is that it forms sulfuric acid upon contact with water.",opd:"Other hazardous material may not be stowed in the same hold as the sulfur but may be carried on deck above the hold.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the hogging numeral.",opa:"91.42 numeral",opb:"85.60 numeral",opc:"79.23 numeral",opd:"74.73 numeral",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are loading 475,000 barrels of cargo oil. At 0800 on 8 July, you find that you have loaded 174,000 barrels. At 1000, you find that you have loaded 192,000 barrels. If you continue loading at the same rate, you will finish at approximately ____________.",opa:"1752, 8 July",opb:"1940, 8 July",opc:"0143, 9 July",opd:"1727, 9 July",ans:"opd"},{question:"The 'rolling hitch' could be used to ____________.",opa:"join two lines of different sizes",opb:"join two lines of equal sizes",opc:"add strength to a weak spot in a line",opd:"act as a stopper to transfer a line under strain",ans:"opd"},{question:"The 'Mode' selector switch on the autopilot steering stand is used to select any of the following with the EXCEPTION of ____________.",opa:"automatic pilot steering",opb:"hand-electric steering",opc:"non-follow-up steering",opd:"rudder adjustment",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement concerning a 298 GRT inspected tug engaged in towing from Seattle, WA, to Alaska is TRUE?",opa:"A licensed Master of Towing Vessels may serve as Master.",opb:"Crew must be signed on before a Shipping Commissioner.",opc:"Each crew member must be issued a certificate of discharge at the time of discharge.",opd:"No able seamen are required.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) and wish to send a message by rapid transmission which does not require a higher precedence. Which precedence would you assign this message?",opa:"R (ROUTINE)",opb:"P (PRIORITY)",opc:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opd:"Z (FLASH)",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which can be prevented only by segregating two lots of cargo into separate holds?",opa:"Contamination of dry cargo by a wet cargo",opb:"Contamination of a clean cargo by a dirty cargo",opc:"Contamination of a food cargo by an odorous cargo",opd:"Overcarriage, overstowage, and short landing",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which knot should be used to send a man over the side when he may have to use both hands?",opa:"Bowline",opb:"French bowline",opc:"Bowline on a bight",opd:"Running bowline",ans:"opb"},{question:"The type of welding employed in shipyards is primarily ____________.",opa:"brazing",opb:"electric arc",opc:"pressure welding",opd:"thermite welding",ans:"opb"},{question:"To ensure the best results during the Mediterranean moor, the chains should ____________.",opa:"be crossed around the bow",opb:"tend out at right angles to the bow",opc:"tend aft 60\xb0From each bow",opd:"tend forward 30\xb0 on either bow",ans:"opd"},{question:"What does item 'G' refer to in this illustration of a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Mast",opb:"Pillar",opc:"Turntable",opd:"Pedestal",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which part of an anchor actually digs into the bottom?",opa:"Stock",opb:"Fluke",opc:"Shank",opd:"Crown",ans:"opb"},{question:"The stowage factor for a cargo is based upon ____________.",opa:"one short ton",opb:"one short metric ton",opc:"one long ton",opd:"one long metric ton",ans:"opc"},{question:"What does item 'D' refer to in this illustration of a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Heel block",opb:"Gin block",opc:"Rider block",opd:"Hook block",ans:"opd"},{question:"While on duty as a look-out, which other duty may you perform?",opa:"Sweep down the fo'c'sle",opb:"Paint any area near your station",opc:"Overhaul a block, as long as it is at your look-out station",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A holder of a license as Master of towing vessels may work each 24 hours for a period not to exceed ____________.",opa:"6 hours",opb:"12 hours",opc:"18 hours",opd:"24 hours",ans:"opb"},{question:"A seaman leaves a vessel before it sails from a foreign port. He informs the Chief Officer that he won't return. After the vessel sails, the Chief Officer finds the seaman's work clothes in his locker. How should the Master handle this matter?",opa:"Log the seaman as a deserter.",opb:"Log the seaman as a fail to join.",opc:"Log the seaman for misconduct.",opd:"Take no action.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When towing in an open seaway, it is important to use a towing line ____________.",opa:"made only of wire rope, due to possible weather conditions",opb:"that will have the tow on a crest while your vessel is in a trough",opc:"that will have the tow on a crest while your vessel is on a crest",opd:"with little dip to gain maximum control of the tow",ans:"opc"},{question:"The exact and complete identification of all cargo on board must be found on the ____________.",opa:"Cargo Manifest",opb:"Mate's Receipt",opc:"Hatch Report",opd:"Loading List",ans:"opa"},{question:"Instead of whipping an end of a line, a temporary means of preventing the line from unraveling is to tie a ____________.",opa:"becket bend",opb:"blackwall hitch",opc:"figure-eight knot",opd:"square knot",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is a cofferdam?",opa:"Tube fitted to an ullage hole",opb:"Area the product is loaded into",opc:"Void or empty space separating two tanks",opd:"Opening in the deck used for cleaning a tank",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is required to be posted in the pilothouse of a vessel?",opa:"Official Crew List",opb:"Company Mission Statement",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Maneuvering Characteristics",ans:"opd"},{question:"The space above the engine room is called the ____________.",opa:"fidley",opb:"gold locker",opc:"middle hatch",opd:"noble",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which party must ensure that legal work hour limitations (for both officers and crew members), rest periods and regulations governing work on Sundays and holidays are followed when the vessel is in a safe harbor?",opa:"The owner of the vessel",opb:"The company operating the vessel",opc:"The Master of the vessel",opd:"The company chartering the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"A breeches buoy is being rigged from the shore to a stranded vessel. The initial shot line passed to the vessel is normally made fast to a ____________.",opa:"hawser which is used to pass a tail-block and whip to the vessel",opb:"hawser with breeches buoy and harness attached",opc:"hawser which should be made fast to the vessel below the intended location of the tail-block",opd:"tail-block and whip which may be used to pass a hawser to the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the knots, bends, or hitches shown in the illustration would you use to properly secure a bosun's chair to a gantline?",opa:"I",opb:"P",opc:"R",opd:"X",ans:"opc"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the hogging numeral.",opa:"49.73 numeral",opb:"52.76 numeral",opc:"55.29 numeral",opd:"57.93 numeral",ans:"opa"},{question:"When cleaning cargo tanks with portable machines, how is the machine grounded?",opa:"Bonding wires are secured from the machine to a convenient location on deck.",opb:"The machines must maintain physical contact with the deck at the Butterworth opening.",opc:"The water supply hoses contain internal wires that act as conductors",opd:"The water jets impinging on the vessel's structure form a pathway to ground.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The process of lowering a boom to a horizontal position and onto its deck support is called ____________.",opa:"spotting a boom",opb:"collaring a boom",opc:"cradling a boom",opd:"toppling a boom",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement about general average is TRUE?",opa:"Damage to a ship must have been incurred while the ship and/or its machinery was being used for its intended purpose.",opb:"Property must have been sacrificed or an expenditure of money incurred.",opc:"The loss or damage to deck cargo due to heavy weather constitutes general average.",opd:"Of the ship, the freight, and the cargo interests, only one need be involved.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is a solid at ambient temperature?",opa:"Aniline",opb:"Formic acid",opc:"Methyl chloride",opd:"Napthalene",ans:"opd"},{question:"Barges and vessels are ballasted before departure to ____________.",opa:"improve their stability",opb:"avoid polluting waters where liquid ballast may not be discharged",opc:"prevent free surface effects",opd:"allow movement of liquids within the barge for tank cleaning",ans:"opa"},{question:"A U.S. vessel engaged in foreign trade must be ____________.",opa:"classed",opb:"enrolled",opc:"licensed",opd:"registered",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are the licensed operator of a 100 GT towing vessel sailing coastwise. What percentage of the deck crew must be able to understand the language commonly used onboard the vessel?",opa:"1",opb:"0.75",opc:"0.65",opd:"0.5",ans:"opb"},{question:"A 'liner' in riveted construction of a vessel is a(n) ____________.",opa:"small plate which fills the aperture between riveted strakes and the vessel framing",opb:"backing plate which is used to level the strakes while riveting, and then removed",opc:"internal frame to which the side shell is riveted",opd:"seam that is welded after riveting is completed",ans:"opa"},{question:"When loading bulk liquid cargo, what is the FIRST action you should take if a cargo valve jammed open?",opa:"Trip the pump relief valve.",opb:"Order the dock man to shut down.",opc:"Call the owner, operator, or terminal supervisor.",opd:"Run out the vessel's or terminal's fire hose.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE about using a wire bridle on an ocean tow?",opa:"The inboard end of each bridle leg should have a large eye splice to fit over the bitts.",opb:"The strength of each leg should be at least one-half that of the main towing hawser.",opc:"Each leg should be at least 60 to 90 feet long.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"One of your crew members falls overboard from the starboard side. You should IMMEDIATELY ____________.",opa:"apply left rudder",opb:"throw the crew member a life preserver",opc:"begin backing your engines",opd:"position your vessel to windward and begin recovery",ans:"opb"},{question:"A bollard is found on the ____________.",opa:"beach",opb:"deck",opc:"pier",opd:"towed vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Reinforcing frames attached to a bulkhead on a vessel are called ____________.",opa:"side longitudinals",opb:"intercostals",opc:"stiffeners",opd:"brackets",ans:"opc"},{question:"A welded joint's effectiveness is considered ____________.",opa:"0.48",opb:"0.9",opc:"1",opd:"1.21",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the situation arose where it became necessary to tow a disabled vessel, which statement is TRUE concerning the towing line?",opa:"The towing line between the two vessels should be clear of the water.",opb:"The towing line should be taut at all times between the vessels.",opc:"There should be a catenary so the line dips into the water.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The opening in the deck that leads the anchor cable outside the hull is the ____________.",opa:"hawsepipe",opb:"fall pipe",opc:"drop-pipe",opd:"spill pipe",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a single-screw vessel, when coming port side to a pier and being set off the pier, you should ____________.",opa:"swing wide and approach the pier so as to land starboard side to",opb:"approach the pier on a parallel course at reduced speed",opc:"make your approach at a greater angle than in calm weather",opd:"point the vessel's head well up into the slip and decrease your speed",ans:"opc"},{question:"The machinery associated with heaving in and running out anchor chain is the ____________.",opa:"winch",opb:"windlass",opc:"draw works",opd:"dynamic pay out system",ans:"opb"},{question:"Sweat damage will occur in a cargo hold containing cased machinery when the ____________.",opa:"air temperature of the hold is higher than the temperature of the outside air",opb:"dew point of the hold is higher than the temperature of the ship's skin",opc:"dew point of the outside air is lower than the temperature of the cargo",opd:"outside air temperature is colder than the temperature of the cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which cargoes require strips of common building lathe as dunnage in order to carry away heat generated by the cargo?",opa:"Canned soups packaged in crates",opb:"Cardboard cartons of shoes",opc:"Paper products packaged in rolls",opd:"Refrigerated fruit that is ripening",ans:"opd"},{question:"If an electric cargo winch is being used to lift a draft of cargo and the engine room loses all power, which will occur?",opa:"A pawl, forced by a spring mechanism, will engage the teeth of the bull gear and hold the load.",opb:"An electromagnetic brake will hold the load where it is suspended.",opc:"The load will fall rapidly to the deck unless the foot brake is engaged.",opd:"The load will slowly lower to the deck under control of the drag of the winch motor.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which safety check(s) should be made before letting go the anchor?",opa:"See that the anchor is clear of obstructions.",opb:"See that the chain is all clear.",opc:"See that the wildcat is disengaged.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What part of the ground tackle is the most likely to develop fractures due to extensive anchor use?",opa:"Anchor shank",opb:"Swivel",opc:"Jews' harp",opd:"Fluke",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which knot is suitable for hoisting an unconscious person?",opa:"Bowline on a bight",opb:"Fisherman's loop",opc:"French bowline",opd:"Spider hitch",ans:"opc"},{question:"Defense plans may cause the operation of electronic aids to navigation to be suspended with ____________.",opa:"no notice",opb:"one day's notice",opc:"a week's notice",opd:"thirty (30) days notice",ans:"opa"},{question:"When using a Mediterranean Moor, the vessel is moored with her ____________.",opa:"bow to the pier",opb:"anchors crossed",opc:"anchor chains forward, side to the pier",opd:"stern to the pier",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your twin-screw vessel is moving ASTERN with rudders amidships. The starboard screw suddenly stops turning. Your vessel's head will ____________.",opa:"go to port",opb:"go to starboard",opc:"remain stationary",opd:"suddenly drop down",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which entry on a dangerous cargo manifest concerning the classification of a cargo is NOT correct?",opa:"Class 8",opb:"Division 3.1",opc:"Division 2.3",opd:"All of the above are incorrect",ans:"opb"},{question:"A racetrack turn would be better than a Williamson turn in recovering a man overboard if ____________.",opa:"the man has been missing for a period of time",opb:"the sea water is very cold and the man is visible",opc:"there is thick fog",opd:"the wind was from astern on the original course",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning lifeboat installations on Great Lakes vessels?",opa:"All davit installations shall have 3 lifelines fitted to a davit span.",opb:"All vessels over 3,000 gross tons must be fitted with gravity davits.",opc:"All lifelines shall be able to reach the water at the vessel's lightest draft with a 20\xb0 list.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The original Bill of Lading, once signed by the Master, is NOT ____________.",opa:"a receipt and proof that goods have been received on board",opb:"surrendered to the customs agency of the country where the cargo is discharged",opc:"used to transfer ownership of the cargo while the ship is enroute",opd:"proof of title or ownership of the cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"The certificate of loading required by each vessel carrying grain in bulk is issued by the ____________.",opa:"owner or charterer of the vessel",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"shipper of the cargo",opd:"National Cargo Bureau",ans:"opd"},{question:"Flanking rudders effect a vessel's heading because of the ____________.",opa:"effect of the propeller flow on the rudders",opb:"water flow due to the vessel's movement through the water",opc:"tunnel affect of the water flow past opposing rudders",opd:"discharge current being channeled to impinge on the vessel's deadwood",ans:"opa"},{question:"Where, due to the arrangement of the vessel, lifejackets may become inaccessible, additional lifejackets shall be carried ____________.",opa:"for the people on bridge watch",opb:"for the forward lifeboats",opc:"as determined by the OCMI",opd:"for 50% of the crew of the vessel, not including those assigned to engineering duties",ans:"opc"},{question:"To find the distance the strands should be unlaid for an eye splice, multiply the diameter of the wire in inches by ____________.",opa:"12",opb:"24",opc:"36",opd:"48",ans:"opc"},{question:"The standard unit of liquid volume used in the petroleum industry, as well as the tanker industry, is a ____________.",opa:"barrel",opb:"drum",opc:"gallon",opd:"liter",ans:"opa"},{question:"A snatch block would most likely be used as a ____________.",opa:"boat fall",opb:"fairlead",opc:"riding pawl",opd:"topping lift",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning the handling characteristics of a fully loaded vessel as compared with those of a light vessel is FALSE?",opa:"A fully loaded vessel will be slower to respond to the engines.",opb:"A fully loaded vessel will maintain her headway further.",opc:"A light vessel will be more affected by the wind.",opd:"A light vessel loses more rudder effect in shallow water.",ans:"opd"},{question:"When being towed by one tug, the towing bridle should be connected to towing ____________.",opa:"bitts with figure eights",opb:"pad eyes with pelican hooks",opc:"pad eyes with safety hooks",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 85\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 73\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.42",opb:"0.56",opc:"0.67",opd:"0.85",ans:"opb"},{question:"In which casualty case is it UNNECESSARY to notify the local Coast Guard Marine Safety Office?",opa:"A seaman is injured and in the hospital for four days.",opb:"Nylon mooring line parts while the vessel is tied up and kills a harbor worker who was on the pier.",opc:"Your vessel is backing from a dock and runs aground, but is pulled off by tugs in 30 minutes.",opd:"Your vessel strikes and sinks an anchored sailboat costing a total of$20,000 for salvage and repair.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is an example of failure to exercise due diligence?",opa:"Overloading",opb:"Sailing short of union manning requirements",opc:"Sailing with less than 30% reserve fuel oil supply",opd:"Sailing short of being full and down",ans:"opa"},{question:"In general, a reinforced vessel can safely navigate in ice provided the concentration does not exceed how many tenths?",opa:"1-2 tenths",opb:"3-4 tenths",opc:"5-7 tenths",opd:"8-9 tenths with ice breaker assistance",ans:"opc"},{question:"The safe working load for the assembled cargo gear and the minimum angle to the horizontal for which the gear is designed shall be marked on the ____________.",opa:"deck",opb:"head of the boom",opc:"heel of the boom",opd:"mast or king post",ans:"opc"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated FLASH will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"10 minutes",opb:"3 hours",opc:"30 minutes",opd:"6 hours",ans:"opa"},{question:"When towing, a tow hook is used to ____________.",opa:"provide quick release of the hawser",opb:"pull a tow alongside",opc:"attach a hawser to a tow which has no bitts or pad eyes",opd:"join two hawsers for lengthening a tow",ans:"opa"},{question:"A tow astern is veering from side to side on its towline. The best way of controlling the action is to ____________.",opa:"trim the tow by the bow",opb:"trim the tow by the stern",opc:"list the tow to windward",opd:"adjust the length of the towing bridle",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which factor(s) must you consider when making up a towing bridle?",opa:"The horsepower of the tug",opb:"The beam of the barge",opc:"The weight of the tow",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The joint indicated by letter D is a ____________.",opa:"seam",opb:"butt",opc:"span",opd:"sheet line",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master may require part of the crew to work when needed for ____________.",opa:"maneuvering, shifting berth, mooring and unmooring",opb:"performing work necessary for the safety of the vessel, its passengers, crew or cargo",opc:"performing fire, lifeboat or other drills in port or at sea",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"While loading cargo, a white trimming light on the starboard side comes on. This indicates that ____________.",opa:"the vessel has a list of about 1` to starboard",opb:"the chutes should be directed to the starboard side",opc:"the chutes in No. 1 hold should be directed to the starboard side",opd:"a severe list to starboard has developed and all loading should cease",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Certificate of Freeboard is the ____________.",opa:"Load Line Certificate",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Admeasurer's Certificate",opd:"Forecastle Card",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are proceeding under NCS (Naval Control of Shipping) and wish to send a message by rapid transmission which does not require a higher precedence. Which precedence would you assign this transmission?",opa:"O (IMMEDIATE)",opb:"Z (FLASH)",opc:"P (PRIORITY)",opd:"R (ROUTINE)",ans:"opd"},{question:"When anchoring a vessel under normal conditions, which scope of chain is recommended?",opa:"Four times the depth of water",opb:"Two and one-half times the depth of water",opc:"Five to seven times the depth of water",opd:"Fifteen times the depth of water",ans:"opc"},{question:"A 'figure eight' knot is used to ____________.",opa:"be a stopper",opb:"shorten a line",opc:"join lines of equal size",opd:"keep a line from passing through a sheave",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which weakens a line the LEAST?",opa:"Clove hitch",opb:"Long splice",opc:"Short splice",opd:"Square knot",ans:"opc"},{question:"What provides little or no indication that a vessel is dragging anchor?",opa:"Changing range to an object abeam",opb:"Drift lead with the line tending forward",opc:"The cable alternates between slack and heavy tension",opd:"Changing bearing to a fixed distant object abeam",ans:"opa"},{question:"All entries in the Official Logbook must be signed by the Master and ____________.",opa:"the Union Representative",opb:"the person about whom the entry concerns",opc:"no one else",opd:"one other crew member",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is used to prevent twisting of a towing bridle?",opa:"A bitt",opb:"A bulkhead",opc:"A V-spring",opd:"A fishplate",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in the process of loading 465,000 barrels of cargo oil. At 1030, on 5 November, you gauge the vessel and find that you have loaded 203,000 barrels. At 1200 you find that you have loaded 218,000 barrels. If you continue loading at the same rate, you will finish at approximately ____________.",opa:"1510, 5 November",opb:"1104, 6 November",opc:"1242, 6 November",opd:"0735, 7 November",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lines led forward from the bow and aft from the stern when a vessel is moored to the dock are ____________.",opa:"bow and stern lines",opb:"breast lines",opc:"halyards",opd:"warps",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning hawser towing?",opa:"The catenary in a hawser should be sufficient so that the hawser just touches the bottom.",opb:"The hawser is of sufficient length for towing when taut between tug and tow.",opc:"Increasing speed usually increases the catenary in the hawser.",opd:"Shortening the tow hawser generally decreases the maneuverability of the tug.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Odorous cargoes are those that ____________.",opa:"are susceptible to damage by tainting",opb:"are exceptionally dusty and leave a residue",opc:"are liquid, but in containers",opd:"give off fumes that may damage other cargoes",ans:"opd"},{question:"Segregation of cargoes refers to ____________.",opa:"separating cargoes so that the inherent characteristics of one cannot damage the other",opb:"separating cargoes by destination",opc:"classifying cargoes according to their toxicity",opd:"listing the cargoes in order of their flammability",ans:"opa"},{question:"The cheek length of a block in inches should be about ____________.",opa:"three times the circumference of a manila line",opb:"five times the diameter of a manila line",opc:"twice the diameter of its sheaves for manila line",opd:"twenty times the diameter of a manila line",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 1?",opa:"0.5",opb:"1",opc:"1.5",opd:"2",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following is/are the optional component(s) of a twin crane set as shown?",opa:"Boom assembly",opb:"Hook block assembly",opc:"Rider block tagline system",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"A crack in the deck plating of a vessel may be temporarily prevented from increasing in length by ____________.",opa:"cutting a square notch at each end of the crack",opb:"drilling a hole at each end of the crack",opc:"slot-welding the crack",opd:"welding a doubler over the crack",ans:"opb"},{question:"Signs of racking stresses generally appear at the ____________.",opa:"bow and stern shell frames and plating",opb:"junction of the frames with the beams and floors",opc:"garboard strake, at each side of the keel",opd:"thrust bearing of the main shaft",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many legs does the bridle for an ocean tow have?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opb"},{question:"What does item 'C' refer to in this illustration of a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Equalizing beam",opb:"Hoist fall spreader",opc:"Rider block",opd:"Block/hook assembly",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which weld fault can only be detected by a method that examines the internal structure of a weld?",opa:"Undercut",opb:"Lack of reinforcement",opc:"Overlap",opd:"Lack of penetration",ans:"opd"},{question:"The vertical motion of a floating vessel is known as ____________.",opa:"surge",opb:"sway",opc:"heave",opd:"yaw",ans:"opc"},{question:"A proper look-out must be kept ____________.",opa:"only in fog",opb:"only between the hours of sunset and sunrise",opc:"only when entering and leaving port",opd:"at all times",ans:"opd"},{question:"A licensed Master of Towing Vessels may NOT serve as the Captain of which towing vessel?",opa:"99 GRT towing vessel operating on Chesapeake Bay",opb:"199 GRT towing vessel operating in the Gulf of Alaska",opc:"400 GRT towboat operating on the Western Rivers",opd:"375 GRT towing vessel operating between Texas and Puerto Rico",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a sea going towing vessel of 150 gross tons, there are six (6) seamen in the deck crew. How many certificated able seamen are required if the voyage is over 600 miles?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opd"},{question:"As operator of a 199 GT towing vessel sailing foreign, it shall be your duty to enter in the Official Logbook or other permanent record ____________.",opa:"all information contained on the barge's Certificate of Inspection",opb:"the condition of all towing gear to be used",opc:"all navigational aids to be used",opd:"the barges load line and draft readings",ans:"opd"},{question:"Prior to being able to sail, each vessel that carries grain in bulk must have a certificate of loading issued by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Lloyds of London",opc:"National Cargo Bureau",opd:"U.S. Salvage",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are approaching the pilot station with the wind fine on the starboard bow and making about 3 knots. You can help to calm the seas by taking what action just before the pilot boat comes along on the port side?",opa:"Backing full",opb:"Stopping the engines",opc:"Giving right full rudder",opd:"A short burst of ahead full with left full rudder",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the knots, bends, or hitches shown in the illustration would you use to properly secure a bosun's chair to a gantline?",opa:"G",opb:"I",opc:"Q",opd:"R",ans:"opd"},{question:"The part of a windlass which physically engages the chain during hauling or paying out is the ____________.",opa:"devil's claw",opb:"bull gear",opc:"wildcat",opd:"cat head",ans:"opc"},{question:"The flash point of vinyl chloride is ____________.",opa:"-108\xb0F (-78\xb0C)",opb:"-20\xb0F (-29\xb0C)",opc:"32\xb0F (0\xb0C)",opd:"97\xb0F (36\xb0C)",ans:"opa"},{question:"With the exception of a Coast Guard approved commercial hybrid Personal Flotation Device (PFD), which type of life preserver must be carried for each person on board an uninspected passenger vessel?",opa:"Type I",opb:"Type II",opc:"Type III",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have water washed your cargo tanks using the fixed machines. What should you do before using portable machines to clean areas screened from the wash of the fixed machine by structural members?",opa:"Ventilate the tank to eliminate any electrostatically charged mist.",opb:"Attach the water supply hose to the portable machine after the cleaning head is positioned inside the tank.",opc:"Insure that the tanks are not stripped until the final wash is started.",opd:"Ground the fixed machines to eliminate any electrostatic buildup on the cleaning head.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which type of ballast is most commonly used in barges and ships?",opa:"Water",opb:"Oil",opc:"Concrete and barite",opd:"Sand, rock and gravel",ans:"opa"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated IMMEDIATE will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"30 minutes",opb:"3 hours",opc:"6 hours",opd:"10 minutes",ans:"opa"},{question:"The revolving drum of a winch used to haul lines is called a ____________.",opa:"bull gear",opb:"gypsyhead",opc:"spanner",opd:"wildcat",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel is involved in a casualty. The cost of property damage includes the ____________.",opa:"loss of revenue while the vessel is being repaired, up to a maximum of $50,000",opb:"cost of labor and material to restore the vessel to the service condition which existed before the casualty",opc:"damage claims awarded to individuals or companies involved in the casualty, up to a maximum of$50,000",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"What should NOT be used as an indicator that ice may be nearby?",opa:"A dark appearance of the sky",opb:"A gradual drop in sea water temperature to below 32\xb0F",opc:"A yellowish glare in the sky",opd:"The presence of seals or certain type birds",ans:"opa"},{question:"Every entry required to be made in the Official Logbook shall be signed by the ____________.",opa:"Mate on watch",opb:"Master and Chief Mate or other member of the crew",opc:"Master only",opd:"Purser, one of the Mates, and some other member of the crew",ans:"opb"},{question:"Gross tonnage indicates the vessel's ____________.",opa:"displacement in metric tons",opb:"total weight including cargo",opc:"volume in cubic feet",opd:"draft in feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A deck fitting, used to secure line or wire rope, consisting of a single body with two protruding horns is called a ____________.",opa:"bitt",opb:"bollard",opc:"capstan",opd:"cleat",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about the dangerous cargo manifest is FALSE?",opa:"The manifest must be made up by the carrier, agents, and any person designated for this purpose.",opb:"Shipments of hazardous and non-hazardous cargoes may be listed on the manifest if they are destined for the same consignee.",opc:"The manifest must be kept in a designated holder on or near the bridge.",opd:"The hazard class of each cargo must be indicated.",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the cargo manifest, the weight of the cargo inside a box is called ____________.",opa:"gross weight",opb:"net weight",opc:"light weight",opd:"rate weight",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement about a vessel's stability while dry-docking is TRUE?",opa:"Every ton of weight bearing on the blocks acts as if a ton of weight was removed at keel level.",opb:"When the ship touches the blocks, the beam for stability purposes increases to the beam of the dry-dock.",opc:"The stability of the vessel increases as a dock is pumped out due to the support of the keel blocks.",opd:"As the dock begins to support the weight of the vessel, stability calculations are based on the ship and dock as a single unit.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Pinching of the cargo hose between the vessel and the dock should be prevented by ____________.",opa:"adjusting the hose supports",opb:"laying out an excess length of hose on deck",opc:"tying off the topping lifts and runners to winch heads",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"When carrying a full or nearly full load of bulk ore in a general cargo type vessel which has engine spaces amidships, the cargo in each hold should be trimmed so that the bulk of the cargo lies ____________.",opa:"along the centerline",opb:"toward the forward bulkhead of the forward holds and toward the after bulkhead of the after holds",opc:"toward the after bulkhead of the forward holds and the forward bulkhead of the after holds",opd:"toward the after bulkhead of all holds",ans:"opc"},{question:"A fire has damaged 20 bales of cotton on a freighter loaded with general cargo. This claim would come under ____________.",opa:"constructive total loss",opb:"general average",opc:"particular average",opd:"total loss of a part",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which would you NOT use to report the amount of anchor chain out? 'Three shots ____________.'",opa:"at the water's edge",opb:"on deck",opc:"on the bottom",opd:"well in the water",ans:"opc"},{question:"The owner or Master of a towing vessel must evaluate whether the entire towline, or a part of it, is no longer serviceable. The towline should be removed from service in all cases EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"when recommended by the manufacturer or an authorized classification society",opb:"in accordance with a replacement schedule",opc:"when the vessel is underway",opd:"depending on the mileage or time that the towline has been in service",ans:"opc"},{question:"Many sheath-screw davits have markings to indicate the maximum angle to which they should be cranked out. If the angle is exceeded, the davit ____________.",opa:"may jam against the stops",opb:"will not automatically position the boat at the embarkation station",opc:"screw may come out of the sheath",opd:"will chafe against the falls and may cause their failure",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are proceeding at a slow speed with your starboard side near the right bank of a channel. If your vessel suddenly sheers toward the opposite bank, the best maneuver would be ____________.",opa:"full ahead, hard left rudder",opb:"full ahead, hard right rudder",opc:"full astern, hard left rudder",opd:"full astern, hard right rudder",ans:"opb"},{question:"A 'Mediterranean moor' should be used when ____________.",opa:"when anchoring in the Mediterranean",opb:"when docking stern to a berth",opc:"when docking bow to a berth",opd:"when anchoring in a strong current",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which category of able seaman is not authorized to be counted as an able seaman on a seagoing tug of over 100 gross tons?",opa:"Unlimited",opb:"Limited",opc:"Special",opd:"Special (OSV)",ans:"opd"},{question:"The type of joint formed when a third small plate is riveted over two plates butted together is called a ____________.",opa:"butted joint",opb:"lap joint",opc:"strap joint",opd:"stringer joint",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which operating procedure(s) should be adhered to on a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"One officer assigned to oversee the initial loading and lashing",opb:"All lashings should be completed before leaving port",opc:"Periodic inspection and re-tensioning of lashings during the voyage",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A 'barrel' is a unit of liquid measure equivalent to ____________.",opa:"40 U.S. gallons at 50\xb0F",opb:"42 U.S. gallons at 60\xb0F",opc:"43 U.S. gallons at 65\xb0F",opd:"45 U.S. gallons at 75\xb0F",ans:"opb"},{question:"In preparation for receiving chilled reefer cargo, the reefer space has been precooled for over twenty-four hours. Loading may begin when the space has been cooled to a temperature between ____________.",opa:"-10\xb0F (-23\xb0C) and+10\xb0F (-12\xb0C)",opb:"12\xb0F (-11\xb0C) and20\xb0F (-7\xb0C)",opc:"28\xb0F (-2\xb0C) and40\xb0F ( 4\xb0C)",opd:"42\xb0F (6\xb0C) and 55\xb0F (13\xb0C)",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are going ahead on twin engines with rudder amidships. Your starboard engine stalls. To continue on course, you should ____________.",opa:"apply left rudder",opb:"apply right rudder",opc:"increase engine speed",opd:"keep your rudder amidships",ans:"opa"},{question:"After riveting is completed, the joints on the shell of a vessel are generally made watertight by ____________.",opa:"faying",opb:"caulking",opc:"felt or canvas packing",opd:"red lead",ans:"opb"},{question:"A snatch block is a ____________.",opa:"block used only with manila rope",opb:"chock roller",opc:"hinged block",opd:"strong block used for short, sharp pulls",ans:"opc"},{question:"Electric cargo winches have an overload safety device which normally cuts the current to the winch motor ____________.",opa:"after torque causes line pull to exceed the rated capacity of the winch",opb:"before the line pull reaches the rated capacity of the winch",opc:"when the line pull reaches the breaking strength of the fall",opd:"before the safe working load of the fall is reached",ans:"opa"},{question:"A claim for cargo damages may be held against the ship owner if such damage is the result of failure of the ship's officers to ____________.",opa:"correct all defects in the ship's construction",opb:"ensure the fitness and safety of cargo spaces",opc:"ensure adequate packaging of the cargo",opd:"prevent delays due to quarantine restrictions",ans:"opb"},{question:"What descriptive term indicates that the dimension is measured from the inner face of the shell or deck plating?",opa:"Molded",opb:"Register",opc:"Tonnage",opd:"Effective",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is underway and approaching an overhead obstruction on Lake Superior. Given the following information, determine the clearance between your vessel and the obstruction. Highest point on vessel: 74 ft. Lowest point of obstruction: 126 (LWD) Monthly lake level: +2 (LWD) International Great Lakes Datum: 600.0 (182.88 meters)",opa:"474 feet",opb:"400 feet",opc:"175 feet",opd:"50 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"One major advantage of the round turn maneuver in a man overboard situation is that it ____________.",opa:"is the fastest method",opb:"is easy for a single-screw vessel to perform",opc:"requires the least shiphandling skills to perform",opd:"can be used in reduced visibility",ans:"opa"},{question:"Keel scantlings of any vessel are greatest amidships because ____________.",opa:"connections between forebody and afterbody are most crucial",opb:"of maximum longitudinal bending moments",opc:"of severest racking stresses",opd:"resistance to grounding is at a maximum amidships",ans:"opb"},{question:"When picking up your mooring at the buoy, the correct method is to ____________.",opa:"approach the buoy with the wind and current astern",opb:"approach the buoy with the wind and current ahead",opc:"approach the buoy with wind and sea abeam",opd:"stop upwind and up current and drift down on the buoy",ans:"opb"},{question:"A licensed Master of Towing Vessels may NOT serve as the person in charge of which towing vessel?",opa:"99 GRT towing vessel operating on Chesapeake Bay",opb:"199 GRT towing vessel operating in the Gulf of Alaska",opc:"500 GRT towboat operating on the Western Rivers",opd:"349 GRT towing vessel operating between Florida and Puerto Rico",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about tunnel bow thrusters fitted to large vessels is TRUE?",opa:"They are effective on most vessels at speeds up to 10 knots.",opb:"Because of their location, most modern installations have as much power as a tug.",opc:"They are fully effective at all drafts.",opd:"When going astern at slow speed, they provide effective steering control.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel in Great Lakes service shall carry anchors in accordance with standards established by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Canadian Coast Guard",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"underwriter of the vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are in charge of a 225-gross ton tug preparing to depart from Houston, Texas, with a loaded 2500-gross ton tank barge bound for New York. Prior to departure, regulations require that you ____________.",opa:"record the status of all firefighting equipment",opb:"record the barge's load line and draft readings",opc:"record the condition of the towing gear",opd:"have on board an Official Logbook in lieu of other forms of records",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the cargo manifest, the gross weight of a box containing cargo is the weight of the ____________.",opa:"cargo",opb:"box",opc:"cargo and box",opd:"rate weight",ans:"opc"},{question:"A chain stripper is used to ____________.",opa:"prevent chain from clinging to the wildcat",opb:"clean the marine debris from the chain",opc:"flake chain from a boat's chain locker",opd:"clean chain prior to an x-ray inspection",ans:"opa"},{question:"The joint formed when two steel plates are placed end-to-end is called a ____________.",opa:"bevel",opb:"seam",opc:"butt",opd:"bond",ans:"opc"},{question:"A seaman is entitled by law to a release from Foreign Articles when ____________.",opa:"intoxicated",opb:"deductions are made from wages",opc:"injured",opd:"the vessel is overloaded",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is a TRUE statement concerning the examining of cargo equipment at the time of a vessels Inspection for Certification.",opa:"Cargo booms must be weight tested at this time by the U.S. Coast Guard.",opb:"Cargo booms must be weight tested at this time by the American Bureau of Shipping.",opc:"Cargo booms must be weight tested at this time by the National Cargo Bureau.",opd:"No test at this time is required.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A report of casualty to a vessel must include ____________.",opa:"the estimated cost of damage",opb:"an evaluation of who was at fault",opc:"the amount of ballast on board",opd:"the name of the owner or agent of the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"The standing part of a tackle is ____________.",opa:"all the fall except the hauling part",opb:"the hook that engages the weight to be moved",opc:"that part to which power is applied",opd:"that part of the falls made fast to one of the blocks",ans:"opd"},{question:"When checking a mooring line, you should ____________.",opa:"ensure the bight is not fouled between the ship and the dock by taking up slack",opb:"pay out slack smartly and keep free for running",opc:"secure more turns to hold the line against any strain, then clear the area",opd:"surge the line so that it maintains a strain without parting",ans:"opd"},{question:"By paying out more anchor cable, you ____________.",opa:"decrease the holding power of your anchor",opb:"decrease the swing of your vessel while at anchor",opc:"increase the holding power of your anchor",opd:"increase the possibility that your vessel will drag anchor",ans:"opc"},{question:"At the establishment of Naval Control of Shipping (NCS), ships at sea will ____________.",opa:"stop and await further orders",opb:"attempt to make their way to the nearest port of a friendly nation and await further instructions",opc:"continue voyages unless in danger areas defined in the advisory or supplemental message",opd:"keep radio silence",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 84\xb0, and the wet bulb temperature is 81\xb0, what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.71",opb:"0.79",opc:"0.81",opd:"0.88",ans:"opd"},{question:"Back-up wires on a towed vessel provide ____________.",opa:"a factor of safety",opb:"additional strength",opc:"a distribution of the towing load",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A butt is indicated by which letter?",opa:"J",opb:"F",opc:"E",opd:"D",ans:"opd"},{question:"The biggest problem encountered when towing bridle legs are too short is ____________.",opa:"retrieval",opb:"adjusting tension",opc:"excessive strain",opd:"hookup to main towline",ans:"opc"},{question:"A 'spring line' is a ____________.",opa:"mooring line made of spring lay wire rope",opb:"mooring line running diagonally to the keel",opc:"mooring line parallel to the keel",opd:"wire rope used for securing an anchor buoy",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which line cannot be spliced?",opa:"Braided line with a hollow core",opb:"Double-braided line",opc:"Braided line with a solid core",opd:"Any line can be spliced",ans:"opc"},{question:"The legs of a tow bridle are joined together with a ____________.",opa:"bridle plate",opb:"shackle",opc:"fishplate",opd:"tri-link",ans:"opc"},{question:"Buckler plates are ____________.",opa:"triangular-shaped plates connecting the bull chain to the topping lift",opb:"metal plates secured over the tops of the hawsepipes",opc:"faired shell plates with curvature in two directions",opd:"sheets of dunnage used to prevent heavy cargo from buckling the deck plates",ans:"opb"},{question:"Separating both blocks of a tackle to prepare it for reuse is called ____________.",opa:"chockablocking",opb:"out-hauling",opc:"over-hauling",opd:"two-blocking",ans:"opc"},{question:"Bulk cargo refers to ____________.",opa:"cargo which occupies a large volume of space",opb:"cargo which requires refrigeration",opc:"cargo which is very dense",opd:"homogeneous cargo not enclosed in a container",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which certificate is issued by the American Bureau of Shipping?",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Load Line Certificate",opc:"Safety Equipment Certificate",opd:"Permit to Proceed for repairs",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a ship that has broken down and are preparing to be taken in tow. You will use your anchor cable as part of the towline. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The anchor cable should be veered enough to allow the towline connection to be just forward of your bow.",opb:"The anchor cable should be veered enough to allow the towline connection to be immediately astern of the towing vessel.",opc:"The strain of the tow is taken by the riding pawl, chain stopper, and anchor windlass brake.",opd:"The anchor cable should be led out through a chock, if possible, to avoid a sharp nip at the hawsepipe lip.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are in the process of loading 465,000 barrels of cargo oil. At 1030, on 5 November, you gauge the vessel and find that you have loaded 203,000 barrels. At 1200, you find that you have loaded 219,000 barrels. If you continue loading at the same rate, you will finish at approximately ____________.",opa:"1510, 5 November",opb:"0140, 6 November",opc:"1104, 6 November",opd:"0735, 7 November",ans:"opc"},{question:"Horizontal fore or aft motion of a vessel is known as ____________.",opa:"pitch",opb:"surge",opc:"sway",opd:"roll",ans:"opb"},{question:"Certain cargoes must be segregated because of their ____________.",opa:"inherent characteristics",opb:"weight",opc:"destination",opd:"danger to humans",ans:"opa"},{question:"Cargo that gives off fumes that may contaminate other cargo is known as a(n) ____________.",opa:"delicate cargo",opb:"dirty cargo",opc:"toxic cargo",opd:"odorous cargo",ans:"opd"},{question:"When dropping anchor, you are stationed at the windlass brake. The most important piece(s) of gear is(are) ____________.",opa:"a hard hat",opb:"a long sleeve shirt",opc:"gloves",opd:"goggles",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you shorten the scope of anchor cable, your anchor's holding power ____________.",opa:"decreases",opb:"increases",opc:"remains the same",opd:"has no relation to the scope",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a long ocean tow, the bridle should be made up of two equal lengths of ____________.",opa:"chain",opb:"wire",opc:"nylon",opd:"polyester",ans:"opa"},{question:"Two falls are supporting a 1.5 ton load. The port fall is at an angle of 40\xb0 from the vertical. The starboard fall is at an angle of 70\xb0 from the vertical. What is the stress on each fall?",opa:"Port 1.5 tons, starboard 1.0 tons",opb:"Port 1.5 tons, starboard 1.5 tons",opc:"Port 1.7 tons, starboard 1.3 tons",opd:"Port 1.7 tons, starboard 2.0 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are going ahead on twin engines with rudders amidships. Your port engine stalls. To continue your course you should ____________.",opa:"apply right rudder",opb:"apply left rudder",opc:"keep your rudder amidships",opd:"increase engine speed",ans:"opa"},{question:"What does item 'A' refer to in this illustration of a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Boom luffing falls",opb:"Cargo hoist falls",opc:"Remote block tagline system",opd:"Slewing cable",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which item is rigged to transmit the thrust from one barge to another barge when going ahead?",opa:"I",opb:"H",opc:"E",opd:"B",ans:"opc"},{question:"The tankship Northland is loaded as shown. Use the salmon colored pages in the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the sagging numeral.",opa:"81.79 numeral",opb:"85.02 numeral",opc:"89.68 numeral",opd:"91.92 numeral",ans:"opd"},{question:"With a given load on the cargo hook, the thrust on a cargo boom ____________.",opa:"increases as the angle to the horizontal increases",opb:"increases as the angle to the horizontal decreases",opc:"is greatest at an angle of 45\xb0 and decreases as the boom is raised or lowered",opd:"is least at an angle of 45\xb0 and increases as the boom is raised or lowered",ans:"opa"},{question:"A metal eye spliced into a wire is called a ____________.",opa:"cyclops",opb:"fish eye",opc:"thimble",opd:"chip",ans:"opc"},{question:"A licensed Master of Towing Vessels may NOT serve as the person in charge of which towing vessel?",opa:"99 GRT towing vessel operating on Chesapeake Bay",opb:"199 GRT towing vessel operating in the Gulf of Alaska",opc:"480 GRT towboat operating on the Western Rivers",opd:"405 GRT towing vessel operating between Florida and the US Virgin Islands",ans:"opd"},{question:"The proximity of pack ice may be indicated by ____________.",opa:"changes in seawater salinity",opb:"glare on clouds on the horizon",opc:"changes in air temperature",opd:"icebergs",ans:"opb"},{question:"While in dry dock your vessel will be belt-gauged. This process involves ____________.",opa:"measuring the thickness of the tail shaft liner",opb:"taking the vessel's offsets to check for hull deformation",opc:"testing and examining the anchor cables for defective links",opd:"drilling or sonic-testing the hull to determine the plate thickness",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to the illustration, which of the figures protects the stress bearing end of a wire rope from being crushed while forming a temporary eye splice using wire rope clips?",opa:"A.",opb:"B.",opc:"C.",opd:"All the above.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which action should be taken FIRST if your tow is sinking in shallow water?",opa:"Pay out the towline until the sunken tow reaches bottom.",opb:"Sever the towline.",opc:"Immediately head for the nearest shoreline.",opd:"Contact the Coast Guard.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Under normal operating conditions aboard a ship, who has the overall responsibility in maintaining the Oil Record Book?",opa:"Chief Engineer",opb:"First Assistant Engineer",opc:"Master",opd:"Chief Mate",ans:"opc"},{question:"No hot work shall be performed on board a vessel with hazardous materials as cargo unless the work is approved by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"local U.S. Coast Guard Captain of the Port",opc:"National Cargo Bureau",opd:"harbormaster",ans:"opb"},{question:"In a transversely framed ship, the transverse frames are supported by all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"girders",opb:"longitudinals",opc:"side stringers",opd:"web plates",ans:"opd"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated PRIORITY will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"6 hours",opb:"10 minutes",opc:"30 minutes",opd:"3 hours",ans:"opd"},{question:"Tonnage openings must be closed by means of ____________.",opa:"press board",opb:"steel hatch boards",opc:"steel plates",opd:"wooden hatch boards",ans:"opc"},{question:"The owner or Master of a vessel pushing ahead or towing alongside must ensure that each of the following is appropriate for the vessel's horsepower and tow arrangement EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"hydraulic couplings",opb:"face wires",opc:"push gear",opd:"spring lines",ans:"opa"},{question:"The wildcat is linked to the central drive shaft on most windlasses by ____________.",opa:"an electromagnetic brake",opb:"a hydraulic coupling",opc:"aligning the keyways on both and inserting a key",opd:"a mechanical coupling where lugs engage detents",ans:"opd"},{question:"A 'stopper' is ____________.",opa:"a short length of line used for temporarily holding another line",opb:"a snatch block for handling a topping lift",opc:"an engine order telegraph",opd:"the brake on a cargo winch",ans:"opa"},{question:"The American Consul has asked the Master of a vessel bound for a port in the U.S. to transport a destitute seaman back to the U.S. Which action may the Master take?",opa:"He may refuse to take the seaman if the ship will not stop at a U.S. port within 30 days.",opb:"He is required to accept the seaman only if the seaman is medically unfit.",opc:"He may refuse to take the seaman if the seaman has a contagious disease.",opd:"He is required to take the seaman under any circumstance.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A 'gypsy' or 'gypsyhead' is a ____________.",opa:"punt used for painting over the side",opb:"small, reciprocating steam engine",opc:"spool-shaped drum fitted on a winch",opd:"swinging derrick",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are landing a single-screw vessel with a right-handed propeller port side to a dock. As you approach the dock, you back down on your engine with rudder amidships. You would expect the vessel to ____________.",opa:"drift away from the dock",opb:"lose headway without swinging",opc:"swing its stern towards the dock",opd:"swing its stern away from the dock",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a 120,000 DWT loaded bulk carrier. When anchoring without the aid of tugs, your maximum speed should not exceed how many feet per second?",opa:"0.5 (0.3 knot)",opb:"1.0 (0.6 knot)",opc:"1.3 (0.8 knot)",opd:"1.75 (1.0 knot)",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which part of a conventional cargo gear rig provides for vertical control and positioning of a boom?",opa:"Cargo whip",opb:"Gooseneck fitting",opc:"Spider band",opd:"Topping lift",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are cleaning the tanks after carrying a cargo of crude oil. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Washing water should be recirculated if possible because it has the same electric potential as the cargo tank being cleaned.",opb:"The hoses to portable cleaning machines should be disconnected before the machines are removed from the tank.",opc:"The principal hazard with steaming cargo tanks is raising the ambient temperature above the flame point of the cargo residue.",opd:"Steam cleaning and water washing are both capable of generating electrostatic charges within a tank.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The most likely time for oil pollution while bunkering is when ____________.",opa:"final topping off is occurring",opb:"first starting to receive fuel",opc:"hoses are being blown down",opd:"hoses are disconnected and being capped",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which arrangement of shell plating is used most in modern shipbuilding?",opa:"Clinker",opb:"Flush",opc:"In-and-Out",opd:"Joggled",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has the symbol shown inscribed on the side. Which statement concerning this symbol is TRUE?",opa:"This represents the load line marks when engaged on a voyage upon the Great Lakes.",opb:"The line directly under the triangle is at the same level as the summer load line.",opc:"The symbol is the equivalent of a load line marking and is used by government vessels (USN, MSC, USCG) only.",opd:"The applicable gross and net tonnage of the ship will change if this mark is submerged and the load line mark is visible.",ans:"opd"},{question:"While underway, part of your cargo is damaged by fire. In marine insurance terms this partial loss is called ____________.",opa:"absolute total loss",opb:"constructive total loss",opc:"general average",opd:"particular average",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 3?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are being towed by one tug. As you lengthen the bridle legs you ____________.",opa:"increase your chances of breaking the towing hawser",opb:"reduce the yawing of your vessel",opc:"reduce the spring effect of the tow connection",opd:"increase your chances of breaking the bridle legs",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which standard operating procedure(s) should be adhered to on a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Periodic inspection and re-tensioning of lashings as required during voyage",opb:"Battery cables must be disconnected to prevent fire hazard",opc:"One deck engine mechanic assigned to oversee the initial loading and lashing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel must moor port side to a berth limited by vessels ahead and astern using a single tug. You are stemming a slight current and there is a light breeze of the dock. Your tug should be made up to the vessel's ____________.",opa:"stern on a hawser",opb:"quarter",opc:"waist",opd:"bow",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which factor is most likely to impair the strength and durability of synthetic line?",opa:"Dry rot",opb:"Mildew",opc:"Sunlight",opd:"Washing with mild soap",ans:"opc"},{question:"Ship's officers should check every cargo compartment after it is filled with bulk grain to ensure ____________.",opa:"all lighting circuits are energized",opb:"all void spaces are filled",opc:"the correct grade of cargo has been loaded",opd:"the heavier grade is in the lower hold",ans:"opb"},{question:"As defined in the regulations governing marine casualties a 'marine employer' may be the ____________.",opa:"owner",opb:"agent",opc:"Master",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel traveling down a narrow channel, especially if the draft is nearly equal to the depth of the water, may set off the nearer side. This effect is known as ____________.",opa:"smelling the bottom",opb:"squatting",opc:"bank suction",opd:"bank cushion",ans:"opd"},{question:"A survey of refrigerated cargo, to certify that proper methods of stowage were utilized, can be conducted by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Occupational Safety and Health Administration",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"National Cargo Bureau",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to regulations when, if ever, may cargo hatches on Great Lakes vessels, with more than 6 feet of freeboard, be left uncovered or open while the vessel is being navigated?",opa:"If a Mate deems it necessary for ship's maintenance",opb:"At the discretion of the Master, for reasonable purposes",opc:"On the authority of the Bosun",opd:"The hatch may never be uncovered",ans:"opb"},{question:"Conventional anchors are least likely to hold in a bottom consisting of ____________.",opa:"soft clay",opb:"hard mud",opc:"sand",opd:"rock",ans:"opd"},{question:"A mooring line leading 45\xb0 to the keel, used to check forward or astern movement of a vessel, is called a ____________.",opa:"spring line",opb:"warp line",opc:"bow line",opd:"breast line",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are scheduled to load a bulk shipment of steel turnings. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The primary hazard of this cargo is that it is subject to spontaneous heating and ignition.",opb:"The shipping papers should describe this cargo as 'Waste; steel borings'.",opc:"After loading, you may not sail if the temperature in each hold of steel turnings exceeds 130\xb0F.",opd:"This cargo may not be transported in bulk unless a special permit is issued by the Coast Guard.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When riveted joints occur at the ends of plating they are called ____________.",opa:"trailers",opb:"terminals",opc:"seams",opd:"butts",ans:"opd"},{question:"Synchronous towing means that the ____________.",opa:"tug is on the crest of a wave while the tow is in the trough",opb:"tug is in the trough while the tow is riding on the crest of a wave",opc:"tug and tow are both in the same relative position on different waves at the same time",opd:"port and starboard engines on the tug are turning at the same RPM",ans:"opc"},{question:"An intermediate spring is ____________.",opa:"fitted in each leg of the towing bridle",opb:"generally located between the 'fishplate' and the main towing hawser",opc:"secured at the 'H' bitts",opd:"usually made of manila hawser",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement describes the motion of a yawing tow?",opa:"The tow twists, sometimes violently, astern of the tug",opb:"The tow sheers to one side behind the tug and maintains a position in a line diagonal to the tug's forward movement",opc:"The tow snakes behind the tug",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Immigration and Naturalization Service is concerned with which document on a vessel making preliminary entry into a U.S. port from a foreign port?",opa:"Cargo Manifest",opb:"Certified Crew List",opc:"Curio List",opd:"Shipping Articles",ans:"opb"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has his arm extended with the palm down and holds this position rigidly. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"hoist",opb:"swing",opc:"stop",opd:"lower",ans:"opc"},{question:"Where should a vessel being towed alongside be positioned for increased maneuverability?",opa:"Stern of the towed vessel aft of the stern of the towing vessel",opb:"Stern of the towed vessel even with the stern of the towing vessel",opc:"Stern of the towed vessel forward of the stern of the towing vessel",opd:"Bow of the towed vessel even with the bow of the towing vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"The load line markings shown are inscribed on the vessel's ____________.",opa:"port side",opb:"starboard side",opc:"port and starboard sides",opd:"stern",ans:"opc"},{question:"The choice of length of tow bridle legs is governed by the ____________.",opa:"expected towing forces",opb:"capability of retrieving gear",opc:"freeboard of the unit being towed",opd:"need to reduce yaw",ans:"opd"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has his arm extended and is pointing his finger in the direction to move the boom. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"extend",opb:"lower",opc:"hoist",opd:"swing",ans:"opd"},{question:"You may BEST turn a twin-screw vessel about, to the right, in a narrow channel by using ____________.",opa:"both engines ahead and helm",opb:"one engine only",opc:"port engine ahead and the starboard engine astern",opd:"both engines astern and use helm",ans:"opc"},{question:"A wooden float placed between a ship and a dock to prevent damage to both is called a ____________.",opa:"camel",opb:"dolphin",opc:"rat guard",opd:"wedge",ans:"opa"},{question:"A standard net barrel of petroleum products is ____________.",opa:"42 gallons at 60\xb0F",opb:"48 gallons at 70\xb0F",opc:"50 gallons at 50\xb0F",opd:"60 gallons at 100\xb0F",ans:"opa"},{question:"When handling cargo, the majority of cargo gear breakdowns is due to ____________.",opa:"compression bending of the boom",opb:"extension failure of the boom",opc:"guy failures",opd:"topping lift failures",ans:"opc"},{question:"A sufficient amount of chain must be veered when anchoring a vessel to ensure ____________.",opa:"the vessel has enough room to swing while at anchor",opb:"the anchor flukes bite into the ocean bottom",opc:"there is a sufficient scope of chain to keep the anchor on the bottom",opd:"there is more chain out than there is in the chain locker",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are in charge of a towing vessel that operates exclusively on inland waters. You regularly tow barges that provide services (cargo lighters, fuel barges, etc.) to foreign flag vessels in port. What will be accepted as proper credentials for you and your crew?",opa:"No credentials are required since you operate on inland waters only",opb:"Social Security card",opc:"State driver's license with photo ID",opd:"Merchant Mariner Credential",ans:"opd"},{question:"The purpose of item G is to ____________.",opa:"distribute the vessel's thrust over a wider area",opb:"prevent the towboat from capsizing if item I should part",opc:"prevent the knee from shifting when the rudder is put hard over",opd:"keep the barges from shifting fore and aft",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lower hold of your vessel has a bale capacity of 60,000 cubic feet. How many tons of cotton in bales having a stowage factor of 85 can be stowed in the lower hold, assuming a broken stowage factor of 20%?",opa:"141",opb:"565",opc:"706",opd:"847",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tanker is loaded with 8,000 barrels of fuel oil. The temperature of the cargo is 50\xb0F. API gravity is 37\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. What is the net amount in barrels of cargo loaded?",opa:"8040",opb:"8016",opc:"7984",opd:"7960",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel's bottom will be subjected to tension when weight is concentrated ____________.",opa:"amidships",opb:"aft",opc:"at both ends of the vessel",opd:"forward",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which is an example of cargo damage caused by inherent vice?",opa:"Sublimation of chemicals",opb:"Heating of grain",opc:"Stevedore damage",opd:"Wear and tear",ans:"opb"},{question:"The stringer plate is represented by which letter?",opa:"A",opb:"C",opc:"I",opd:"N",ans:"opa"},{question:"Horizontal transverse motion of a vessel is known as ____________.",opa:"pitch",opb:"surge",opc:"sway",opd:"heave",ans:"opc"},{question:"Keeping certain cargoes separated because of their inherent characteristics is known as ____________.",opa:"overstowage",opb:"segregation",opc:"spot loading",opd:"cargo typing",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your load line certificate expires on 27 May 1988. The vessel is surveyed on that date and is found satisfactory. You are sailing foreign the same day. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"A new certificate must be issued before you sail.",opb:"The existing certificate is endorsed as valid for a five year period commencing 27 May1988.",opc:"The existing certificate is extended for a period of up to 150 days.",opd:"The existing certificate is extended until the first foreign port of call where a new certificate will be issued by the local surveyor.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The American Consul has asked the Master of a vessel bound for a port in the U.S. to transport a destitute seaman back to the U.S. Which action may the Master take?",opa:"He must always take the seaman.",opb:"He is required to accept the seaman only if the seaman is medically unfit.",opc:"He may refuse the seaman if the seaman has a contagious disease.",opd:"He may refuse to take the seaman if he is being held by shore authorities.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The MINIMUM acceptable size for a towing bridle would be that size in which the safe working load (SWL) of each leg of the bridle is equal to ____________.",opa:"one-half the SWL of the main towing hawser",opb:"three-fourths the SWL of the main towing hawser",opc:"that of the main towing hawser",opd:"twice that of the main towing hawser",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which is the correct procedure for anchoring a small to medium size vessel in deep water?",opa:"Let the anchor fall free from the hawsepipe, but apply the brake at intervals to check the rate of fall.",opb:"Back the anchor slowly out of the hawsepipe a few feet, and then let it fall in the normal fashion.",opc:"Let the anchor fall off the brake right from the hawsepipe, but keep a slight strain on the brake.",opd:"Under power, back the anchor out until it is near, but clear, of the bottom before letting it fall.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are operating a twin-screw vessel and lose your port engine. You continue to operate on your starboard engine only. Which action would you take to move your vessel ahead in a straight line?",opa:"Compensate with right rudder.",opb:"Compensate with left rudder.",opc:"Surge the starboard engine.",opd:"Rudder amidships -no compensation is necessary on a twin-screw vessel.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The American Consul has asked the Master of a vessel bound for a port in the U.S. to transport a destitute seaman back to the U.S. Which action may the Master take?",opa:"He may refuse to accept the seaman if the seaman is medically unfit.",opb:"He must take the seaman even if the seaman has a contagious disease.",opc:"He is always required to take the seaman.",opd:"He may refuse to take the seaman if it will violate the Certificate of Inspection.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following is/are the component(s) of a twin crane set as shown?",opa:"Foundation assembly",opb:"Turntable assembly",opc:"Crane house assembly",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When bunkering is complete, the hoses should be ____________.",opa:"cleaned internally with a degreaser",opb:"washed out with hot soapy water",opc:"drained, blanked off, and stored securely",opd:"stowed vertically and allowed to drain",ans:"opc"},{question:"An alien crewmember with a D-1 permit leaves the vessel in a U.S. port and fails to return. The first report you make should be to the ____________.",opa:"Customs Service",opb:"Immigration Service",opc:"local police",opd:"OCMI",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which agency issues a certificate of loading that is evidence that the rules and regulations concerning bulk grain cargoes have been observed?",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Department of Agriculture",opc:"National Cargo Bureau",opd:"Public Health Service",ans:"opc"},{question:"A temporary wire eye splice made with three wire rope clamps will hold approximately what percentage of the total rope strength?",opa:"0.2",opb:"0.5",opc:"0.8",opd:"0.99",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are loading a cargo tank on your container ship. The tank displays the red label shown. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The tank contains propylene.",opb:"The tank's volume is 1077 cubic feet.",opc:"There are three tanks in the shipment.",opd:"The tank contains an oxidizing material.",ans:"opa"},{question:"With an increase in temperature the volume of flammable and combustible liquids ____________.",opa:"expands",opb:"contracts",opc:"remains constant",opd:"remains constant if pressure remains constant",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel has been damaged by fire. The survey shows the cost of repairs will exceed the value of the repaired vessel. This is an example of a(n) ____________.",opa:"constructive total loss",opb:"salvage loss",opc:"actual loss",opd:"preferred loss",ans:"opa"},{question:"When using wire rope clips to form a temporary eye in wire rope, you should ____________.",opa:"place the U-bolt of the wire rope clips on the dead end of the rope",opb:"check the clips after an hour of operation to determine if the clips loosened due to wire rope expansion",opc:"replace the entire wire rope if broken wires are detected around the clips",opd:"wire rope clips should never be used to form a temporary eye splice",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using a safety factor of 6, determine the safe working load of manila line with a breaking stress of 8 tons.",opa:"0.75 tons",opb:"1.25 tons",opc:"1.33 tons",opd:"8.00 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The sprocket wheel in a windlass, used for heaving in the anchor, is called a ____________.",opa:"capstan",opb:"dog wheel",opc:"fairlead",opd:"wildcat",ans:"opd"},{question:"For towing vessels over 100 gross tons that are permitted to maintain a two-watch system, what percentage of the deck crew must be able seamen?",opa:"0.5",opb:"0.65",opc:"0.75",opd:"1",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel loads edible oil in a deep tank through a manhole at the mid-length of the tank. In order to fill the tank to maximum capacity, what trim should the vessel have?",opa:"Down by the bow",opb:"Down by the stern",opc:"Down by either the bow or stern",opd:"In level trim",ans:"opd"},{question:"If an attempt is made to hoist a load that exceeds the capacity of an electric winch, an overload safety device causes a circuit breaker to cut off the current to the winch motor ____________.",opa:"when the line pull reaches the rated winch capacity",opb:"after the line pull exceeds the rated winch capacity",opc:"after a short build-up of torque",opd:"immediately",ans:"opb"},{question:"'Hanging a barge off' means to ____________.",opa:"moor a barge to the bank and leave",opb:"remove and deliver a loaded barge from a multiple tow",opc:"remove a barge while locking through",opd:"tow an empty barge astern",ans:"opa"},{question:"The maximum theoretical stress that can be developed on a guy in a yard and stay rig is limited by the ____________.",opa:"lifting capacity of the winch",opb:"location of the boom",opc:"position of the guy",opd:"weight of the load",ans:"opa"},{question:"In some cases, the 50% duty on all foreign repairs made to American flag merchant vessels may be remitted. Which work does NOT come under the remitting policy of U.S. Customs?",opa:"Chipping, painting, and scaling by foreign labor",opb:"Repairs to hull structural damage",opc:"Repairs due to damage done by heavy weather",opd:"Repairs to the main propulsion machinery",ans:"opa"},{question:"A twin-screw ship going ahead on the starboard screw only tends to move ____________.",opa:"in a straight line",opb:"to port",opc:"from side to side",opd:"to starboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"In a longitudinally-framed ship, the longitudinal frames are held in place and supported by athwartship members called ____________.",opa:"floors",opb:"margin plates",opc:"stringers",opd:"web frames",ans:"opd"},{question:"Nylon line is NOT suitable for ____________.",opa:"towing",opb:"lashings",opc:"stoppers",opd:"mooring lines",ans:"opb"},{question:"A Great Lakes bulk ore vessel would use an 'Iron Deckhand' to assist in ____________.",opa:"unloading bulk cargo",opb:"steering the vessel",opc:"making the vessel fast to a dock",opd:"removing hatch covers",ans:"opd"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated FLASH will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"3 hours to start of business the following day",opb:"1 to 6 hours",opc:"30 minutes to 1 hour",opd:"less than 10 minutes",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 8?",opa:"3",opb:"1.5",opc:"1",opd:"0.5",ans:"opa"},{question:"To allow for the rise or fall in tide and for change in draft of a tankship during cargo transfer, cargo hoses must be suspended with ____________.",opa:"slings or saddles placed at 25-foot (8 meter) intervals",opb:"enough slack in their bight",opc:"topping lifts and runners tied off to winches",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which knot would serve best as a safety sling for a person working over the side?",opa:"Bowline on a bight",opb:"French bowline",opc:"Jug sling",opd:"Lifting hitch",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tow consists of 8 barges: 6 jumbo barges made up 3 abreast and 2 long, with 2 standard barges abreast as lead barges. How long is this tow?",opa:"525 feet",opb:"545 feet",opc:"565 feet",opd:"595 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Rolling is angular motion of the vessel about what axis?",opa:"Longitudinal",opb:"Transverse",opc:"Vertical",opd:"Centerline",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are proceeding down a channel and lose the engine(s). You must use the anchors to stop the ship. Which statement is true?",opa:"Pay out all of the cable before setting up on the brake to insure the anchors dig in and hold.",opb:"For a mud, mud and clay, or sandy bottom pay out a scope of 5 to 7 times the depth before setting up on the brake.",opc:"Use one or both anchors with a scope of twice the depth before setting the brake.",opd:"Drop the anchor to short stay and hold that scope.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is a single-screw ship with a right-hand propeller. There is no current. The easiest way to make a landing is ____________.",opa:"port side to",opb:"starboard side to",opc:"dropping anchor and swinging the ship in to the pier",opd:"either port or starboard side to, with no difference in degree of difficulty",ans:"opa"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has his arm extended, with the thumb pointing up, and is flexing his fingers in and out for as long as the load movement is desired. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"lower the boom and raise the load",opb:"raise the boom and lower the load",opc:"lower the boom and lower the load",opd:"raise the boom and raise the load",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is usually NOT required in preparing a hold for reception of a bulk grain cargo?",opa:"Remove residue of previous cargo.",opb:"Remove loose rust and scale.",opc:"Steam clean areas obstructed by structural members.",opd:"Spray or fumigate any insect colonies.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The most common method of securing a line to a cleat is a ____________.",opa:"half hitch, then round turns",opb:"round turn, then figure eights",opc:"figure eight, then round turns",opd:"figure eight, then half hitches",ans:"opb"},{question:"The S.S. Hollowpoint has a charter party in which the charterer assumes no responsibility for the operation of the vessel but pays stevedoring expenses. What is the name of the charter party?",opa:"Bareboat",opb:"Dispatch",opc:"Voyage",opd:"Demise",ans:"opc"},{question:"While a vessel is at sea, the mate on watch discovers a fire in one of the hatches. Fire hoses are used to put the fire out and some of the cargo is damaged by water. In marine insurance terms, this partial loss by water is called ____________.",opa:"an Act of God",opb:"fire and water damage",opc:"general average",opd:"particular average",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have arrived at your anchorage location. You have put the engines astern prior to letting go the anchor. How will you know when the vessel has stopped making way?",opa:"The ship's Doppler log reads zero",opb:"The backwash of the propeller reaches amidships",opc:"An azimuth bearing on the beam remains steady",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which type of stopper should be used to stop off wire rope?",opa:"Chain",opb:"Manila",opc:"Polypropylene",opd:"Wire",ans:"opa"},{question:"When accepting vehicles for shipment, the Master should ensure that ____________.",opa:"all decks intended for the stowage of vehicles are, in so far as is practicable, free from oil and grease",opb:"the ship has on board an adequate supply of cargo securing gear, which is maintained in sound working condition",opc:"vehicles are in apparent good order and condition suitable for sea transport, particularly with regards to securing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The terminology 'able to understand any order spoken by the officers' refers to all of the following situations EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"in response to a fire",opb:"directing the use of lifesaving equipment",opc:"for deck department crew members to understand the terminology used in the engine room",opd:"in response to a man overboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"On which form do you provide a written report of Marine Casualty to the nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety Office?",opa:"DD 214",opb:"CG 2692",opc:"DOT 211",opd:"CG 5511",ans:"opb"},{question:"The plating indicated by the letter N is known as the ____________.",opa:"inner bottom",opb:"floor riders",opc:"tank-top rider plating",opd:"ceiling",ans:"opa"},{question:"The York-Antwerp Rules relate to the ____________.",opa:"minimum required number of officers and crew",opb:"settlement of general average claims",opc:"ship owner's responsibilities to provide a well-found vessel in a charter party",opd:"navigation regulations that apply in the English Channel",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is proceeding along a narrow channel. The effect called bank cushion has which effect on the vessel?",opa:"Forces the bow away from the bank",opb:"Forces the stern away from the bank",opc:"Forces the entire vessel bodily away from the bank",opd:"Decreases the draft at the bow",ans:"opa"},{question:"The BEST holding ground for conventional anchors is ____________.",opa:"very soft mud",opb:"hard mud",opc:"shale",opd:"rock",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which organization would conduct a survey of the insulation in a reefer compartment prior to loading cargo?",opa:"U.S. Customs Service",opb:"OSHA",opc:"American Bureau of Shipping",opd:"National Cargo Bureau",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Sheer Plan ____________.",opa:"shows a longitudinal side elevation",opb:"is an endwise view of the ship's molded form",opc:"is usually drawn for the port side only",opd:"has the forebody to the right of centerline and afterbody to the left of centerline",ans:"opa"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has his arm extended, his fingers closed, and his thumb pointing downward. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"hoist the load",opb:"raise the boom",opc:"lower the boom",opd:"lower the load",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using a safety factor of five, determine the safe working load of a line with a breaking strain of 20,000 pounds.",opa:"4000",opb:"5000",opc:"20000",opd:"100000",ans:"opa"},{question:"The main advantage of a Chinese stopper over the one line stopper is that it ____________.",opa:"will not jam on the mooring line",opb:"is stronger",opc:"is easier to use when under heavy tension",opd:"is safer to use when under heavy tension",ans:"opa"},{question:"All handling and stowage of packaged hazardous materials on board a domestic vessel engaged in foreign trade shall be done under the supervision of ____________.",opa:"a U.S. Coast Guard Marine Inspector",opb:"an officer assigned to the vessel",opc:"the American Bureau of Shipping",opd:"the National Cargo Bureau",ans:"opb"},{question:"SOLAS requires a lifesaving training manual be provided in each crew cabin or in the ____________.",opa:"bridge",opb:"engineering control station",opc:"recreation and messrooms",opd:"fire control room",ans:"opc"},{question:"To obtain better steering control when you are towing alongside, your vessel should be positioned with its ____________.",opa:"bow extending forward of the tow",opb:"stern amidships of the tow",opc:"stern extending aft of the tow",opd:"bow even with the bow of the tow",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have a tow of chemical barges. The mate reports an ammonia smell around the head of the tow. You would suspect a leak in the barge carrying ____________.",opa:"methyl chloride",opb:"heptane",opc:"propanolamine",opd:"morpholine",ans:"opd"},{question:"When several salvors are on-scene at the same time to assist a vessel that has not been abandoned, which principal governs the decision as to which one's services will be accepted?",opa:"The Master of the ship needing assistance has the absolute right to decide.",opb:"The first salvor on-scene has the prior claim providing he has adequate facilities to assist the vessel needing assistance.",opc:"The salvors must agree to a division of any salvage among themselves with the major share allotted to those doing the most work.",opd:"The first salvor on-scene has the absolute right to provide assistance; however, he is liable if the ship is lost due to his lack of experience, equipment, etc.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A smooth, tapered pin, usually of wood, used to open up the strands of a rope for splicing is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"batten",opb:"bench hook",opc:"awl",opd:"fid",ans:"opd"},{question:"An underwriter is liable for ____________.",opa:"loss arising from the subject itself because of its inherent qualities",opb:"loss caused by the ordinary evaporation of liquids",opc:"loss caused by heavy weather",opd:"the natural decay of the vessel due to the passage of time",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lowest temperature at which a liquid will give off sufficient vapors to form a flammable mixture with air is known as the ____________.",opa:"fire point",opb:"flash point",opc:"lower explosive limit",opd:"threshold limit value",ans:"opb"},{question:"The facewire refers to item ____________.",opa:"I",opb:"H",opc:"B",opd:"A",ans:"opa"},{question:"Catenary as applied to tow lines denotes the ____________.",opa:"dip of the line",opb:"stretch of the line",opc:"strain on the line",opd:"length of the line",ans:"opa"},{question:"What best describes an anchor buoy?",opa:"A black ball that is hoisted when the ship anchors",opb:"A buoy attached to the anchor",opc:"A buoy attached to the scope of an anchor chain",opd:"A mark of the number of fathoms in an anchor chain",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on watch at night in clear visibility and the vessel has just been anchored. The first thing that you should do after the anchor has been let go is to ____________.",opa:"stop the engines",opb:"take bearings to obtain ship's position",opc:"turn off the running lights and turn on the anchor lights",opd:"lower the accommodation ladder and illuminate it",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the anchor is brought to and holding, the horizontal component of anchor cable tensions should equal the ____________.",opa:"displacement tonnage",opb:"weight forces",opc:"buoyancy forces",opd:"environmental forces",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which towing method maintains the most control over the tow?",opa:"Tandem towing",opb:"Honolulu towing",opc:"Tandem tug towing",opd:"Breasted tug towing",ans:"opd"},{question:"For vessels fitted with cargo gear, an initial test of the units under a proof load shall be conducted. Subsequent tests and exams of the same nature shall be carried out at what time interval?",opa:"1 year",opb:"3 years",opc:"4 years",opd:"5 years",ans:"opd"},{question:"The run of plating labeled A is known as the ____________.",opa:"sheer strake",opb:"stringer plate",opc:"deck strake",opd:"deck longitudinal",ans:"opb"},{question:"Damage to cargo caused by dust is known as ____________.",opa:"contamination",opb:"oxidation",opc:"tainting",opd:"vaporization",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have orders to load cargoes of carbon disulfide, diisopropylamine and pyridine on your multi-product tankship. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Carbon disulfide may be carried in NOS. 1 and 2 center tanks and diisopropylamine in NOS. 1 and 2 wing tanks.",opb:"Pyridine and diisopropylamine may be carried in tanks having a common header vent.",opc:"Carbon disulfide must be separated from pyridine by two barriers (cofferdams, voids, empty tanks, etc.).",opd:"A tank of pyridine may be used to separate a tank of carbon disulfide from a tank of diisopropylamine.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Battens are fitted in cargo holds across the frames of the vessel from the turn of the bilge upward. The purpose of these cargo battens is ____________.",opa:"for securing a snatch block when snaking cargo into the wings of the hold",opb:"to prevent cargo from coming in contact with the vessel's frames or shell plating",opc:"to provide fittings to which cargo lashings may be secured",opd:"to support the dunnage floors which are laid down between tiers of cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"How are riveted lap joints made watertight?",opa:"The faying surfaces are coated with white lead (or similar product) before the rivets are set.",opb:"A sealing weld bead of 1/8' or less pitch is run along the plate edge.",opc:"The plate edge is split close to an adjacent plate and mechanically forced into contact with the adjacent plate.",opd:"A properly riveted joint will be watertight; any leakage is stopped by setting up on the rivets.",ans:"opc"},{question:"When connecting the tow bridle to a tug, the end of the bridle is passed with a ____________.",opa:"heaving line",opb:"shot line",opc:"high line",opd:"messenger line",ans:"opd"},{question:"Upon completion of a voyage, the official logbook shall be filed with the ____________.",opa:"nearest Regional Exam Center (REC)",opb:"the Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection (OCMI)",opc:"Captain of the Port (COTP)",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"When bunkering at a dock which of the following signals must be displayed?",opa:"A yellow flag by day, red light by night",opb:"A red flag by day, red light by night",opc:"A green flag by day, green light by night",opd:"A red flag by day, a blue light by night",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a tug is pulling on a hawser at right angles to the ship, and the pilot wants to come ahead or astern on the ship's engine, care must be taken that the pilot ____________.",opa:"does not break the towline",opb:"does not get too much way on the vessel",opc:"keeps a steady course so the towline will remain tight",opd:"turns the ship toward the direction of pull",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tanker is loaded with 8,000 barrels of fuel oil. The temperature of the cargo is 50\xb0F. API gravity is 37\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. What is the net amount in gallons of cargo loaded?",opa:"334320",opb:"337680",opc:"437800",opd:"442200",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are coming to anchor in 8 fathoms of water. In this case, the ____________.",opa:"anchor may be dropped from the hawsepipe",opb:"anchor should be lowered to within 2 fathoms of the bottom before being dropped",opc:"anchor should be lowered to the bottom then the ship backed and the remainder of the cable veered",opd:"scope should be less than 3 times the depth of the water",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a tankship discharging oil. When all of the oil that the main cargo pumps can handle is pumped out of a tank, the remainder is ____________.",opa:"stripped out and pumped directly ashore into the mainline as the remaining cargo tanks are pumped out with the main pumps",opb:"stripped to one tank and then pumped out with the main pumps",opc:"stripped out and pumped directly ashore after all the tanks have been emptied by the main pumps",opd:"gravitated to the centers from the wings and pumped out with the main pumps",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE concerning precautions during fueling operations?",opa:"All engines, motors, fans, etc. should be shut down when fueling.",opb:"All windows, doors, hatches, etc. should be closed.",opc:"A fire extinguisher should be kept nearby.",opd:"Fuel tanks should be topped off with no room for expansion.",ans:"opd"},{question:"When steering by hand, which of the following may be a functional input to the steering gear as a result of turning the wheel?",opa:"Non-follow-up",opb:"Rudder adjustment",opc:"Weather adjustment",opd:"All the above may be activated",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are Master of a U.S. flag vessel which was dry docked for bottom cleaning in Rotterdam, Netherlands. Upon return to a U.S. port, you must ____________.",opa:"file a customs' form for duty on this repair",opb:"file no extra reports",opc:"file a report of the dry docking with the U.S.C.G.. Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection",opd:"obtain a U.S. Coast Guard diver to certify the work",ans:"opa"},{question:"You must load as much of a large shipment of case goods as possible into a hold which has 24,000 cubic feet of space. Each case measures 2 feet by 2-1/2 feet by 4 feet and weights 448 pounds. If you allow for broken stowage of 15%, how many long tons can be loaded?",opa:"280",opb:"233",opc:"204",opd:"190",ans:"opc"},{question:"While a vessel is in a foreign port where there is no American Consul, a seaman becomes violent prior to sailing. The Master should ____________.",opa:"call local police, put the seaman in prison ashore, and sail the vessel",opb:"pay off the seaman and make arrangements with the agent to return him to the original port of signing on in the U.S.",opc:"put the seaman in irons and sail to the next port where there is an American Consul",opd:"send the seaman ashore and arrange with the agent to repatriate him by armed guard",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the United States, the load line markings are set by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Coast Guard",opc:"Federal Maritime Board",opd:"IMO",ans:"opa"},{question:"If your vessel is dragging her anchor in a strong wind, you should ____________.",opa:"shorten the scope of anchor cable",opb:"increase the scope of anchor cable",opc:"put over the sea anchor",opd:"put over a stern anchor",ans:"opb"},{question:"The connection to the towline must be secured with a ____________.",opa:"galvanized screw-pin shackle",opb:"hardened steel thimble",opc:"shackle secured a nut and cotter pin",opd:"shackle fitted with a swivel piece",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel arrives in a foreign port and the Master is informed that the vessel is being sold to foreign interests. The new owners request that the crew remain on board to complete the voyage. Under these circumstances, the crew ____________.",opa:"has the right to an immediate discharge and transportation to original port of engagement",opb:"must remain on board",opc:"must comply with the decision made by the Master",opd:"must remain aboard until the vessel is delivered to the new owners at a mutually agreed upon port",ans:"opa"},{question:"The best way to determine if a load is within maximum lift limits is to use ____________.",opa:"a boom angle indicator",opb:"a load weight indicator",opc:"material invoices for shipping weights",opd:"prior experience with similar lifts",ans:"opb"},{question:"A method used to make an eye in a bight of line where it cannot be spliced is known as ____________.",opa:"braiding",opb:"plaiting",opc:"seizing",opd:"serving",ans:"opc"},{question:"One of the requirements for a general average act is ____________.",opa:"a successful venture",opb:"no imminent peril",opc:"no losses",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the signals listed is required to be displayed during the day while bunkering?",opa:"A red flag",opb:"A yellow flag",opc:"A red and yellow flag",opd:"A red light",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each crewmember has an assigned firefighting station. This assignment is shown on the ____________.",opa:"fire fighting plan",opb:"shipping articles",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"muster list",ans:"opd"},{question:"Under which condition is a tug likely to be tripped?",opa:"When the tow 'jumps' on the line",opb:"While making up to tow a large oil rig",opc:"When the towing hawser leads forward of the quarter",opd:"When the tug exerts maximum bollard pull with the tow close astern",ans:"opc"},{question:"What are reef points used for?",opa:"Reduce the area of a sail",opb:"Keep the sail taut in light airs",opc:"Reduce the draft if the boat runs aground",opd:"Increase the strength of the mast",ans:"opa"},{question:"The half-breadth plan is ____________.",opa:"an endwise view of the ship's molded form",opb:"a plan with the forebody to right of centerline and afterbody to the left of centerline",opc:"a longitudinal side elevation",opd:"usually drawn for the port side only",ans:"opd"},{question:"To warp a vessel means to ____________.",opa:"anchor the vessel",opb:"bring the head into the wind",opc:"clean the decks",opd:"move the vessel by hauling on lines",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 9?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opd"},{question:"If a mooring line should part while you are tying up at a dock, you should make a temporary eye by tying a ____________.",opa:"becket bend",opb:"clove hitch",opc:"bowline",opd:"square knot",ans:"opc"},{question:"Anchors are prevented from running out when secured by the ____________.",opa:"brake",opb:"devil's claw",opc:"pawls",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are going ahead on twin engines when you want to make a quick turn to port. Which actions will turn your boat the fastest?",opa:"Reverse port engine; apply left rudder",opb:"Reverse port engine; rudder amidships",opc:"Reverse starboard engine; apply left rudder",opd:"Reverse starboard engine; rudder amidships",ans:"opa"},{question:"The BEST holding ground for conventional anchors is ____________.",opa:"sand",opb:"very soft mud",opc:"shale",opd:"rock",ans:"opa"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator uses one hand to give any motion signal and places the other hand motionless in front of the hand giving the motion signal. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"move slowly",opb:"increase speed",opc:"proceed with caution",opd:"stop",ans:"opa"},{question:"The minimum temperature required to ignite gas or vapor without a spark or flame being present is called ____________.",opa:"flash point",opb:"fire point",opc:"autoignition temperature",opd:"lower explosive limit",ans:"opc"},{question:"Pitching is angular motion of the vessel about what axis?",opa:"Longitudinal",opb:"Transverse",opc:"Vertical",opd:"Centerline",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT considered maritime property in a salvage claim?",opa:"buoys",opb:"semi-submerged shipwreck",opc:"sea plane",opd:"cargo",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is to dock bow first at a pier. Which line will be the most useful when maneuvering the vessel alongside the pier?",opa:"Bow spring line",opb:"Bow breast line",opc:"Stern breast line",opd:"Inshore head line",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are onboard a 120 GT uninspected sea going tug which carries one Master and one Mate of Towing Vessels and four (4) seamen when underway. How many of the four seamen must have a rating as able seamen if the voyage is under 600 miles?",opa:"4",opb:"3",opc:"2",opd:"1",ans:"opc"},{question:"When an Official logbook is not required, an unofficial logbook is required to be kept aboard for review by a marine inspector for ____________.",opa:"one month",opb:"six months",opc:"12 months",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"A bench hook is used for ____________.",opa:"handling of cargo cases",opb:"hanging oilskins",opc:"sewing canvas",opd:"splicing small stuff",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is an example of the term 'Restraint of Rulers, Princes, or Peoples' in a marine insurance policy?",opa:"A prohibition from loading a cargo from a country's government interference.",opb:"Arrest of a vessel by legal authorities to satisfy claims through exercise of a maritime lien.",opc:"Damage caused by riot of the population of a port.",opd:"Losses caused by fines from polluting the harbor after malfunction of a piping system.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When can the US citizenship requirement for the Master of a US-flag uninspected towing vessel be waived?",opa:"When US-licensed Masters are not readily available",opb:"When it costs too much to hire a US-licensed Master",opc:"When the towing vessel operates shoreward of the boundary line",opd:"Never, under any circumstances",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are preparing to relieve the mate on watch while underway at sea. The watch should not be transferred ____________.",opa:"during an engine speed change",opb:"while the Master is on the bridge",opc:"during a collision avoidance maneuver",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"A wedge of water building up between the bow and nearer bank which forces the bow out and away describes ____________.",opa:"bank cushion",opb:"bank suction",opc:"combined effect",opd:"bend effect",ans:"opa"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has one hand occupied and one fist in front of his chest with the thumb pointing outward and is tapping his chest with the heel of his fist. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"extend the boom",opb:"lower the boom",opc:"retract the boom",opd:"hoist the boom",ans:"opc"},{question:"The annual survey for endorsement of a Load Line Certificate must be held within ____________.",opa:"the three month period immediately following the certificate's anniversary date",opb:"the three month period immediately preceding the certificate's anniversary date",opc:"three months either way of the certificate's anniversary date",opd:"the three month period centered on the certificate's anniversary date",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are steaming in a heavy gale and find it necessary to heave to ____________. Under most circumstances, this is best done by ____________.",opa:"stopping the engines and drifting beam to the seas",opb:"going slow astern and taking the seas on the quarter",opc:"taking the sea fine on the bow and reducing the speed to the minimum to hold that position",opd:"maintaining speed and taking the sea broad on the bow",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel puts into the port of Kobe, Japan to discharge cargo. While awaiting completion of the cargo operation, the vessel contracts with a local shipyard to have the hull chipped, scaled, and painted. How is the cost of this maintenance handled with the Collector of Customs?",opa:"A declaration is required and duty is involved on the total cost.",opb:"No declaration is required since this is considered routine maintenance.",opc:"A declaration is made and duty is charged on the materials only.",opd:"A declaration is made, but duty is charged on the labor only.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The head block is located ____________.",opa:"at the base of the boom",opb:"at the head of the boom",opc:"at the head of the mast",opd:"on top of the jack staff",ans:"opb"},{question:"An example of a messenger is a ____________.",opa:"fairlead",opb:"heaving line",opc:"stay",opd:"warp",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel has a charter party for one voyage to carry a full load of manganese from Durban, South Africa, to Baltimore, Maryland, at a stipulated rate per ton. Which type of contract is involved?",opa:"Bareboat charter party",opb:"Voyage charter party",opc:"Demise charter party",opd:"Time charter party",ans:"opb"},{question:"The space indicated by the letter J is known as the ____________.",opa:"double bottom",opb:"flooding barrier",opc:"floor space",opd:"bilge tank",ans:"opa"},{question:"If reefer spaces are not properly cleaned prior to loading cargo, it will most likely cause ____________.",opa:"mold to develop on commodities",opb:"malfunction of the refrigeration equipment",opc:"contamination of the insulation in the space",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have arrived at your anchorage location. You have put the engines astern prior to letting go the anchor. How will you know when the vessel has stopped over the ground?",opa:"The ship's log reads zero",opb:"The backwash of the propeller reaches amidships",opc:"An azimuth bearing on the beam remains steady",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Under the forces of its own weight, the suspended length of line will fall into a shape known as a ____________.",opa:"polygon",opb:"holding arc",opc:"catenary curve",opd:"parabolic curve",ans:"opc"},{question:"The body plan of a vessel is a(n) ____________.",opa:"endwise view of the ship's molded form",opb:"longitudinal side elevation view",opc:"plan made looking down on the ship, showing it's hull cut horizontally by the first set of planes",opd:"vertical view made looking up in the ship, with the keel at the center",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about splices is TRUE?",opa:"A back splice is used to permanently connect two lines together.",opb:"A long splice is used to connect two lines that will pass through narrow openings.",opc:"A short splice is used to temporarily connect two lines.",opd:"In splicing fiber rope, you would splice with the lay of the line.",ans:"opb"},{question:"When bunkering at anchorage which of the following signals must be displayed?",opa:"A red flag by day, red light by night",opb:"A red flag by day ONLY",opc:"A red light by night ONLY",opd:"No signal required at anchorage",ans:"opb"},{question:"A nylon line is rated at 15,000 lbs. breaking strain. Using a safety factor of 5, what is the safe working load (SWL)?",opa:"3,000 lbs.",opb:"5,000 lbs.",opc:"15,000 lbs.",opd:"65,000 lbs.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When using the anchor to steady the bow while approaching a dock you must be aware of the fact that ____________.",opa:"the vessel will tend to take a large sheer towards the side where the anchor is down",opb:"steering control is ineffective in trying to turn to the side opposite to that of the anchor being used",opc:"the anchor cable must never lead under the hull",opd:"using an offshore anchor decreases the chances of the anchor holding",ans:"opd"},{question:"Entries should be made in a Ro-Ro vessel\u2019s cargo-securing device record book for ____________.",opa:"procedures for accepting cargo securing devices",opb:"procedures for maintaining and repairing cargo-securing devices",opc:"record of cargo securing device inspections",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Lighter longitudinal stiffening frames on the vessel's side plating are called ____________.",opa:"stringers",opb:"side frames",opc:"side stiffeners",opd:"intercostals",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you carry packaged hazardous cargoes on a break bulk vessel bound foreign, you must ____________.",opa:"stow the hazardous cargoes on deck available for jettisoning if necessary",opb:"remove the hazardous cargo labels from a portable tank after the tank is emptied",opc:"have the shipping papers indicate the proper shipping name and the technical name of n.o.s.. cargoes",opd:"log the receipt of hazardous cargoes in the Official Logbook",ans:"opc"},{question:"One of the greatest hazards of pushing ahead is parting which item shown?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"F",opd:"I",ans:"opd"},{question:"If given equal care, nylon line should last how many times longer than manila line?",opa:"Three",opb:"Four",opc:"Five",opd:"Six",ans:"opc"},{question:"What will be accepted as the shipping papers for an unmanned tank barge but will not be accepted if the tank barge is manned?",opa:"Bill of Lading",opb:"Logbook entry",opc:"Manifest",opd:"Shipping document",ans:"opb"},{question:"On which vessels may licensed individuals be required to stand watch under the two-watch system, on voyages of more than 600 miles in length?",opa:"Uninspected towing vessels",opb:"Offshore supply vessels",opc:"Cargo ships",opd:"Tank vessels",ans:"opa"},{question:"Flammable liquid means any liquid which gives off flammable vapors at or below ____________.",opa:"40\xb0F (4.4\xb0C)",opb:"80\xb0F (26.7\xb0C)",opc:"110\xb0F (43.3\xb0C)",opd:"150\xb0F (65.6\xb0C)",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have completed a Dangerous Cargo Manifest for dangerous cargoes loaded on board. It should be kept in a conspicuous location ____________.",opa:"in the radio room",opb:"in the ship's office",opc:"on or near the bridge",opd:"outside the Captain's stateroom",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a shallow water tow, the catenary of the towline should be ____________.",opa:"large",opb:"small",opc:"eliminated",opd:"adjusted frequently",ans:"opb"},{question:"When hip towing, a line led from the stern of the towboat forward to the barge provides the towing pull when ____________.",opa:"going ahead",opb:"dead in the water",opc:"in a following current",opd:"backing",ans:"opd"},{question:"Angular motion about the longitudinal axis of a vessel is known as ____________.",opa:"pitch",opb:"surge",opc:"sway",opd:"roll",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have the 'conn' at the time the helmsman who is steering by hand reports that the rudder is not responding to the wheel. Your FIRST action should be to ____________.",opa:"call the engineroom and report that you have lost steering",opb:"signal the engineroom to stop the engines",opc:"shift the selector switch to the other steering system",opd:"call the Master",ans:"opc"},{question:"If an alien stowaway is discovered aboard your vessel, his name must be placed on the ____________.",opa:"Alien Crew List",opb:"Crew List",opc:"Passenger List",opd:"separate Passenger List marked stowaways",ans:"opd"},{question:"What safety precautions must you take when maneuvering on a towing hook?",opa:"The engines must be operated on the slow bell.",opb:"Clear the afterdeck and fantail of personnel.",opc:"Lash the hook closed so it does not open accidentally.",opd:"The towing winch engine must be running.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Butadiene, inhibited, is labeled as a ____________.",opa:"combustible liquid",opb:"flammable gas",opc:"flammable liquid",opd:"flammable solid",ans:"opb"},{question:"When preparing to hoist the anchor, you should FIRST ____________.",opa:"engage the wildcat",opb:"put the brake in the off position",opc:"take off the chain stopper",opd:"take the riding pawl off the chain",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Muster List ('Station Bill') shows each person's lifeboat station, duties during abandonment, basic instructions, and ____________.",opa:"all emergency signals",opb:"instructions for lowering the lifeboats",opc:"the time each weekly drill will be held",opd:"work schedule",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which is characteristic of a 'special cargo'?",opa:"The cargo gives off toxic gases when heated.",opb:"Periodic inspection is required while in transit to prevent spoilage.",opc:"It is of high value or easily pilferable.",opd:"It must be stowed on deck.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A wooden deck installed on top of the plating lettered N is known as ____________.",opa:"spar decking",opb:"furring",opc:"ceiling",opd:"flooring",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are anchoring in 16 fathoms of water. On a small to medium size vessel, the ____________.",opa:"anchor may be dropped from the hawsepipe",opb:"anchor should be lowered to within 2 fathoms of the bottom before being dropped",opc:"scope should always be at least ten times the depth of the water",opd:"scope should always be less than 5 times the depth of the water",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE about the use of a 'gob rope'?",opa:"The gob rope is a mooring line for tying up lighters for working cargo alongside a vessel anchored in an open roadstead.",opb:"The gob rope is used to secure the towline aft over the centerline of a tug..",opc:"The gob rope is a line hung over a vessel's side to assist in boarding.",opd:"The gob rope is a rope used in mooring a vessel to a buoy.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the minimum standard for making an eye splice in a wire to be used as cargo gear?",opa:"Make three tucks with full strands, remove half the wires from each strand, and make two more tucks.",opb:"Make four tucks in each strand, cut away every other strand, and make two more tucks with each remaining strand.",opc:"Make four tucks with each full strand.",opd:"Make six tucks with each strand, removing a few wires from each strand as each additional tuck is made.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A situation has occurred where it becomes necessary for you to be towed. What action should be taken to prevent your vessel from yawing?",opa:"Shift weight to the bow",opb:"Shift weight to the center of the boat",opc:"Shift weight to the stern",opd:"Throw excess weight overboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is to dock bow first at a pier without the assistance of tugboats. Which line will be the most useful when maneuvering the vessel alongside the pier?",opa:"Bow breast line",opb:"Bow spring line",opc:"Inshore head line",opd:"Stern breast line",ans:"opb"},{question:"On vessels over 100 gross tons, whose responsibility is it to ensure that all able seamen in the vessel's crew have the documents and qualifications required by law and regulation?",opa:"Master of the vessel",opb:"USCG Officer in Charge of Marine Inspection",opc:"Owner or operator of the vessel",opd:"Company's personnel director",ans:"opa"},{question:"The damage to a vessel is over $25,000. Who must notify the nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety or Marine Inspection Office as soon as possible?",opa:"The owner of the vessel",opb:"The Master of the vessel",opc:"The person in charge of the vessel at the time of casualty",opd:"Any one of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are using tackle number 12, as shown, to lift a weight. The hauling part of this tackle is bent to the weight hook (w) of tackle number 2. What is the mechanical advantage of this rig?",opa:"9",opb:"10",opc:"14",opd:"21",ans:"opc"},{question:"The deck beam brackets of a transversely framed vessel resist ____________.",opa:"hogging stresses",opb:"sagging stresses",opc:"racking stresses",opd:"shearing stresses",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which splice is used to connect two separate lines together?",opa:"Back splice",opb:"Chain splice",opc:"Eye splice",opd:"Long splice",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a twin-screw, twin-rudder vessel, the most effective way to turn in your own water, with no way on, is to put ____________.",opa:"one engine ahead and one engine astern, with full rudder",opb:"one engine ahead and one engine astern, with rudders amidships",opc:"both engines ahead, with full rudder",opd:"both engines astern, with full rudder",ans:"opa"},{question:"The purpose of the stripping bar on an anchor windlass is to ____________.",opa:"clean off any mud that may have accumulated on the chain",opb:"engage or disengage the wildcat",opc:"fairlead the chain from the hawsepipe to the wildcat",opd:"prevent the chain from fouling the wildcat",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following statements concerning the rigging and use of bosun's chairs is TRUE?",opa:"When riding a stay, make sure that the bow of the shackle passes through the becket of the bridle.",opb:"Always have the chair hoisted manually.",opc:"The lowering hitch should always be made before getting into the chair.",opd:"Always secure the gantline to the chair with a clove hitch.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a cargo vessel carrying toluol in bulk in portable tanks. Which is a requirement for pumping the toluol?",opa:"Hose connections to the tank must be made with a minimum of three bolts.",opb:"There must be water pressure on the fire main.",opc:"You must shut down if another vessel comes alongside.",opd:"If transferring at anchor, you must display a red flag by day and a red light at night.",ans:"opb"},{question:"In astern towing, a tow span, also called the 'tow bar' or 'towing arch', is used to ____________.",opa:"insure that the hawser leads directly aft as it passes over the stern of the towing vessel",opb:"increase the stability of the towing vessel by raising the hawser off the deck",opc:"reduce chafing of the towing hawser",opd:"prevent fouling of the hawser on deck gear located on the stern of the towing vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the main purpose of dunnage?",opa:"To act as ballast for light vessels",opb:"To provide ventilation and drainage for cargo",opc:"To secure the tarpaulins in place",opd:"To support weakened bulkheads",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning the navigation of a vessel in ice is FALSE?",opa:"Anchoring in the presence of ice is not recommended except in an emergency.",opb:"Towing a vessel through an ice field is not recommended except in an emergency.",opc:"The 'Free and Proceed' system of escorting a beset vessel cuts down on the number of freeing operations.",opd:"When anchoring in ice, it is advisable to increase the scope of the chain over what is normally used for non-icing conditions.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has his hands clasped in front of his body. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"dog everything",opb:"stop",opc:"stand-by",opd:"prepare for signal",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which mooring line is likely to undergo the most strain when docking a ship under normal conditions?",opa:"Bow line",opb:"Breast line",opc:"Spring line",opd:"Stern line",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 10?",opa:"4",opb:"4.5",opc:"5",opd:"5.5",ans:"opc"},{question:"A tanker is loaded with 12,000 barrels of #2 fuel oil. The temperature of the product is 88\xb0F. API gravity is 39\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. The net amount of cargo in barrels, loaded is ____________.",opa:"12168",opb:"12006",opc:"11994",opd:"11832",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you are bunkering and you close off one tank in the line of tanks being filled, the rate of flow to other open tanks on the same line will ____________.",opa:"increase",opb:"decrease",opc:"stop",opd:"remain constant",ans:"opa"},{question:"The helm command 'meet her' means ____________.",opa:"use rudder to check the swing",opb:"decrease the rudder angle which is on",opc:"steer more carefully",opd:"note the course and steady on that heading",ans:"opa"},{question:"The terminal indicates to you that they are going to use a booster pump to assist the discharging operation. You start the discharge, and in a few minutes the pressure drops sharply. This could be a result of the ____________.",opa:"booster pump coming on the line and discharging properly",opb:"booster pump failing to start",opc:"booster pump being lined up in the wrong direction",opd:"ship's pump speeding up",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the period of validity of a De-Rat certificate?",opa:"Specific voyage",opb:"6 months",opc:"1 year",opd:"2 years",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which vessel is exempt from the load line and marking requirements for vessels operating on the Great Lakes System?",opa:"A 300 GT tank barge operating exclusively on Lake Michigan",opb:"A 200 GT passenger vessel operating between Duluth, MN and Munising, MI",opc:"A 79-foot, 150 GT pleasure craft operating on the St. Lawrence River",opd:"A 500 GT dry cargo river barge operated continuously between Calumet Hbr Chicago, IL and Burns Hbr, IN",ans:"opd"},{question:"The scuppers had been plugged as required at the time an oil spill occurs on deck. After shutting down the transfer, the engineroom should first be informed and then ____________.",opa:"rig a fire hose and call for water on deck",opb:"spread an absorbent material, such as sawdust",opc:"remove the plugs from the scuppers",opd:"sound the general alarm",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are underway in heavy weather and your bow is into the seas. To prevent pounding, you should ____________.",opa:"change course, in order to take the seas at an 85 degree angle from the bow",opb:"decrease speed",opc:"increase speed",opd:"secure all loose gear",ans:"opb"},{question:"When carrying a cargo of asphalt or molten sulfur, which are carried at temperatures of over 300\xb0F, one of the biggest dangers is ____________.",opa:"water in the tanks or pipelines",opb:"having the cargo too cool",opc:"explosion of vapors after discharge",opd:"inadequate ullage space",ans:"opa"},{question:"Before leaving port on an ocean tow, a tug captain should assure himself of all the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"the towing hawser can be released quickly in an emergency",opb:"the correct navigation lights are rigged and operable on the tug and tow",opc:"an insurance underwriter has prepared a pre-sailing survey",opd:"a pick-up wire has been rigged on the tow in case of a breakaway.",ans:"opc"},{question:"When evacuating a seaman by helicopter lift, the vessel should be ____________.",opa:"stopped with the wind dead ahead",opb:"stopped with the wind on the beam",opc:"underway with the wind 30\xb0 on the bow",opd:"underway on a course to provide no apparent wind",ans:"opc"},{question:"A lashing used to secure three or four barges at a common corner, lashed in an 'X' fashion, is called a ____________.",opa:"scissor wire",opb:"towing wire",opc:"breast wire",opd:"cross wire",ans:"opa"},{question:"Periodic surveys to renew the load line assignment must be made at intervals NOT exceeding ____________.",opa:"18 months",opb:"two years",opc:"three years",opd:"five years",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is disabled and in imminent danger of grounding on a lee shore. The Master agrees to salvage services using Lloyd's Open Form of Salvage Agreement. Which is TRUE?",opa:"The salvage award will be decided by suit in Admiralty Court.",opb:"The salvage service is on a 'no cure-no pay' basis.",opc:"Underwriters will repudiate the agreement if it is unsuccessful, due to their increased liability.",opd:"The salvor becomes the owner of the vessel until the salvage award, if any, is paid.",ans:"opb"},{question:"If two mooring lines are to be placed on the same bollard, which method is BEST?",opa:"Place the eye from the forward line on the bollard and then place the eye from the second line directly over the first.",opb:"It makes no difference how the lines are placed.",opc:"Place the eye from either line on the bollard, and then bring the eye of the other line up through the eye of the first, and place it on the bollard.",opd:"Place both eyes on the bollard, in any manner, but lead both lines to the same winch head on the vessel and secure them on the winch.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The latch of a safety hook ____________.",opa:"increases the strength of the hook",opb:"prevents the sling ring from coming out of the hook if the strain is abruptly eased",opc:"prevents the sling ring from coming out of the hook if there is a strain on the sling ring",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A person is found operating a vessel while under the influence of alcohol. He/she is liable for ____________.",opa:"imprisonment for up to three years",opb:"a civil penalty of not more than $5,000",opc:"a fine of not more than $3,000",opd:"a fine of not more than $10,000",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement about bilge keels is CORRECT?",opa:"They are critical strength members and require careful design consideration.",opb:"They increase resistance to rolling.",opc:"They attach to a low stress area.",opd:"They provide support when the vessel is dry docked.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You would properly secure a gantline to a bosun's chair with a ____________.",opa:"fisherman's bend",opb:"bowline",opc:"double sheet bend",opd:"double blackwall hitch",ans:"opc"},{question:"A term used to describe the dip in a towline that acts as a shock absorber is ____________.",opa:"catenary",opb:"step",opc:"shock dip",opd:"bight",ans:"opa"}],this.data5=[{question:"The helm command 'Left twenty' means ____________.",opa:"change course twenty degrees to the left",opb:"put the rudder left twenty degrees",opc:"put the rudder hard left for the first twenty degrees of swing",opd:"put the rudder left twenty degrees and then ease back as the vessel starts swinging",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the stress on the hauling part when lifting a 4900 lbs. weight using a twofold purchase rove to least advantage? (Allow 10 percent of the weight per sheave for friction.)",opa:"980 lbs.",opb:"1225 lbs.",opc:"1715 lbs.",opd:"1837 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the signals listed is required to be displayed at night while bunkering at a dock?",opa:"One red light",opb:"Two red lights",opc:"One red light over a yellow light",opd:"One red light over a white light",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Officers Competency Certificates Convention of 1936 applies to all of these vessels operating seaward of the boundary line EXCEPT a/an ____________.",opa:"offshore supply vessel over 200 gross tons",opb:"passenger vessel of 295 gross tons",opc:"uninspected towing vessel of less than 200 gross tons",opd:"inspected towing vessel of 305 gross tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is backing on the starboard screw, and going ahead on the port screw. The bow will ____________.",opa:"back on a straight line",opb:"move ahead on a straight line",opc:"swing to port",opd:"swing to starboard",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which part of a cargo boom has the greatest diameter?",opa:"Head",opb:"Middle",opc:"Heel",opd:"It has the same diameter along its complete length.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are conducting trials to determine the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel. While making a turn, you take ranges and bearings of an isolated light with the results as shown. Based on this information, what is the advance for a turn of 45\xb0?",opa:"590 yards",opb:"635 yards",opc:"690 yards",opd:"740 yards",ans:"opc"},{question:"A document which has a list of names, birthplaces, and residences of persons employed on a merchant vessel bound from a U.S. port on a foreign voyage and is required at every port is called the ____________.",opa:"Certified Crew List",opb:"Crew Manifest",opc:"Shipping Articles",opd:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",ans:"opa"},{question:"The size and material used for towline(s) must meet all of the following requirements, EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"be appropriate to the vessel's horsepower or bollard pull",opb:"be strong enough to handle any static or dynamic loads expected during its service life",opc:"fit any spare wire clips carried on board the vessel for repair purposes",opd:"be suitable for exposure to the marine environment",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is taking on cargo oil when a small leak develops in the hose. You order the pumping stopped. Before you resume pumping, you should ____________.",opa:"notify the terminal superintendent",opb:"place a large drip pan under the leak and plug the scuppers",opc:"repair the hose with a patch",opd:"replace the hose",ans:"opd"},{question:"Payment of penalty for a ship's delay after the expiration of lay days due to some fault of the charterer or his agent is known as ____________.",opa:"demurrage",opb:"late fee",opc:"miscibility",opd:"volatility",ans:"opa"},{question:"A petroleum liquid has a flash point of 135\xb0 Fahrenheit. This liquid is classed as a grade ____________.",opa:"B flammable liquid",opb:"C flammable liquid",opc:"D combustible liquid",opd:"E combustible liquid",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Plimsoll mark on a vessel is used to ____________.",opa:"align the vessel's tail shaft",opb:"determine the vessel's trim",opc:"determine the vessel's freeboard",opd:"locate the vessel's centerline",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 11?",opa:"7",opb:"6",opc:"5.5",opd:"5",ans:"opb"},{question:"In towing, heaving lines are used for ____________.",opa:"passing a tow bridle to the tug",opb:"passing a messenger line",opc:"heaving in the tow bridle",opd:"service lines with rocket line throwers",ans:"opb"},{question:"The document that establishes the facts of a casualty and is the prima facie relief from liability for the damage is the ____________.",opa:"adjuster's report",opb:"insurance policy",opc:"invoice",opd:"Master's protest",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you are loading fruit in reefer spaces and you notice that the fruit is beginning to mold, you should ____________.",opa:"carry the cargo at a cooler temperature than originally planned",opb:"write up exceptions on the cargo",opc:"refuse to carry the cargo",opd:"discharge CO2 into the compartment after loading",ans:"opb"},{question:"What minimum size manila line is required to hold a weight of 932 pounds, if you use a safety factor of six?",opa:"2.0'",opb:"2.5'",opc:"3.0'",opd:"3.5'",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are approaching a disabled vessel in order to remove survivors from it. If your vessel drifts faster than the disabled vessel, how should you make your approach?",opa:"To windward of the disabled vessel",opb:"To leeward of the disabled vessel",opc:"Directly astern of the disabled vessel",opd:"At three times the drifting speed of the disabled vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"Nylon line is better suited than manila for ____________.",opa:"towing alongside",opb:"towing astern",opc:"holding knots and splices",opd:"resisting damage from chemicals",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT considered maritime property in a salvage claim?",opa:"tug boat",opb:"rafts",opc:"light-vessels",opd:"cargo",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a vessel is on autopilot steering, the 'weather' control is adjusted to compensate for which severe weather effect on a vessel?",opa:"Yaw",opb:"Roll",opc:"Pitch",opd:"Leeway",ans:"opa"},{question:"Mooring with two bow anchors has which major advantage over anchoring with one bow anchor?",opa:"The vessel will not reverse direction in a tidal current.",opb:"The radius of the vessel's swing will be shortened.",opc:"A mooring approach may be made from any direction.",opd:"The vessel will not swing with a change in wind.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is to dock bow first at a pier. Which line will be the most useful when maneuvering the vessel alongside the pier?",opa:"Stern breast line",opb:"Bow spring line",opc:"Bow breast line",opd:"Inshore head line",ans:"opb"},{question:"You start a centrifugal cargo pump to discharge cargo. The pump works for a while and then loses suction. This could be caused by ____________.",opa:"the pump running backwards",opb:"incomplete priming",opc:"the discharge head being too high",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"You should attach a towline to a trailer eye bolt using a(n) ____________.",opa:"eye splice",opb:"bowline",opc:"towing hitch",opd:"square knot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Heave is motion along the ____________.",opa:"longitudinal axis",opb:"transverse axis",opc:"vertical axis",opd:"centerline axis",ans:"opc"},{question:"The vessel shown has broken down and you are going to take her in tow. The wind is coming from her starboard beam. You are making more leeway than she. Where should you position your vessel when you start running lines?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are heading into the sea during rough weather. Having too much weight forward can cause your small boat to ____________.",opa:"broach",opb:"plunge into the wave",opc:"rise rapidly over the wave",opd:"list",ans:"opb"},{question:"A seaman assaults the Second Mate and injures him with a beer bottle while the ship is at sea. The incident is logged in the Official Logbook. In subsequent suspension and revocation proceedings against the seaman, according to the regulations, ____________.",opa:"the Second Mate and the Master must testify as to the facts of the assault",opb:"the case will be dismissed if the logbook entries are improperly made",opc:"the logbook entry is prima facie evidence of the facts if it complies with the law",opd:"the logbook is inadmissible if the logbook entries do not conform to the law",ans:"opc"},{question:"When hip towing, a line led from the bow of the towing vessel aft to the vessel being towed would be a ____________.",opa:"backing line",opb:"towing line",opc:"stern line",opd:"breast line",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are the Chief Mate of a 30,000-DWT tankship. The vessel is engaged in trade with another country signatory to MARPOL 73/78. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The Certificate of Inspection serves as prima facie evidence of complying with MARPOL 73/78.",opb:"The IOPP Certificate for an inspected vessel is valid for 5 years.",opc:"An IOPP Certificate is invalidated if the ship carries cargoes outside the classes authorized thereon.",opd:"An IOPP Certificate is renewed at each inspection for certification.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is normally used to pass a mooring line to a dock?",opa:"Distance line",opb:"Gantline",opc:"Heaving line",opd:"Tag line",ans:"opc"},{question:"A mooring line that checks forward motion of a vessel at a pier is a ____________.",opa:"bow line",opb:"forward bow line",opc:"stern line",opd:"stern breast line",ans:"opc"},{question:"In addition to the load lines indicated in illustration D003DG, some vessels have a Winter North Atlantic line. Which statement about this load line mark is TRUE?",opa:"It is carried on VLCC/ULCC type vessels and allows reduced freeboard considering their size.",opb:"It is marked above line B in the diagram.",opc:"It is applied to vessels on restricted trade routes between the United Kingdom, Iceland, and Northern European countries.",opd:"It applies only to vessels not exceeding 328 ft. navigating in the Winter North Atlantic zones.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Conditions for crossing a rough bar are usually best at ____________.",opa:"low water slack",opb:"high water slack",opc:"high water ebb",opd:"high water flood",ans:"opb"},{question:"While assigned to a 120 GRT vessel, you are required to sign 'foreign' articles on a voyage from New York City to which port?",opa:"Halifax, Canada",opb:"Long Beach, California",opc:"Veracruz, Mexico",opd:"Saint Maarten, Netherlands Antilles",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which vessel is most likely to be loaded full but not down?",opa:"A bulk carrier loaded with heavy ore",opb:"A bulk carrier loaded with steel",opc:"A break bulk vessel loaded with palletized cargo",opd:"A tanker loaded with heavy grain",ans:"opc"},{question:"Beams are cambered to ____________.",opa:"increase their strength",opb:"provide drainage from the decks",opc:"relieve deck stress",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following statements is TRUE regarding lashing requirements to secure vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"It is NOT imperative that the securing of cargo on flats and trailers and in containers be adequate for BOTH road and sea motions.",opb:"The generally recommended lash angle should not be greater than 45 degrees relative to the deck in any direction.",opc:"For effective securing vehicles should be stowed athwartships whenever possible.",opd:"It is not necessary to lash automobiles since setting the brakes is sufficient to keep them from moving.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Under the federal regulations, what minimum level of Blood Alcohol Content (BAC) constitutes a violation of the laws prohibiting Boating Under the Influence of Alcohol (BUI) on commercial vessels?",opa:".18% BAC",opb:".10% BAC",opc:".06% BAC",opd:".04% BAC",ans:"opd"},{question:"While on watch at sea you must maintain a proper lookout at all times. You are on a 200-foot cargo vessel with an unobstructed view astern from the steering position. The vessel is being hand-steered during daylight hours in good visibility and clear of any navigational hazards. The lookout may be ____________.",opa:"the helmsman",opb:"the officer on watch",opc:"Either A or B",opd:"Neither A nor B",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 6?",opa:"6",opb:"5.5",opc:"5",opd:"3",ans:"opa"},{question:"Of which type of material may a towing hawser be constructed?",opa:"Wire rope",opb:"Nylon",opc:"Polyester",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Securing cargo by running timbers from an upper support down to the cargo, either vertically or at an angle, is called ____________.",opa:"braces",opb:"dunnage",opc:"shores",opd:"toms",ans:"opd"},{question:"The citizenship of a crew member of a vessel in a U.S. port is determined solely by the ____________.",opa:"Customs Officer",opb:"Immigration Officer",opc:"Coast Guard",opd:"Union Official",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a vessel that carries liquefied gasses in bulk. The person on watch is required to have what information about the cargo easily accessible?",opa:"Port of loading",opb:"Exact quantity on board",opc:"Name and address of consignee",opd:"Firefighting procedures",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to hoist?",opa:"With forearm vertical and forefinger pointing up, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opb:"With arm extended downwards and forefinger pointing down, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opc:"Extend arm with fingers closed and thumb pointing upward.",opd:"Place both fists in front of body with the thumbs pointing upward.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Small hull leaks can be temporarily repaired by ____________.",opa:"parceling",opb:"parbuckling",opc:"caulking",opd:"seizing",ans:"opc"},{question:"A Chinese stopper (two lines) will hold best when you ____________.",opa:"fasten the bitter ends to the mooring line with half hitches",opb:"twist the ends together and hold them in the direction of the pull",opc:"twist the ends together and hold them in the direction opposite to the pull",opd:"twist the ends together and hold them at right angles to the mooring line",ans:"opb"},{question:"What produces the MOST dangerous vapors?",opa:"Anhydrous ammonia",opb:"Camphor oil",opc:"Methyl alcohol",opd:"Pentane",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a tow is trimmed by the stern it is said to ____________.",opa:"hog",opb:"sag",opc:"drag",opd:"list",ans:"opc"},{question:"An example of an anchor which has a stock is a ____________.",opa:"Bruce anchor",opb:"Dunn anchor",opc:"Hook anchor",opd:"Danforth anchor",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your U.S. tankship is designed to carry anhydrous ammonia in bulk. The keel was laid in 1980. Which statement concerning the carriage of this cargo is TRUE?",opa:"A flammable gas detection system must be installed in each cargo pump room.",opb:"The cargo may be gauged by automatic float type devices.",opc:"Carriage of this cargo is authorized by issuance of an IMO Certificate.",opd:"Aluminum, copper, zinc, and mercury are allowed in valve parts in contact with the cargo.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tanker is loaded with 12,000 barrels of #2 fuel oil. The temperature of the product is 88\xb0F. API gravity is 39\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. The net amount of cargo in gallons, loaded is ____________.",opa:"496944",opb:"511056",opc:"650760",opd:"669240",ans:"opa"},{question:"An advantage of nylon rope over manila rope is that nylon rope ____________.",opa:"can be used in conjunction with wire or spring-lay rope",opb:"can be stored on decks exposed to sunlight",opc:"can hold a load even when a considerable amount of the yarns have been abraded",opd:"gives audible warning of overstress whereas manila does not",ans:"opc"},{question:"A 'check' line is ____________.",opa:"a safety line attached to a man working over the side",opb:"used to measure water depth",opc:"used to slow the headway of a barge",opd:"used to measure the overhead height of a bridge",ans:"opc"},{question:"A disadvantage of using chain lashing on heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels is that it is ____________.",opa:"heavy",opb:"easily damaged",opc:"affected by temperature",opd:"costly relative to the strength ratio",ans:"opa"},{question:"With rudders amidships and negligible wind, a twin-screw vessel moving ahead on the port screw and backing on the starboard screw will ____________.",opa:"move in a straight line",opb:"pivot to starboard",opc:"pivot to port",opd:"walk sideways to starboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"When selecting the fuel oil tanks for the 'burn-out' of bunkers during a voyage consideration of all of the following must be taken with the EXCEPTION of ____________.",opa:"flashpoint",opb:"stability",opc:"trim",opd:"list",ans:"opa"},{question:"A Notice of Marine Casualty to a vessel must include ____________.",opa:"the estimated cost of damage",opb:"the name of the owner or agent of the vessel",opc:"an evaluation of who was at fault",opd:"the amount of ballast on board",ans:"opb"},{question:"The section of each end of a barge which is heavily reinforced to take the pressure of pushing is called the ____________.",opa:"headlog",opb:"towhead",opc:"collision bulkhead",opd:"bullnose",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is a CORRECT reply to a pilot's request, 'How's your head'?",opa:"'Steady'",opb:"'Eased to 10\xb0 rudder'",opc:"'Checked'",opd:"'Passing 50\xb0'",ans:"opd"},{question:"Single hull vessels operating exclusively on the Great Lakes must be dry docked at intervals not to exceed ____________.",opa:"12 months",opb:"24 months",opc:"48 months",opd:"60 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"The purpose of sheer in ship construction is to ____________.",opa:"allow the ship to ride waves with drier decks",opb:"eliminate the need for butt straps",opc:"eliminate the need for margin plates",opd:"give greater strength at the deck edge",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which U.S. Government agency can suspend or revoke a Merchant Mariner's license for violating the load line act?",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"U.S. Coast Guard",opc:"U.S. Customs Service",opd:"U.S. Maritime Administration",ans:"opb"},{question:"A precaution you should take before bunkering is to ____________.",opa:"plug the vents",opb:"plug the sounding pipes",opc:"plug the scuppers",opd:"close the lids on the vents",ans:"opc"},{question:"The amount of force a tug can exert on a stationary pull is called its ____________.",opa:"brake horsepower",opb:"indicated horsepower",opc:"shaft horsepower",opd:"bollard pull",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are conducting trials to determine the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel. While making a turn you take the ranges and bearings of an isolated light with the results shown. Based on this information, what is the transfer for a turn of 75\xb0?",opa:"340 yards (306 meters)",opb:"300 yards (274 meters)",opc:"230 yards (207 meters)",opd:"190 yards (171 meters)",ans:"opb"},{question:"The term 'bollard pull' refers to a towing vessel's ____________.",opa:"propulsion horsepower available",opb:"pulling ability at cruise power",opc:"towing winch capability",opd:"pulling ability under static conditions",ans:"opd"},{question:"When moored with a Mediterranean moor, the ship should be secured to the pier by having ____________.",opa:"a stern line and two quarter lines crossing under the stern",opb:"a stern line, 2 bow lines, and 2 quarter lines leading aft to the pier",opc:"all regular lines leading to the pier in opposition to the anchor",opd:"two bow lines and two midship lines leading aft to the pier",ans:"opa"},{question:"What will NOT reduce yawing of a tow?",opa:"Increasing the length of the towing hawser",opb:"Trimming the tow by the stern",opc:"Stowing deck loads forward",opd:"Drogues put over the stern",ans:"opc"},{question:"The best way to lift many small articles aboard your vessel is with a ____________.",opa:"pallet",opb:"barrel hook",opc:"spreader",opd:"snotter",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel which is being assisted by an icebreaker would display a flag hoist consisting of the code numeral '4' when the vessel ____________.",opa:"speed begins to drop",opb:"stops",opc:"receives ice damage",opd:"becomes icebound",ans:"opd"},{question:"The usual method of arranging a line on deck so that it will run out easily without kinking or fouling is ____________.",opa:"coiling the line",opb:"faking down the line",opc:"flemishing the line",opd:"racking the line",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT an advantage of a wire towing hawser?",opa:"Easy to handle when properly spooled on the drum of a towing winch.",opb:"Has more spring and shock resistance than synthetic.",opc:"Can be used to tow heavier loads because of its smaller diameter and more manageable size.",opd:"Subject to less deterioration than synthetic if properly maintained.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A long pole with a hook at one end, used to reach for lines, is known as a ____________.",opa:"pike pole",opb:"jack staff",opc:"line rod",opd:"hooker",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are using tackle number 2 to lift a weight of 100 lbs. If you include 10 percent of the weight for each sheave for friction, what is the pull on the hauling part required to lift the weight?",opa:"50 lbs.",opb:"55 lbs.",opc:"60 lbs.",opd:"110 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the stress on the hauling part when lifting a 4,200 lbs. weight using a threefold purchase rove to advantage? (Allow 10 percent of the weight per sheave for friction.)",opa:"571.4",opb:"715.2",opc:"960",opd:"1066.7",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are operating a 150 GT towing vessel. What is NOT required on the vessel?",opa:"Certificate of Documentation",opb:"FCC station license",opc:"Your Coast Guard license",opd:"Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about the deck line is TRUE?",opa:"The top of the deck line is marked at the highest point of the freeboard deck, including camber, at the midships point.",opb:"A vessel with wooden planks on a steel deck will have the deck line marked at the intersection of the upper line of the wood sheathing with the side shell.",opc:"The deck edge is marked at the intersection of the freeboard deck with the side shell, at the lowest point of sheer, with the vessel at even trim.",opd:"On a vessel with a rounded stringer-sheer plate, the deck line is marked where the stringer plate turns down from the plane of the deck line.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The maximum length allowed between main, transverse bulkheads on a vessel is referred to as the ____________.",opa:"floodable length",opb:"factor of subdivision",opc:"compartment standard",opd:"permissible length",ans:"opd"},{question:"Delivery of a vessel to a charterer is called ____________.",opa:"chartering",opb:"dispatching",opc:"fixing",opd:"tendering",ans:"opd"},{question:"A document used to indicate suspected cargo damage caused by rough weather would be the ____________.",opa:"cargo report",opb:"hull damage report",opc:"Master's Note of Protest",opd:"Unseaworthy Certificate",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following grade classifications is assigned to camphor oil?",opa:"A",opb:"C",opc:"D",opd:"E",ans:"opc"},{question:"You start a centrifugal cargo pump to discharge cargo. The pump works for a while and then loses suction. This could NOT be caused by ____________.",opa:"leaking shaft seals",opb:"air pockets in the liquid",opc:"high cargo level in the tanks",opd:"a leaking suction line",ans:"opc"},{question:"When 'checking down' a barge using a check line you should use ____________.",opa:"one round turn and at least two figure-eights around the timber heads",opb:"at least three figure-eights around the timber heads",opc:"a clove hitch around one timber head",opd:"at least three round turns around one timber head",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the computed breaking strength of a 4-inch manila line?",opa:"5,280 lbs.",opb:"7,700 lbs.",opc:"12,200 lbs.",opd:"14,400 lbs.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The recessed areas on a wildcat are called ____________.",opa:"pawls",opb:"sockets",opc:"pockets",opd:"devil's claws",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are conducting trials to determine the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel. While making a turn, you take ranges and bearings of an isolated light with the results shown. Based on this information, what is the transfer for a turn of 45\xb0?",opa:"130 yards",opb:"165 yards",opc:"195 yards",opd:"230 yards",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 1?",opa:"Whip",opb:"One-fold purchase",opc:"Gun tackle",opd:"Runner",ans:"opa"},{question:"When fruit is carried as refrigerated cargo, the most frequent cause of its being infected at the discharge port is ____________.",opa:"leaks in the ship's refrigeration system",opb:"improper cleaning of the cargo spaces",opc:"carriage at the wrong temperature",opd:"improper precooling of the cargo spaces",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have anchored in a mud and clay bottom. The anchor appears to be dragging in a storm. What action should you take?",opa:"Shorten the scope of the cable.",opb:"Veer cable to the anchor.",opc:"Drop the other anchor underfoot.",opd:"Drop the second anchor, veer to a good scope, then weigh the first anchor.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has been damaged and you must shore a bulkhead. You should cut the shore ____________.",opa:"approximately 1/2 inch longer than the measured length to allow for trimming",opb:"approximately 1/2 inch shorter than the measured length to allow for wedges",opc:"approximately 1/2 inch shorter per foot of shoring to allow for wet expansion",opd:"to the same length as the measured length",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is NOT a required entry in the ship's Official Logbook?",opa:"Sale of effects of a deceased crew member",opb:"Medical treatment of an injury",opc:"Inspections of cargo gear",opd:"Dry docking of the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a vessel carrying liquefied butadiene in bulk. Which document is NOT required to be either in the wheelhouse or easily accessible to the person on watch while underway?",opa:"Cargo manual",opb:"Cargo information card",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Shipping document",ans:"opa"},{question:"It is permissible to place an eye splice in wire rope used as cargo gear providing the splice is made using ____________.",opa:"two tucks with whole strands and one tuck with one-half strand",opb:"three tucks with whole strands and two tucks with 1/2 the wire cut from the tucking strand",opc:"three tucks with whole strands",opd:"two tucks with whole strands and three tucks with half strands",ans:"opb"},{question:"A fid is a ____________.",opa:"mallet used when splicing wire rope",opb:"sharp pointed crow bar used to unlay wire rope",opc:"tapered steel pin used to separate wire rope",opd:"tapered wooden pin used when splicing heavy rope",ans:"opd"},{question:"The 'weather adjustment' control on an autopilot steering stand is used to ____________.",opa:"allow leeway according to the weather conditions",opb:"proportionally set the number of degrees of rudder response per degree of course error",opc:"set the null band or dead zone signal before actuating the rudder",opd:"set the speed at which the rudder responds",ans:"opc"},{question:"A rope made of a combination of wire and fiber is known as ____________.",opa:"independent",opb:"lang lay",opc:"preformed",opd:"spring lay",ans:"opd"},{question:"A periodic thorough examination of the cargo gear proves satisfactory. What percentage of the total gear must be dismantled to determine actual internal condition?",opa:"None",opb:"0.1",opc:"0.25",opd:"1",ans:"opa"},{question:"The fittings used to secure a watertight door are known as ____________.",opa:"clamps",opb:"clasps",opc:"dogs",opd:"latches",ans:"opc"},{question:"When maneuvering a heavy barge up a wide channel with a tug, the tow may be most closely controlled by making up to the barge ____________.",opa:"with a short tow astern",opb:"nearly bow to bow, at a small angle",opc:"amidships, parallel to the barge",opd:"nearly stern to stern, at a small angle to the barge",ans:"opd"},{question:"When making a wire fast to bitts it is recommended that you ____________.",opa:"use only figure eights",opb:"take 2 round turns around one bitt, then make figure eights",opc:"take 3 round turns around both bitts, then make figure eights",opd:"alternate round turns and figure eights around both bitts",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to use the main hoist?",opa:"Use one hand to give any motion signal, and place the other hand motionless in front of the hand giving the motion signal.",opb:"Extend arm with the thumb pointing up and flex the fingers in and out for as long as the load movement is desired.",opc:"First tap your elbow with one hand, and then proceed to use regular signals.",opd:"First tap the top of your head with your fist, and then proceed to use regular signals.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You may be able to avoid loss of suction in a pump by ____________.",opa:"using a full tank to keep the pump primed",opb:"opening the vent cock on the pump",opc:"closing down on the tank valve",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A Kort nozzle is a(n) ____________.",opa:"hollow tube surrounding the propeller used to improve thrust",opb:"nozzle attached to a firefighting hose",opc:"intake valve on a diesel engine",opd:"piston cylinder on a diesel engine",ans:"opa"},{question:"The damage to a vessel is over $25,000. Who must notify the nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety or Marine Inspection Office as soon as possible?",opa:"The person in charge of the vessel",opb:"The operator of the vessel",opc:"The Master of the vessel",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The disadvantage of using three strand nylon line for towing is its ____________.",opa:"inherent weakness",opb:"tendency to rot if left damp",opc:"danger to crew if it parts",opd:"strength and shock absorbing abilities",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the stowage of deck cargo, 'cribbing' is ____________.",opa:"placed on deck to support the cargo",opb:"separation pieces used to keep cylinders upright and steady",opc:"shims for stowing baled cargo",opd:"nets placed across the hatch opening to keep the cargo from falling in the hatch",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is an example of a fundamental objective of cargo stowage?",opa:"Load so the trim does not exceed 3 feet by the stern.",opb:"Make maximum use of existing dunnage.",opc:"Separate wet and dry cargoes into separate holds.",opd:"Prevent overcarriage by block stowage.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are 15 feet off a pier and docking a vessel using only a bow breast line and stern breast line. Once the slack is out of both lines you begin to haul in on the bow breast line. What is the effect on the vessel?",opa:"The bow will come in and the stern will go out.",opb:"The bow and stern come in equally closer toward the pier.",opc:"The bow will come in and the stern will remain the same distance off the pier.",opd:"The stern will come in and the bow will remain the same distance off the pier.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Tensile stress is a result of two forces acting in ____________.",opa:"opposite directions on the same line, tending to pull the material apart",opb:"opposite directions on the same line, tending to compress the object",opc:"opposite directions along parallel lines",opd:"the same direction along parallel lines",ans:"opa"},{question:"The easiest way to anchor a vessel in a current is to ____________.",opa:"stem the current and make very slow headway when the anchor is dropped",opb:"stem the current and be falling aft very slowly when the anchor is dropped",opc:"stem the current and endeavor to make neither headway nor sternway when the anchor is dropped",opd:"stop all headway through the water and keep the current astern when the anchor is dropped",ans:"opb"},{question:"A 30,000 DWT tankship is required to have an IOPP certificate when ____________.",opa:"engaged in the coastwise trade",opb:"going foreign",opc:"calling at ports in another country signatory to MARPOL 73/78",opd:"carrying cargoes listed in the MARPOL regulations",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to stop?",opa:"Place both fists in front of your body with the thumbs pointing outward.",opb:"With both arms extended out and palms down, move arms back and forth.",opc:"Extend arm with the palm down and hold this position rigidly.",opd:"Clasp hands in front of your body.",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to Pollution Prevention Regulations (33CFR), after every designated operation, the Oil Record Book is to be signed by ____________.",opa:"the master",opb:"a licensed officer present at the operation designated by the master",opc:"person(s) in charge of the operation",opd:"person(s) in charge of the operation and a licensed officer present at the operation",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the available references, determine the dew point when the dry bulb temperature is 74\xb0F (23\xb0C) and the wet bulb temperature is 60\xb0F (16\xb0C).",opa:"14\xb0F",opb:"20\xb0F",opc:"28\xb0F",opd:"50\xb0F",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which term describes a rope in which three right-handed strands are laid up left-handed?",opa:"Soft-laid",opb:"Hard-laid",opc:"Shroud laid",opd:"Hawser-laid",ans:"opd"},{question:"What does 'end for end' mean in regard to a towing hawser?",opa:"To take the kinks out of the hawser",opb:"To fake it down in figure eights",opc:"To increase the catenary",opd:"To swap ends of the hawser to minimize wear",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are standing look-out duty at night. A dim light on the horizon will be seen quickest by looking ____________.",opa:"at an area just a little below the horizon",opb:"at the horizon, where the sky and water appear to meet",opc:"a little above the horizon",opd:"well below the horizon",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are mooring to a buoy. You should approach the buoy with the current from ____________.",opa:"ahead",opb:"broad on the bow",opc:"abeam",opd:"astern",ans:"opa"},{question:"The holding capability of an anchor is primarily determined by the ____________.",opa:"shape of the anchor",opb:"stowage of the anchor on board",opc:"anchor's ability to dig in",opd:"size of the vessel and its draft",ans:"opc"},{question:"When measuring the oxygen content of the cargo tanks prior to loading cargoes requiring vapor recovery, check it ____________.",opa:"one meter from the tank bottom and one meter below the tank top",opb:"one half the ullage of the tank and one meter below the tank top",opc:"one half the ullage of the tank and one meter above the tank bottom",opd:"at three meter intervals from the tank top to the bottom",ans:"opb"},{question:"What does a Visaed Alien Crew List which is made and submitted to the U.S. Consul for visa show?",opa:"All aliens aboard",opb:"All crew members",opc:"Nonresident aliens aboard",opd:"Registered aliens aboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"The angle at which the fluke penetrates the soil is called the ____________.",opa:"tripping angle",opb:"fluke angle",opc:"penetration angle",opd:"holding angle",ans:"opb"},{question:"When relieving the helm, the new helmsman should find it handy to know the ____________.",opa:"leeway",opb:"variation in the area",opc:"amount of helm carried for a steady course",opd:"deviation on that heading",ans:"opc"},{question:"Each open lifeboat carried on a vessel on an international voyage must have ____________.",opa:"hand-propelling gear",opb:"a davit span with at least 2 lifelines",opc:"a mast and a sail",opd:"a motor",ans:"opb"},{question:"The disadvantage(s) of using chain lashing on heavy vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels is that ____________.",opa:"it is heavy",opb:"the links lose strength if placed over corners",opc:"it does not absorb shock",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Considering manning requirements for US flag vessels, your 2 watch cargo vessel has a deck crew of 20 people, exclusive of officers. How many of these people do the manning regulations require to be able seamen?",opa:"13",opb:"10",opc:"7",opd:"5",ans:"opb"},{question:"A contract of affreightment is a ____________.",opa:"Bill of Lading",opb:"Bottomry Bond",opc:"manifest",opd:"Portage Bill",ans:"opa"},{question:"Kort nozzles are installed around the propellers of some vessels to ____________.",opa:"increase the thrust of the propeller",opb:"protect the propeller from striking sawyers",opc:"prevent the propeller from striking barges towed on the hip",opd:"prevent the propeller from touching bottom in low water",ans:"opa"},{question:"When barge headlogs do not meet or are not even with one another, the void or opening between them is called a ____________.",opa:"notch",opb:"hole",opc:"spacing",opd:"gap",ans:"opa"},{question:"A cargo of 10,000 barrels of gasoline is loaded at a temperature of 90\xb0F, and a cargo temperature of 55\xb0F, is expected on this voyage. It has a coefficient of expansion of .0006. How many barrels would you expect to discharge at your destination?",opa:"9790",opb:"9994",opc:"10210",opd:"10410",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your U.S. tankship is designed to carry anhydrous ammonia in bulk. The keel was laid in 1980. Which statement concerning the carriage of this cargo is TRUE?",opa:"A flammable gas detection system must be installed in each cargo pump room.",opb:"Tanks may not be located 'on deck'.",opc:"Carriage of this cargo is authorized by issuance of an IMO Certificate.",opd:"Aluminum and copper alloys are prohibited from being in valve parts in contact with the cargo.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Molded depth is measured from the ____________.",opa:"inside of the shell",opb:"outside of the shell",opc:"top of the center vertical keel",opd:"top of the garboard stake",ans:"opa"},{question:"The static bollard pull of a tug is measured in tons and consists of the brake horsepower of the tug's engine divided by 100 and multiplied by a factor of ____________.",opa:"0.5",opb:"1.3",opc:"3",opd:"10",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are as shown. Based on this data what is the transfer for a turn of 90\xb0?",opa:"400 yards",opb:"430 yards",opc:"485 yards",opd:"525 yards",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on watch at sea and find it prudent to call the Master to the bridge due to traffic congestion. The moment that the Master officially relieves you of the conn is whenever ____________.",opa:"a watch stander announces 'Captain's on the bridge'",opb:"you call the Captain to the bridge in a traffic situation",opc:"the Master specifically informs you that he has the conn",opd:"the Captain states the course being steered",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is port side to a pier with a spring line led aft from the bow. In calm weather, putting the engines ahead with the rudder hard left should bring ____________.",opa:"the bow in and the stern out",opb:"both the bow and stern in",opc:"the bow out and the stern in",opd:"both the bow and stern out",ans:"opa"},{question:"In order to pay out or slack a mooring line which is under strain, you should ____________.",opa:"sluice the line",opb:"surge the line",opc:"stopper the line",opd:"slip the line",ans:"opb"},{question:"Commercial ships or other persons or agencies requiring the assistance of Canadian Coast Guard icebreakers should first contact ____________.",opa:"the Canadian Coast Guard",opb:"Ice Sarnia",opc:"the Ice Navigation Center",opd:"the icebreaker assigned to the area",ans:"opb"},{question:"How does the effect known as 'bank suction' act on a single-screw vessel proceeding along a narrow channel?",opa:"It pulls the stern toward the bank.",opb:"It heels the vessel toward the bank.",opc:"It pushes the entire vessel away from the bank.",opd:"It pulls the bow toward the bank.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE about hooks and shackles?",opa:"Hooks are stronger than shackles of the same diameter.",opb:"Shackles are stronger than hooks of the same diameter.",opc:"Hooks and shackles of the same diameter are of equal strength.",opd:"All the above may be true, depending on the hook's or shackle's overall length.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tug in irons is ____________.",opa:"rudder bound",opb:"being tripped by the towline",opc:"unable to maneuver",opd:"broached",ans:"opc"},{question:"'Avast' means ____________.",opa:"let go",opb:"pull",opc:"slack off",opd:"stop",ans:"opd"},{question:"Where should the foundation supports for towing bitts terminate?",opa:"Forward of the towing winch",opb:"In the frames or other substantial structural members below decks",opc:"On the deck plates in the engineroom",opd:"On deck, aft of the towing winch",ans:"opb"},{question:"When towing another vessel astern, the length of the towline should be ____________.",opa:"as long as possible",opb:"such that one vessel will be on a crest while the other is in a trough",opc:"such that the vessels will be 'in step'",opd:"not over two wave lengths in seas up to 10 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A towing vessel's capability is BEST measured by horsepower, maneuverability, displacement, and ____________.",opa:"stability",opb:"propeller design",opc:"bollard pull",opd:"towing winch horsepower",ans:"opc"},{question:"Freeing ports on a vessel with solid bulwarks ____________.",opa:"prevent stress concentration in the bulwark",opb:"permit easy jettison of deck cargo in an emergency",opc:"provide openings through the bulwarks for mooring lines",opd:"allow water shipped on deck to flow off rapidly",ans:"opd"},{question:"Weight concentration in which area will cause a vessel's bottom to be subjected to tension stresses?",opa:"Aft",opb:"Amidships",opc:"At both ends",opd:"Forward",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which ending is NOT acceptable in a wire rope that is free to rotate when hoisting?",opa:"Poured socket",opb:"Liverpool eye splice",opc:"Eye formed with a pressure clamped sleeve",opd:"Eye formed by clips",ans:"opb"},{question:"A nylon line is rated at 12,000 lbs. breaking strain. Using a safety factor of 5, what is the safe working load (SWL)?",opa:"2,000 lbs.",opb:"2,400 lbs.",opc:"12,000 lbs.",opd:"60,000 lbs.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are using tackle number 5 to lift a weight. The hauling part of this tackle is bent to the weight hook (w) of tackle number 8. What is the mechanical advantage of this rig?",opa:"20",opb:"15",opc:"10",opd:"5",ans:"opb"},{question:"For the purpose of regulating tank vessels, flammable liquids are liquids which will ____________.",opa:"give off flammable vapors at or below 80\xb0F (27\xb0C)",opb:"have a Reid vapor pressure of 18 pounds or more",opc:"give off flammable vapors only above 80\xb0F (27\xb0C)",opd:"sustain combustion at a temperature at or below 100\xb0F (38\xb0C)",ans:"opa"},{question:"The best information on the location of the blocks when dry docking a vessel is contained in the ____________.",opa:"shell expansion plan",opb:"docking diagram",opc:"ship's docking plan",opd:"general arrangement plan",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT required on an uninspected towing vessel?",opa:"Certificate of Documentation",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Operators Merchant Marine license",opd:"FCC Station License",ans:"opb"},{question:"How much force would be required to lift a weight of 200 lbs. using a gun tackle rigged to disadvantage (do not consider friction)?",opa:"50 lbs.",opb:"100 lbs.",opc:"150 lbs.",opd:"200 lbs.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You should keep clear of ____________.",opa:"any line under a strain",opb:"lines that are paying out",opc:"lines that are coiled down only",opd:"None of the above are correct",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are conducting trials to determine the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel. While making a turn, you take ranges and bearings of an isolated light with the results as shown. Based on this information, what is the transfer for a turn of 180\xb0?",opa:"875 yards",opb:"910 yards",opc:"975 yards",opd:"1015 yards",ans:"opb"},{question:"The 'rudder adjustment' control on an autopilot steering stand is used to ____________.",opa:"align the rudder angle indicator with the true rudder angle",opb:"set the number of degrees of rudder per degree of course error",opc:"set the departure from base course before actuating the rudder",opd:"set the rate at which the rudder responds",ans:"opb"},{question:"What should you be concerned with when loading and securing vehicles aboard a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"That all fuel is drained from the vehicles' tanks to prevent fire hazard",opb:"The size, weight, and center of gravity of vehicle/cargo unit",opc:"The preferred stowage of vehicles is athwartships wherever possible",opd:"The vehicles' brakes should not be set to allow for adjusting the lashings",ans:"opb"},{question:"A Master should file a marine note of protest if ____________.",opa:"cargo was received at ship side which was damaged in land transit",opb:"longshore labor went on strike in the port causing undue vessel delay",opc:"portions of his vessel's cargo were illegally impounded in a foreign port",opd:"the vessel encountered heavy weather which might have caused cargo damage",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 2?",opa:"Whip",opb:"One fold purchase",opc:"Single purchase",opd:"Gun tackle",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Oil Record Book for all fixed or floating drilling rigs is the property of the ____________.",opa:"U.S. government",opb:"state in whose water the drilling rig is located",opc:"drilling rig's owner",opd:"company leasing the drilling rig",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following is a characteristic of a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Passenger tours available upon docking",opb:"Long port stays necessary to secure vehicles",opc:"Short in port turnaround times",opd:"Heavy vehicles only require lightweight securing equipment",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are landing a single-screw vessel, with a right-hand propeller, starboard side to the dock. When you have approached the berth and back the engine, you would expect the vessel to ____________.",opa:"lose headway without swinging",opb:"turn her bow toward the dock",opc:"turn her bow away from the dock",opd:"head into the wind, regardless of the side the wind is on",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are anchoring in a river where the current is from one direction only. The best way to lay out two anchors is to have them ____________.",opa:"directly in line with the bow",opb:"side by side, with their lines on the port and starboard side",opc:"so that their lines form an angle",opd:"on top of one another",ans:"opc"},{question:"A whipping on a fiber line ____________.",opa:"keeps the ends from fraying",opb:"strengthens it",opc:"protects your hands",opd:"becomes part of a splice",ans:"opa"},{question:"To coil a left-hand laid rope, you should coil the line in ____________.",opa:"a clockwise direction only",opb:"a counterclockwise direction only",opc:"an alternating clockwise and counterclockwise direction",opd:"either a clockwise or a counterclockwise direction",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your tankship is carrying a 30% solution of hydrogen peroxide. The cargo containment system must have a permanent inert gas system. While discharging this cargo the inert gas system must maintain a minimum pressure of ____________.",opa:"0.5 psig",opb:"3.0 psig",opc:"5.0 psig",opd:"atmospheric pressure",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which type of shackle is used for most towing connections?",opa:"Safety shackles",opb:"Round pin anchor shackles",opc:"Screw pin shackles",opd:"Heart shaped shackles",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a cargo boom or crane is rated at varying capacities, there will be a table at the controls which relates safe working load to ____________.",opa:"winch speed",opb:"boom strength",opc:"load radius",opd:"cable strength",ans:"opc"},{question:"As seen from the tow, what should connect the leading ends of both towing bridle legs to the main towing hawser?",opa:"A cable clamp",opb:"A fishplate, flounder, or towing plate",opc:"A pad eye",opd:"The towing bitts",ans:"opb"},{question:"The official logbook is filed with the Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection (OCMI) ____________.",opa:"upon completion of the voyage",opb:"at the next Certificate of Inspection",opc:"within 30 days of the date of arrival of the first U.S. port",opd:"at the end of the year with all other official logbooks",ans:"opa"},{question:"A metal ring on the bottom of a block, to which the standing part of a tackle is spliced, is known as a(n) ____________.",opa:"becket",opb:"loop",opc:"swivel",opd:"eye",ans:"opa"},{question:"The critical point in nylon line elongation is about ____________.",opa:"0.2",opb:"0.3",opc:"0.4",opd:"0.5",ans:"opc"},{question:"Ice is often strong enough to halt navigation through the St. Lawrence Seaway by mid-____________.",opa:"October",opb:"November",opc:"December",opd:"January",ans:"opc"},{question:"When oily ballast has been pumped overboard, an entry must be made in the ____________.",opa:"Oil Record Book",opb:"Official Logbook",opc:"deck rough log",opd:"engine rough log",ans:"opa"},{question:"When loading a tanker, you should ____________.",opa:"load only one tank at a time",opb:"keep the seamen on watch on standby in the mess room",opc:"keep a strain on the loading hoses",opd:"close valves by closing them down, reopening one or two turns, and re-closing",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is likely to occur when you are surging synthetic mooring lines on the gypsyhead during mooring operations?",opa:"The lines may jam and then jump off the gypsyhead.",opb:"If there is sudden strain on the line, the man tending the line may be pulled into the gypsyhead.",opc:"The lines' surging may cause the vessel to surge.",opd:"The heat generated may cause the lines to temporarily fuse to the gypsyhead.",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to the IMO Code, what are the minimum number of securing points that should be on each side of a 'road vehicle', whose gross vehicle mass is between 20 tons and 30 tons, when carried on Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Freeboard is measured from the upper edge of the ____________.",opa:"bulwark",opb:"deck line",opc:"gunwale bar",opd:"sheer strake",ans:"opb"},{question:"When making up a long, large coastwise tow, which of the following procedures is INCORRECT?",opa:"A chain towing bridle is generally preferred",opb:"Safety shackles should be used when connecting to the fishplate",opc:"Rig tripping ropes (retrieving lines)",opd:"Back-up wires are left slack",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT surveyed at an annual load line survey?",opa:"The overall structure and layout of the vessel for alterations to the superstructure",opb:"The bilge pumping system",opc:"Main deck hatch covers",opd:"Portholes and deadlights in the side plating",ans:"opb"},{question:"A 'contra-guide' is a type of ____________.",opa:"bow thruster",opb:"cargo gear",opc:"steering engine",opd:"rudder",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 6?",opa:"Triple purchase",opb:"Clew garnet tackle",opc:"Boat falls",opd:"Threefold purchase",ans:"opd"},{question:"When steering a vessel, a good helmsman does NOT ____________.",opa:"consider steering a vessel a highly responsible job",opb:"use as much rudder as possible to keep the vessel on course",opc:"use as little rudder as possible to keep the vessel on course",opd:"advise his relief of the course being steered",ans:"opb"},{question:"The holding capabilities of an anchor are determined PRIMARILY by the ____________.",opa:"design of the anchor",opb:"weight of the anchor",opc:"scope of the anchor chain",opd:"size of the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"The S.S. Ossel Hitch arrives in Capetown, South Africa, and the Master affects a note of protest with the U.S. Consul. Why would the Master affect this document?",opa:"Crew misconduct",opb:"Inability of vessel to comply with voyage charter",opc:"Suspicion of cargo pilferage by crew",opd:"Suspicion of heavy weather damage to vessel or cargo",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 4?",opa:"Double whip",opb:"Luff tackle",opc:"Two-fold purchase",opd:"2-2 tackle",ans:"opc"},{question:"To 'ease' a line means to ____________.",opa:"cast off",opb:"double up so that one line does not take all the strain",opc:"pay out line to remove most of the tension",opd:"slack it off quickly",ans:"opc"},{question:"'Block stowage' means ____________.",opa:"having the cargo on pallets",opb:"stowing all the cargo for a port in the same area",opc:"using port marks on the cargo",opd:"using separation cloths to separate different kinds of cargo",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which shallow water effect will increase dramatically if you increase your ship's speed past its 'critical speed'?",opa:"Squatting",opb:"Smelling the bottom",opc:"Sinkage",opd:"Bank cushion",ans:"opa"},{question:"Following a serious marine incident, a device to test an individuals breath can be used by ____________.",opa:"any individual trained to conduct such tests",opb:"the marine employer",opc:"qualified medical personnel only",opd:"any USCG licensed deck officer",ans:"opa"},{question:"'Cribbing' is ____________.",opa:"wooden blocks or dunnage placed between a deck load and the deck",opb:"the chains and shackles used to secure a deck cargo",opc:"a crate in which a deck cargo is packaged",opd:"cardboard separation pieces placed between deck loads to prevent chafing",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which factor(s) can affect the performance of a river towboat?",opa:"The draft of the towboat and the draft of the barges under tow",opb:"The placement of the barges within the tow",opc:"The presence of flanking rudders and Kort nozzles",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which logbook is required to be submitted to the Coast Guard?",opa:"Official Log",opb:"Smooth log",opc:"Rough log",opd:"Bell log",ans:"opa"},{question:"A seaman may not make an allotment to his ____________.",opa:"minor children",opb:"grandparents",opc:"brother",opd:"mother-in-law",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement concerning dual-tonnage vessels is TRUE?",opa:"The dual-tonnage mark is always marked above the load line marks.",opb:"The tonnages referred to are the displacement tonnage and gross tonnage.",opc:"A single-deck vessel may not be assigned dual tonnages.",opd:"The dual-tonnage mark must never be submerged beyond the freshwater allowance.",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to dog everything?",opa:"Place both fists in front of your body with thumbs pointing toward each other.",opb:"Clasp hands in front of your body.",opc:"Extend arm with the palm down and hold this position rigidly.",opd:"Extend arm with the thumb pointing up, and flex the fingers in and out.",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to Pollution Prevention Regulations (33CFR), each completed page in the Oil Record Book is to be signed by ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard representative designated by COTP",opb:"the master",opc:"person(s) in charge of the operation",opd:"oil terminal representative",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 22,000 barrels of crude oil, departing Valdez, Alaska for Panama. When loaded the cargo temperature was 90\xb0F. API was 15\xb0.The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0004. If the cargo temperature is expected to be 100\xb0F at the discharge port, how many gallons will be offloaded?",opa:"1214840",opb:"1205160",opc:"927696",opd:"920304",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to raise the boom and lower the load?",opa:"Extend arm with the palm down and hold this position rigidly.",opb:"Place both fists in front of your body with thumbs pointing toward each other.",opc:"Clasp hands in front of your body.",opd:"Extend arm with the thumb pointing up, and flex the fingers in and out for as long as the load movement is desired.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are arriving in port and are assigned to anchor in anchorage circle B-4. It has a diameter of 600 yards and your vessel's LOA is 525 feet. If you anchor in 10 fathoms at the center of the circle, what is the maximum number of shots of chain you can use and still remain in the circle?",opa:"4 shots",opb:"5 shots",opc:"6 shots",opd:"7 shots",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel arrives in San Francisco from a foreign voyage. When MUST the Master make formal entry at the custom house?",opa:"Within 24 hours after arrival, Sundays and holidays excepted",opb:"Within 48 hours after arrival, Sundays and holidays excepted",opc:"Within 48 hours and before all foreign cargo is discharged for that port",opd:"Within 24 hours after arrival",ans:"opb"},{question:"When inspecting ground tackle, fractures are most frequently found in the ____________.",opa:"anchor shank",opb:"end links",opc:"swivel",opd:"fluke",ans:"opb"},{question:"A cargo exception would appear on ____________.",opa:"a Bill of Lading",opb:"the cargo manifest",opc:"the Export Declaration",opd:"a Letter of Indemnity",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which type of line would have the LEAST resistance to mildew and rot?",opa:"Manila",opb:"Nylon",opc:"Dacron",opd:"Polypropylene",ans:"opa"},{question:"Bilge soundings indicate ____________.",opa:"the amount of condensation in the hold",opb:"whether the cargo is leaking or not",opc:"whether the vessel is taking on water",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of davit is not considered to be a mechanical davit?",opa:"Sheath-screw boom",opb:"Radial",opc:"Crescent",opd:"Quadrantal",ans:"opb"},{question:"When casting a heaving line to a disabled vessel, cast the line ____________.",opa:"well over vessel's center to drop on deck",opb:"directly at the most forward positioned crewmember",opc:"on the windward side of the cockpit",opd:"with a float attached",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 80\xb0F (27\xb0C) and the wet bulb temperature is 70\xb0F (21\xb0C), what is the relative humidity in a cargo hold?",opa:"0.45",opb:"0.52",opc:"0.61",opd:"0.65",ans:"opc"},{question:"What should be done after putting down the ramp on a Ro-Ro vessel, prior to loading or discharging cargo?",opa:"Turn on red cargo light.",opb:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds.",opc:"Call out the deck department for all hands.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"What does the term 'end-for-end' refer to in regard to a wire towing hawser?",opa:"Cutting off the bitter and towing ends of the wire rope",opb:"Splicing two wire ropes together",opc:"Removing the wire rope from the drum and reversing it so that the towing end becomes the bitter end",opd:"Removing the wire rope from the drum and turning it over so that the wire bends in the opposite direction when rolled on a drum",ans:"opc"},{question:"Where are the towing bitts best placed for towing purposes?",opa:"Near the centerline and over the rudders",opb:"On each side of the vessel near the stern",opc:"Forward of the rudder post and close to the tug's center of pivot",opd:"As far aft as possible",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a small craft's anchor fouls in a rocky bottom, the first attempt to clear it should be made by ____________.",opa:"hauling vertically on the line",opb:"making the line fast to the bitt and bringing the vessel further forward",opc:"reversing the angle and direction of pull, with moderate scope",opd:"increasing the scope and running slowly in a wide circle with the anchor line taut",ans:"opc"},{question:"You attach a line to a stationary barge lying off your starboard beam in order to maneuver it into position to make up tow. The line used to do this is a ____________.",opa:"jockey line",opb:"fore and aft line",opc:"check line",opd:"swing line",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a tankship designed to carry molten sulfur. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"There must be two portable toxic vapor detectors on board.",opb:"The cargo tank ventilation system must maintain the H2S vapor concentration at 1.85% or more by volume.",opc:"Cargo temperature may be taken by portable thermometers.",opd:"The pressure in the heating coils in the tanks must be less than that of the cargo exerted on them.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT a precaution to be taken when topping off?",opa:"Reduce the loading rate.",opb:"Notify the engine room of the procedure.",opc:"Maintain communications with the dock man.",opd:"Give the operation your undivided attention.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Chafing gear is normally used ____________.",opa:"for portable fenders",opb:"for ground tackle",opc:"on the inside of the hawsepipe",opd:"on mooring lines",ans:"opd"},{question:"It is good practice to use long towlines for ocean tows because the ____________.",opa:"wear on the towline is equalized",opb:"weight of the towline increases the towing force",opc:"dip in the towline absorbs shock loads",opd:"danger of overriding is reduced",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which vessel, if navigating independently in ice, is more likely to become beset due to inadequate horsepower?",opa:"A 254 ft. 'Whaleback' tanker with 1800 H.P.",opb:"A 309 ft. cement carrier with 2000 H.P.",opc:"A 385 ft. shallow draft tanker with 2400 H.P.",opd:"A 630 ft. bulk ore carrier with 3500 H.P.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The danger of a towing vessel tripping is increased the closer the towline is secured to ____________.",opa:"the stern",opb:"amidships",opc:"the bow",opd:"the quarter",ans:"opb"},{question:"Wale shores would be used when dry docking a vessel with ____________.",opa:"tumble home",opb:"excessive deadrise",opc:"excessive trim",opd:"a list",ans:"opb"},{question:"The figure obtained by dividing the total volume of the ship in cubic feet (after omission of exempted spaces) by 100 is the ____________.",opa:"bale cubic",opb:"gross tonnage",opc:"light displacement",opd:"net tonnage",ans:"opb"},{question:"What purpose does a tow hook serve?",opa:"To quickly connect or release the towing hawser",opb:"To help pick up the towing hawser from the water",opc:"To prevent the towing hawser from fouling the propeller",opd:"To recover the towing hawser from a barge",ans:"opa"},{question:"When making a short splice in wire rope ____________.",opa:"all tucks go against the lay",opb:"all tucks go with the lay",opc:"the first three wires are tucked against the lay and the last three go with the lay",opd:"the first three wires are tucked with the lay and the last three go against the lay",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which pump must always be primed?",opa:"Centrifugal pump",opb:"Reciprocating pump",opc:"Rotary pump",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The lookout sights a vessel dead ahead. This should be reported on the bell with ____________.",opa:"one bell",opb:"two bells",opc:"three bells",opd:"four bells",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking the radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are listed in illustration D035DG. Based on this data what is the advance for a turn of 30\xb0?",opa:"380 yards",opb:"420 yards",opc:"470 yards",opd:"525 yards",ans:"opc"},{question:"Ice concentration is measured in tenths. What concentration range of ice corresponds to 1-3 tenths?",opa:"Very Open Pack",opb:"Open Pack",opc:"Close Pack",opd:"Very Close Pack",ans:"opa"},{question:"The wire rope used for cargo handling on board your vessel has a safe working load of eight tons. It shall be able to withstand a breaking test load of ____________.",opa:"32 tons",opb:"40 tons",opc:"48 tons",opd:"64 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"A license for apprentice mate (steersman) of uninspected towing vessels shall be renewed within what time period before or after the expiration date?",opa:"30 days",opb:"90 days",opc:"6 months",opd:"12 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking the radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are as listed. Based on this data what is the transfer for a turn of 180\xb0?",opa:"745 yards",opb:"770 yards",opc:"850 yards",opd:"890 yards",ans:"opc"},{question:"Why are stern towing bitts placed well forward of the rudder when hawser towing?",opa:"To keep the hawser from fouling the rudder",opb:"To keep the towing bitts as far away as possible from the tugs pivoting point",opc:"To allow the stern to swing more freely when using rudder",opd:"To have as much of the towing hawser in use as possible",ans:"opc"},{question:"How much weight can you lift by applying 100 lbs. of force to a twofold purchase rigged to disadvantage (do not consider friction)?",opa:"200 lbs.",opb:"300 lbs.",opc:"400 lbs.",opd:"500 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is issued a load line certificate dated 27 May 1992. What is NOT an acceptable date for one of the surveys for endorsements?",opa:"26 August 1994",opb:"27 May 1995",opc:"27 November 1993",opd:"28 February 1993",ans:"opc"},{question:"In a national emergency, when communicating via the Navy, messages are sent by precedence. A message designated FLASH will be delivered within ____________.",opa:"6 hours",opb:"3 hours",opc:"10 minutes",opd:"30 minutes",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are riding to a single anchor. The vessel is yawing excessively. Which action should be taken to reduce the yawing?",opa:"Veer chain to the riding anchor",opb:"Heave to a shorter scope of chain on the riding anchor",opc:"Drop the second anchor at the extreme end of the yaw and veer the riding anchor",opd:"Drop the second anchor at the extreme end of the yaw, then adjust the cables until the scope is equal",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a vessel with a single propeller, transverse force has the most effect on the vessel when the engine is put ____________.",opa:"full ahead",opb:"full astern",opc:"half ahead",opd:"slow astern",ans:"opb"},{question:"A seaman deserts the vessel in a foreign port. What should the Master do with any of the deserter's personal effects remaining on board?",opa:"Sell them at auction and deposit the money in the ship's morale or welfare fund.",opb:"Donate them to a local charity upon return to the United States.",opc:"Transfer them to the appropriate district court of the U.S. at the end of the voyage.",opd:"Inventory them, make an appropriate entry in the Official Logbook and dispose of them at sea.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are using tackle number 6 to lift a weight. The hauling part of this tackle is bent to the weight hook (w) of tackle number 8. Disregarding friction, what is the mechanical advantage of this rig?",opa:"11",opb:"16",opc:"18",opd:"24",ans:"opc"},{question:"It is easier to dock a right-hand, single-screw vessel ____________.",opa:"starboard side to the wharf",opb:"either side to the wharf",opc:"port side to the wharf",opd:"stern to the wharf",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which will cause a wire rope to fail?",opa:"Using a medium graphite grease as a lubricant",opb:"Operating a winch too slow",opc:"Using a sheave with an undersized throat",opd:"A sheave diameter of 24 times the wire's diameter",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a vessel is swinging from side to side off course due to quartering seas, the vessel is ____________.",opa:"broaching",opb:"pitchpoling",opc:"rolling",opd:"yawing",ans:"opd"},{question:"A shore is a piece of securing dunnage that ____________.",opa:"runs from a low supporting level up to the cargo at an angle",opb:"is also known as a 'distance piece'",opc:"is placed on the deck under the cargo to distribute its weight evenly",opd:"is run horizontally from a support to the cargo",ans:"opa"},{question:"Protective clothing must be worn while sampling hazardous cargo on a tankship, and as a minimum includes ____________.",opa:"a hood or hard hat",opb:"a face mask or goggles",opc:"boots",opd:"chemical resistant gloves",ans:"opb"},{question:"The main advantage and chief characteristic of a Steulchen boom is that it can be ____________.",opa:"operated by one winchman",opb:"cradled on deck",opc:"swung from one hatch to the adjacent hatch",opd:"collared to the mast",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel (185 GT) is on a voyage between New York and San Francisco. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The maintenance of an Official Logbook is optional.",opb:"The vessel must be on foreign articles.",opc:"This is considered a coastwise voyage.",opd:"An Official Logbook must be maintained.",ans:"opd"},{question:"How is the size of chain determined?",opa:"Length of link in inches",opb:"Diameter of metal in link in inches",opc:"Links per fathom",opd:"Weight of stud cable in pounds",ans:"opb"},{question:"What characterizes a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"May carry up to 24 passengers",opb:"High freeboard and sail area",opc:"Long port stays required for cargo securing",opd:"Lightweight securing equipment trailers",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master must maintain the Oil Record Book onboard for at least ____________.",opa:"1 month",opb:"12 months",opc:"24 months",opd:"36 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"While loading or discharging vehicles, which is the most important safety consideration aboard a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Preventing the asphyxiation of personnel below decks",opb:"Notifying the engine room prior to completing operations",opc:"Calling out the deck department for all hands periodically",opd:"Ensuring that a fuel barge cannot come alongside",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which space(s) is(are) deducted from gross tonnage to derive net tonnage?",opa:"Galley fitted with range or oven",opb:"Open structures",opc:"Passenger spaces",opd:"Boatswain's stores",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 7?",opa:"Runner",opb:"Inverted whip",opc:"Whip",opd:"Single purchase",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which U.S. agency assigns an official number to a vessel?",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Collector of Customs",opc:"Treasury Department",opd:"Coast Guard",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in charge while handling a synthetic hawser on a capstan. The hawser has a heavy strain and you wish to avoid the hawser's slipping on the capstan drum. Which action should you take?",opa:"Back off on the capstan a bit and have the seaman take several more turns on the drum.",opb:"Have the seaman take a strain on the hawser and carefully have several turns added on the drum.",opc:"Have more than one seaman hold a good strain on the hawser and continue to heave easy.",opd:"While continuing to heave slowly on the capstan, have the seaman take several more turns on the drum.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are the person in charge of a vessel involved in a marine casualty. You must notify the nearest Coast Guard Marine Inspection Office if the property damage is over ____________.",opa:"1,500",opb:"10000",opc:"25000",opd:"50000",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is considered a Serious Marine Incident?",opa:"an allision that results in $500 damage to a boat dock",opb:"an injury to a crewmember, passenger, or other person which requires professional medical treatment beyond first aid",opc:"grounding of a vessel on a sandbar that does not result in injuries and/or any damage to the vessel",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The 'iron mike' is a(n) ____________.",opa:"pilot",opb:"speaker",opc:"standby wheel",opd:"automatic pilot",ans:"opd"},{question:"A drift lead indicates that the vessel is dragging anchor when the line is ____________.",opa:"taut and leading forward",opb:"slack",opc:"leading out perpendicular to the centerline",opd:"leading under the hull",ans:"opa"},{question:"To determine the number of inflatable life rafts required on a vessel, you should check the ____________.",opa:"Load Line Certificate",opb:"SOLAS Certificate",opc:"Stability Letter",opd:"Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"To 'belay' a line means to ____________.",opa:"coil it down",opb:"heave it taut",opc:"stow it below",opd:"secure it to a cleat",ans:"opd"},{question:"When patching holes in the hull, pillows, bedding, and other soft materials can be used as ____________.",opa:"shores",opb:"gaskets",opc:"strongbacks",opd:"wedges",ans:"opb"},{question:"The knot lettered S is a ____________.",opa:"bowline",opb:"blackwall hitch",opc:"half hitch",opd:"hook hitch",ans:"opb"},{question:"Chafing gear ____________.",opa:"reduces and prevents corrosion of standing rigging",opb:"prevents corrosion of running rigging",opc:"reduces and prevents wear caused by the rubbing of one object against another",opd:"protects the body against extreme cold",ans:"opc"},{question:"What does the helm command 'shift the rudder' mean?",opa:"Put the rudder over to the opposite side, the same number of degrees it is now.",opb:"Put the rudder amidships and hold the heading steady as she goes.",opc:"Shift the rudder control to the alternate steering method.",opd:"Stop the swing of the ship.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A new coil of nylon line should be opened by ____________.",opa:"pulling the end up through the eye of the coil",opb:"taking a strain on both ends",opc:"uncoiling from the outside with the coil standing on end",opd:"unreeling from a spool",ans:"opd"},{question:"To 'shore up' the main deck for the stowage of deck cargo means to ____________.",opa:"weld pad eyes on deck in proper position to secure the cargo",opb:"strengthen the main deck by placing pillars underneath it in the tween-decks",opc:"distribute the weight of the cargo by placing fore-and-aft planks on the main deck",opd:"package the cargo in wooden crates so it will not damage the deck",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel has completed loading cargo in the port of San Francisco. What document is signed by the Master stating the terms that goods were delivered and received by the ship?",opa:"Bill of Goods",opb:"Bill of Lading",opc:"Cargo Manifest",opd:"Cargo Receipt",ans:"opb"},{question:"An International Tonnage Certificate will be issued to a vessel when it meets several requirements, one of which is that the vessel must ____________.",opa:"admeasure over 100 GT",opb:"be 79 or more feet in length",opc:"engage in intercoastal or international trade",opd:"be issued a Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 9,000 barrels of fuel oil at a cargo temperature of 35\xb0C (95\xb0F). API gravity is 44\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. You are bound for New Jersey from Venezuela. How many barrels would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 55\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"9090",opb:"9180",opc:"8820",opd:"8910",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of weld testing can be used to detect internal flaws?",opa:"Radiographic",opb:"Magnetic particle",opc:"Dye penetrant",opd:"Chemical reaction",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 9?",opa:"Single purchase",opb:"One-two tackle",opc:"Double whip",opd:"Luff tackle",ans:"opd"},{question:"The lifeboats on your vessel are stowed on cradles on deck and are handled by sheath-screw boom davits. Which of the following statements about launching a boat is TRUE?",opa:"The boat should be hoisted a few inches clear of the cradle before cranking out the davits.",opb:"The inboard gripes should be cast off before the outboard gripes.",opc:"The outboard section of the cradle must be released.",opd:"The tricing pendants will automatically bring the boat alongside at the embarkation deck.",ans:"opc"},{question:"When carrying out a parallel track search pattern, the course of the search units should normally be which of the following?",opa:"In the same direction as the anticipated drift",opb:"In the opposite direction of the anticipated drift",opc:"Perpendicular to the line of anticipated drift",opd:"Downwind",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following is not an acceptable unit of measure to be used consistently through out an Oil Record Book?",opa:"cubic meters",opb:"gallons",opc:"tons",opd:"barrels",ans:"opc"},{question:"Upon receipt of a distress message, a merchant vessel is bound to proceed to the scene of the distress. Under which of the following cases would this NOT be true?",opa:"The vessel would arrive at the distress scene more than 36 hours after the receipt of the initial distress message.",opb:"There are vessels closer to the distress scene that are proceeding to assist.",opc:"The Master of the vessel in distress has requisitioned another vessel, and that vessel has accepted the requisition.",opd:"You are on a tank vessel and the distress involves a major fire on board the other vessel.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are docking a vessel starboard side to with the assistance of two tugs. You are attempting to hold the vessel off by operating both tugs at right angles to the vessel and at full power. You must ensure that ____________.",opa:"steerageway is not taken off",opb:"the bow doesn't close the dock first",opc:"the bow closes the dock first",opd:"the ship has no headway at the time",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel has arrived in a U.S. port from a foreign voyage. Preliminary entry has been made. Formal entry at the U.S. Custom House must be made within how many hours after arrival (Sundays and holidays excepted)?",opa:"12",opb:"24",opc:"48",opd:"72 without exception",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to swing?",opa:"With both arms extended out and palms down, move arms back and forth.",opb:"With arm extended downwards and forefinger pointing down, move hand in small horizontal circles.",opc:"Extend arm and point finger in the direction to move the boom.",opd:"Place both fists in front of the body with the thumbs pointing outward.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What term indicates the length measured along the summer load line from the intersection of that load line with the foreside of the stem and the intersection of that load line with the aft side of the rudder post?",opa:"Length overall",opb:"Register length",opc:"Length between perpendiculars",opd:"Length on the waterline",ans:"opc"},{question:"Before entering an ice area, the ship should be ____________.",opa:"either trimmed by the head or the stern",opb:"on an even keel",opc:"trimmed down by the head",opd:"trimmed down by the stern",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the best splice for repairing a parted synthetic fiber mooring line?",opa:"Liverpool splice",opb:"Locking long splice",opc:"Long splice",opd:"Short splice",ans:"opd"},{question:"What size block shell should be used with a 4-inch manila line?",opa:"8'",opb:"12'",opc:"16'",opd:"24'",ans:"opb"},{question:"One reason a tug's towing bitts are located forward of the rudders is because ____________.",opa:"it makes it easier to hook up the towing hawser",opb:"this is where the towhook is located",opc:"this allows more responsive steering",opd:"it is traditional",ans:"opc"},{question:"A license issued by the U.S. Coast Guard for apprentice mate (steersman) of Uninspected Towing Vessels is valid for ____________.",opa:"2 years and must be renewed",opb:"3 years and must be renewed",opc:"5 years and must be renewed",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"When tandem tug towing, the more powerful of the two tugs should be ____________.",opa:"the lead tug",opb:"behind the lead tug",opc:"towing at a right angle to the smaller tug",opd:"towing at a faster speed than the smaller tug",ans:"opb"},{question:"A face line is used to ____________.",opa:"prevent barge movement in a lock",opb:"secure two barges end-to-end",opc:"secure barges to the towboat",opd:"secure barges side-by-side",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the available references, if the dry bulb temperature is 55\xb0F (13\xb0C) and the wet bulb is 50\xb0F (10\xb0C), what is the relative humidity?",opa:"0.55",opb:"0.7",opc:"0.75",opd:"0.82",ans:"opb"},{question:"Indicated horsepower refers to a towing vessel's power which is ____________.",opa:"theoretically available",opb:"measured on a test bed",opc:"developed at the shaft",opd:"measured by dynamometer",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the gyro-pilot is used for steering, what control is adjusted to compensate for varying sea conditions?",opa:"Rudder control",opb:"Sea control",opc:"Lost motion adjustment",opd:"Weather adjustment",ans:"opd"},{question:"What should be done before energizing the cargo hold ventilation on a Ro-Ro vessel, prior to loading or discharging cargo?",opa:"Call out the deck department for all hands.",opb:"Notify the boarding agent.",opc:"Notify the engine room.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which will most likely occur when entering shallow water?",opa:"Rudder action will become more effective.",opb:"The vessel's list will change.",opc:"The vessel's trim will change.",opd:"An increase in speed will occur.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which rope has the greatest breaking strength?",opa:"Manila",opb:"Nylon",opc:"Polyester",opd:"Polypropylene",ans:"opb"},{question:"What may prevent a tug from tripping or capsizing when towing a large vessel?",opa:"Surge lines",opb:"Norman Pins",opc:"Under riders",opd:"Safety shackles",ans:"opb"},{question:"The welds used to join shell plates in flush construction are known as ____________.",opa:"butt welds",opb:"seam welds",opc:"fillet welds",opd:"continuous welds",ans:"opa"},{question:"Where is the best location to install a towing hook?",opa:"Forward of the towing bitts",opb:"On the fantail",opc:"Near the Norman Pins",opd:"Just aft of amidships",ans:"opd"},{question:"Who is responsible for properly manning a vessel in accordance with all applicable laws, regulations and international conventions?",opa:"The (USCG) Officer in Charge of Marine Inspection",opb:"The (USCG) Captain of the Port",opc:"The owner or operator of the vessel",opd:"The Master of the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"When considering a vessel's stability which spaces in a general cargo vessel are the best locations for the carriage of bulk grain?",opa:"Deep tanks",opb:"Lower holds",opc:"Lower holds at the ends of the vessel",opd:"Tween-decks",ans:"opa"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has his forearm vertical, forefinger pointing up, and moves his hand in a small horizontal circle. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"swing",opb:"lower",opc:"hoist",opd:"extend",ans:"opc"},{question:"An icebreaker may use the code letter 'K' to remind ships of their obligation to listen continuously on their radio. This signal may be made by any of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"sound signal",opb:"light signal",opc:"visual signal",opd:"radiotelephone",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are planning to anchor in an area where several anchors have been lost due to fouling. As a precaution, you should ____________.",opa:"anchor using both anchors",opb:"anchor with scope of 8 or more to 1",opc:"use a stern anchor",opd:"fit a crown strap and work wire to the anchor",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a cargo vessel carrying portable tanks of dangerous cargoes in bulk. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"If the tanks are pumped out while remaining on board, each hose connection must have a minimum of three bolts.",opb:"If the tanks are off loaded, no more than two tanks may be lifted together in a hoist.",opc:"When transferring sulfuric acid, you must display a red flag by day whether at anchor or moored.",opd:"All electrical equipment within 10 feet horizontally must be explosion proof or intrinsically safe.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A look-out at the bow sights an object on your port side. How many bell strokes should he sound?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opb"},{question:"The valve on the discharge side of a cargo pump on a tank vessel will usually be a ____________.",opa:"gate valve",opb:"butterfly valve",opc:"globe valve",opd:"check valve",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are arriving in port and are assigned to anchor in anchorage circle B-4. It has a diameter of 500 yards and your vessel's LOA is 484 feet. If you anchor in 8 fathoms at the center of the circle, what is the maximum number of shots of chain you can use and still remain in the circle?",opa:"6 shots",opb:"5 shots",opc:"4 shots",opd:"3 shots",ans:"opd"},{question:"Two mooring lines may be placed on the same bollard and either one cast off first if ____________.",opa:"the eye of the second line is dipped",opb:"the mooring lines are doubled",opc:"the bollard has two horns",opd:"one of the lines is a breast line",ans:"opa"},{question:"In controlling pollution, which action should be taken after all dirty ballast has been transferred to the slop tank and prior to discharge through the oily water separator?",opa:"The clean tanks should be ballasted.",opb:"The slops should be allowed time to settle.",opc:"Chemicals should be added to emulsify the oil.",opd:"The dirty ballast tank is crude oil washed.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Under title 46 of the United States Code, the person in charge of a documented vessel who fails to report a complaint of a sexual offense may be ____________.",opa:"fined up to $5,000",opb:"imprisoned for up to one year",opc:"charged with accessory to sexual assault",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is a correct reply to a pilot's request, 'How's your head'?",opa:"'Steady'",opb:"'Checked'",opc:"'Passing 200\xb0'",opd:"'Eased to 10\xb0 rudder'",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are loading 465,000 barrels of cargo oil. At 0900 you find that you have loaded 207,000 barrels. At 1030 you find that you have loaded 223,000 barrels. If you continue loading at the same rate, you will finish at approximately ____________.",opa:"2100 that night",opb:"0730 the next day",opc:"0910 the next day",opd:"1215 the next day",ans:"opc"},{question:"The document on a vessel, annually endorsed by an American Bureau of Shipping surveyor, is called the ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Classification Certificate",opc:"Load Line Certificate",opd:"Seaworthy Certificate",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which factor must be considered when determining the order of loading of dissimilar products through the same piping system aboard a tanker?",opa:"Contamination of the cargo",opb:"Flash points",opc:"Reid vapor pressures",opd:"Specific gravities",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which space(s) is(are) NOT exempt when measuring gross tonnage?",opa:"Auxiliary machinery spaces above the deck",opb:"Steering gear room",opc:"Cargo holds",opd:"Galley in a deckhouse",ans:"opc"},{question:"When taking a Pilot from a pilot vessel in a seaway, which way should you head your vessel if the ladder is on the leeward side?",opa:"Bow to the sea and no way on your vessel",opb:"Sea on the lee quarter with ship moving ahead slowly",opc:"Sea on the weather bow and ship moving ahead slowly",opd:"Sea on the quarter with sternway on the ship",ans:"opc"},{question:"In most cases, when a large merchant vessel enters shallow water at high speed the ____________.",opa:"maneuverability will increase",opb:"speed will increase",opc:"bow will squat farther than the stern",opd:"vessel will rise slightly, on a level plane",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a large vessel fitted with a right-handed controllable-pitch propeller. When making large speed changes while decreasing pitch, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You will probably have full directional control throughout the speed change.",opb:"You may lose rudder control until the ship's speed has dropped to correspond to propeller speed.",opc:"The stern will immediately slew to starboard due to unbalanced forces acting on the propeller.",opd:"The stern will immediately slew to port due to unbalanced forces acting on the propeller.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel arrives at the port of San Francisco from Yokohama, Japan. The passengers fill out the Baggage Declaration and Entry form. A passenger has baggage arriving on another vessel. How must this baggage be handled for U.S. Customs purposes?",opa:"It need not be declared at this time.",opb:"It must be declared on the same form and marked 'Unaccompanied Baggage'.",opc:"It must be declared on another form entitled 'Continuation Sheet'.",opd:"It must be declared only if the other vessel's name is known.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You will be advised of any hazardous areas due to the fallout of a nuclear explosive by a message with the code word ____________.",opa:"MERWARN",opb:"NUCLEAR",opc:"FALLOUT",opd:"FALLWARN",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of the freeing ports on a vessel with solid bulwarks?",opa:"Allow water which may be shipped on deck to flow off rapidly",opb:"Permit easy jettisoning of deck cargo in an emergency",opc:"Prevent the formation of any unusual stress concentration points",opd:"Lighten the above deck weight caused by a solid bulwark",ans:"opa"},{question:"Wire rope is galvanized to ____________.",opa:"protect it from corrosion due to contact with saltwater",opb:"make it bend more easily",opc:"increase its strength",opd:"increase its circumference",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are using tackle number 10 to lift a weight. The hauling part of this tackle is bent to the weight hook (w) of tackle number 4. What is the mechanical advantage of this rig?",opa:"24",opb:"20",opc:"13",opd:"9",ans:"opb"},{question:"Stress on the topping lift of a swinging boom can be reduced by ____________.",opa:"rigging a back stay",opb:"raising the boom",opc:"increasing the mechanical advantage of the cargo purchase",opd:"taking all slack out of the preventer",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking the radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are listed in illustration D035DG. Based on this data what is the tactical diameter of the turning circle?",opa:"755 yards",opb:"780 yards",opc:"820 yards",opd:"880 yards",ans:"opd"},{question:"A person has fallen overboard and is being picked up with a lifeboat. If the person appears in danger of drowning, the lifeboat should make ____________.",opa:"an approach from leeward",opb:"an approach from windward",opc:"the most direct approach",opd:"an approach across the wind",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of weld testing can be used to detect internal flaws?",opa:"Magnetic particle",opb:"Dye penetrant",opc:"Ultrasonic",opd:"Chemical reaction",ans:"opc"},{question:"Dunnage may be used to protect a cargo from loss or damage by ____________.",opa:"ship's sweat",opb:"inherent vice",opc:"tainting",opd:"hygroscopic absorption",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Oil Record Book on a vessel NOT engaged on a foreign voyage shall be maintained on board for not less than ____________.",opa:"12 months",opb:"24 months",opc:"36 months",opd:"48 months",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following is not a loading or transfer feature aboard a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Stern ramp and/or side ramp",opb:"Cargo lift",opc:"Hatch opening designed as a lift",opd:"Stuelcken boom",ans:"opd"},{question:"A change of a documented vessel's name can only be made by the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Commissioner of Customs",opc:"Treasury Department",opd:"Coast Guard",ans:"opd"},{question:"The pea is indicated by which letter?",opa:"J",opb:"H",opc:"G",opd:"F",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 8,000 barrels of gasoline at a cargo temperature of 85\xb0F, departing Aruba bound for New Jersey. API gravity is 55\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0006. How many gallons would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 50\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"449240",opb:"430760",opc:"343056",opd:"328944",ans:"opd"},{question:"When you enter shallow water, you would expect your rudder response to ____________.",opa:"be sluggish and your speed to decrease",opb:"be sluggish and your speed to increase",opc:"improve and your speed to decrease",opd:"improve and your speed to increase",ans:"opa"},{question:"Under identical load conditions, nylon, when compared with natural fiber line, will stretch ____________.",opa:"less and have less strength",opb:"more and have less strength",opc:"more and have greater strength",opd:"less and have greater strength",ans:"opc"},{question:"The most important safety consideration during loading or discharge aboard a Ro-Ro vessel is ____________.",opa:"having all crewmembers and longshoremen wear hard hats",opb:"the thorough ventilation of all cargo spaces",opc:"ensuring that visitors cannot come aboard",opd:"having the outboard anchor down",ans:"opb"},{question:"If two falls are attached to lift a one-ton load, what angle between the falls will result in the stress on each fall being equal to the load being lifted?",opa:"60\xb0",opb:"75\xb0",opc:"120\xb0",opd:"150\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which picture represents a bowline?",opa:"G",opb:"H",opc:"L",opd:"Q",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which factor(s) affect lashing requirements aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Ship\u2019s characteristics and motion in a seaway",opb:"Trim of the vessel",opc:"Wide variations of air temperature",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Before being certified by the American Bureau of Shipping, anchor chain must undergo ____________.",opa:"USCG inspection",opb:"a breaking test",opc:"x-ray inspection",opd:"spectroanalysis",ans:"opb"},{question:"Fairleads perform the same function as ____________.",opa:"deadeyes",opb:"bollards",opc:"bitts",opd:"chocks",ans:"opd"},{question:"What accident situation is considered a Serious Marine Incident?",opa:"An injury to a crewmember that renders that person unfit to continue working on the vessel",opb:"Damage to property in excess of$100,000",opc:"A discharge of 10,000 gallons or more of oil into navigable waters of the U.S.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are the operator of an uninspected vessel which is involved in an accident. You are not required to assist people affected by the accident if ____________.",opa:"the other vessel did not appear to be sinking",opb:"it would unduly delay your voyage",opc:"the other vessel was at fault",opd:"it would cause serious danger to your vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 9,000 barrels of fuel oil at a cargo temperature of 35\xb0C (95\xb0F). API gravity is 44\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0005. You are bound for New Jersey from Venezuela. How many gallons would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 55\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"370440",opb:"85560",opc:"485100",opd:"504900",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your tank vessel is fully loaded, and you find that she is down slightly by the head. To adjust the trim, you may ____________.",opa:"add ballast aft",opb:"load more cargo aft",opc:"shift cargo aft",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are handling a mooring line and are instructed to 'Check the line'. What should you do?",opa:"Ensure the bight is not fouled by taking up slack.",opb:"Pay out the line smartly and keep it free for running.",opc:"Secure the line by adding more turns.",opd:"Surge the line so it maintains a strain without parting.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are docking an oceangoing single-screw vessel under normal circumstances with a single tug. The tug is usually used to ____________.",opa:"control the bow and is tied to the offshore bow",opb:"control the stern and is tied to the stern on the offshore side",opc:"pull the vessel into the slip and is tied to the bow",opd:"push the ship bodily alongside and is tied to the offshore side amidships",ans:"opa"},{question:"The total weight of cargo, fuel, water, stores, passengers and crew, and their effects, that a ship can carry, is the ____________.",opa:"bale cubic",opb:"deadweight",opc:"gross tonnage",opd:"loaded displacement",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 11?",opa:"Three-two purchase",opb:"Double luff tackle",opc:"Gun tackle",opd:"Topping lift",ans:"opb"},{question:"It is possible, and sometimes necessary, to strengthen the deck of a vessel for carriage of deck cargo by ____________.",opa:"placing bunker on the deck",opb:"building a stage on which to place the cargo",opc:"welding steel 'feet' to the deck, on which the cargo is placed",opd:"erecting vertical pillars under the deck to support the cargo",ans:"opd"},{question:"Splices made in nylon should ____________.",opa:"be long splices only",opb:"have extra tucks taken",opc:"be short splices only",opd:"be around a thimble",ans:"opb"},{question:"Under U.S. law, what is the penalty for assaulting the Master?",opa:"Fine of not more than $1000",opb:"Fine of not more than $500 and/or imprisonment for not more than 1 year",opc:"Imprisonment for not more than 2 years",opd:"Revocation of the Merchant Mariner's Document (and license if applicable)",ans:"opc"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator first taps his elbow with one hand and then proceeds to use regular signals. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"use the main hoist",opb:"proceed slowly",opc:"increase speed",opd:"use the whip line",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are proceeding to a distress site where the survivors are in liferafts. Which action will assist in making your vessel more visible to the survivors?",opa:"Steering a zigzag course with 5 to 10 minutes on each leg",opb:"Steering a sinuous course",opc:"Dumping debris over the side to make a trail to your vessel",opd:"Making smoke in daylight",ans:"opd"},{question:"To rigidly fasten together the peak frames, the stem, and the outside framing, a horizontal plate is fitted across the forepeak of a vessel. This plate is known as a(n) ____________.",opa:"apron plate",opb:"breasthook",opc:"intercostal plate",opd:"joiner",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which tanker discharge pattern would be the safest and most efficient?",opa:"Empty the forward tanks and start working aft, emptying each tank in sequence",opb:"Start discharging with most of the discharge coming from forward, but include some from midships and after tanks",opc:"Start pumping from forward, midships, and aft with the discharge distributed equally among the tanks",opd:"Start pumping from midships and then work forward and aft simultaneously as the midships tank is emptied",ans:"opb"},{question:"When must the Master of a vessel log the position of load line marks in relation to the surface of the water in the Official Logbook?",opa:"Once a day",opb:"At the change of every watch",opc:"Only when in fresh or brackish water",opd:"Prior to getting underway",ans:"opd"},{question:"An ocean tow is sinking in deep water. Attempts to sever the towing hawser are unsuccessful. Which action should now be taken?",opa:"Abandon the towing vessel.",opb:"Radio for emergency assistance.",opc:"Slip the towline and allow it to run off the drum.",opd:"Secure all watertight openings on the towing vessel.",ans:"opc"},{question:"An implied warranty of seaworthiness on the part of the vessel's owner lies in the ____________.",opa:"Cargo Manifest",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Classification Certificate",opd:"contract of carriage, i.e.. Bill of Lading",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are the licensed Master of a 100 GT towing vessel sailing coastwise. What percentage of the deck crew must be able to understand any order spoken by the officers?",opa:"0.5",opb:"0.65",opc:"0.75",opd:"1",ans:"opc"},{question:"A mechanical davit is designed to automatically ____________.",opa:"position the boat at the embarkation station",opb:"lift the boat off the inboard chocks",opc:"energize the winch for the falls",opd:"set the brake on the winch",ans:"opb"},{question:"An ocean towing bridle whose legs are of equal length, but too short, may ____________.",opa:"put excessive strain on each leg",opb:"cause unequal distribution of the load to one leg",opc:"cause the bridle legs to jump clear of the chocks or fairleads",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The name and hailing port of a documented commercial vessel is ____________.",opa:"not required to be marked anywhere on the vessel",opb:"required to be marked on both bows and on the keel",opc:"required to be marked on the stern with the name of the vessel marked on both bows",opd:"required to be marked on the keel, stern, and both bows",ans:"opc"},{question:"A tug is to assist in docking an oceangoing vessel on a hawser. The greatest danger to the tug is ____________.",opa:"from the ship's propeller when making up aft",opb:"from being overrun if making up forward",opc:"hull damage while alongside passing a hawser",opd:"getting in a tripping position",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in the process of adding a barge to your tow. A line run from your power capstan and around timber heads on your tow is made fast on the new barge so that it can be pulled into position. This line is called a ____________.",opa:"scissors wire",opb:"capstan line",opc:"spring line",opd:"fore and aft line",ans:"opb"},{question:"The measurement of the amount of force a towing vessel is capable of applying to a motionless tow is called ____________.",opa:"shaft horsepower",opb:"delivered horsepower",opc:"bollard pull",opd:"towrope pull",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a multiple-product chemical tanker and will carry cargoes of butyric acid, propylene oxide, and octyl alcohol. Which statement is true?",opa:"Butyric acid is incompatible with octyl alcohol but not propylene oxide.",opb:"Propylene oxide may not be stowed in a tank adjacent to butyric acid.",opc:"All of these cargoes are compatible.",opd:"Octyl alcohol is incompatible with both butyric acid and propylene oxide.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is meant by 'spotting the boom'?",opa:"Lowering it into a cradle",opb:"Placing it in a desired position",opc:"Spotting it with wash primer and red lead",opd:"Two-blocking it",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE with respect to the elasticity of nylon mooring lines?",opa:"Nylon can stretch over forty percent without being in danger of parting.",opb:"Nylon can be elongated by one-hundred percent before it will part.",opc:"Nylon will part if it is stretched any more than twenty percent.",opd:"Under load, nylon will stretch and thin out but will return to normal size when free of tension.",ans:"opd"},{question:"What should be done immediately after putting down the stern ramp on a Ro-Ro vessel, prior to loading or discharging cargo?",opa:"Turn on the red cargo light.",opb:"Turn on pump room ventilation.",opc:"Call out the deck department for all hands.",opd:"Raise/open the stern door.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You intend to overtake a vessel in a narrow channel. As you approach the other vessel's stern ____________.",opa:"you will gain speed",opb:"both vessels will gain speed",opc:"the vessels will drift together",opd:"the vessels will drift apart",ans:"opc"},{question:"Given a dry bulb temperature of 78\xb0F and wet bulb temperature of 66.5\xb0F, the dew point is ____________.",opa:"47.0\xb0F",opb:"51.5\xb0F",opc:"59.0\xb0F",opd:"70.0\xb0F",ans:"opc"},{question:"Who may perform as a lookout?",opa:"A member of the engineering watch",opb:"A member of the navigational watch",opc:"A member of the Stewards Department",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Nylon rope is often used in the makeup of a towline because it ____________.",opa:"floats",opb:"stretches",opc:"handles easily",opd:"resists rot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Before loading bulk grain, bilge wells must be covered to ____________.",opa:"add strength to the bilge well strainer",opb:"permit rapid flow of water to the bilge wells",opc:"prevent cargo sifting into the bilge wells",opd:"prevent oil, water, or other liquid from reaching the cargo",ans:"opc"},{question:"The perforated, elevated bottom of the chain locker, which prevents the chains from touching the main locker bottom and allows seepage water to flow to the drains, is called a ____________.",opa:"cradle",opb:"draft",opc:"harping",opd:"manger",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to stop in an emergency?",opa:"Extend arm with the palm down and hold this position rigidly.",opb:"Place clasped hands in front of your body.",opc:"Extend arm and move hand rapidly right and left with the palm down.",opd:"Place both fists in front of the body with the thumbs pointing outward.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is being towed and you are using a tripping rope. A tripping rope of fiber or wire is used to ____________.",opa:"give added strength to the main tow hawser",opb:"retrieve the main tow hawser",opc:"retrieve the outboard legs of the bridle where they are connected to the fishplate",opd:"open the pelican hook at the fishplate",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which is NOT a duty of a look-out?",opa:"Refuse to talk to others, except as required by duty.",opb:"Remain standing during your watch.",opc:"Report every sighting.",opd:"Supervise any deck work going on in the area.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Considering the manning requirements for U.S. vessels (100 gross tons and above), your cargo vessel has a deck crew of 20 men, exclusive of the officers. How many of these men do the manning regulations require to be Able Seamen?",opa:"5",opb:"7",opc:"10",opd:"13",ans:"opd"},{question:"To insure proper seating when closing a valve on a tank, the valve should be ____________.",opa:"closed against the stop and the locking pin inserted",opb:"closed, opened a half turn, and then closed again",opc:"set up as tight as possible by hand",opd:"set up tight using a valve wrench",ans:"opb"},{question:"When more than one vessel is being assisted by an icebreaker, distances between vessels should be constant. Which signal should be given by a vessel which is ahead of another and whose speed suddenly begins to drop?",opa:"Four short blast on the whistle",opb:"A flag hoist consisting of the code figure '4'",opc:"A flag hoist consisting of the code figure '5'",opd:"A flag hoist consisting of the code letters 'FE' (Foxtrot-Echo)",ans:"opc"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator first taps the top of his head with his fist and then proceeds to use regular signals. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"use the whip line",opb:"use the main hoist",opc:"use the auxiliary line",opd:"proceed slowly",ans:"opb"},{question:"The helm command 'Steady as you go' means ____________.",opa:"steer the course you are on now",opb:"steer the course when the swing stops",opc:"maintain the rate of swing",opd:"don't allow the vessel to swing off course so much",ans:"opa"},{question:"Most very large ocean going vessels, such as bulk carriers and large tankers, tend to squat ____________.",opa:"by the bow",opb:"by the stern",opc:"at the end nearest the bottom",opd:"evenly fore and aft",ans:"opa"},{question:"When securing a synthetic line to a bitt what is the minimum number of round turns you should take before figure-eighting the line?",opa:"None",opb:"1",opc:"2",opd:"3",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which space cannot be deducted from gross tonnage when calculating net tonnage?",opa:"Crew messroom",opb:"Forepeak ballast tank",opc:"Master's cabin",opd:"Chain locker",ans:"opb"},{question:"As Master or person in charge, you must notify the U.S. Coast Guard if an injury leaves a crewman unfit to perform routine duties for more than ____________.",opa:"24 hours",opb:"48 hours",opc:"72 hours",opd:"Any amount of time",ans:"opd"},{question:"'Ice blink' is ____________.",opa:"the dark appearance of the underside of a cloud layer due to reflection of a surface of open water",opb:"the soft light appearance on the underside of a cloud layer due to reflection from a surface of open water",opc:"the yellowish-white glare on the underside of a cloud layer",opd:"'water sky'",ans:"opc"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'A' is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"onshore stern line",opb:"offshore stern line",opc:"after breast line",opd:"after spring line",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are arriving in port and are assigned to anchor in anchorage circle B-4. It has a diameter of 700 yards and your vessel's LOA is 600 feet. If you anchor in 11 fathoms at the center of the circle, what is the maximum number of shots of chain you can use and still remain in the circle?",opa:"4 shots",opb:"5 shots",opc:"6 shots",opd:"7 shots",ans:"opb"},{question:"The operator of an uninspected vessel MUST assist people affected by an accident if he or she can do so without ____________.",opa:"serious danger to his or her own vessel",opb:"further damaging the other vessel",opc:"undue delay",opd:"creating a panic on either vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"Stuffer-braid rope has ____________.",opa:"a yarn core",opb:"no core",opc:"three strands",opd:"12 threads",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following actions are stated in the correct order prior to loading or discharging cargo on a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, lower the stern ramp, raise/open the stern door",opb:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, raise/open the stern door, lower the stern ramp",opc:"Lower the stern ramp, raise/open the stern door, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",opd:"Raise/open the stern door, lower the stern ramp, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using a scope of five, determine how many shots of chain you should put out to anchor in 5 fathoms of water?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"5",ans:"opb"},{question:"With rudders amidships and negligible wind, a twin-screw vessel moving astern with both engines backing will back ____________.",opa:"to port",opb:"to starboard",opc:"in a fairly straight line",opd:"in a circular motion",ans:"opc"},{question:"A sling is rigged on a piece of pipe weighing 1000 lbs. The angle between the sling legs is 140\xb0 and the legs are of equal length. What stress is exerted on each sling leg when the pipe is lifted?",opa:"1318 lbs.",opb:"1366 lbs.",opc:"1414 lbs.",opd:"1462 lbs.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A towing vessel becomes tripped while towing on a hawser astern. What factor is LEAST important when assessing the risk of capsizing?",opa:"Length of the towline",opb:"Height of the towline connection",opc:"Length of the barge",opd:"Direction of opposing force",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are docking a vessel in a slip which has its entrance athwart the tide. You land the ship across the end of the pier, stemming the tide, preparatory to breaking the ship around the corner. You have one tug to assist. Where would you generally tie up the tug?",opa:"Have her on a hawser from the stern.",opb:"Tie her up on the inshore bow to hold the ship off the end.",opc:"Tie her up on the offshore bow.",opd:"Tie her up on the inshore quarter to lift the stern.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The helm command 'Nothing to the left' means do NOT ____________.",opa:"use left rudder",opb:"steer left of the ordered course",opc:"steer right of the ordered course",opd:"leave any buoys on the port side",ans:"opb"},{question:"The usual depth of a beam bracket is ____________.",opa:"2 1/2 times the depth of the beam",opb:"5 times the depth of the beam",opc:"10 times the depth of the beam",opd:"same depth as the beam",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a deck cargo is secured with chain or wire lashings and grab (pear) links, which statement is FALSE?",opa:"The amount of take-up is limited by the length of the turnbuckle.",opb:"At the grab (pear) link, the slack end of chain should be led back and secured to the chain above the link.",opc:"The lashings should be inspected each day and any slack taken up.",opd:"The turnbuckle should be secured with a stick or lock nuts.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel has run hard aground in an area subject to heavy wave action. Backing full astern failed to free her. Which action should be taken next?",opa:"Continue backing to scour out the bottom.",opb:"Wait for high tide and then try backing.",opc:"Flood empty tanks to increase bottom pressure and prevent inshore creep.",opd:"Shift weight aft to reduce the forward draft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The primary objective of a Ro-Ro vessel is to ____________.",opa:"transfer containers without chassis",opb:"load the vessel with palletized cargo",opc:"transport vehicles",opd:"be loaded full and down to her marks",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your tank vessel is loaded down to her marks, and you find that she has too much trim by the stern. To adjust the trim you may ____________.",opa:"add ballast forward",opb:"load more cargo forward",opc:"shift bunkers forward",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning protection of double bottom tanks against excessive pressure?",opa:"Each vent for the tank must be equal to the area of the tank filling line.",opb:"The tanks must be protected by overflows.",opc:"The total area of the vents or the overflow shall be at least 125% of the area of the fill line.",opd:"There must be twice as much vent area as the area of the fill line.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which space(s) is(are) deducted from gross tonnage to derive net tonnage?",opa:"Companions and booby hatches",opb:"Open structures",opc:"Spaces for the exclusive use of the officers or crew",opd:"Water ballast spaces",ans:"opc"},{question:"You intend to tow a barge with one tug and expect continuous high winds from the north. To reduce the yaw of your tow, you should ____________.",opa:"reduce the draft of the barge",opb:"shorten one leg of the bridle",opc:"place bulky deck loads as far aft as possible",opd:"trim the barge down by the bow",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 20,000 barrels of crude oil, departing Valdez, Alaska for San Francisco. When loaded the cargo temperature was 96\xb0F. API was 15\xb0.The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0004. If the cargo temperature is expected to be 56\xb0F at the discharge port, how many barrels will be offloaded?",opa:"19680",opb:"19712",opc:"20288",opd:"20320",ans:"opa"},{question:"How can the Coast Guard determine that a crew member is 'able to understand any order spoken by the officers'?",opa:"Require a demonstration by the officer and the crew member",opb:"Require a written test",opc:"Require that an interpreter be provided",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage of tackle number 2?",opa:"0.5",opb:"1",opc:"2",opd:"3",ans:"opc"},{question:"In order to reduce your wake in a narrow channel you should ____________.",opa:"apply enough rudder to counter the effect of the current",opb:"change your course to a zigzag course",opc:"reduce your speed",opd:"shift the weight to the stern",ans:"opc"},{question:"The rope which is the lightest is ____________.",opa:"manila",opb:"nylon",opc:"polypropylene",opd:"dacron",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking the radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are as listed. Based on this data what is the transfer for a turn of 30\xb0?",opa:"40 yards",opb:"140 yards",opc:"190 yards",opd:"230 yards",ans:"opa"},{question:"The heel block is located ____________.",opa:"at the base of the boom",opb:"at the cargo hook",opc:"near the midships guy",opd:"near the spider band",ans:"opa"},{question:"When discharging an oil cargo, the first consideration is to ____________.",opa:"get the bow up",opb:"discharge from the wings first",opc:"discharge from the centerline tanks first",opd:"discharge from amidships first",ans:"opa"},{question:"What does the proof test load of an anchor chain demonstrate?",opa:"Breaking strength of the chain",opb:"Strength of the chain to a specified limit",opc:"Adequate holding power for new bottom conditions",opd:"Safe working load of the chain",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are picking up an unconscious person that has fallen overboard in a fresh breeze. For safety reasons a small craft should approach with the ____________.",opa:"victim to leeward",opb:"victim to windward",opc:"wind on your port side",opd:"wind on your starboard side",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following is/are TRUE regarding lashing requirements to secure vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"The securing of cargo on flats and trailers and in containers must be adequate to withstand both road and sea motions",opb:"The generally recommended lash angle cannot be greater than 45 degrees relative to the deck in any direction.",opc:"It is necessary for an adequate number of securing points on the vehicles themselves in order that lashings may be properly and safely utilized.",opd:"All the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The signal man assisting the crane operator has his arm extended downwards, forefinger pointing down, and moves his hand in small horizontal circles. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"lower",opb:"swing",opc:"hoist",opd:"extend",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 8,000 barrels of gasoline at a cargo temperature of 36\xb0C (97\xb0F). API gravity is 54\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0006. You are bound for New Jersey from Ecuador. How many barrels would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 55\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"7798",opb:"7827",opc:"8173",opd:"8202",ans:"opa"},{question:"In illustration D044DG, the mooring line labeled 'B' is called a(n) ____________.",opa:"inshore stern line",opb:"offshore stern line",opc:"after spring line",opd:"after breast line",ans:"opa"},{question:"The best method of determining if a vessel is dragging anchor is to note ____________.",opa:"the amount of line paid out",opb:"how much the vessel sheers while at anchor",opc:"any change in the tautness of the anchor chain",opd:"changes in bearings of fixed objects onshore",ans:"opd"},{question:"A tackle is 'two blocked' when the blocks are ____________.",opa:"equally sharing the load",opb:"jammed together",opc:"as far apart as possible",opd:"rove to the highest mechanical advantage",ans:"opb"},{question:"Displacement refers to the ____________.",opa:"cubic capacity of a vessel",opb:"deadweight carrying capacity of a vessel",opc:"gross tonnage of a vessel",opd:"number of long tons of water displaced by a vessel afloat",ans:"opd"},{question:"A stopper used in securing the ground tackle for sea that consists of a grab attached to a turnbuckle is a ____________.",opa:"riding pawl",opb:"buckler",opc:"devil's claw",opd:"locking ring",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the name of tackle number 12?",opa:"Threefold purchase",opb:"Davit tackle",opc:"Deck tackle",opd:"Gin tackle",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which method should be used to secure a manila line to bitts?",opa:"A round turn on the bitt farthest from the strain and then figure eights",opb:"A round turn on the bitt closest to the strain and then figure eights",opc:"Figure eights and then a round turn at the top of both bitts",opd:"Only figure eights are necessary on both bitts",ans:"opb"},{question:"During a period of 'whiteout', you should expect which of the following?",opa:"Snowfall or blowing snow",opb:"Lack of ability to estimate distance",opc:"Harsh contrast between sun-illuminated snow cover and the background",opd:"Hazy horizons with extensive mirage effects",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement about two lines spliced together is TRUE?",opa:"Splicing is used to increase the circumference of each line.",opb:"Splicing two lines together is stronger than knotting two lines together.",opc:"Splicing is used to increase the overall strength of the line.",opd:"Splicing is used to prevent rotting of the lines bitter end.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are transiting the Straits of Mackinac by way of an improved channel. You have information which indicates that the channel's Federal project depth is 28 ft. Which of the following statements is true with regards to this channel?",opa:"The least depth within the limits of the channel is 28 ft.",opb:"The design dredging depth of the channel is 28 ft.",opc:"The channel has 28 ft. in the center but lesser depths may exist in the remainder of the channel.",opd:"The maximum depth which may be expected within the limits of the channel is 28 ft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The load line regulations are administered by the ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"Maritime Administration",opc:"Lloyd's Register of Shipping",opd:"National Cargo Bureau",ans:"opa"},{question:"A seaman dies during a voyage. What is NOT required to be entered into the Official Log?",opa:"Statement that the Master has taken custody of the deceased's MMD and passport",opb:"An inventory of the money and property",opc:"Statement of the wages due",opd:"Statement as to the total deductions to be made from the wages",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE about nylon line?",opa:"Manila line will usually last longer than nylon line.",opb:"Nylon line is excellent for use in alongside towing.",opc:"A normal safe working load will stretch nylon line 50%.",opd:"Nylon stoppers should be used with nylon line.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Ultrasonic testing is used to determine the thickness of a vessel's shell plating and to ____________.",opa:"provide tail shaft clearances",opb:"test welds for subsurface defects",opc:"check the wear of the rudder carrier bearing",opd:"test the links of the anchor cables while being ranged",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has the symbol shown inscribed on the sides amidships. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"This line represents the load line mark for a Great Lakes voyage.",opb:"The gross and net tonnage of the ship will change if this mark is submerged and the load line is visible.",opc:"The line directly under the triangle is at the same level as the summer load line.",opd:"This is the equivalent of a load line marking for government (COE, NOAA, MSC)vessels.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You would NOT secure a line to a ____________.",opa:"kevel",opb:"stand pipe",opc:"button",opd:"timber head",ans:"opb"},{question:"The periodic weight testing of a vessel's cargo booms may be performed by the ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"National Cargo Bureau",opd:"Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a 120,000 DWT loaded bulk carrier. What is the maximum safe docking speed when coming alongside?",opa:"0.1 foot per second (0.06 knot)",opb:"0.2 foot per second (0.12 knot)",opc:"0.5 foot per second (0.30 knot)",opd:"0.75 foot per second (0.44 knot)",ans:"opb"},{question:"Right-laid line should be coiled ____________.",opa:"clockwise",opb:"counterclockwise",opc:"either clockwise or counterclockwise",opd:"on a reel",ans:"opa"},{question:"The greatest strain, when lifting a load with the jumbo purchase, is on ____________.",opa:"all of the parts, dividing the load equally",opb:"the hauling part because it must absorb the frictional losses of all the sheaves",opc:"the parts in the movable block",opd:"the standing part because it is directly connected to the weight",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is a negotiable document?",opa:"Bill of Lading",opb:"Cargo Manifest",opc:"Export Declaration",opd:"Receiving Report",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about the carriage of coal is true?",opa:"Most problems with spontaneous combustion will occur within 72 hours of loading and after that the risk decreases.",opb:"Wet coal is more liable to spontaneous heating than dry coal.",opc:"Coal absorbs nitrogen from the air which reacts with methane and causes spontaneous heating.",opd:"Freshly worked coal is more dangerous than weathered coal.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Several merchant ships are arriving at the scene of a distress incident. One of the them must assume the duties of the Coordinator Surface Search (CSS). Which of the following statements is TRUE?",opa:"CSS duties are always assumed by passenger vessels, dry cargo vessels, or tankers in that order of precedence.",opb:"The CSS must be established by mutual agreement between the ships concerned.",opc:"A tank vessel should never be assigned CSS duties unless only tank vessels are present.",opd:"The first vessel to arrive at the distress incident is designated as the CSS.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Two vessels are abreast of each other and passing port to port in a confined waterway. What should you expect as your bow approaches the screws of the other vessel?",opa:"Your speed will significantly increase.",opb:"Your draft will significantly decrease.",opc:"Your bow will sheer towards the other vessel.",opd:"Your bow will sheer away from the other vessel.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Overcarriage is best prevented by ____________.",opa:"assuring heavy cargo is stowed low in the vessel",opb:"checking the vessel's load line calculations carefully",opc:"inspection of the hold at completion of discharge",opd:"stowing the cargo which is to be discharged last on the bottom",ans:"opc"},{question:"To facilitate passing the end of a large rope through a block, you could use a ____________.",opa:"gantline",opb:"head line",opc:"reeving line",opd:"sail line",ans:"opc"},{question:"A device used to tighten up remaining slack in wire rope when you are making up to a tow in inland waters is a ____________.",opa:"tripping line",opb:"tripping bracket",opc:"norman pin",opd:"steamboat ratchet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What does item 'K' refer to in this illustration of a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Manual slewing cables",opb:"Rider block taglines",opc:"Jib luffing cables",opd:"Cargo snaking cables",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which letter in illustration D030DG represents a plain whipping?",opa:"E",opb:"F",opc:"J",opd:"V",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following is NOT necessary, prior to loading or discharging cargo on a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds.",opb:"Lower the stern ramp.",opc:"Turn on the red cargo light.",opd:"Raise/open the stern door.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A large vessel is equipped with a controllable pitch propeller. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"When dead in the water, it is often difficult to find the neutral position and slight headway or sternway may result.",opb:"When going directly from full ahead to full astern, there is complete steering control.",opc:"When the vessel has headway and the propeller is in neutral, there is no effect on rudder control.",opd:"When maneuvering in port, full ahead or astern power can usually be obtained without changing shaft RPM.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The regulations require that inspected vessels on an international voyage, other than small passenger vessels, must carry which of the following distress signals on or near the navigating bridge?",opa:"12 hand red flares",opb:"12 rocket parachute flares",opc:"12 hand combination flares and orange smoke signals",opd:"6 hand red flares, and 6 hand orange smoke signals",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a multiple-product chemical tanker and will carry cargoes of allyl alcohol, benzene, and propanolamine. Which of the following is true?",opa:"All of these cargoes are mutually compatible.",opb:"Benzene may not be carried in a tank adjacent to either of the other two cargoes.",opc:"Allyl alcohol is incompatible with propanolamine but both are compatible with benzene.",opd:"Propanolamine is compatible with allyl alcohol but must be segregated from benzene.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Centrifugal pumps have what advantage(s) over reciprocating pumps?",opa:"They are less expensive.",opb:"They are smaller for equivalent pumping ability.",opc:"They pump more cargo in less time.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The signal man assisting a crane operator has his arm extended with his fingers closed and thumb pointing upward. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"raise the boom",opb:"raise the hook",opc:"raise the boom and hook",opd:"check the boom stop",ans:"opa"},{question:"The helm command 'Check her' means ____________.",opa:"test the steering control",opb:"read the compass heading",opc:"stop the swing using hard over rudder",opd:"slow the swing using moderate rudder",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are signing on crew members. The minimum number of people required aboard, and the qualifications of each, is listed on the ____________.",opa:"Crew list",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Articles of Agreement",opd:"fo'c'sle card",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are signing on a crew. A man presents a Merchant Mariner's Document that you suspect has been tampered with. Which action should you take?",opa:"Confiscate the document and deliver it to the Coast Guard.",opb:"Sign the man on and notify the Coast Guard at the first U.S.. port of call.",opc:"Refuse to sign the man on articles until authorized by the Coast Guard.",opd:"Refuse to sign the man on and notify the FBI of unauthorized use of a federal document.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What should you do to a line to prevent fraying where it passes over the side of the vessel?",opa:"Worm that part of the line.",opb:"Splice that part of the line.",opc:"Cover it with chafing gear.",opd:"Install a cleat.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A look-out should report objects sighted using ____________.",opa:"true bearings",opb:"magnetic bearings",opc:"gyro bearings",opd:"relative bearings",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has gone aground in waters where the tide is falling. The BEST action you can take is to ____________.",opa:"set out a kedge anchor",opb:"shift the vessel's load aft and repeatedly surge the engine(s) astern",opc:"shift the vessel's load forward and wait until the next high tide",opd:"slowly bring the engine(s) to full speed astern",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are the credentialed Master of a towing vessel operating between New York and Tampa, Florida. If you carry four (4) deckhands onboard, how many must be able seamen?",opa:"4",opb:"3",opc:"2",opd:"1",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are the Master of a 500-gross ton passenger vessel operating on rivers. Your vessel accidentally runs aground. Under the regulations for passenger vessels, you must notify the ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard, only if the grounding results in damage to property in excess of$25,000",opb:"nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety or Marine Inspection Office as soon as possible",opc:"Coast Guard, only if the grounding results in a loss of life",opd:"Coast Guard, only if the grounding results in injury to personnel",ans:"opb"},{question:"While discharging a cargo, the stripping of the tanks falls behind schedule. This would indicate the ____________.",opa:"main pumps are working at a high discharge pressure",opb:"main pumps are leaving too much oil in the tanks",opc:"stripping pump is not primed",opd:"stripping line is cross-connected to the main line",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which space(s) is(are) deducted from gross tonnage to derive net tonnage?",opa:"Boatswain's stores",opb:"Chart room",opc:"Spaces for the exclusive use of the officers or crew",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"In polar regions you should NOT expect to see ____________.",opa:"mirage effects",opb:"sea smoke",opc:"extensive snowfall",opd:"false horizons",ans:"opc"},{question:"A load line is assigned by ____________.",opa:"the U.S. Customs",opb:"the U.S. Department of Energy",opc:"the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers",opd:"a recognized classification society approved by the U.S. Coast Guard",ans:"opd"},{question:"Corrosive liquids and acids should have which kind of label?",opa:"Skull and crossbones",opb:"Yellow and white",opc:"Red and white",opd:"White and black",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are arriving in port and are assigned to anchor in anchorage circle B-4. It has a diameter of 550 yards and your vessel's LOA is 449 feet. If you anchor in 9 fathoms at the center of the circle, what is the maximum number of shots of chain you can use and still remain in the circle?",opa:"6 shots",opb:"5 shots",opc:"4 shots",opd:"3 shots",ans:"opc"},{question:"Small floes of rough, hummocky sea ice capable of damaging a vessel ____________.",opa:"can usually be detected by radar in a smooth sea at a range of 4 to 6 kilometers",opb:"are indistinguishable from sea return on the PPI",opc:"are invisible to radar when covered with a thick layer of snow",opd:"are usually seen at night before they are close enough to provide a radar echo",ans:"opa"},{question:"To reduce the amount of catenary you may ____________.",opa:"shorten the hawser or increase the tug's speed",opb:"lengthen the hawser or reduce the tug's speed",opc:"place your tug in irons",opd:"make a sharp turn",ans:"opa"},{question:"The amount of strain on each runner of a married fall system lifting 2000 lbs. when the angle made by the legs is 90\xb0 would be ____________.",opa:"1000 lbs.",opb:"1154 lbs.",opc:"1414 lbs.",opd:"2000 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Cargo that is suitable for carriage on Ro-Ro vessels includes ____________.",opa:"trailers",opb:"rolling vehicles",opc:"containers",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in port A in the United States, and your Certificate of Inspection has expired. You wish to go to port B in the United States for repairs and to complete the inspection. If the Officer-in-Charge Marine Inspection deems it safe, he may issue a ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Seaworthiness",opb:"Limited Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Temporary Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Permit to Proceed",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage, neglecting friction, of tackle number 5?",opa:"2",opb:"4",opc:"5",opd:"5.5",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using a scope of 5, determine how many feet of cable you should put out to anchor in 5 fathoms of water.",opa:"100 feet",opb:"150 feet",opc:"200 feet",opd:"250 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning a tagline as used with a 30-ton pedestal crane?",opa:"Taglines are wire rope purchases that raise and lower the jib.",opb:"Taglines can be fastened to the corners of the jib when lifting containers.",opc:"The crane might not have taglines installed in its rigging system.",opd:"The taglines are wire rope purchases that raise and lower the topping lift.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 20,000 barrels of crude oil, departing Valdez, Alaska for San Francisco. When loaded the cargo temperature was 96\xb0F. API was 15\xb0.The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0004. If the cargo temperature is expected to be 56\xb0F at the discharge port, how many gallons will be offloaded?",opa:"1117600",opb:"1082400",opc:"853440",opd:"826560",ans:"opd"},{question:"Spontaneous heating of coal rapidly accelerates at the approximate minimum temperature of ____________.",opa:"88\xb0F",opb:"100\xb0F",opc:"111\xb0F",opd:"119\xb0F",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which variable factor affects the initial lashing requirements aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Vessel's draft",opb:"Center of gravity of vehicle or cargo unit",opc:"Changes in humidity",opd:"Age of vehicle or cargo unit",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is FALSE?",opa:"Nylon can stretch approximately 40% and still recover.",opb:"Only nylon stoppers should be used on nylon hawsers.",opc:"Nylon is most practical for use on hip towing.",opd:"With proper care nylon hawsers will greatly outlast manila and other natural fibers.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following actions are stated in the correct order prior to loading or discharging cargo on a Ro-Ro vessel?",opa:"Lower the stern ramp, raise/open the stern door, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",opb:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, raise/open the stern door, lower the stern ramp",opc:"Turn on ventilation for cargo holds, lower the stern ramp, raise/open the stern door",opd:"Raise/open the stern door, lower the stern ramp, turn on ventilation for cargo holds",ans:"opa"},{question:"Towlines should be inspected for chafing where the towline ____________.",opa:"passes over the stern of the towing vessel",opb:"passes through chocks",opc:"is attached to the disabled vessel",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have taken another vessel in tow at sea. You can tell that the towing speed is too fast when the ____________.",opa:"vessels are not in step",opb:"tow line feels like it is 'jumping' when touched",opc:"catenary comes clear of the water",opd:"towed vessel goes 'in irons'",ans:"opc"},{question:"The American Consul has asked the Master of a vessel bound for a port in the U.S. to transport a destitute seaman back to the U.S. Which action may the Master take?",opa:"He is normally required to take the seaman.",opb:"He may refuse to take the seaman if the seaman has a contagious disease.",opc:"He may refuse to take the seaman if it will violate the Certificate of Inspection.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of ice is a hazard to navigation?",opa:"Ice rind",opb:"Pancake ice",opc:"Frazil ice",opd:"Growlers",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a transpacific voyage, you receive a message from your vessel's operators saying that your vessel has been consigned to Naval Control of Shipping. Further information is contained in ____________.",opa:"the Light List",opb:"the Coast Pilot",opc:"the International Code of Signals (PUB 102)",opd:"Radio Aids to Navigation (PUB 117)",ans:"opd"},{question:"Item A is the ____________.",opa:"lashing",opb:"drag wire",opc:"scissor wire",opd:"tandem wire",ans:"opa"},{question:"Petroleum cargo tanks should not be topped off at deck level when loading on a cold day because ____________.",opa:"a subsequent temperature rise will cause the cargo to overflow",opb:"air pockets may cause the cargo to bubble out of the ullage hole",opc:"the increased viscosity of the product requires higher loading pressure which increases the chances of a spill",opd:"the tank valve may be stiff and a spill will occur before the valve can be closed",ans:"opa"},{question:"While your vessel is docked port side to a wharf, a sudden gale force wind causes the vessel's stern lines to part. The stern begins to fall away from the dock, and no tugs are immediately available. Which measure(s) should you take FIRST?",opa:"Notify the engineroom of the need for propulsion.",opb:"Shut down any cargo transfer that's in progress.",opc:"Let go the port anchor and veer to a short scope of chain.",opd:"Obtain assistance from the terminal to put new stern lines out.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The signal man assisting a crane operator has his arm extended, thumb pointing downwards, flexing fingers in and out. This is the signal to ____________.",opa:"lower the boom and raise the load",opb:"lower the load and raise the boom",opc:"raise the boom and lower the load",opd:"raise the load and lower the boom",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 8,000 barrels of gasoline at a cargo temperature of 36\xb0C (97\xb0F). API gravity is 54\xb0. The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0006. You are bound for New Jersey from Ecuador. How many gallons would you expect to unload if the cargo temperature is 55\xb0F at the discharge port?",opa:"451110",opb:"428890",opc:"344484",opd:"327533",ans:"opd"},{question:"Compared to manila line, size for size, nylon line ____________.",opa:"has less strength than manila line",opb:"has more strength than manila line",opc:"is equivalent to manila line",opd:"will rot quicker than manila line",ans:"opb"},{question:"The holding power of an anchor at a given scope of cable increases when the ____________.",opa:"amount of chain lying along the bottom increases",opb:"length of the catenary is reduced",opc:"mooring line tension is increased",opd:"amount of chain lying along the bottom decreases",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which material should NOT be used to secure cargo on deck for a voyage?",opa:"Steel chain",opb:"Wire rope",opc:"Steel strapping",opd:"Fiber rope",ans:"opd"},{question:"Peck and Hale gear is used most commonly for securing ____________.",opa:"automobiles",opb:"baled cargo",opc:"large wooden crates",opd:"palletized cargo",ans:"opa"},{question:"The joint formed when two steel shell plates are placed longitudinally side to side is called a ____________.",opa:"bevel",opb:"bond",opc:"strake",opd:"seam",ans:"opd"},{question:"The forecastle card is a(n) ____________.",opa:"quarters allocation",opb:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opc:"unlicensed shipping card from the union",opd:"copy of the shipping agreement",ans:"opd"},{question:"When anchoring in a clay bottom, what is one hazard that may cause the anchor to drag?",opa:"The flukes may dig in unevenly and capsize the anchor when under stress.",opb:"The flukes may not dig in.",opc:"The anchor may get shod with clay and not develop full holding power.",opd:"The anchor will tend to dig in and come to rest near the vertical.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the period of validity of the SOLAS required Cargo Ship Safety Construction Certificate?",opa:"12 months",opb:"24 months",opc:"48 months",opd:"60 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the mechanical advantage, neglecting friction, of tackle number 12?",opa:"3",opb:"5.5",opc:"6",opd:"7",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have determined the maneuvering characteristics of your vessel by taking the radar ranges and bearings of an isolated light while making a turn. The results are listed. Based on this data what is the transfer for a turn of 60\xb0?",opa:"155 yards",opb:"195 yards",opc:"255 yards",opd:"295 yards",ans:"opa"},{question:"The knot lettered O is a ____________.",opa:"timber hitch",opb:"barrel hitch",opc:"carrick bend",opd:"blackwall hitch",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement about damage control is TRUE?",opa:"A hole in the hull at the waterline is more dangerous than a hole below the inner bottom.",opb:"The amount of water entering a ship through a hole varies inversely to the area of the hole.",opc:"Water flowing into a lower compartment on a ship is more dangerous than water on deck or flowing into an upper compartment.",opd:"Water flowing over the fo'c'sle bulwark is more dangerous than a hole in the hull at the waterline.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Angular motion about the vertical axis of a vessel is called ____________.",opa:"yaw",opb:"surge",opc:"sway",opd:"roll",ans:"opa"},{question:"To reconnect a broken tow line, it is better to use a polypropylene messenger line because it ____________.",opa:"has great strength",opb:"is very supple",opc:"floats",opd:"absorbs shock by stretching",ans:"opc"},{question:"A crew member has just fallen overboard off your port side. Which action should you take?",opa:"Immediately put the rudder over hard right.",opb:"Immediately put the rudder over hard left.",opc:"Immediately put the engines astern.",opd:"Wait until the stern is well clear of the man and then put the rudder over hard right.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Regulations concerning the stowage, lashing, and securing of timber deck cargoes aboard general cargo vessels may be found in the ____________.",opa:"International Cargo Bureau Regulations",opb:"Load Line Regulations",opc:"Rules and Regulations for Cargo and Miscellaneous Vessels",opd:"vessel's classification society rules and regulations",ans:"opb"},{question:"When securing a manila line to a bitt what is the minimum number of round turns you should take before figure-eighting the line?",opa:"None",opb:"1",opc:"2",opd:"3",ans:"opb"},{question:"The anchors should be dropped well out from the pier while at a Mediterranean moor to ____________.",opa:"eliminate navigational hazards by allowing the chain to lie along the harbor bottom",opb:"increase the anchor's reliability by providing a large catenary in the chain",opc:"permit the ship to maneuver in the stream while weighing anchors",opd:"prevent damage to the stern caused by swinging against the pier in the approach",ans:"opc"},{question:"With a large tow astern, there is immediate danger to the tug in the event of the ____________.",opa:"tug losing power",opb:"tow line parting",opc:"bridle twisting",opd:"tow broaching",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which lashing materials would be used in securing light vehicles aboard Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Chain lever or turnbuckle",opb:"Webbing",opc:"Chain",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A U.S. or foreign flag vessel that does not comply with the Officers Competency Certificates Convention of 1936 may be detained by certain designated officials. These officials include all of the following EXCEPT a/an ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard officer",opb:"employee of the U.S. Customs Service",opc:"Coast Guard petty officer",opd:"State Police officer",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your ship has loaded 22,000 barrels of crude oil, departing Valdez, Alaska for Panama. When loaded the cargo temperature was 90\xb0F. API was 15\xb0.The volume correction factor (VCF) is .0004. If the cargo temperature is expected to be 100\xb0F at the discharge port, how many barrels will be offloaded?",opa:"21252",opb:"21912",opc:"22088",opd:"22748",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are standing the wheel watch when you hear the cry, 'Man overboard starboard side'. You should instinctively ____________.",opa:"give full left rudder",opb:"give full right rudder",opc:"put the rudder amidships",opd:"throw a life ring to mark the spot",ans:"opb"},{question:"While discharging a tanker, list can be controlled by ____________.",opa:"shoreside personnel",opb:"using a center tank near the bow, discharging as necessary",opc:"using wing tanks near the longitudinal center, discharging as necessary",opd:"using the after peak tank, loading as necessary",ans:"opc"},{question:"A long splice in a line ____________.",opa:"is used in running rigging",opb:"doubles the size of the line",opc:"is only used on fiber rope",opd:"is very weak",ans:"opa"},{question:"The declaration made by the Master when he anticipates hull and/or cargo damage due to unusual weather conditions is a ____________.",opa:"Note of Protest",opb:"Notice of Casualty",opc:"Portage Bill",opd:"Bottomry Bond",ans:"opa"},{question:"The fitting that allows a boom to move freely both vertically and laterally is called the ____________.",opa:"swivel",opb:"lizard",opc:"spider band",opd:"gooseneck",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are the Master of a 500-gross ton passenger vessel operating on rivers. Your vessel accidentally runs aground. Under the regulations for passenger vessels, you must notify the ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard, only if the grounding results in damage to property in excess of$25,000",opb:"Coast Guard, only if the grounding results in a loss of life",opc:"Coast Guard, only if the grounding results in injury to personnel",opd:"nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety or Marine Inspection Office as soon as possible",ans:"opd"},{question:"A sail hook is used for ____________.",opa:"hoisting a windsail",opb:"parceling",opc:"sewing canvas",opd:"testing canvas",ans:"opc"},{question:"The function of the bilge keel is to ____________.",opa:"reduce the rolling of the vessel",opb:"serve as the vessel's main strength member",opc:"add strength to the bilge",opd:"protect the vessel's hull when alongside a dock",ans:"opa"},{question:"The 30 ton capacity pedestal cranes shown in the illustration can lift a maximum weight of how many tons in the single mode?",opa:"15 tons",opb:"30 tons",opc:"60 tons",opd:"120 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tug's horsepower available at the shaft is ____________.",opa:"indicated horsepower",opb:"brake horsepower",opc:"dynamic horsepower",opd:"net horsepower",ans:"opb"},{question:"Line is called 'small stuff' if its circumference is less than ____________.",opa:"1/2'",opb:"3/4'",opc:"1'",opd:"1 3/4'",ans:"opd"},{question:"A V-shaped ripple with the point of the V pointing upstream in a river may indicate a ____________.",opa:"submerged rock, not dangerous to navigation",opb:"sunken wreck, not dangerous to navigation",opc:"towed-under buoy",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"While towing in shallow water you should consider ____________.",opa:"using a short towing hawser",opb:"using a floating hawser",opc:"the catenary and the effect it may have on the tow",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is NOT a recommended practice when handling nylon line?",opa:"Nylon lines which become slippery because of oil or grease should be scrubbed down.",opb:"Manila line stoppers should be used for holding nylon hawsers.",opc:"When easing out nylon line, keep an extra turn on the bitt to prevent slipping.",opd:"Iced-over nylon lines should be thawed and drained before stowing.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which letter shown represents a clove hitch?",opa:"X",opb:"U",opc:"T",opd:"R",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the vessel is on coastwise articles, the original certificate of the seaman's certificate of discharge is ____________.",opa:"given to the seaman",opb:"retained on board",opc:"sent to Commandant, U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"sent to the shipping company",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Coordinator Surface Search (CSS) in a SAR situation should display by night ____________.",opa:"deck lights forward and aft",opb:"a white light over two red lights",opc:"a red light, white light, and blue light in a vertical line",opd:"a distinctive signal promulgated by the CSS",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following statements is/are TRUE concerning cranes being installed on the centerline of vessels?",opa:"One crane is able to work both sides of the ship.",opb:"One crane is able to work one end of two adjacent hatches.",opc:"They are more economical and weigh less.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Chafing gear is used to ____________.",opa:"anchor the boat",opb:"pick up heavy loads",opc:"protect fiber rope from abrasion",opd:"strengthen mooring lines",ans:"opc"},{question:"The system of valves and cargo lines in the bottom piping network of a tank vessel that connects one section of cargo tanks to another section is called a ____________.",opa:"crossover",opb:"runaround",opc:"come-along",opd:"manifold",ans:"opa"},{question:"The vessel has broken down and you are going to take her in tow. The wind is on her starboard beam. Both vessels are making the same amount of leeway. Where should you position your vessel when you start running lines?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opc"},{question:"The signal man has both arms extended out, palms down, and is moving his arms back and forth. This is the signal for ____________.",opa:"keep lifting",opb:"swing right",opc:"swing left",opd:"emergency stop",ans:"opd"},{question:"A channel is stated as having a controlling depth of 38 feet. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"At least 80% of the channel is cleared to the charted depth.",opb:"At least 50% of the channel is cleared to the charted depth.",opc:"100% of the channel width is clear to 38 feet.",opd:"The sides of the channel conform to at least 50% of the controlling depth.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The terms 'cant frame' and 'counter' are associated with the vessel's ____________.",opa:"cargo hatch",opb:"forecastle",opc:"steering engine",opd:"stern",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a line is subject to wear where it passes through a mooring chock, it should be ____________.",opa:"wormed, parceled, and served",opb:"wrapped with heavy tape",opc:"wrapped with chafing gear",opd:"wrapped in leather",ans:"opc"},{question:"The term that indicates how many tons of cargo a vessel can carry is ____________.",opa:"bale cubic",opb:"deadweight",opc:"gross tonnage",opd:"loaded displacement",ans:"opb"},{question:"What form of ice is of land origin?",opa:"Shuga",opb:"Floe",opc:"Spicule",opd:"Bergy bit",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which lashing gear used aboard Ro-Ro vessels should be painted or soaked in oil when not in use?",opa:"Wire rope.",opb:"Chain",opc:"Webbing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which characteristic is a disadvantage of a controllable-pitch propeller as compared to a fixed-pitch propeller?",opa:"Slightly higher fuel consumption",opb:"Lack of directional control when backing",opc:"Inefficient at high shaft RPM",opd:"Some unusual handling characteristics",ans:"opd"},{question:"Cottonseed oil is classed as a ____________.",opa:"combustible liquid",opb:"flammable liquid",opc:"flammable solid",opd:"poison B",ans:"opa"},{question:"When clearing customs for a foreign voyage, which of the following is processed at the custom's house and returned to the vessel?",opa:"Shipping Articles",opb:"Traveling Curio Manifest",opc:"Official Logbook",opd:"Cargo Gear Register",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are making mooring lines fast to bitts, stern to, as in some Mediterranean ports. A swell is liable to make the vessel surge. How should you tie up?",opa:"Use manila or synthetic fiber hawsers only.",opb:"Use wires only from the stern and each quarter.",opc:"Use synthetic fiber and/or manila hawsers as required.",opd:"Use wires from each quarter and manila hawsers from the stern.",ans:"opa"},{question:"To determine the number of able seamen required on an inspected vessel, you should check the ____________.",opa:"Load Line Certificate",opb:"operations manual",opc:"Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opd:"Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"To overcome the effects of static forces between two vessels of vastly different tonnages that may potentially part a line, you should ____________.",opa:"rig a bridle at both the bow of the disabled vessel and stern of the towing vessel",opb:"commence tow at a slow bell and increase speed incrementally",opc:"pay out extra towline and increase speed rapidly to 'jump start' disabled vessel",opd:"at slow bell alter course 30 degrees to both side of disabled tow",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a multiple-product chemical tanker and will carry cargoes of isophorone, ethylenediamine, and creosote. Which of the following is TRUE?",opa:"All of these cargoes are compatible.",opb:"Isophorone is incompatible with ethylenediamine but may be stowed adjacent to creosote.",opc:"All of these cargoes are incompatible.",opd:"Ethylenediamine is compatible with isophorone but both are incompatible with creosote.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Bilge keels are more effective at dampening rolls as the ____________.",opa:"pitching increases",opb:"list increases",opc:"rolling increases",opd:"draft decreases",ans:"opc"},{question:"A block that can be opened at the hook or shackle end to receive a bight of the line is a ____________.",opa:"bight block",opb:"gin block",opc:"heel block",opd:"snatch block",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should you signal the crane operator to use the whip line?",opa:"Extend arm with the thumb pointing up, and flex the fingers in and out for as long as the load movement is desired.",opb:"First tap your elbow with one hand, and then proceed to use regular signals.",opc:"First tap the top of your head with your fist, and then proceed to use regular signals.",opd:"Use one hand to give any motion signal, and place the other hand motionless in front of the hand giving the motion signal.",ans:"opb"},{question:"In terms of vessel manning, a watch is the ____________.",opa:"direct performance of deck or engine operations in a scheduled and fixed rotation",opb:"performance of maintenance work necessary for the vessel's safe operation, on a daily basis",opc:"performance of lookout duties",opd:"direct performance of cargo loading and discharge operations only",ans:"opa"},{question:"Naval Control of Shipping (NCS) publications should be ____________.",opa:"in the Master's custody",opb:"safely stowed",opc:"turned over to the relieving Master",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the effect of releasing the towline in a tripping situation?",opa:"It disconnects the capsizing force and allows the tug to recover from its list.",opb:"It frees the tug from its towing responsibilities.",opc:"There is no effect other than relief.",opd:"Yawing",ans:"opa"},{question:"By law, the maximum penalty for failing (without reasonable cause) to give aid in the case of collision is ____________.",opa:"one year imprisonment or$500",opb:"two years imprisonment or$1000",opc:"two years imprisonment or$1500",opd:"two years imprisonment or$2000",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following are considered to be 'road vehicles' that can be carried on Ro-Ro vessels?",opa:"Semi-trailer",opb:"Road train",opc:"Articulated road train",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When operating in an area where sea ice and icebergs are present, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Icebergs may travel in a direction many degrees different from the sea ice.",opb:"Both icebergs and sea ice will move in approximately the same direction and at the same speed.",opc:"Icebergs and sea ice will move in the same direction, but at different speeds due to the sail effect of the berg.",opd:"Icebergs and sea ice will move in the same direction, but the iceberg will move slower because of its underwater bulk.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which Naval Control of Shipping publication should be aboard your vessel?",opa:"ATP-2, Volume II 'Allied Control of Shipping Manual -Guide to Masters'",opb:"ATP-1, Volume II 'Allied Tactical Signals'",opc:"NWP-14,'Amphibious Operations'",opd:"PUB 102,'International Code of Signals'",ans:"opa"},{question:"A thirty pound plate would be ____________.",opa:"3/8' thick",opb:"1/2' thick",opc:"3/4' thick",opd:"1' thick",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lashings used on Ro-Ro vessels should be capable of withstanding the forces of ____________.",opa:"rolling",opb:"pitching",opc:"heaving",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of bottom is best suited for holding an anchor of a small boat?",opa:"Mud and clay",opb:"Rocky",opc:"Sandy",opd:"Gravel",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about the ventilation of bulk coal is TRUE?",opa:"Coal should not be ventilated; all oxygen should be excluded from the cargo.",opb:"Coal should be through-ventilated to remove methane and reduce the heat of spontaneous combustion.",opc:"Coal should be ventilated only if temperatures in the center of the cargo exceed 125\xb0F.",opd:"Coal should be surface ventilated only.",ans:"opd"},{question:"When steaming through an anchorage, a shipmaster should ____________.",opa:"avoid crossing close astern of the anchored ships",opb:"avoid crossing close ahead of the anchored ships",opc:"keep the ship moving at a good speed to reduce set",opd:"transit only on a flood tide",ans:"opb"},{question:"The owner or Master of a towing vessel that tows astern must keep records of the towline(s) that include all of the following information EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"the towline's initial minimum breaking strength as determined by the manufacturer",opb:"an invoice showing the cost of the towline",opc:"the towline's nautical miles of use or time in service",opd:"the history of loading of the towline",ans:"opb"},{question:"The 'lay' of a line refers to ____________.",opa:"its normal location of stowage",opb:"the direction of twist in the strands",opc:"the manner in which it is coiled",opd:"the manner in which it is rigged",ans:"opb"},{question:"The best method to secure a tow line to a cleat is to ____________.",opa:"take a turn around the cleat, then figure-eights, and a half-hitch",opb:"make figure-eights, followed by a half-hitch, then a figure-eight knot",opc:"take a turn, a half turn, and a figure-eight",opd:"take several turns around the cleat only",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which letter indicates a longitudinal?",opa:"C",opb:"E",opc:"L",opd:"M",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which device is designed to automatically hold the load if power should fail to an electric winch?",opa:"Pneumatic brake",opb:"Electromagnetic brake",opc:"Hand brake",opd:"Motor controller",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is at a dock taking bunkers. If oil begins to flow out of a tank vent, what should you do FIRST?",opa:"Open the intake valve to an adjacent tank.",opb:"Set out drip pans and sawdust and begin to mop up the spill.",opc:"Signal the shore control point to shut down.",opd:"Close the valve on the tank vent line.",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the DEEP DRILLER, TCG is obtained from the sum of the transverse moments by ____________.",opa:"adding the free surface correction",opb:"subtracting the free surface correction",opc:"multiplying by displacement",opd:"dividing by displacement",ans:"opd"},{question:"A thrust block is designed to ____________.",opa:"absorb the shock of wave pressure at the bow",opb:"be placed between the engines and the foundation to absorb the vibration",opc:"transmit the thrust of the engine to the propeller",opd:"transmit the thrust of the propeller to the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"In the absence of external forces, the center of buoyancy of an inclined vessel is vertically aligned directly below the ____________.",opa:"center of gravity",opb:"amidships station",opc:"center of flotation",opd:"geometric center of the waterplane area",ans:"opa"},{question:"A double male coupling is one that ____________.",opa:"has left hand twist",opb:"has inside threads on both ends",opc:"has outside threads on both ends",opd:"takes two men to operate",ans:"opc"},{question:"A fire in trash and paper waste is classified as class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Additional deck load may be placed aboard. If the maximum permissible deck load were placed in the pipe racks at a VCG of 130 feet, the KG increases ____________.",opa:"1.43 feet",opb:"1.89 feet",opc:"2.23 feet",opd:"2.43 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"When treating a person for third-degree burns, you should ____________.",opa:"submerge the burn area in cold water",opb:"make the person stand up and walk to increase circulation",opc:"cover the burns with thick, sterile dressings",opd:"break blisters and remove dead tissue",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the minimum license requirement of a GMDSS Radio Operator?",opa:"Holding the Marine Radio Operator Permit is a pre-requisite before the GMDSS Radio Operator Endorsement can be obtained.",opb:"Holding the General Radiotelephone Operator License with RADAR endorsement is sufficient.",opc:"Holding a valid GMDSS Radio Operator License is sufficient.",opd:"Holding either the General Radiotelephone Operator License or the First or Second Class Radiotelegraph License with GMDSS Radio Maintainer's Endorsement is sufficient.",ans:"opc"},{question:"In a storm, the windward lines of a MODU's mooring system provide ____________.",opa:"a positive righting moment",opb:"an increase in KM",opc:"a negative restoring force",opd:"a positive restoring force",ans:"opd"},{question:"When starting a long ocean tow at a displacement of 18,000 short tons and a KG of 70 feet, you dump 100 short tons of water which had a VCG of 88 feet. What is the new KG?",opa:"59.9 feet",opb:"69.9 feet",opc:"79.9 feet",opd:"89.9 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are operating 10 miles offshore with three people aboard. What kind of survival craft must you carry?",opa:"An inflatable liferaft with a coastal pack",opb:"A life float",opc:"An inflatable buoyant apparatus",opd:"No survival craft is required.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Before personnel are lifted from a vessel in a personnel basket, the vessel should be?",opa:"directly under the boom",opb:"moving away from the boom",opc:"stopped dead in the water",opd:"tied to the boom",ans:"opa"},{question:"Any firefighting equipment that is carried in addition to the minimum required number on a MODU must ____________.",opa:"meet the applicable standards",opb:"be marked as additional equipment",opc:"be stowed in a separate area",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"With no environmental forces on the DEEP DRILLER, the average of the forward drafts is 59.0 feet, and the average of the aft drafts is 61.0 feet. KGL is 51.13 feet. What is the value of LCG?",opa:"-0.12 foot",opb:"0.12 foot",opc:"2.11 feet",opd:"2.35 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You should be most concerned about a possible explosion or fire in fuel tanks ____________.",opa:"during fueling when the fuel first strikes the tank bottom",opb:"during fueling when the fuel strikes fuel already in the tank",opc:"when underway as the fuel is moved by wave action",opd:"shortly after fueling when fuel vapors gather",ans:"opa"},{question:"What information must be entered on the MODU's muster list?",opa:"Names of all crew members",opb:"Use and application of special equipment",opc:"Listing of approved emergency equipment",opd:"Duties and station of each person during emergencies",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your sailing drafts are: FWD 17'-07', AFT 18'-03' and the GM is 2.8 feet. What will be the angle of list if the #4 starboard double bottom (capacity 141 tons, VCG 2.6 feet, and 23.8 feet off the centerline) is filled with saltwater? (Use the data in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"6\xb0",opb:"8\xb0",opc:"10\xb0",opd:"12\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"When leveling the elevated COASTAL DRILLER, you may raise the low corner instead of lowering the high corner ____________.",opa:"in all cases, it is optional",opb:"if lowering the high corner places the unit in the wave action",opc:"if proper air gap has been exceeded",opd:"if a potential punch-through threatens",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are at sea on a vessel that has a beam of 50 feet, and you calculate the period of roll to be 22 seconds. What is the vessel's metacentric height?",opa:"0.8 ft.",opb:"1.0 ft.",opc:"1.2 ft.",opd:"1.4 ft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You will extinguish a fire when you remove ____________.",opa:"nitrogen",opb:"oxygen",opc:"sodium",opd:"carbon dioxide",ans:"opb"},{question:"A combustible gas indicator will operate correctly ONLY when the ____________.",opa:"hydrocarbon content of the atmosphere is less than the U.E.L.",opb:"atmosphere is deficient in oxygen",opc:"compartment to be tested is free of CO2",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"To prevent damage by and to storage batteries aboard small passenger vessels they should be located ____________.",opa:"in trays constructed of material that is resistant to the electrolyte",opb:"so as to prevent movement when the vessel pitches and rolls",opc:"in a well ventilated area",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). If the maximum permissible deck load were placed aboard at a VCG of 130 feet, what would be the new draft?",opa:"19 feet 9 inches",opb:"20 feet 4 inches",opc:"20 feet 8 inches",opd:"21 feet 4 inches",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have 480 tons of below deck tonnage including liquid mud. Your existing deck cargo is 200 tons with a VCG above the deck of 2.8 feet. What is the maximum additional cargo tonnage you are permitted to load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"34 tons",opb:"62 tons",opc:"134 tons",opd:"186 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"When referring to quantity of barite in a P-tank, ullage is the ____________.",opa:"distance of the barite surface above the tank bottom",opb:"percentage of barite in the tank",opc:"distance of the barite surface below the tank cover",opd:"total weight of barite in UPC (ullages per centimeter)",ans:"opc"},{question:"The bottom row of plating next to the keel of a lifeboat is known as the ____________.",opa:"sheer strake",opb:"bilge strake",opc:"garboard strake",opd:"keel rib",ans:"opc"},{question:"The most likely location for a liquid cargo fire to occur on a tanker would be ____________.",opa:"in the midships house",opb:"at the main deck manifold",opc:"at the vent header",opd:"in the pumproom",ans:"opd"},{question:"The time required to ballast the DEEP DRILLER to survival draft, when threatened with heavy weather, while under tow, is about ____________.",opa:"2 hours",opb:"3 hours",opc:"4 hours",opd:"5 hours",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using a sea anchor will ____________.",opa:"reduce your drift rate",opb:"keep the liferaft from turning over",opc:"aid in recovering the liferaft",opd:"increase your visibility",ans:"opa"},{question:"After conducting an abandonment drill, the Master or person in charge of a MODU shall log ____________.",opa:"the names of crew members who participated in the drill",opb:"the length of time that each motor propelled lifeboat was operated in the drill",opc:"the length of time the lifeboat was in the water",opd:"the time it took to lower the boat",ans:"opa"},{question:"Preparing to move on a location, you find that you must remove 450 tons of drill water, with a VCG of 8 feet, to enable you to meet the draft limitations. You started with a displacement of 17,000 tons and a KG of 69 feet. What is the KG after pumping out the drill water?",opa:"49.13 feet",opb:"59.13 feet",opc:"69.13 feet",opd:"70.66 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 45 feet and total vertical moments of 981,567 ft.-long tons, floods 2068.7 long tons of sea water through the overboard discharge into tanks 3 and 8 on both sides. The VCG of the added ballast is 7.22 feet. The shift in the height of the center of gravity is ____________.",opa:"0.93 foot",opb:"6.16 feet",opc:"6.95 feet",opd:"7.88 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Life preservers must be marked with the ____________.",opa:"stowage space assigned",opb:"vessel's name",opc:"vessel's home port",opd:"maximum weight allowed",ans:"opb"},{question:"In a fixed CO2 fire extinguishing system where pressure from pilot cylinders is used to release the CO2 from the main bank of cylinders, the number of required pilot cylinders shall be at least ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"6",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement concerning GMDSS maintenance requirements is FALSE?",opa:"Compulsory vessels sailing in Sea Areas A1 and A2 must provide any one of the three maintenance options which are duplication of equipment, shore-based or at-sea maintenance capability.",opb:"Compulsory vessels sailing in Sea Areas A3 and A4 must provide any two of the three maintenance options which are duplication of equipment, shore-based or at-sea maintenance capability.",opc:"If shore-based maintenance is used, maintenance services do not have to be completed or performance verified unless the vessel will be sailing to a non-US port.",opd:"Equipment warranties do not satisfy GMDSS maintenance requirements.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What would white exhaust smoke from a diesel engine probably mean?",opa:"Late fuel injection",opb:"Excess combustion air",opc:"High compression temperature",opd:"Excessive lube oil consumption",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of the intake/exhaust valves in a diesel engine?",opa:"They regulate the combustion cycle.",opb:"They supply cooling water.",opc:"They synchronize the ignition spark.",opd:"They supply and regulate the lubricant flow.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Aboard a vessel, dividing the sum of the transverse moments by the total weight yields the vessel's ____________.",opa:"vertical moments",opb:"transverse position of the center of gravity",opc:"inclining moments",opd:"righting moments",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is taking on fuel when a small leak develops in the hose. You order the pumping stopped. Before you resume pumping, you should ____________.",opa:"notify the terminal superintendent",opb:"place a large drip pan under the leak and plug the scuppers",opc:"repair the hose with a patch",opd:"replace the hose",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 2.8 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.2 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.5 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The longitudinal location of the center of flotation for the COASTAL DRILLER has a value of ____________.",opa:"207.33 feet AF0",opb:"160.33 feet AF0",opc:"119.44 feet AF0",opd:"38.33 feet AF0",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which problem is virtually impossible to detect during an in-service inspection of used mooring chain?",opa:"Cracks",opb:"Elongation",opc:"Loose studs",opd:"Fatigue",ans:"opd"},{question:"While the DEEP DRILLER is operating as shown in Sample Form #4 (Drilling), casing is accidentally dropped over the starboard side. If the starboard aft inclination is slowly increasing, which tank is probably damaged?",opa:"9S",opb:"8S",opc:"10S",opd:"10P",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to the SOLAS regulations, lifeboat falls must be renewed at intervals of how many years?",opa:"2.5",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"5",ans:"opd"},{question:"When treating a chemical burn, you should flood the burned area for at least ____________.",opa:"five minutes",opb:"ten minutes",opc:"fifteen minutes",opd:"twenty minutes",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fixed CO2 systems would not be used on crew's quarters or ____________.",opa:"the paint locker",opb:"spaces open to the atmosphere",opc:"cargo holds",opd:"the engine room",ans:"opb"},{question:"In order to check your vessel's stability, a weight of 40 tons is lifted with the jumbo boom, the boom head being 50 feet from the ship's centerline. The clinometer is then carefully read and shows a list of 5\xb0. The vessel's displacement is 8,000 tons including the suspended weight. What will be the metacentric height of the vessel at this time?",opa:"2.74 feet",opb:"2.80 feet",opc:"2.86 feet",opd:"2.93 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Free communication will adversely affect transverse stability only when the flooded space is ____________.",opa:"off-center",opb:"on the centerline",opc:"completely flooded",opd:"open to the sea above and below the waterline",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the contents of #6 and #7 drill water tanks are discharged, what would be the new height of the longitudinal metacenter?",opa:"249.47 feet",opb:"250.16 feet",opc:"252.92 feet",opd:"253.90 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"After the boat is at the top of the davit heads, the davit arms begin moving up the tracks and are stopped by the ____________.",opa:"hoist man",opb:"limit switch",opc:"brake handle",opd:"preventer bar",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 14'-06', AFT 17'-00'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"0.52 foot",opb:"0.70 foot",opc:"0.84 foot",opd:"1.10 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a MODU, how many ring buoys are required to have a buoyant line attached?",opa:"One ring life buoy",opb:"One ring life buoy on each side of the MODU",opc:"Three ring life buoys",opd:"Two ring life buoys on each side of the MODU",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which will improve stability?",opa:"Closing watertight doors",opb:"Pumping the bilges",opc:"Loading cargo on deck",opd:"Consuming fuel from a full tank",ans:"opb"},{question:"onboard small passenger vessels, storage batteries containing an electrolyte must be set in trays constructed of ____________.",opa:"a fireproof material",opb:"a material resistant to damage by the electrolyte",opc:"a porous material that permits drainage of any acid overflow",opd:"suitably strong to hold the weight of the batteries",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are operating an ocean-going vessel of 322 gross tons. If your vessel does NOT have an oily-water separator then she must have a fixed piping system to discharge oily ballast to a shore facility. This system must include ____________.",opa:"containment capacity for at least 5 gallons at the tank vents",opb:"a means to stop each pump near the discharge outlet",opc:"at least two pumps that may be put in line",opd:"at least two outlets accessible from the weather deck",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which types of portable fire extinguishers are designed for use on electrical fires?",opa:"Dry chemical and carbon dioxide",opb:"Foam (stored pressure) and soda-acid",opc:"Carbon dioxide and foam (stored pressure)",opd:"Dry chemical and soda-acid",ans:"opa"},{question:"In storm conditions, with the wind and waves from the port bow of the DEEP DRILLER in 400 feet water depth, the tensions in mooring lines 1 and 2 are 400 kips. Completely slacking the mooring lines 5 and 6 reduces the tension in mooring lines 1 and 2 to about ____________.",opa:"375 kips",opb:"330 kips",opc:"275 kips",opd:"220 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #3 (Preparing to Drill). If the liquid mud in mud pit #4 (see table 8) is dumped, what would be the new height of the center of gravity corrected for transverse free surface effects?",opa:"51.50 feet",opb:"52.54 feet",opc:"52.88 feet",opd:"53.54 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged and listing to port. There is a short rolling period around the angle of list. The port side freeboard is reduced to 1 foot. There is no trim and the weather is calm. You should FIRST ____________.",opa:"press up a slack double bottom tank on the port side",opb:"fill an empty centerline double bottom tank",opc:"pump out a slack marine portable tank located on the portside amidships",opd:"jettison the anchors and anchor cables",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your voyage planning indicates you will arrive at a waypoint in longitude 149\xb016.3'E at 0947 ZT on 3 March 1988. How should this date be entered into an AMVER report?",opa:"030947K MAR",opb:"094703K",opc:"022347Z",opd:"234703Z",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the displacement of a barge which measures 85' x 46' x 13' and is floating in salt water with a draft of ten feet?",opa:"1117 tons",opb:"1452 tons",opc:"500 tons",opd:"17.5 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have called another vessel by flashing light and he has answered your call properly. You now send your call sign 'DE KLIS'. He should respond with ____________.",opa:"TTTT",opb:"his own call letters",opc:"KLIS, DE, his own call letters",opd:"R",ans:"opc"},{question:"What lighting characteristic is required of an obstruction light on a mobile offshore drilling unit on the waters of the U.S. Outer Continental Shelf?",opa:"Fixed",opb:"Flashing",opc:"Quick-flashing",opd:"Occulting",ans:"opc"},{question:"First aid treatment for small cuts and open wounds is to ____________.",opa:"lay the patient down and cover the wound when the bleeding stops",opb:"stop the bleeding, clean, medicate, and cover the wound",opc:"apply an ice pack to the wound and cover it when the bleeding stops",opd:"apply a hot towel to purge the wound, then medicate and cover it",ans:"opb"},{question:"Ambient air, which you normally breathe, contains what percent of oxygen?",opa:"0.06",opb:"0.1",opc:"0.15",opd:"0.21",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the minimum number of fire pumps required on a cargo vessel of 900 GT?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opa"},{question:"When in command of a lifeboat under oars, the command 'Backwater' means to ____________.",opa:"lift oars to vertical position, trim blades fore and aft with handles resting on footings",opb:"complete the stroke, come to 'Oars', raise oars smartly to vertical, rest handles on footing, trim blades fore and aft",opc:"row in astern motion",opd:"complete stroke, stop rowing, dip blade about halfway into water, hold water to stop the way on the boat",ans:"opc"},{question:"Temporary Certificates of Inspection for offshore drilling units are effective until the ____________.",opa:"Operations Manual is approved",opb:"Minerals Management Service approval is issued",opc:"classification society approval is issued",opd:"permanent Certificate of Inspection is issued",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in charge of a fishing vessel with 18 individuals onboard. You are required to conduct drills and give safety instruction at least once ____________.",opa:"every week",opb:"every 15 days",opc:"every month",opd:"before you begin fishing",ans:"opc"},{question:"What are the two main types of stud link chain?",opa:"Oil Rig chain and Oil Field Stud Link chain",opb:"Flash-butt welded chain and Di-Lok chain",opc:"Flash-butt welded chain and Oil Rig chain",opd:"Oil Field Stud Link chain and Flash-butt welded chain",ans:"opb"},{question:"The instructions for rescue boats and liferafts on an OSV must be approved by the ____________.",opa:"lease operator",opb:"Minerals Management Service",opc:"Coast Guard",opd:"person-in-charge of the unit",ans:"opc"},{question:"For small, first-degree burns the quickest method to relieve pain is to ____________.",opa:"immerse the burn in cold water",opb:"administer aspirin",opc:"apply petroleum jelly",opd:"apply a bandage to exclude air",ans:"opa"},{question:"During a storm, the chance of fatigue failure of a mooring line will increase as ____________.",opa:"vessel motions increase",opb:"mooring tensions decrease",opc:"KG increases",opd:"KG decreases",ans:"opa"},{question:"Use the floodable length curve in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the curve represents 45 percent permeability and number 2 hold floods, the vessel will sink if the permeability exceeds what percent?",opa:"76",opb:"67",opc:"60",opd:"52",ans:"opb"},{question:"Addition of weight to a vessel will ALWAYS ____________.",opa:"reduce reserve buoyancy",opb:"increase righting moments",opc:"increase GM",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"A slow and easy motion of a vessel in a seaway is an indication of a ____________.",opa:"small GM",opb:"low center of gravity",opc:"stiff vessel",opd:"large GZ",ans:"opa"},{question:"How much drill water should be transferred from tanks #23 and #24 to tank #1 to level the COASTAL DRILLER, in transit at a draft of 10 feet 6 inches, if the total longitudinal moments are 1,700,000 ft.-kips?",opa:"438 kips",opb:"451 kips",opc:"521 kips",opd:"537 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming over the port side is said to be on a ____________.",opa:"port jibe",opb:"starboard jibe",opc:"port tack",opd:"starboard tack",ans:"opc"},{question:"By regulation, cargo tank atmosphere must be inert before and during which operation?",opa:"Stripping",opb:"Loading",opc:"Cleaning",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"With regard to aerodynamic lift, which statement is TRUE?",opa:"If the thrust on a sail becomes excessive when close-hauled, it is likely to capsize the vessel rather than drive it.",opb:"When a sail is trimmed too tight, turbulence will break out on the windward side of the sail and cause a telltale there to flutter.",opc:"A properly trimmed sail should have laminar flow on the windward side and turbulent flow on the leeward side.",opd:"Adjusting the angle of attack on a mainsail is accomplished by adjusting the outhaul or the vang, if fitted.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Burning wood is which class of fire?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a sea anchor for a lifeboat is properly rigged, it will ____________.",opa:"completely stop the lifeboat from drifting",opb:"help to prevent broaching",opc:"prevent the lifeboat from pitching",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"With no environmental forces on the DEEP DRILLER, the average of the forward drafts is 61.0 feet, and the average of the aft drafts is 59.0 feet. KGL is 51.13 feet. What is the value of LCG?",opa:"-0.12 foot",opb:"0.12 foot",opc:"2.11 feet",opd:"2.35 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The liquid mud tanks on your vessel measure 22'L by 16'B by 7'D. The vessel's displacement is 568 T and the specific gravity of the mud is 1.6. What is the reduction in GM due to 2 of these tanks being slack?",opa:"0.56 foot",opb:"0.96 foot",opc:"1.18 feet",opd:"1.43 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 24'-06', AFT 25'-04'; and the KG is 17.8 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the remaining righting arm at 75\xb0 inclination if the center of gravity is 2.5 feet off the centerline.",opa:"2.5 feet",opb:"3.3 feet",opc:"5.4 feet",opd:"9.7 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are attempting to administer CPR to a victim. When you blow into his mouth it is apparent that no air is getting into the lungs. What should you do?",opa:"Blow harder to force the air past the tongue.",opb:"Raise the victim's head higher than his feet.",opc:"Press on the victim's lungs so that air pressure will blow out any obstruction.",opd:"Re-tip the head and try again.",ans:"opd"},{question:"While in transit at a draft of 10.5 feet, the COASTAL DRILLER has a KGT of 60.0 feet. What is the GMT?",opa:"139.92 feet",opb:"138.89 feet",opc:"79.92 feet",opd:"78.89 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, when burning, the grade B flammable liquid, carbon disulfide produces ____________.",opa:"phosgene gas",opb:"sulfuric acid gas",opc:"sulfur dioxide gas",opd:"carbon tetrachloride",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 13'-10', AFT 16'-04'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.30 feet",opb:"1.07 foot",opc:"0.96 foot",opd:"0.73 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"The operating cord on an inflatable liferaft should be renewed by ____________.",opa:"removing the top half of the shell, cutting the line at its source, and renewing completely",opb:"cutting the line where it enters the case and replacing that portion",opc:"leaving the original line and tying another one to it so the two lines will take the strain",opd:"an approved servicing facility ashore",ans:"opd"},{question:"You must shift a weight from the upper 'tween deck to the lower hold. This shift will ____________.",opa:"make the vessel more tender",opb:"make the vessel stiffer",opc:"increase the rolling period",opd:"decrease the metacentric height",ans:"opb"},{question:"The person or company, either proprietor or lessee, actually operating an oil well or lease is the ____________.",opa:"production company",opb:"company representative",opc:"drilling contractor",opd:"operator",ans:"opd"},{question:"If there are a number of survivors in the water after abandoning an OSV and no rescue craft are in sight, they should ____________.",opa:"tie themselves to the unit to avoid drifting with the current",opb:"group to form a small circle of survivors to create a warmer pocket of water in the center of the circle",opc:"send the strongest swimmer to shore for assistance",opd:"from a raft by lashing their life jackets together",ans:"opb"},{question:"Coast Guard regulations require a shipboard Oil Pollution Emergency Plan to be reviewed ____________.",opa:"annually",opb:"once every two years",opc:"once every four years",opd:"once every five years",ans:"opa"},{question:"The effect of ocean currents is usually more evident on a rig being towed than on a tug navigating independently because the ____________.",opa:"speed of the tow is less",opb:"tow line catches the current",opc:"current causes yawing",opd:"current will offset the rig",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the proper direction of flow through a globe valve when the valve is installed to be in a normally open position?",opa:"Direction is unimportant",opb:"Depends on seat configuration",opc:"From below the seat",opd:"From above the seat",ans:"opc"},{question:"While being towed at a 19.5 foot draft, the DEEP DRILLER experiences single amplitude pitching of 7.5 degrees with an 8 second period. You should ____________.",opa:"continue towing operations and carefully monitor vessel motions",opb:"alter course into the wind to improve motion characteristics",opc:"ballast the rig to a 45 foot draft and check the vessel motion at the new draft",opd:"ballast the rig to a 60 foot draft and check vessel motion at the new draft",ans:"opa"},{question:"The color of the signal flares sent up by a submarine surfacing from periscope depth is ____________.",opa:"yellow",opb:"red",opc:"green",opd:"white",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are part of a team to overhaul a fire that was just extinguished in the crew lounge. Where is the nearest fire axe to break apart the furniture?",opa:"Midships, frame 123",opb:"Starboard side, frame 123",opc:"Port side, frame 132",opd:"Starboard side, frame 132",ans:"opd"},{question:"In small angle stability, the metacentric height ____________.",opa:"is found in the hydrostatic tables for a level vessel",opb:"multiplied by the displacement yields the righting moment",opc:"is always positive",opd:"is calculated by subtracting KG from KM",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Fire Control Plan must contain detailed information on which of the following systems?",opa:"Fixed fire suppression",opb:"Ship construction",opc:"Ventilation",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A damaged 'T-Boat' that is unable to meet the requirements of its Certificate of Inspection but is able to travel to a shipyard under its own power should ____________.",opa:"make the trip only after obtaining a 'Permit to Proceed to Another Port for Repair', Form CG-948",opb:"get underway as soon as possible",opc:"hire a tug and pilot instead",opd:"request an Expiration Certificate if the vessel displays a tendency to sink",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are underway in mid-ocean when you hear a distress message. The position of the sender is 150 miles away. No other vessel has acknowledged the distress. Your maximum speed is 5 knots and due to the seriousness of the distress, you cannot arrive on scene to provide effective assistance. What action should you take?",opa:"Do not acknowledge the distress message.",opb:"Send an urgency message about the distress.",opc:"Use the signal MAYDAY RELAY and transmit the distress message.",opd:"Transmit a message as though your vessel was in distress.",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the maximum amount of weight is stored in the pipe racks of the DEEP DRILLER, what is the weight per square foot?",opa:"250.0 pounds per square foot",opb:"312.5 pounds per square foot",opc:"350.0 pounds per square foot",opd:"400.0 pounds per square foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement about the pressure in a tank being inerted by an inert gas system is TRUE?",opa:"The maximum pressure permitted is 8 psi.",opb:"A positive pressure should be maintained at all times.",opc:"The pressure must remain within the limits of +5 psi to -1 psi.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the function of wearing rings found on some centrifugal pumps?",opa:"Absorb erosion of high velocity discharge stream",opb:"Seal pump shaft against entry of air",opc:"Isolate the outlet side from the inlet side",opd:"Dampen the turbulent discharge flow",ans:"opc"},{question:"The true mean draft of a MODU is the draft ____________.",opa:"midway between drafts forward and aft",opb:"at the center of flotation",opc:"at the load line",opd:"at the center of buoyancy",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). What are the new TM (transverse moments) if the entire contents of Salt Water Ballast Tanks 1P and 1S are discharged?",opa:"-3,436 ft.-tons",opb:"3,446 ft.-tons",opc:"3,594 ft.-tons",opd:"22,682 ft.-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"An offshore drilling unit is required to carry onboard an operations manual approved by the ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard",opb:"National Cargo Bureau",opc:"Minerals Management Service",opd:"builder",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which action should the GMDSS radio operator take in a distress situation when embarking in survival craft?",opa:"Switch on EPIRB and SART immediately and leave on.",opb:"Switch on EPIRB and SART manually prior to launching and remain aboard vessel in distress.",opc:"Notify RCC (Rescue Coordination Center) through VHF DSC with portable equipment.",opd:"Communicate via Inmarsat-C from the survival craft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"If, during helicopter refueling operations, fuel is spilled on clothing, the person should first ____________.",opa:"see the medic immediately",opb:"spray himself with foam or CO2",opc:"complete his task and then see the medic",opd:"remove the clothing and wash",ans:"opd"},{question:"What should be used to remove corrosion from the swivel on the female coupling of a fire hose?",opa:"Bearing grease and a wire brush",opb:"Talc and fine sandpaper",opc:"Fish oil and a soft brush",opd:"Fresh water, soap, and a stiff brush",ans:"opd"},{question:"The TCG of a vessel may be found by dividing the displacement of the vessel into the ____________.",opa:"transverse center of gravity of the vessel",opb:"sum of the vertical moments of the vessel",opc:"sum of the transverse moments of the vessel",opd:"transverse baseline of the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"The International Oil Pollution Prevention Certificate on a MODU is valid for a period of ____________.",opa:"one year from the date of issue",opb:"two years from the date of issue",opc:"three years from the date of issue",opd:"four years from the date of issue",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 4850 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 274.46 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 271.23 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 270.96 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 269.52 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 267.88 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Because there is a possibility of fuel oil being discharged overboard from a full fuel oil tank, it is decided to transfer 25 kips from tank #14 to tank #13. See COASTAL DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What would be the change in transverse free surface moments?",opa:"47.2 kips tank #7 to tank #6",opb:"23.6 kips tank #7 to tank #6",opc:"23.6 kips tank #6 to tank #7",opd:"47.2 kips tank #6 to tank #7",ans:"opc"},{question:"If you have to abandon ship, the EPIRB can be used to ____________.",opa:"hold the survival craft's head up into the seas",opb:"generate orange smoke",opc:"seal leaks in rubber rafts",opd:"send radio homing signals to searching aircraft",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a vessel of 9,000 tons displacement there are two slack deep tanks of palm oil (SG .86). Each tank is 40 feet long and 30 feet wide. What is the reduction in metacentric height due to free surface with the vessel in sea water (SG 1.025)?",opa:".27 ft.",opb:".48 ft.",opc:".57 ft.",opd:".74 ft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Assuming that the recommended hatch loading sequence is followed, how many long tons of iron ore may be loaded through hatches 2, 6, & 10, while using a single belt loader, to arrive at a desired mean keel draft of 27'-07'? (use the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN)",opa:"510 tons per hatch",opb:"530 tons per hatch",opc:"590 tons per hatch",opd:"610 tons per hatch",ans:"opb"},{question:"When experiencing heavy winds, you should reef sails to ____________.",opa:"bring the sails parallel to the wind",opb:"reduce sail area exposed to the wind",opc:"allow the sails to catch more wind",opd:"remove all tension on the main and jib sheets",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the minimum diameter allowed for bilge piping on small passenger vessels which are more than 65 feet in length?",opa:"1'",opb:"1-1/2'",opc:"2'",opd:"2-1/2'",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your sailing drafts are: FWD 14'-04', AFT 16'-02' and the GM is 3.0 feet. What will be the angle of list if #5 port double bottom (capacity 195 tons, VCG 2.6 feet, and 18.5 feet off the centerline) is filled with saltwater? (Use the data in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"4\xb0",opb:"8\xb0",opc:"13\xb0",opd:"16\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who must ensure that the emergency lighting and power systems on cargo vessels are operated at least weekly?",opa:"Master",opb:"Chief Engineer",opc:"Deck officer assigned",opd:"Engineering officer assigned",ans:"opa"},{question:"When hoisting personnel from a vessel, with the MODU cranes, the crane operator must assure that ____________.",opa:"the personnel carrier remains directly over the vessel",opb:"all personnel are inside the net type carrier",opc:"the personnel carrier remains directly over water",opd:"he does not swing the load until it is above the landing area",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are the operator of a 290 GRT uninspected towing vessel whose construction was contracted for after August 27, 2003. Which type of semi-portable fire-extinguishing system is required on your vessel? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"B-V",opb:"B-IV",opc:"B-III",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about the free surface effect is TRUE?",opa:"It has the same affect on initial stability whether the tank is 75% full or 25% full.",opb:"The free surface effect usually increases at angles of heel above 25\xb0.",opc:"The effect increases if the tank is off the centerline.",opd:"The effect can be reduced by shifting weights vertically.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is meant by the term 'radio silence'?",opa:"Stations not directly involved with the on-going Distress communications may not transmit on the distress frequency or channel",opb:"Stations remaining off the air to safeguard proprietary information",opc:"Two three-minute silent periods, at 15 and 45 minutes after the hour, that provide a transmitting 'window' for distressed vessels to transmit distress alerts using J3E",opd:"Communications on a distress frequency or channel is banned for 24 hours following the cessation of the distress traffic",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are having a Coast Guard inspection. All carbon dioxide fire extinguishers aboard will be ____________.",opa:"weighed",opb:"discharged and recharged",opc:"checked for pressure loss",opd:"sent ashore to an approved service facility",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is experiencing a single amplitude roll angle of 2 degrees and a roll period of 10 seconds. What is the maximum recommended water depth for elevating?",opa:"50 feet",opb:"100 feet",opc:"150 feet",opd:"200 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"For an OSV not on an international voyage, an approved substitute for an impulse projected type line throwing appliance is a ____________.",opa:"spring-loaded line thrower",opb:"hand thrown buoyant line",opc:"shoulder type line throwing gun",opd:"heaving line",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers damage to the starboard aft column below the waterline. Pumping from tanks 8S and 9S is not sufficient to prevent increasing starboard list and stern down trim. You should consider counter flooding in tank ____________.",opa:"1S",opb:"1P",opc:"C2BP",opd:"10P",ans:"opb"},{question:"When using a high-velocity fog stream in a passageway, the possibility of a blow back must be guarded against. Blow back is most likely to occur when ____________.",opa:"pressure builds up in the nozzle which causes a surge of water",opb:"the only opening in a passageway is the one from which the nozzle is being advanced",opc:"pressure in the fire hose drops below 100 psi",opd:"a bulkhead collapses due to heat and pressure",ans:"opb"},{question:"The heading of a vessel is indicated by what part of the compass?",opa:"Card",opb:"Needle",opc:"Lubber's line",opd:"Gimbals",ans:"opc"},{question:"Assuming that the recommended hatch loading sequence is followed, how many long tons of iron ore may be loaded through hatches 8 & 12 while using a single belt loader to arrive at a desired mean keel draft of 28'-03'? (use the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN).",opa:"460 tons per hatch",opb:"520 tons per hatch",opc:"690 tons per hatch",opd:"730 tons per hatch",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is equipped with a fixed CO2 system and a fire main system. In the event of an electrical fire in the engine room what is the correct procedure for fighting the fire?",opa:"Use the CO2 system and evacuate the engine room.",opb:"Use the fire main system and evacuate the engine room.",opc:"Evacuate the engine room and use the CO2 system.",opd:"Evacuate the engine room and use the fire main system.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's has a beam of 40 feet, and you observe a still water rolling period of 20 seconds. What is the vessel's metacentric height?",opa:"0.3 ft.",opb:"0.5 ft.",opc:"0.8 ft.",opd:"1.1 ft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the contents of #6 and #7 drill water tanks are discharged, what would be the new height of the transverse metacenter?",opa:"134.95 feet",opb:"135.91 feet",opc:"136.38 feet",opd:"136.89 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Whenever a 'T-Boat' is hauled out for repairs or alterations affecting its safety you must ____________.",opa:"provide a complete set of plans to the Commandant for review",opb:"notify the cognizant OCMI",opc:"schedule a full safety equipment inspection",opd:"Both B and C",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is level at a draft of 58 feet when there are no environmental forces. What is the value of TCG?",opa:"0.00 on the centerline",opb:"2.23 feet forward of amidships",opc:"2.26 feet forward of amidships",opd:"2.31 feet forward of amidships",ans:"opa"},{question:"For a cargo vessel of 1,000 GT or over, on an international voyage, the required minimum pitot tube pressure from the two highest outlets when two fire pumps are operating simultaneously is required to be which of the following?",opa:"35 psi",opb:"50 psi",opc:"70 psi",opd:"100 psi",ans:"opb"},{question:"The number of fire extinguishers required on an uninspected 'motor vessel' is based on the vessel's ____________.",opa:"length",opb:"gross tonnage",opc:"draft",opd:"crew list",ans:"opb"},{question:"Fire alarm system thermostats are actuated by ____________.",opa:"smoke sensors",opb:"the difference in thermal expansion of two dissimilar metals",opc:"pressure loss due to air being heated",opd:"an electric eye which actuates when smoke interferes with the beam",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are loading in the winter in Albany, N.Y., for a voyage to a port governed by the tropical load line mark. Which of the following statements is TRUE? (Hydrometer reading in Albany is 1.000)",opa:"You may not exceed the winter load line mark when you finish loading except for the burnout to sea.",opb:"The freshwater allowance and burnout to sea may be subtracted from the required freeboard in Albany.",opc:"You may calculate the burnout necessary to reach the tropical zone and load extra cargo to compensate.",opd:"You may load to the winter mark less the fresh water allowance if you will be at the tropical mark upon arrival in the tropical zone.",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a MODU, a fire drill shall be conducted once every ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"month",opc:"crew change",opd:"other week",ans:"opa"},{question:"Open ullage holes in tanks which are not gas-free must be protected by ____________.",opa:"PV valves",opb:"warning signs",opc:"flame screens",opd:"stop-check valves",ans:"opc"},{question:"Requirements for H2S preparation and equipment usage aboard MODU's in U.S. offshore waters are administered by the ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"U.S. Corps of Engineers",opc:"Minerals Management Service",opd:"American National Standards Institute",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have 300 tons of below deck tonnage including liquid mud. Your existing deck cargo is 180 tons with a VCG above the deck of 1.9 feet. What is the maximum additional cargo tonnage you are permitted to load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"108 tons",opb:"124 tons",opc:"162 tons",opd:"342 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the meaning of the signal 'G1325'?",opa:"The GMT is 1325.",opb:"The latitude is 13\xb025'.",opc:"The zone time is 1325.",opd:"The longitude is 13\xb025'.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER arrived in port with drafts of: FWD 18'-10', AFT 18'-06'. Cargo was loaded and discharged as indicated. Use sheet 2 in the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts.",opa:"FWD 18'-00', AFT19'-06'",opb:"FWD 18'-02', AFT19'-04'",opc:"FWD 18'-04', AFT19'-02'",opd:"FWD 18'-06', AFT19'-00'",ans:"opc"},{question:"Pollution of the waterways may result from the discharge of ____________.",opa:"sewage",opb:"the galley trash can",opc:"an oily mixture of one part per million",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Starboard ballast pump #1 on the DEEP DRILLER has failed. To deballast from tank C2SA using starboard ballast pump #2, it is necessary to open the manual valve and which motor driven valves?",opa:"15, 34, 35, 36, 46, 48",opb:"16, 27, 32, 35, 36, 48",opc:"15, 33, 43, 48",opd:"14, 34, 35, 36, 46, 48",ans:"opa"},{question:"What color are obstruction lights on mobile offshore drilling units that are located on the waters of the U.S. Outer Continental Shelf seaward of the line of demarcation?",opa:"White",opb:"Red",opc:"Yellow",opd:"Blue",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a MODU crane, the load chart relates the allowable load to the combination of boom length and ____________.",opa:"boom angle",opb:"boom strength",opc:"load radius",opd:"cable strength",ans:"opc"},{question:"If your vessel is aground at the bow, it would be preferable that any weight removals be made from the ____________.",opa:"bow",opb:"mid-section",opc:"stern",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The last 1.0 meter (3.3 feet) of vapor piping before the vessel vapor connection must be painted ____________.",opa:"red/yellow/red",opb:"yellow/red/yellow",opc:"international orange",opd:"hi-visibility yellow",ans:"opa"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 020\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"coming about",opb:"close hauled on the port tack",opc:"running before the wind",opd:"on a broad reach on the starboard tack",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are hoisting a heavy lift with the jumbo boom. Your vessel displaces 5230 T. The 35-ton weight is on the pier and its center is 60' to starboard of the centerline. The head of the boom is 105' above the base line and the center of gravity of the lift when stowed on deck will be 42' above the base line. As the jumbo boom takes the strain the ship lists to 5\xb0. What is the GM with the cargo stowed?",opa:"4.11",opb:"4.54",opc:"4.98",opd:"5.13",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 4.81 ft.",opb:"Available GM 4.69 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.60 ft.",opd:"Available GM 4.28 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The AMVER system for vessels in the Gulf of Mexico is administered by the ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"Minerals Management Service",opc:"Department of Energy",opd:"Corps of Engineers",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #2 (Ballast to Survival), suffers major damage which results in flooding in tank 10S. Your best countermeasure is to ____________.",opa:"pump from 10S",opb:"pump from C3S",opc:"pump from 9S",opd:"counter flood in 1P",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which vessel is required to carry a Category I, 406 MHz EPIRB installed to automatically float free and activate? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"A vessel operating within 3 miles from the coastline in the Gulf of Mexico.",opb:"A vessel operating on the ocean within 5 miles from the coastline.",opc:"A vessel operating beyond 3 miles from the coastline of the Great Lakes.",opd:"A vessel operating exclusively on inland waters.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What must the Master or person in charge of a MODU enter in the logbook after conducting an abandonment drill?",opa:"The sea condition at the time of the drill",opb:"Which survival craft was used",opc:"The names of all crew members participating in the drill",opd:"The name of the lifeboatman in charge of each boat",ans:"opb"},{question:"How does combustion air enter the cylinder of a two-cycle diesel engine?",opa:"Cylinder head valves",opb:"Ports",opc:"Turbo chargers",opd:"Bleeder valves",ans:"opb"},{question:"The carbon dioxide cylinders of a fixed fire extinguishing system may be located inside the protected space, if the quantity of CO2 required to protect that space is not more than ____________.",opa:"300 pounds",opb:"400 pounds",opc:"500 pounds",opd:"600 pounds",ans:"opa"},{question:"Because there is a possibility of fuel oil being discharged overboard from a full fuel oil tank, it is decided to transfer 25 kips from tank #14 to tank #13. See COASTAL DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What would be the change in transverse free surface moments?",opa:"1492 ft.-kips",opb:"674 ft.-kips",opc:"404 ft.-kips",opd:"270 ft.-kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the required minimum length of the painter for a lifeboat in ocean service?",opa:"60 fathoms",opb:"the distance from the main deck to the light waterline",opc:"twice the distance from the main deck to the light waterline or 50 feet whichever is greater",opd:"two times the distance from the boat deck to the light waterline or 50 feet whichever is greater",ans:"opd"},{question:"The helicopter deck on an offshore drilling unit is required to be fitted with perimeter lights in alternating colors of ____________.",opa:"red and white",opb:"yellow and white",opc:"yellow and blue",opd:"yellow and red",ans:"opc"},{question:"A fire in a pile of linen is a class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Lethal Concentration of H2S that will cause death with short-term exposure is a minimum of ____________.",opa:"100 ppm",opb:"200 ppm",opc:"400 ppm",opd:"700 ppm",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which action must be taken when an individual cargo tank is closed off from the inert gas system by the tank isolation valve?",opa:"The tank must be gas freed.",opb:"The tank must be ballasted.",opc:"The tank must be vented to the atmosphere.",opd:"The bypass valve must also be closed.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers damage to the port center column below the waterline. Pumping from tanks 2P and 9P is not sufficient to prevent increasing port list. You should consider counter flooding in tank ____________.",opa:"2S",opb:"9S",opc:"C2BS",opd:"C2BP",ans:"opc"},{question:"The minimum concentration of a vapor in air which can form an explosive mixture is called the ____________.",opa:"auto-ignition point",opb:"flash point",opc:"lower explosive limit (LEL)",opd:"threshold limit value (TLV)",ans:"opc"},{question:"Initial stability refers to stability ____________.",opa:"at small angles of inclination",opb:"when loaded with minimum deck load",opc:"when at transit draft",opd:"when GZ is zero",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to regulations, cargo pump rooms, on the tank vessels handling grades A, B, or C liquid cargo, shall be equipped with power ventilation of the exhaust type having capacity sufficient to effect a complete change of air in not more than ____________.",opa:"1 minute",opb:"2 minutes",opc:"3 minutes",opd:"5 minutes",ans:"opc"},{question:"The center of flotation for the COASTAL DRILLER is located at the geometric center of the ____________.",opa:"underwater volume",opb:"above water volume",opc:"amidships section",opd:"waterplane area",ans:"opd"},{question:"During the required periodic abandon ship drill aboard a MODU, each person not assigned duties in the muster list is ____________.",opa:"instructed in the use of portable fire extinguishers",opb:"shown a video demonstrating lifeboat launching",opc:"instructed in the use of life jackets",opd:"not required to attend the boat drill",ans:"opc"},{question:"The danger associated with using carbon dioxide in an enclosed space is ____________.",opa:"frostbite",opb:"skin burns",opc:"asphyxiation",opd:"an explosive reaction",ans:"opc"},{question:"Installing tandem anchors on the same mooring line is referred to as ____________.",opa:"doubling",opb:"pretensioning",opc:"piggybacking",opd:"paralleling",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 40,301 foot-long tons, TM = 3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons. What is the LCG?",opa:"0.00 feet",opb:"1.69 feet",opc:"2.22 feet",opd:"3.91 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"It is the responsibility of the Master or person in charge of a MODU to ensure that ____________.",opa:"the Muster List ('Station Bill') is posted in each compartment",opb:"temporary personnel and visitors are advised of emergency stations",opc:"names of crew members are listed on the Muster List ('Station Bill')",opd:"no changes are made to the Muster List ('Station Bill')",ans:"opb"},{question:"A small passenger vessel's Official Number must be marked ____________.",opa:"in block type Arabic numerals not less than 1-1/2 inch high",opb:"or mounted so its alteration, removal, or replacement would be obvious",opc:"on some clearly visible exterior structural hull part",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are bound from port A governed by the summer load line mark to port B also governed by the summer mark. The great circle track will take you into a zone governed by the winter mark. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You cannot load beyond the summer mark at port A and must be at the winter mark upon arrival at port B.",opb:"You can only load to the winter mark plus any fresh water allowance and burnout to sea at port A.",opc:"You must be at the winter mark when you enter the winter zone and cannot exceed the summer mark upon departing port A.",opd:"You can load so that upon arrival at the pier at port B your freeboard is equal to the summer mark less any fresh water allowance.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Proper GMDSS watchkeeping includes ____________.",opa:"monitoring all required frequencies in the proper mode",opb:"reading all displays and/or printouts after silencing an alarm",opc:"notifying the Master of any distress alerts",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"To maintain a high state of readiness against the possibility of damage and subsequent flooding while aboard the DEEP DRILLER, you should ____________.",opa:"post a watch in the pump room",opb:"keep tanks no more than half filled",opc:"cap sounding tubes except when in use",opd:"keep bilge pumps operating continuously",ans:"opc"},{question:"Fuel oil tank vents are fitted with a screen which will stop ____________.",opa:"oil from flowing out of the tank vent",opb:"air from entering the tank vent",opc:"vapors from leaving the tank vent",opd:"flames on deck from entering the tank vent",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the ullage in P-Tank #4 of the DEEP DRILLER if the weight is 75.24 long tons?",opa:"4.0 feet",opb:"5.0 feet",opc:"10.2 feet",opd:"16.0 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you receive the signal over radiotelephone of 'Romeo Papa Tango' while using the International Code of Signals, you should ____________.",opa:"report to the caller",opb:"repeat your last transmission",opc:"continue since he received your last transmission",opd:"end the transmission",ans:"opb"},{question:"Controls for a fixed carbon dioxide system shall be mounted ____________. (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"directly outside the space protected by the system",opb:"as near the gas cylinders as possible",opc:"in the pilothouse",opd:"on the main deck near the bow",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 25.0 feet and the drafts are: FWD 15'-04', AFT 15'-08'.",opa:"12\xb0",opb:"17\xb0",opc:"20\xb0",opd:"23\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement concerning GMDSS Radio Operator requirements is FALSE?",opa:"Each compulsory vessel must carry at least two licensed GMDSS Radio Operators at all times while at sea.",opb:"Each compulsory vessel must carry at least two licensed GMDSS Radio Operators at all times while at sea and may elect to carry a GMDSS Radio Maintainer as well.",opc:"Communications involving safety of life at sea do not have to be logged as long as the compulsory vessel was not involved in such communications.",opd:"While at sea, adjustments to, and the maintaining of, GMDSS equipment may be performed by the GMDSS Radio Operator as long as the work is supervised by an onboard licensed GMDSS Radio Maintainer.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 180\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"close hauled on the starboard tack",opb:"close hauled on the port tack",opc:"on a broad reach on a port tack",opd:"running before the wind",ans:"opd"},{question:"The full period of motion of the DEEP DRILLER while tripping is 7 seconds and the maximum pitch angle as seen on the inclinometers is 4\xb0. From the standpoint of critical motion, the motion is ____________.",opa:"unsatisfactory, place setback in the pipe racks",opb:"satisfactory, continue tripping",opc:"unsatisfactory, deballast to survival draft",opd:"satisfactory, but prepare to hang off",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to regulations, cargo pumps in tank vessels carrying grade A, B, C, or D liquid cargo, shall be isolated from sources of vapor ignition by ____________. (vessel constructed 1970)",opa:"cofferdams",opb:"general cargo spaces",opc:"passageways or living quarters",opd:"gastight bulkheads",ans:"opd"},{question:"The life jackets on all vessels shall be ____________.",opa:"inspected weekly",opb:"worn at all times",opc:"readily available",opd:"tested yearly",ans:"opc"},{question:"A branch line valve of a fire extinguishing system on a MODU must be marked with the ____________.",opa:"maximum pressure allowed at that branch",opb:"name of the space or spaces which it serves",opc:"date of the last maintenance inspection",opd:"pressure needed to maintain an effective stream at that point",ans:"opb"},{question:"In order to prevent galvanic corrosion, an aluminum boat must be insulated from the davits and gripes. Which of the following is acceptable as an insulator?",opa:"Hard rubber",opb:"Canvas",opc:"Leather",opd:"Sponge rubber",ans:"opa"},{question:"A CO2 portable extinguisher is annually checked by ____________.",opa:"reading the gage pressure",opb:"weighing the extinguisher",opc:"discharging a small amount of CO2",opd:"seeing if the seal has been broken",ans:"opb"},{question:"Offshore drilling units must have at least two ring buoys with water lights that, when released from the mounting rack, activate a ____________.",opa:"smoke signal",opb:"steam whistle",opc:"battery powered horn",opd:"radio signal",ans:"opa"},{question:"A cargo information card does NOT contain ____________.",opa:"instructions for the safe handling of the cargo",opb:"appearance and odor characteristics of the cargo",opc:"precautions to be observed in case of a spill or leak",opd:"duties of the person in charge during the transfer of cargo",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel measures 119 feet long by 17 feet in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 5'-05' is 6 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"1.14 feet",opb:"1.36 feet",opc:"1.55 feet",opd:"1.96 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"When transferring personnel with a MODU crane, the weight of the loaded personnel carrier must not exceed ____________.",opa:"1/2 of the static rated load at the lift radius",opb:"1/3 of the static rated load at the lift radius",opc:"1/2 of the breaking strength of the hoist rope times the parts of line used",opd:"1/3 of the breaking strength of the hoist rope times the parts of line used",ans:"opb"},{question:"Spontaneous combustion is caused by ____________.",opa:"an outside heat source heating a substance until it ignites",opb:"conduction of heat through a wall of material to the substance",opc:"chemical action within a substance",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol is NOT part of a fixed sprinkler system?",opa:"37",opb:"38",opc:"39",opd:"40",ans:"opa"},{question:"The blowers of an inert gas generation system aboard a tanker, will be automatically secured if ____________.",opa:"normal water supply at the water seal is lost",opb:"the temperature of the inert gas being delivered to the cargo tanks is more than 150\xb0F",opc:"the cooling water supply to the scrubbers is lost",opd:"all of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A yellow signal, floating in the air from a parachute, about 300 feet above the water, indicates that a submarine ____________.",opa:"will be coming to periscope depth",opb:"will be coming to the surface",opc:"is on the bottom in distress",opd:"is in distress and will try to surface",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 2.8 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.2 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.5 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #2 (Ballasting to Survival). What is the metacentric height corrected for transverse free surface effects if 100.76 long tons of ballast are added to Ballast Tank #8S to replace the discharge of all bulk materials?",opa:"10.42 feet",opb:"10.87 feet",opc:"11.50 feet",opd:"12.13 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"A documented vessel operating over 50 miles offshore must carry an inflatable liferaft with a ____________.",opa:"SOLAS A pack",opb:"SOLAS B pack",opc:"coastal pack",opd:"small vessel pack",ans:"opa"},{question:"Transverse stability calculations require the use of ____________.",opa:"hog or sag calculations or tables",opb:"hydrostatic curves",opc:"general arrangement plans",opd:"cross-sectional views of the vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 60 feet, has VM of 942,120 ft.-tons, and FSML of 36,235 ft.-tons. What is the KGL?",opa:"52.0 feet",opb:"53.0 feet",opc:"54.0 feet",opd:"55.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a lifeboat is stowed 40 feet above the light water draft and 200 feet from the bow, how long must the sea painter be?",opa:"80 feet",opb:"160 feet",opc:"Sufficiently long enough to reach the water when the vessel has an adverse list of 15\xb0",opd:"One third the length from the bow to where the lifeboat is stowed",ans:"opa"},{question:"Limit switches ____________.",opa:"control the descent rate of a lifeboat",opb:"control the ascent rate of a lifeboat",opc:"cut off power to the winch when the lifeboat nears the final stowed position",opd:"cut off power to the winch when the lifeboat reaches the davit bumpers",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a semisubmersible drilling unit, increasing riser tension reduces ____________.",opa:"list",opb:"KM",opc:"KG",opd:"GM",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, piperylene possesses which characteristic?",opa:"Specific Gravity of 0.86",opb:"A boiling point of 43\xb0F",opc:"A Reid vapor pressure of 14 psia",opd:"Insoluble in water",ans:"opd"},{question:"Aluminum lifeboats are subject to damage by electrolytic corrosion (the aluminum being eaten away). In working around boats of aluminum you must be very careful ____________.",opa:"to keep the boats covered at all times",opb:"not to leave steel or iron tools lying in or near these boats",opc:"to keep an electric charge on the hull at all times",opd:"to rinse these boats regularly with salt water",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the operating principal of a flash type evaporator?",opa:"Sea water is heated to boiling temperature under a vacuum.",opb:"Sea water is passed over heated plates in a thin film.",opc:"Heated sea water is injected into a vacuum chamber.",opd:"Sea water is forced through a heated eductor.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using a sea anchor with the survival craft will ____________.",opa:"reduce your drift rate",opb:"keep the survival craft from turning over",opc:"aid in recovering the survival craft",opd:"increase your visibility",ans:"opa"},{question:"Chemical burns are caused by the skin coming in contact with ____________.",opa:"acids or alkalies",opb:"diesel oil",opc:"acids, but not alkalies",opd:"alkalies, but not acids",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are fueling your vessel when you notice oil in the water around your vessel. You should immediately stop fueling and ____________.",opa:"begin cleanup operations",opb:"notify the U. S. Coast Guard",opc:"leave the area",opd:"notify the Corps of Engineers",ans:"opb"},{question:"Signals between an icebreaker and an assisted vessel may NOT be given by ____________.",opa:"whistle",opb:"flag hoist",opc:"radiotelephone",opd:"radiotelegraph",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 22'-04', AFT 23'-06'; and the KG is 22.4 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 19\xb0 inclination if the center of gravity is 1.3 feet off center.",opa:"0.2 foot",opb:"0.8 foot",opc:"1.4 feet",opd:"2.2 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The sprinkler system of an enclosed lifeboat is used to ____________.",opa:"cool the craft in a fire",opb:"cool the engine",opc:"spray oil on the sea to calm it",opd:"spray personnel during a fire",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which group should be used to send the signal 'Latitude 73\xb025'North'?",opa:"G17325N",opb:"L7325N",opc:"LA7325N",opd:"N7325",ans:"opb"},{question:"The sea painter of a lifeboat should be secured ____________.",opa:"to the bow of the lifeboat",opb:"to an inboard thwart in the forward one-third of the boat",opc:"as close as possible to amidships of the lifeboat",opd:"anywhere along the inboard side of the boat",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tanker loads at a terminal within the tropical zone. She will enter the summer zone six days after departing the loading port. She will burn off 45 tons/day and daily water consumption is 8 tons. How many tons may she load over that allowed by her summer load line?",opa:"270",opb:"278",opc:"291",opd:"318",ans:"opd"},{question:"In reference to accidental oil pollution, the most critical time during bunkering is when ____________.",opa:"you first start to receive fuel",opb:"hoses are being blown down",opc:"final topping off is occurring",opd:"hoses are being disconnected",ans:"opc"},{question:"Fighting a rig fire in a watertight compartment with hoses could reduce the stability of the rig by ____________.",opa:"progressive downflooding",opb:"reducing the level of drill water from the storage tanks",opc:"causing a list due to the water in the compartment",opd:"reducing the KG to minimum allowable",ans:"opc"},{question:"The prohibition against exceeding the load line draft may be considered temporarily not applicable when ____________.",opa:"column-stabilized units are operating in water depths over 600 feet",opb:"column-stabilized units are operating in waters outside U.S. jurisdiction",opc:"bottom supported units are being raised or lowered to the sea bed",opd:"bottom supported units are being towed on a move of less than 12 hours",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Severe motion makes it necessary to ballast down to survival draft. It is decided to check stability at the intermediate draft of 32 feet. If the added ballast has an average VCG of 9.03 feet, and the sum of free surface moments is 56,244 foot-tons, what is the new GML?",opa:"6.23 feet",opb:"5.11 feet",opc:"4.86 feet",opd:"4.06 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Stability is determined by the relationship of the center of gravity and the ____________.",opa:"water depth",opb:"keel",opc:"center of flotation",opd:"center of buoyancy",ans:"opd"},{question:"What do regulations allow to be marked with EITHER the name of the fishing vessel OR the name of the person to whom it is assigned?",opa:"Immersion suit",opb:"Buoyant apparatus",opc:"Ring buoy",opd:"Life float",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are preparing to contain an oil spill. You must first receive approval from the Federal On-Scene Coordinator (OSC) prior to ____________.",opa:"employing a boom",opb:"using suction equipment",opc:"applying chemical agents",opd:"deploying skimmers",ans:"opc"},{question:"Signaling devices required on inflatable liferafts include a(n) ____________.",opa:"Very pistol",opb:"orange smoke signal",opc:"air horn",opd:"lantern",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a ship is abandoned and there are several liferafts in the water, one of the FIRST things to be done is ____________.",opa:"separate the rafts as much as possible to increase chances of detection",opb:"transfer all supplies to one raft",opc:"transfer all the injured to one raft",opd:"secure the rafts together to keep them from drifting apart",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the stability term for the distance from the center of gravity (G) to the Metacenter (M), when small-angle stability applies?",opa:"metacentric height",opb:"metacentric radius",opc:"height of the metacenter",opd:"righting arm",ans:"opa"},{question:"A cargo hose is marked with the ____________.",opa:"maximum working pressure",opb:"bursting pressure",opc:"safety relief valve setting",opd:"maximum temperature",ans:"opa"},{question:"If the steersman of your lifeboat gives the command 'Way enough', you should ____________.",opa:"complete the stroke, hold your oar out from the boat and level with the water",opb:"dip the blade of your oar into the water and leave it there",opc:"lift your oar to a vertical position",opd:"complete the stroke, raise your oar slightly, swing it forward, and place it in the boat",ans:"opd"},{question:"Before issuing an initial Certificate of Inspection, the construction arrangement and equipment of a vessel must be acceptable to the ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping Surveyor",opb:"U.S. Salvage Marine Surveyor",opc:"Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection",opd:"U.S. Customs Collector",ans:"opc"},{question:"If your vessel is required to have a fire ax onboard, where should it be located? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"In or adjacent to the primary operating station",opb:"In below-decks passenger accommodations",opc:"Just outside the engine room access",opd:"In the galley near the stove",ans:"opa"},{question:"A cargo of 60 tons is to be loaded on deck 20 feet from the ship's centerline. The vessel's displacement including the 60 ton cargo will be 6,000 tons and the GM two feet. The list of the vessel after loading this cargo will be ____________.",opa:"5.4\xb0",opb:"5.72\xb0",opc:"6.12\xb0",opd:"6.4\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 5480 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 274.46 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 271.79 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 272.87 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 274.04 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 275.13 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Assuming that the recommended hatch loading sequence is followed, how many long tons of iron ore may be loaded through hatch No. 20 while using a single belt loader to arrive at a desired mean keel draft of 29'-06'? (Use the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN.)",opa:"1550 tons",opb:"2920 tons",opc:"3010 tons",opd:"3515 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"In the towing vessel fire protection regulations, all of the following are fire detection requirements, EXCEPT that ____________.",opa:"the control panel must have labels for all switches and indicator lights",opb:"the detection system must be powered from two sources, with the switchover being either manual or automatic",opc:"there must be a circuit-fault detector test-switch in the control panel",opd:"none of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Use the material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the KG is 25.8 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 15'-02', AFT 15'-10'; at what angle will the vessel lose positive stability?",opa:"73\xb0",opb:"79\xb0",opc:"87\xb0",opd:"98\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"Where will you find the requirements for the lights that must be displayed on a mobile offshore drilling unit that is being towed?",opa:"Notice to Mariners",opb:"COLREGS",opc:"Coast Pilot",opd:"Light List",ans:"opb"},{question:"In a message sent by flashing light, what group of letters will direct the receiver of a message to repeat the transmission back to the sender?",opa:"REPEAT",opb:"RPT",opc:"RPB",opd:"UD AA",ans:"opb"},{question:"A victim has suffered a second-degree burn to a small area of the lower arm. What is the proper treatment for this injury?",opa:"Immerse the arm in cold water for 1 to 2 hours, apply burn ointment, and bandage.",opb:"Open any blisters with a sterile needle, apply burn ointment and bandage.",opc:"Apply burn ointment, remove any foreign material and insure that nothing is in contact with the burn.",opd:"Immerse the arm in cold water for 1 to 2 hours, open any blister and apply burn ointment.",ans:"opa"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, each EPIRB or SART must be tested once every ____________.",opa:"day",opb:"week",opc:"month",opd:"year",ans:"opc"},{question:"Most medium and slow speed diesels are started by what medium?",opa:"Electric starting motors",opb:"Hydraulics",opc:"Compressed air",opd:"Ether",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a rigid liferaft (SOLAS B pack) which is equipped with all of the required equipment you may NOT find a ____________.",opa:"bailer",opb:"sponge",opc:"whistle",opd:"fishing kit",ans:"opd"},{question:"A device commonly used to secure the pendant wire when it is initially passed to an anchor handling vessel is ____________.",opa:"pelican hook",opb:"connecting link",opc:"shackle",opd:"retaining hook",ans:"opa"},{question:"Before entering the chain locker, you should ____________.",opa:"have someone standing by",opb:"make sure there is sufficient air within the locker",opc:"de-energize the windlass",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in ocean transit at a draft of 10 feet 6 inches with winds less than 70 knots, has a KGT of 50.6 feet and a KGL of 51.4 feet. The margin on the maximum allowable KG is ____________.",opa:"13.6 feet",opb:"14.4 feet",opc:"40.0 feet",opd:"65.0 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The maximum angular tolerance for a bent link of an anchor chain is ____________.",opa:"1 degree",opb:"3 degrees",opc:"5 degrees",opd:"7 degrees",ans:"opb"},{question:"Normally, the percentage of oxygen in air is ____________.",opa:"0.16",opb:"0.18",opc:"0.21",opd:"0.25",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have 640 tons of below deck tonnage. There is no liquid mud aboard. If you have 160 tons of cargo above deck with a VCG above the deck of 3.4 feet, what is the maximum allowed VCG of the remainder of the deck cargo that is permitted? (see illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson)",opa:"1.24 feet",opb:"1.65 feet",opc:"1.98 feet",opd:"2.46 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Except as provided by approved special examinations, each offshore drilling unit must be dry-docked at least once during every ____________.",opa:"12 month period",opb:"18 month period",opc:"24 month period",opd:"36 month period",ans:"opc"},{question:"The liquid mud tanks on your vessel measure 20'L by 18'B by 7'D. The vessel's displacement is 866 T and the specific gravity of the mud is 1.8. What is the reduction in GM due to 2 of these tanks being slack?",opa:"0.24 foot",opb:"0.56 foot",opc:"0.95 foot",opd:"1.12 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"An unstable upright equilibrium position on a vessel means that the metacenter is ____________.",opa:"lower than the center of gravity",opb:"at the same height as the center of gravity",opc:"higher than the baseline",opd:"on the longitudinal centerline",ans:"opa"},{question:"Deballasting a double bottom has what affect on KG?",opa:"KG is increased.",opb:"KG is decreased.",opc:"KG is not affected.",opd:"KG increases at light drafts and decreases at deep drafts.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Where are remote readouts for oxygen concentration, pressure, and temperature of an inert gas system required to be located?",opa:"Bridge and engine control consoles",opb:"Bridge and tank(s) being inerted",opc:"Main deck and engine control consoles",opd:"Cargo control and engine control consoles",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 21'-04', AFT 26'-04'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"0.54 ft.",opb:"0.62 ft.",opc:"0.80 ft.",opd:"0.85 ft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Sign(s) of respiratory arrest requiring artificial respiration is(are) ____________.",opa:"vomiting",opb:"blue color and lack of breathing",opc:"irregular breathing",opd:"unconsciousness",ans:"opb"},{question:"While on an ocean tow, the COASTAL DRILLER is threatened with the approach of a severe storm. The legs should be lowered so that the TOC (tip-of-can) is lowered from 12.38 feet to ____________.",opa:"48.12 feet",opb:"60.50 feet",opc:"68.50 feet",opd:"78.50 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Signaling devices which are required on inflatable liferafts include ____________.",opa:"a rocket shoulder rifle",opb:"an oil lantern",opc:"red flares",opd:"an air horn",ans:"opc"},{question:"In special cases, the Commandant of the Coast Guard may permit cargo piping to pass through machinery spaces, provided that the only cargo carried through such piping is(are) ____________.",opa:"grades A or B",opb:"grades D or E",opc:"grade E",opd:"LFG",ans:"opc"},{question:"Between the side frames on a MODU, support for the deck beams is provided by ____________.",opa:"stanchions",opb:"brackets",opc:"web frames",opd:"deck stringers",ans:"opa"},{question:"When pilot cylinder pressure is used as a means to release the CO2 from a fixed fire extinguishing system consisting of four storage cylinders, the number of pilot cylinders shall be at least ____________.",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER arrived in port with drafts of: FWD 18'-06', AFT 20'-10'. Cargo was loaded and discharged as indicated. Use sheet 2 in the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts.",opa:"FWD 18'-11', AFT20'-02'",opb:"FWD 19'-01', AFT20'-00'",opc:"FWD 19'-03', AFT19'-10'",opd:"FWD 19'-05', AFT19'-08'",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each inert gas system gas main must have an automatic shut down valve at the outlet of the gas production plant. This valve must close automatically upon ____________.",opa:"cargo pump failure",opb:"blower failure",opc:"deck seal low water level",opd:"low inert gas temperature",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the female section of a tool joint called?",opa:"Stem",opb:"Pin",opc:"Box",opd:"Stand",ans:"opc"},{question:"On the vessel\u2019s Fire Control Plan, all parts of the fire main are listed EXCEPT?",opa:"Fire pump(s) location",opb:"Fire pump capacity",opc:"Diameter of fire main",opd:"Fire station locations",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 3.51 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.60 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.98 ft.",opd:"Available GM 4.28 ft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The connected joints of pipe, usually made of three joints of pipe approximately 90 feet long, racked in the derrick when making a trip are called a ____________.",opa:"string",opb:"stand",opc:"joint",opd:"standpipe",ans:"opb"},{question:"The load chart of a MODU crane enables the operator to combine the load radius with boom length to determine the ____________.",opa:"maximum counter weight required",opb:"minimum horsepower required",opc:"hoist rope strength",opd:"allowable load",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel measures 114 feet long by 16 feet in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 5'-06' is 6 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"1.38 feet",opb:"1.53 feet",opc:"1.76 feet",opd:"1.98 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 5'-08', AFT 6'-04'. From past experience, you know that the vessel will increase her draft 1 inch for every 7 tons loaded. There is rig water onboard and 10 tons of deck cargo. How many more tons of cargo can be loaded and still maintain the same trim?",opa:"14.8 tons",opb:"18.0 tons",opc:"25.0 tons",opd:"32.0 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers damage to the starboard center column below the waterline. Pumping from tanks 2S and 9S is not sufficient to prevent increasing starboard list. You should consider counter flooding in tank ____________.",opa:"2P",opb:"9P",opc:"C2BS",opd:"C2BP",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, while in transit, expects the winds to increase to 75 knots. In order to meet the stability and leg strength requirements, the tip-of-can (TOC) position should be at ____________.",opa:"0.00 feet (flush with bottom of hull)",opb:"1.20 feet",opc:"12.38 feet",opd:"60.50 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What entry would NOT be shown on the V line of an AMVER report?",opa:"MD",opb:"MT",opc:"PA",opd:"NURSE",ans:"opb"},{question:"Each life preserver must be readily accessible to the person for whom it is intended while he or she is ____________.",opa:"at work, only",opb:"in his or her berthing area, only",opc:"BOTH at work and in his or her berthing area",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"While communicating with a shore station concerning an injured female, your message should indicate the subject's age is 32. Which code would your message contain?",opa:"MAO 32",opb:"MAJ 32",opc:"MAL 32",opd:"MAK 32",ans:"opd"},{question:"A person suffering from possible broken bones and internal injuries should ____________.",opa:"be assisted in walking around",opb:"be examined then walked to a bunk",opc:"not be moved but made comfortable until medical assistance arrives",opd:"not be allowed to lie down where injured but moved to a chair or bunk",ans:"opc"},{question:"The minimum bursting pressure for each cargo hose assembly must be at least ____________.",opa:"the sum of the relief valve setting and the static head",opb:"twice the sum of the relief valve setting and the static head",opc:"three times the sum of the relief valve setting and the static head",opd:"four times the sum of the relief valve setting and the static head",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type EPIRB must each ocean-going OSV carry?",opa:"Class A",opb:"Class B",opc:"Class C",opd:"Category I",ans:"opd"},{question:"To remedy a leaking fire hose connection at the hydrant, secure the valve and ____________.",opa:"replace the gasket in the male coupling",opb:"reduce fire pump pressure",opc:"replace the gasket in the female coupling",opd:"rethread the male coupling",ans:"opc"},{question:"On Subchapter T small passenger vessels, after loading and prior to departure, the master shall determine the vessel complies with all stability requirements in which of these documents?",opa:"stability letter",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Load Line Certificate",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The weight of the loaded personnel carrier, when transferring personnel from a MODU with a crane, must not exceed ____________.",opa:"2/3 of the static rated load at the lift radius",opb:"1/2 of the static rated load at the lift radius",opc:"1/5 of the breaking strength of the hoist rope times the parts of the line used",opd:"1/10 of the breaking strength of the hoist rope times the parts of line used",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of portable lighting may be used to enter a compartment on a tank barge which is NOT gas-free?",opa:"A three-cell flashlight",opb:"An explosion-proof, self-contained, battery-fed lamp",opc:"A spark resistant and flame retardant lamp",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The sea painter is secured in the lifeboat by ____________.",opa:"a turn around a forward thwart with a toggle pin thru the eye",opb:"a knot around a thwart",opc:"an eye splice placed over one of the hooks of the releasing gear",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"When do the towing vessel fire protection regulations allow a towing vessel to carry portable fuel systems onboard?",opa:"When used for outboard engines",opb:"When permanently attached to portable equipment such as bilge and fire pumps",opc:"If the portable tanks used for portable equipment meet published safety standards",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What are the transverse moments for 10.5 feet of sea water in preload tank #2 for the COASTAL DRILLER?",opa:"15,044 kips",opb:"12,123 kips",opc:"5,468 kips",opd:"2,732 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT listed on the metallic name plate required to be attached to hand portable fire extinguishers? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"The rated capacity in gallons, quarts, or pounds",opb:"The hydrostatic test date of the cylinder",opc:"The name of the item",opd:"An identifying mark of the actual manufacturer",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE of a gasoline spill?",opa:"It is visible for a shorter time than a fuel oil spill.",opb:"It is not covered by the pollution laws.",opc:"It does little harm to marine life.",opd:"It will sink more rapidly than crude oil.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What represents the metacentric height?",opa:"M",opb:"GM",opc:"BM",opd:"GZ",ans:"opb"},{question:"Most enclosed lifeboats will right themselves after capsizing IF the ____________.",opa:"lower ballast tanks are filled with water",opb:"fuel tanks are not less than half full",opc:"passengers are strapped to their seats",opd:"sea anchor is deployed to windward",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many ring life buoys must a small passenger vessel, of less than 65 feet in length, carry?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you were being assisted by an icebreaker and he sent you the single letter 'Q', he would be telling you ____________.",opa:"that he has his engines in reverse",opb:"that he is shortening the distance between vessels",opc:"to shorten the distance between vessels",opd:"that his vessel is healthy",ans:"opc"},{question:"Assuming that the recommended hatch loading sequence is followed, how many long tons of iron ore may be loaded through hatch No. 1 while using a single belt loader to arrive at a desired mean keel draft of 29'-11'? (use the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN)",opa:"2230 tons",opb:"2270 tons",opc:"2310 tons",opd:"2350 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"Cargo hose carried on tank vessels must be designed to withstand the pressure of the shutoff head of the cargo pump or pump relief valve setting, but in no case should it be less than ____________.",opa:"100 psi",opb:"150 psi",opc:"200 psi",opd:"250 psi",ans:"opb"},{question:"The instructions for the launching of lifeboats and liferafts must be approved by the ____________.",opa:"lease operator",opb:"Minerals Management Service",opc:"Coast Guard",opd:"person-in-charge of the unit",ans:"opc"},{question:"A cargo of 30 tons is to be loaded on deck 30 feet from the ship's centerline. The ship's displacement including the 30 tons cargo will be 9,000 tons and the GM will be 5 feet. The list of the vessel after loading this cargo will be ____________.",opa:"1.14\xb0",opb:"2.05\xb0",opc:"2.31\xb0",opd:"3.40\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"For a MODU with trim, a decrease in GMT will cause the angle of inclination to ____________.",opa:"increase",opb:"decrease",opc:"remain constant",opd:"stabilize at an angle of loll",ans:"opa"},{question:"Initial stability of a vessel may be improved by ____________.",opa:"removing loose water",opb:"adding weight low in the vessel",opc:"closing crossover valves between partly filled double bottom tanks",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Stability is determined principally by the location of two points in a vessel: the center of buoyancy and the ____________.",opa:"metacenter",opb:"geometric center of the waterplane area",opc:"center of gravity",opd:"center of flotation",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the shift in the longitudinal center of gravity if 200 short tons are discharged from 30 feet forward of amidships on a MODU with LCG 1.5 feet forward of amidships, and displacement 9,000 short tons?",opa:"0.62 foot aft",opb:"0.65 foot aft",opc:"0.68 foot aft",opd:"0.71 foot aft",ans:"opb"},{question:"The survival craft carried aboard a commercial fishing vessel must safely accommodate ____________.",opa:"all of the people aboard",opb:"the number of people required by the certificate of inspection",opc:"the entire crew",opd:"None of the above are correct.",ans:"opa"},{question:"After extinguishing a paint locker fire using the fixed CO2 system, the next action is to have the space ____________.",opa:"opened and burned material removed",opb:"left closed with vents off until all boundaries are cool",opc:"checked for oxygen content",opd:"doused with water to prevent reflash",ans:"opb"},{question:"While your vessel is taking on fuel you notice oil on the water around the vessel. What should you do FIRST?",opa:"Stop the fueling.",opb:"Notify the Coast Guard.",opc:"Notify the terminal superintendent.",opd:"Determine the source of the oil.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #2 (Ballast to Survival). What is the new longitudinal location of the center of buoyancy if all the bulk materials are discharged?",opa:"2.34 feet",opb:"2.48 feet",opc:"2.50 feet",opd:"2.53 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"In MODU construction, beams are transverse girders which provide support to ____________.",opa:"bulkheads",opb:"deckhouse structures",opc:"decks",opd:"vertical frames",ans:"opc"},{question:"An oil fire is classified as class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the VCG of the additional load if P-tank #4 in the DEEP DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Transit) is completely filled ?",opa:"113.90 feet",opb:"117.01 feet",opc:"121.03 feet",opd:"123.06 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement concerning homing signals in the GMDSS is FALSE?",opa:"A homing signal provides a bearing for rescue personnel to follow to the signal's SOURCE.",opb:"A homing signal is detected by the COSPAS-SARSAT satellites.",opc:"A homing signal cannot be detected by a GPS receiver.",opd:"A homing signal may be transmitted by equipment attached to the survival craft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"During loading, what is the minimum pressure required to be maintained by the inert gas system on cargo tanks?",opa:"2' water gauge",opb:"4' water gauge",opc:"20' water gauge",opd:"40' water gauge",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a vessel of 6,000 tons displacement there are two slack tanks of carbon tetrachloride (SG 1.6). Each tank is 40 feet long and 25 feet wide. What is the reduction in metacentric height due to free surface with the vessel in sea water (SG 1.025)?",opa:".39 ft.",opb:".77 ft.",opc:".88 ft.",opd:".95 ft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Where would you find the FCC authorization for transmitting on your rig's EPIRB?",opa:"On the Ship Station License",opb:"On the side of the EPIRB transmitter",opc:"In the radio log",opd:"On the Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opa"},{question:"When cargo aboard a jack-up in transit becomes adrift, the tow vessel should be asked to ____________.",opa:"turn into the seas",opb:"turn to be parallel to the seas",opc:"reduce speed",opd:"increase speed",ans:"opa"},{question:"If more than one liferaft is manned after the vessel has sunk, ____________.",opa:"each raft should go in a different direction in search of land",opb:"the possibility of a search aircraft finding you is increased by spreading out",opc:"reduce the number of liferafts by getting as many people as possible into as few rafts as possible",opd:"tie each of the rafts together and try to stay in a single group",ans:"opd"},{question:"When should the emergency position-indicating radio beacon be activated after abandoning an OSV?",opa:"Immediately",opb:"After one hour",opc:"Only when another vessel is in sight",opd:"Only after sunset",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a mobile offshore drilling unit on the waters of the U.S. Outer Continental Shelf has more than one obstruction light, the lights must be operated to flash ____________.",opa:"at the same time",opb:"in sequence at intervals of five seconds",opc:"in sequence at intervals of ten seconds",opd:"in sequence at intervals of fifteen seconds",ans:"opa"},{question:"After jacking down your liftboat you have an unexpected list. You find that the only cause of this list must be a flooded leg. To keep adequate stability you should ____________.",opa:"get underway with the flooded leg ONLY half raised to reduce KG",opb:"proceed with all legs half raised to lower KG",opc:"pump out all ballast to increase reserve buoyancy",opd:"jack back up and ballast the vessel's high side as necessary",ans:"opd"},{question:"Error may be introduced into a magnetic compass by ____________.",opa:"making a structural change to the vessel",opb:"a short circuit near the compass",opc:"belt buckles",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is a GMDSS functional or carriage requirement for compulsory vessels?",opa:"A compulsory vessel must carry at least two (2) licensed GMDSS operators",opb:"A compulsory vessel must satisfy certain equipment carriage requirements that are determined by where the vessel sails.",opc:"A compulsory vessel must be able to transmit and respond to Distress alerts.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are at sea in an inflatable liferaft. In high latitudes, the greatest danger is ____________.",opa:"asphyxiation due to keeping the canopy closed",opb:"hypothermia caused by cold temperature",opc:"collapse of the raft due to cold temperatures",opd:"starvation",ans:"opb"},{question:"The longitudinal distance between draft marks for the DEEP DRILLER is ____________.",opa:"122'-09'",opb:"164'-00'",opc:"260'-00'",opd:"260'-05'",ans:"opb"},{question:"In addition to a portable hand-operated bilge pump, a 55 foot long ferry must have a fixed power operated bilge pump capable of pumping at least ____________.",opa:"5 GPM",opb:"10 GPM",opc:"25 GPM",opd:"50 GPM",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a MODU, if there is a probability of encountering H2S during the drilling of a well, air movers (bug blowers) should be installed to dilute concentration of H2S at the ____________.",opa:"pipe rack",opb:"crown block",opc:"shale shaker",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"On Offshore Drilling units, in addition to the life jackets stowed at each berth location, life jackets must be stowed at each work station and ____________.",opa:"the mess room",opb:"each lifeboat",opc:"each industrial work site",opd:"each fire station",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is observed to be level at a draft of 60.0 feet. At the same time, the calculated load form shows the displacement to be 17,845 long tons, total longitudinal moments 51,466 foot-tons, and total transverse moments -10,000 foot-tons. What is the weight of the missing load?",opa:"220.7 long tons",opb:"235.3 long tons",opc:"253.7 long tons",opd:"272.7 long tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"After a liferaft is launched, the operating cord ____________.",opa:"serves as a sea painter",opb:"detaches automatically",opc:"is used to rig the boarding ladder",opd:"is cut immediately as it is of no further use",ans:"opa"},{question:"The explosive range of petroleum vapors mixed with air is ____________.",opa:"0% to 1%",opb:"1% to 10%",opc:"10% to 15%",opd:"12% to 20%",ans:"opb"},{question:"A product is classified at grade B when it has a Reid vapor pressure of ____________.",opa:"7 psia and a flash point of 80\xb0F",opb:"more than 8 1/2 psia but less than 14 psia and a flash point of 72\xb0F",opc:"9 1/2 psia and a flash point of 95\xb0F",opd:"above 14 psia",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in transit with winds expected to exceed 70 knots, must lower the legs to 60.5 feet below the hull in order to meet the requirements for stability and ____________.",opa:"leg strength",opb:"variable load",opc:"environmental load",opd:"load line",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 17'-09', AFT 21'-01'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the location of the center of flotation relative to amidships.",opa:"5.1 feet forward",opb:"4.7 feet forward",opc:"2.6 feet aft",opd:"0.8 foot forward",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Coast Guard requires machinery spaces and enclosed mud handling spaces to have ____________.",opa:"remote ventilation shutdowns",opb:"remote pump shutdowns",opc:"alternative control stations",opd:"smoke and/or fire detection system",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 5'-08', AFT 6'-02'. From past experience, you know that the vessel will increase her draft 1 inch for every 8 tons loaded. There is rig water onboard and 11 tons of deck cargo. How many more tons of cargo can be loaded and still maintain the same trim?",opa:"None",opb:"10 tons",opc:"18 tons",opd:"24 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following is/are NOT required on Ro-Ro vessels, regarding spaces that are 'specially suitable for vehicles'?",opa:"The spaces shall be fitted with an approved fire or smoke detecting system.",opb:"The spaces shall have designated smoking areas.",opc:"The spaces shall be fitted with an approved fixed fire extinguishing system.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are berthed at a cargo facility where you have just completed discharging a dangerous cargo. You must complete topside repairs involving hot work before sailing. Which of the following statements is TRUE?",opa:"You can make repairs with permission of the facility owner since you are empty and the cargo is on the facility.",opb:"The repair area must be inspected by a marine surveyor to ensure that it can be done safely.",opc:"Hot work repairs at such a facility are prohibited.",opd:"The Captain of the Port may give specific approval to make hot work repairs.",ans:"opd"},{question:"How often must a rated load test be performed on a crane on a MODU?",opa:"Every 12 months",opb:"Every 24 months",opc:"Every 36 months",opd:"Every 48 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"In this view of the fire control plan of the lower engine room, what does the arrow between frames 135 and 140 represent?",opa:"Direction of fire main",opb:"Secondary means of escape",opc:"Missing person search pattern",opd:"Primary means of escape",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 4.07 ft.",opb:"Available GM 4.60 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.69 ft.",opd:"Available GM 4.81 ft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Master of a vessel shall make sure the EPIRB is tested ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"daily",opb:"weekly",opc:"every two weeks",opd:"monthly",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each person on the rig has a designated area to proceed to in the event of a fire. This assignment is shown clearly on the rig's ____________.",opa:"fire fighting plan",opb:"shipping articles",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",ans:"opd"},{question:"If the DEEP DRILLER is damaged, the unit is designed to avoid downflooding in wind speeds up to ____________.",opa:"50 knots",opb:"70 knots",opc:"90 knots",opd:"100 knots",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 21.8 feet and the drafts are: FWD 19'-05', AFT 20'-01'.",opa:"52\xb0",opb:"45\xb0",opc:"31\xb0",opd:"26\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is an advantage of a steam turbine over a diesel for the main propulsion?",opa:"Faster response from ahead to astern",opb:"Less fuel consumption",opc:"Cheaper initial installation cost",opd:"Less weight per unit of horsepower",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel's tropical load line is 6 in. above her summer load line. Her TPI is 127 tons. She will arrive in the summer zone 8 days after departure. She will burn off about 47 tons/day fuel and water consumption is 12 tons/day. How many tons may she load above her summer load line if she loads in the tropical zone?",opa:"376",opb:"472",opc:"762",opd:"1016",ans:"opb"},{question:"Why are lifeboats usually double-enders?",opa:"They are more seaworthy and less likely to be swamped or broach to ____________.",opb:"They can go forward and backward more easily.",opc:"They require less space for stowing aboard ship.",opd:"There is no particular reason for this.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Master shall insure that the Emergency Position Indicating Radio beacon (EPIRB) is ____________.",opa:"secured inside the wheelhouse",opb:"tested annually",opc:"tested monthly",opd:"secured in the emergency locker",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the entire contents of bulk tanks #2 and #3 are back-loaded to an offshore supply vessel, what transverse moment would have to be created to level the unit in list at the new draft?",opa:"-3,604 ft.-kips",opb:"-4 ft.-kips",opc:"3,470 ft.-kips",opd:"7,088 ft.-kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have 200 tons of below deck tonnage. There is no liquid mud aboard. If you have 140 tons of cargo above deck with a VCG above the deck of 4.2 feet, what is the maximum allowed VCG of the remainder of the deck cargo that is permitted?",opa:"0.56 foot",opb:"0.87 foot",opc:"1.04 feet",opd:"2.44 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your sails are properly trimmed while on a reaching course. Changing to a close hauled course will ____________.",opa:"require you to sheet in for best speed",opb:"result in a reduction of speed",opc:"cause a greater heeling force to leeward",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The LWT anchor has two angular positions for the flukes. These are ____________.",opa:"30\xb0 and 40\xb0",opb:"30\xb0 and 50\xb0",opc:"30\xb0 and 60\xb0",opd:"40\xb0 and 60\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"The full period of motion of the DEEP DRILLER while tripping is 8 seconds and the maximum pitch angle as seen on the inclinometers is 4 degrees. From the standpoint of critical motion, the motion is ____________.",opa:"unsatisfactory, place setback in the pipe racks",opb:"satisfactory, continue tripping",opc:"unsatisfactory, deballast to survival draft",opd:"unsatisfactory, place unit in standby",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel with a large GM will ____________.",opa:"have more resistance to listing in case of damage",opb:"have less tendency to have synchronous rolling",opc:"be less likely to have cargo shift",opd:"ride more comfortably",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which vessel greater than 100 GT is NOT required to have an EPIRB.",opa:"A sailing vessel",opb:"A fishing vessel",opc:"A non self-propelled vessel in tow",opd:"A towing vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Dry chemical extinguishers extinguish class B fires to the greatest extent by ____________.",opa:"cooling",opb:"smothering",opc:"oxygen dilution",opd:"breaking the chain reaction",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a vessel has positive stability, the distance between the line of force through B and the line of force through G is called the ____________.",opa:"metacentric height",opb:"righting arm",opc:"righting moment",opd:"metacentric radius",ans:"opb"},{question:"What will happen when cargo is shifted from the main deck into the lower hold of a vessel?",opa:"The GM will increase.",opb:"The metacenter will move upward.",opc:"The center of buoyancy will move upward.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Weather conditions require ballasting to survival draft. Assume that 4087 long tons of ballast are added at an average VCG of 8.32 feet. What would be the value of uncorrected KG?",opa:"51.65 feet",opb:"52.67 feet",opc:"55.15 feet",opd:"62.24 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"On small passenger vessels after loading and prior to departure, the master shall determine the vessel complies with all stability requirements in which of these documents?",opa:"stability letter",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Load Line Certificate",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A compound fracture is a fracture in which ____________.",opa:"more than one bone is broken",opb:"the same bone is broken in more than one place",opc:"there is never any internal bleeding",opd:"the bone may be visible",ans:"opd"},{question:"A galley grease fire would be classified as which class of fire?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opb"},{question:"A person on a fixed or floating platform engaged in oil exploration located 10 nautical miles from nearest land MAY discharge ____________.",opa:"food waste",opb:"food, ground to less than 1'",opc:"paper, ground to less than 1'",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the correct procedure to follow when launching an inflatable liferaft by hand from an OSV?",opa:"Connect the float free link to the vessel.",opb:"Pull the painter from the container and make it fast to the cleat provided.",opc:"Open the canopy relief valves.",opd:"Remove the raft from the container to permit complete inflation.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which T-Boat must be fitted with a suitable compass?",opa:"A vessel in river service",opb:"A vessel operating on a short, restricted route on lakes, bays, and sounds",opc:"A vessel engaged in ocean or coastwise service",opd:"The regulations do not require a compass on any vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which equipment is not required for a life float? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Paddles",opb:"Light",opc:"Painter",opd:"Compass",ans:"opd"},{question:"Multiple fire pumps may be used for other purposes provided that one pump is ____________.",opa:"on line to the fire main",opb:"kept available for use on the fire main at all times",opc:"capable of being connected to the fire main",opd:"rated at or above 125 psi",ans:"opb"},{question:"Why is spare fire hose rolled for storage?",opa:"Water in the hose is forced out the end in the rolling process.",opb:"The threads on the male end are protected by the hose.",opc:"Rolling provides maximum protection against entry of foreign objects into the couplings.",opd:"Rolling provides maximum protection to the outer covering of the hose.",ans:"opb"},{question:"For the purposes of the International Rules of the Road, a non-self-propelled mobile offshore drilling unit under tow is considered to be a ____________.",opa:"non-displacement vessel",opb:"limited vessel",opc:"power-driven vessel",opd:"vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"An inflatable liferaft can be launched by ____________.",opa:"the float free method only",opb:"kicking the hydrostatic release",opc:"throwing the entire container overboard, then pulling on the operating cord to inflate the raft",opd:"removing the securing straps",ans:"opc"},{question:"All fire hoses on mobile offshore drilling units must be tested to a pressure of at least ____________.",opa:"100 psi",opb:"110 psi",opc:"120 psi",opd:"130 psi",ans:"opb"},{question:"The airborne concentrations of substances (such as H2S) under which nearly all workers may be repeatedly exposed without adverse effects are called ____________.",opa:"exposure limits",opb:"concentration limits",opc:"threshold limit values",opd:"substance limit values",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 20'-04', AFT 23'-06'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"0.62 foot",opb:"0.80 foot",opc:"0.85 foot",opd:"0.99 foot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 22.4 feet and the drafts are: FWD 15'-03', AFT 15'-09'.",opa:"25\xb0",opb:"33\xb0",opc:"48\xb0",opd:"72\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"451 tons",opb:"1126 tons",opc:"1451 tons",opd:"1726 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"On offshore drilling units each fire station is identified by letters and numbers at least ____________.",opa:"2 inches high",opb:"3 inches high",opc:"5 inches high",opd:"8 inches high",ans:"opa"},{question:"In a fixed CO2 extinguishing system where provision is made for the release of CO2 by operation of a remote control, provision shall also be made for releasing the CO2 ____________.",opa:"from inside the engine room",opb:"from the bridge",opc:"from the cargo control station",opd:"at the cylinder location",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 40,301 foot-long tons, TM = 3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons. What is the uncorrected height of the center of gravity?",opa:"52.14 feet",opb:"53.78 feet",opc:"55.03 feet",opd:"58.50 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"If an ill crew member is beginning to show signs of improvement, what code should your message contain?",opa:"MVP",opb:"MPH",opc:"MPF",opd:"MSO",ans:"opc"},{question:"If you must enter water on which there is an oil fire, you should ____________.",opa:"protect your life preserver by holding it above your head",opb:"enter the water on the windward side of the vessel",opc:"keep both hands in front of your face to break the water surface when diving head first",opd:"wear very light clothing",ans:"opb"},{question:"When you are firing a pyrotechnic distress signal, it should be aimed at ____________.",opa:"straight overhead",opb:"at the vessel whose attention you are trying to get",opc:"into the wind",opd:"about 60 degrees above the horizon",ans:"opd"},{question:"A partially full tank causes a virtual rise in the height of the ____________.",opa:"metacenter",opb:"center of buoyancy",opc:"center of flotation",opd:"center of gravity",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you receive a message 'A243' by any method of signaling, it would be referring to ____________.",opa:"bearing",opb:"altitude",opc:"diving",opd:"speed",ans:"opa"},{question:"A sweep oar is an oar that is ____________.",opa:"generally shorter than the others and is used to steer with",opb:"is longer than the others and is used as the stroke oar",opc:"is raised in the bow of the boat for the steersman to steer by",opd:"longer than the others used for steering",ans:"opd"},{question:"Grade A flammable liquids are those with a Reid vapor pressure of ____________.",opa:"5 to 8 1/2 psia",opb:"more than 8 1/2 psia but less than 14 psia",opc:"14 psia or more",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"How must each storage tank for helicopter fuel on a MODU be marked?",opa:"DANGER -KEEP AWAY",opb:"DANGER -EXPLOSIVE VAPORS",opc:"DANGER -NO SMOKING",opd:"DANGER -FLAMMABLE LIQUID",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #1 (Transit), suffers minor damage which results in flooding in tank 1P. You may pump from ____________.",opa:"2P",opb:"C1P",opc:"1P",opd:"10S",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel heading ENE is on a course of ____________.",opa:"022.5\xb0",opb:"045.0\xb0",opc:"067.5\xb0",opd:"090.0\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"As soon as the officer in charge of the vessel has taken steps to stop the discharge of oil or oily mixture into a U.S. harbor, what must he do FIRST?",opa:"Rig a boom for recovery.",opb:"Call the Coast Guard.",opc:"Alert the fire department.",opd:"Inform the Environmental Protection Agency.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The required number and type of hand portable fire extinguishers for staterooms on cargo vessels is ____________.",opa:"one A-I",opb:"one B-I",opc:"one C-I",opd:"none required",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each life jacket light that has a non-replaceable power source must be replaced ____________.",opa:"every 6 months after initial installation",opb:"every 12 months after initial installation",opc:"every 24 months after initial installation",opd:"on or before the expiration date of the power source",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in transit with winds less than 70 knots, has a draft of 10 feet 8 inches. The VM are 541,257 ft.-kips, FSML are 32,000 ft.-kips, and FSMT are 24,000 ft.-kips. The margin on the maximum allowable KG is ____________.",opa:"-2.3 feet",opb:"0.0 feet",opc:"23.7 feet",opd:"26.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #2 (Ballasting to Survival). What is the new height of the transverse metacenter if all the bulk materials are discharged?",opa:"63.14 feet",opb:"64.05 feet",opc:"64.30 feet",opd:"66.09 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"During a stability test on a small passenger vessel ____________.",opa:"the vessel must be moored snugly",opb:"each tank must be partially full to show it does not leak",opc:"all dunnage, tools, and extraneous items are secured",opd:"water under vessel must be deep enough to prevent grounding",ans:"opd"},{question:"Regulations require that tank vessels handling grade B liquids shall have their cargo pumps separated from all sources of vapor ignition by ____________.",opa:"cofferdams",opb:"empty cargo spaces",opc:"gas tight bulkheads",opd:"areas equipped with power ventilation",ans:"opc"},{question:"Starting motors, generators, and any other spark producing devices shall be ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"of the alternating current type",opb:"mounted as high as practicable above the bilges",opc:"rated for at least 12 volts",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"If you have to jump in the water when abandoning ship, your legs should be ____________.",opa:"spread apart as far as possible",opb:"held as tightly against your chest as possible",opc:"in a kneeling position",opd:"extended straight down and crossed at the ankles",ans:"opd"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 290\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"on a close reach on a port tack",opb:"close hauled on a starboard tack",opc:"on a broad reach on a port tack",opd:"on a beam reach on a starboard tack",ans:"opa"},{question:"Stability is determined principally by the location of the point of application of two forces: the downward-acting gravity force and the ____________.",opa:"upward-acting weight force",opb:"downward-acting weight force",opc:"upward-acting buoyant force",opd:"environmental force",ans:"opc"},{question:"A violation of the 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act' may result in a ____________.",opa:"civil penalty of $650 against the Master or person in charge of a vessel",opb:"civil penalty of$1,000 against the vessel itself",opc:"suspension and/or revocation of an operator's FCC license",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Weather conditions require ballasting to survival draft. Assume that 4087 long tons of ballast are added at an average VCG of 8.32 feet, and upon arrival at 45 feet, port and starboard ballast tanks 1, 3, and 8 are slack. What is the new KGL?",opa:"51.65 feet",opb:"52.67 feet",opc:"55.16 feet",opd:"62.24 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are loading in a port subject to the summer load line mark and bound for a port subject to the tropical load line mark. You will enter the tropical zone after steaming four days. You will consume 33 tons of fuel, water, and stores per day. The hydrometer reading at the loading pier is 1.006, and the average TPI is 66. What is the minimum freeboard required at the start of the voyage?",opa:"78 inches",opb:"82 inches",opc:"86 inches",opd:"88 inches",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers damage to the port aft column below the waterline. Pumping from tank 8P and 9P is not sufficient to prevent increasing port list and stern down trim. You should consider counter flooding in tank ____________.",opa:"1S",opb:"1P",opc:"C2BS",opd:"10S",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #2 (Ballasting to Survival). What is the shift in TCG if 100.76 long tons of ballast are added to Ballast Tank #8S to replace the discharge of all bulk materials?",opa:"0.01 foot starboard",opb:"0.18 foot starboard",opc:"0.27 foot starboard",opd:"0.39 foot starboard",ans:"opa"},{question:"A measurement device for inspecting anchor chain is the ____________.",opa:"slide rule",opb:"go-no-go gauge",opc:"derrick tape",opd:"amp probe",ans:"opb"},{question:"The safest device used to secure the end of the pendant wire when it is initially passed to the anchor handling vessel is a ____________.",opa:"pelican hook",opb:"hydraulic deck stopper",opc:"connecting link",opd:"shackle",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which EPIRB transmits a distress alert that is received and relayed by an INMARSAT satellite?",opa:"Class A EPIRBs",opb:"Class B EPIRBs",opc:"L-Band EPIRBs",opd:"Category I EPIRBs",ans:"opc"},{question:"A fully loaded motor-propelled lifeboat must be capable of attaining a speed of at least ____________.",opa:"3 knots in smooth water",opb:"6 knots in smooth water",opc:"3 knots in rough water",opd:"6 knots in rough water",ans:"opb"},{question:"To meet the regulations governing manning requirements outside U.S. jurisdiction, a person holding a foreign license can serve in any of the following positions EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"able seaman",opb:"ballast control operator",opc:"barge supervisor",opd:"offshore installation manager",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 6048 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 270.71 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 267.03 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 267.92 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 268.66 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 269.94 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which action will best increase the transverse stability of a merchant vessel at sea?",opa:"Ballasting the double bottom tanks",opb:"Deballasting the deep tanks",opc:"Positioning a heavy lift cargo on the main deck",opd:"Raising the cargo booms to the upright position",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 6'-01', AFT 6'-10'. From past experience, you know that the vessel will increase her draft 1 inch for every 6 tons loaded. There is rig water onboard and 11 tons of deck cargo. How many more tons of cargo can be loaded and still maintain the same trim?",opa:"6 tons",opb:"12 tons",opc:"18 tons",opd:"24 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The MINIMUM ventilation requirements for pumprooms on tank vessels (constructed in 1960) carrying grades B or C liquid cargo with machinery spaces located below the freeboard deck specify ____________.",opa:"gooseneck vents and flame screens",opb:"that it be connected to a vent header system",opc:"that it be power ventilation",opd:"that it be fitted with at least two ducts extended to the weather deck",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the maximum number of crew members that may be berthed in one room aboard your cargo vessel?",opa:"Two",opb:"Four",opc:"Six",opd:"Eight",ans:"opb"},{question:"A virtual rise in the center of gravity may be caused by ____________.",opa:"filling a partially filled tank",opb:"using an onboard crane to lift a freely swinging heavy object",opc:"emptying a partially filled tank",opd:"transferring ballast from the forepeak to the after peak",ans:"opb"},{question:"At an angle of loll, the capsizing moment is ____________.",opa:"maximum",opb:"negative",opc:"positive",opd:"zero",ans:"opd"},{question:"On the cargo manifest, the weight of the cargo inside a box is called the ____________.",opa:"gross weight",opb:"net weight",opc:"light weight",opd:"rate weight",ans:"opb"},{question:"When using a handheld smoke signal in a liferaft, you should activate the signal ____________.",opa:"on the upwind side",opb:"inside the boat",opc:"at the stern",opd:"on the downwind side",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about entry into a water ballast tank that has been sealed for a long time is TRUE?",opa:"A 'buddy system' should be used where someone enters the tank with you.",opb:"Sea water acts on the ship's metal and generates chlorine gas which may accumulate in poisonous quantities.",opc:"You should always wear a gas mask.",opd:"After ventilation and testing, and the tank is found safe for entry, someone should stand by at the tank entrance while you are inside.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Where will you find the requirements for the signals that must be sounded by a mobile offshore drilling unit that is being towed through an area of restricted visibility?",opa:"COLREGS",opb:"MMS Rules",opc:"SOLAS Convention",opd:"Coast Pilot",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fire protection regulations for towing vessels allow all of these types of fuel piping, EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"steel",opb:"aluminum in an aluminum-hulled vessel",opc:"schedule 80 fire resistant plastic pipe",opd:"nickel-copper, copper-nickel or annealed copper",ans:"opc"},{question:"Curve B in the Design Limits of Legs Chart of the Coastal Driller Operating Manual, shows the operating limits during normal transit based on ____________.",opa:"leg strength",opb:"variable load",opc:"environmental load",opd:"load line",ans:"opa"},{question:"The light on a life jacket must be replaced ____________.",opa:"when the power source is replaced",opb:"each year after installation",opc:"every six months",opd:"when it is no longer serviceable",ans:"opd"},{question:"A portable foam (stored-pressure type) fire extinguisher would be most useful in combating a fire in ____________.",opa:"generators",opb:"oil drums",opc:"the bridge controls",opd:"combustible metals",ans:"opb"},{question:"The rescue boat on an OSV is not required to carry a ____________.",opa:"fishing kit",opb:"searchlight",opc:"sea anchor",opd:"radar reflector",ans:"opa"},{question:"When there is a small craft advisory winds are predicted up to ____________.",opa:"15 knots",opb:"24 knots",opc:"33 knots",opd:"42 knots",ans:"opc"},{question:"Basic emergency care for third degree electrical burn is to ____________.",opa:"flood the burned area with warm water for two minutes",opb:"brush away the charred skin and wrap the burned area",opc:"cover the burned area with a clean cloth and transport the patient to a medical facility",opd:"apply ointment or spray to the burned area and wrap with a clean cloth",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a vapor control system, each vessel's vapor connection flange must have a ____________.",opa:"6' reducer",opb:"stud at least 1' long projecting from the flange face",opc:"pressure gauge permanently attached to the flange",opd:"hose saddle",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT classified as a flammable liquid?",opa:"Methyl alcohol",opb:"Heptane",opc:"Mineral spirits",opd:"iso-Hexane",ans:"opc"},{question:"After jacking down your liftboat you have an unexpected list. You find that the only cause of this list must be a flooded leg. The list caused by a flooded leg means your vessel has a(n) ____________.",opa:"negative GM (metacentric height)",opb:"decrease in the GZ (righting arm)",opc:"increase in the waterplane and the metacentric height",opd:"less chance of deck edge immersion",ans:"opb"},{question:"Frapping lines ____________.",opa:"secure the lifeboat in the davits when in the stowed position",opb:"bring the lifeboat close alongside the rail in the embarkation position",opc:"give the occupants a safety line when the boat is being lowered from the embarkation level",opd:"reduce the swinging of the lifeboat at the embarkation level",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your fishing vessel is required to have a compass. It must also have a(n) ____________.",opa:"deviation table",opb:"radar reflector",opc:"electronic position-fixing device",opd:"copy of the Sailing Directions",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the COASTAL DRILLER, TCG is obtained from the sum of the transverse moments by ____________.",opa:"adding the sum of the weights",opb:"subtracting the sum of the weights",opc:"multiplying by the sum of the weights",opd:"dividing by the sum of the weights",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is floating in water of density 1010. The fresh water allowance is 8 inches. How far below her marks may she be loaded so as to float at her mark in saltwater of density 1025?",opa:"3.2 inches",opb:"4.8 inches",opc:"6.4 inches",opd:"8.0 inches",ans:"opb"},{question:"Each EPIRB shall be tested using the integrated test circuit and output indicator every ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"two weeks",opc:"month",opd:"quarter",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel heading NNW is on a course of ____________.",opa:"274.5\xb0",opb:"292.0\xb0",opc:"315.5\xb0",opd:"337.5\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT a grade B flammable liquid?",opa:"tert-Butylamine",opb:"Allyl chloride",opc:"Ethyl chloride",opd:"Carbon disulfide",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents an emergency fire pump?",opa:"19",opb:"21",opc:"22",opd:"54",ans:"opa"},{question:"The steering oar in a lifeboat is usually referred to as the ____________.",opa:"bumpkin oar",opb:"stroke oar",opc:"sweep oar",opd:"becket oar",ans:"opc"},{question:"A jack-up displacing 350,000 cubic feet while floating in sea water (64 pounds per cubic foot) weighs ____________.",opa:"10,000 kips",opb:"18,169 kips",opc:"21,841 kips",opd:"22,400 kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"In a water tube marine boiler, what protects the super heater tubes from the fires of combustion?",opa:"Water-wall tubes",opb:"Downcomers",opc:"Screen tubes",opd:"Water drums",ans:"opc"},{question:"What must be carried out in order to manually launch an inflatable liferaft not designed for float-free operation?",opa:"It will be easily launched by simply breaking the weak link.",opb:"Depress the hydrostatic release button.",opc:"It is easily launched by cutting the container securing straps.",opd:"It is only necessary to attach the weak link to the vessel.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the minimum number of portable fire extinguishers required onboard a 45-foot motorboat having a fixed fire system onboard? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"1 B-I",opb:"2 B-I",opc:"3 B-I",opd:"4 B-I",ans:"opb"},{question:"Because there is a possibility of fuel oil being discharged overboard from a full fuel oil tank, it is decided to transfer 25 kips from tank #14 to tank #13. See COASTAL DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What would be the change in vertical moments with this transfer?",opa:"81 ft.-kips increase",opb:"31 ft.-kips increase",opc:"26 ft.-kips decrease",opd:"47 ft.-kips decrease",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is a grade B flammable liquid?",opa:"Ethylene oxide",opb:"Paraldehyde",opc:"Chlorallylene",opd:"Allyl alcohol",ans:"opc"},{question:"A jack-up 180 feet in length with the LCF at 120 feet AFO has a true mean draft (draft at LCF) of 10 feet. If the trim is 3 feet by the stern, what is the draft at the stern?",opa:"8.0 feet",opb:"9.0 feet",opc:"11.0 feet",opd:"12.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of respiratory protection is preferable for repair/investigation personnel on a MODU in a hydrogen sulfide (H2S) environment?",opa:"U.S. Navy Oxygen Breathing Apparatus (OBA)",opb:"Emergency Escape Breathing Apparatus (EEBA)",opc:"Demand Self-Contained Breathing Apparatus (SCBA)",opd:"Pressure-Demand Self-Contained Breathing Apparatus (SCBA)",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a MODU, an extinguisher with 15 lbs. of CO2 or 10 lbs. of dry chemical is a size ____________.",opa:"I",opb:"II",opc:"III",opd:"IV",ans:"opb"},{question:"When fire pumps are used for other than firefighting service, each pipe connecting the other service (except for branch lines used for deck washing) must have a ____________.",opa:"check valve installed in the line",opb:"shut off valve at a manifold near the pump",opc:"quick disconnect union within ten feet of the pump",opd:"regulator in the line set at 125 psi",ans:"opb"},{question:"The carbon dioxide cylinders of all fixed fire extinguishing systems shall be retested and remarked whenever a cylinder remains in place on a vessel for ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"5 years from the latest test date stamped on the cylinder",opb:"7 years from the latest test date stamped on the cylinder",opc:"10 years from the latest test date stamped on the cylinder",opd:"12 years from the latest test date stamped on the cylinder",ans:"opd"},{question:"When the ullage is 5.7 feet in P-Tank #6 for the Deep Driller, the transverse moment for P-Tank #6 is ____________.",opa:"1,288 foot-tons",opb:"1,887 foot-tons",opc:"3,169 foot-tons",opd:"4,596 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The purpose of the deck seal in an inert gas system is to prevent ____________.",opa:"flammable vapors from entering machinery space",opb:"flue gas escaping to atmosphere",opc:"inert gas escaping to atmosphere",opd:"air entering inert gas system",ans:"opa"},{question:"What monitoring device best indicates the load being carried by a diesel engine?",opa:"Lube oil pressure gauge",opb:"Jacket water temperature gauge",opc:"Tachometer",opd:"Exhaust pyrometer",ans:"opd"},{question:"The person assigned to command a lifeboat or inflatable liferaft on a MODU shall have a list of the persons assigned to the lifeboat or liferaft. The list shall include each person's ____________.",opa:"home address",opb:"duties",opc:"home phone number",opd:"nearest relative's address",ans:"opb"},{question:"When used to fight fire, carbon dioxide ____________.",opa:"is effective if used promptly on an oil fire",opb:"has a greater cooling effect than water",opc:"is lighter than air",opd:"is harmless to cargo and crew",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following statements is FALSE, concerning the regulations pertaining to the cylinder room of a fixed CO2 fire extinguishing system?",opa:"The compartment must be properly ventilated.",opb:"The temperature of the room should never exceed 130\xb0F.",opc:"The door must be kept unlocked.",opd:"The compartment shall be clearly marked and identifiable.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1220 tons",opb:"840 tons",opc:"460 tons",opd:"344 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each hand portable fire extinguisher must be marked with ____________.",opa:"the name of the vessel on which it is located",opb:"the date that it was installed",opc:"the names of the individuals qualified to use it",opd:"an identification number",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fire hose couplings ____________.",opa:"are made of bronze, brass, or soft alloy metals",opb:"should be painted red in order to identify hose lengths",opc:"are specially hardened to prevent crushing",opd:"should be greased frequently",ans:"opa"},{question:"Hoses used for cargo transfer operations must be tested and inspected at specified intervals by ____________.",opa:"a representative of the Captain of the Port",opb:"the operator of the vessel or facility",opc:"a representative of the National Cargo Bureau",opd:"a representative of the American Bureau of Shipping",ans:"opb"},{question:"The single letter G, sent by an icebreaker to an assisted vessel, means ____________.",opa:"'I require a pilot'",opb:"'Longitude follows'",opc:"'I am going ahead; follow me'",opd:"'Do not follow me'",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 23.7 feet and the drafts are: FWD 28'-00', AFT 28'-06'.",opa:"16\xb0",opb:"21\xb0",opc:"41\xb0",opd:"56\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"One method of reducing the length of radio transmissions without distorting the meaning of your words is by using ____________.",opa:"slang",opb:"secret codes",opc:"procedure words",opd:"analogies",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER will sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts.",opa:"FWD 17'-06', AFT24'-03'",opb:"FWD 19'-03', AFT22'-06'",opc:"FWD 17'-01', AFT24'-08'",opd:"FWD 21'-04', AFT19'-07'",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, what is the Reid Vapor Pressure of tert-butylamine?",opa:"11 (psig)",opb:"12 (psig)",opc:"13 (psig)",opd:"14 (psig)",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are sailing on a close reach when a strong wind suddenly heels the vessel hard over. To reduce the heeling and yet maintain speed, you should ____________.",opa:"ease the mainsheet and bear more away from the wind",opb:"haul in on the mainsheet and steer more towards the wind",opc:"haul in on the mainsheet and ease the jib sheet",opd:"ease all sheets and bear more into the wind",ans:"opa"},{question:"Switchboards shall be ...... (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Watertight.",opb:"Grounded to the main engine on a wooden hulled boat.",opc:"The dead-front type, totally enclosed",opd:"Equipped with switch locks",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Excessive motion makes it necessary to ballast down to survival draft. It is decided to check the stability at the intermediate draft of 32 feet. If the added ballast has an average VCG of 9.03 feet, and the sum of free surface moments is 56,244 foot-tons, what is the new margin on the maximum allowable KG?",opa:"6.23 feet",opb:"5.11 feet",opc:"4.86 feet",opd:"4.06 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"In launching a lifeboat, when should the tricing pendants be released?",opa:"Before the boat is lowered from the stowage position",opb:"As soon as the boat-fall blocks clear the davit head",opc:"After the limit switch is activated",opd:"After all people have been embarked",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your ship of 12,000 tons displacement has a center of gravity of 21.5 feet above the keel. You run aground and estimate the weight aground is 2500 tons. The virtual rise in the center of gravity is ____________.",opa:"1.26 feet",opb:"3.80 feet",opc:"4.80 feet",opd:"5.66 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"If your Bunker-C barge has operated in salt water for more than 12 months in the 24 month period since it was last dry-docked, when is it required to be hauled out again?",opa:"36 months since last dry-docking",opb:"24 months since last dry-docking",opc:"18 months since last dry-docking",opd:"12 months since last dry-docking",ans:"opb"},{question:"The righting moment created by a MODU that displaces 15,000 tons with a righting arm (GZ) of 0.02 foot is ____________.",opa:"3,000 foot-tons",opb:"750 foot-tons",opc:"600 foot-tons",opd:"300 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"When authorized to use chemical agents on an oil spill they would ____________.",opa:"absorb the oil for easy removal",opb:"dissolve the oil in the water",opc:"facilitate the removal of the pollutant from the water",opd:"sink the oil",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on an inerted tankship. A low pressure alarm must be set to cause an audible and visual alarm if the pressure in the tanks cannot be maintained at more than ____________.",opa:"4' water gauge",opb:"90% of the vacuum relief setting",opc:"90% of the pressure drop through the scrubber",opd:"90% of the vacuum assist fan",ans:"opa"},{question:"Among the possible causes of unexpected constant inclination of the floating COASTAL DRILLER is ____________.",opa:"consumption of onboard liquids",opb:"miscalculation of loads",opc:"liquid transfer through open valves",opd:"flooding due to hull damage",ans:"opb"},{question:"When should the emergency position-indicating radio beacon be activated after abandoning a MODU?",opa:"Immediately",opb:"After one hour",opc:"Only when another vessel is in sight",opd:"Only after sunset",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 6450 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 270.89 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 267.12 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 268.48 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 270.97 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 273.06 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Master or person in charge of a MODU shall ensure the crane record book shows the ____________.",opa:"date and description of each failure",opb:"average load in pounds for each usage",opc:"total number of lifts for each usage",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Foam is effective in combating which class(es) of fire?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"A and B",opd:"B and C",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a vessel of 12,000 tons displacement, what is the reduction in metacentric height due to free surface when a tank 60 feet long and 60 feet wide is partially filled with water?",opa:"2.30 feet",opb:"2.43 feet",opc:"2.48 feet",opd:"2.57 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the basic concept of GMDSS?",opa:"Search and rescue authorities ashore can be alerted to a distress situation.",opb:"Shipping in the immediate vicinity of a ship in distress will be rapidly alerted.",opc:"Shoreside authorities and vessels can assist in a coordinated SAR operation with minimum delay.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"While the COASTAL DRILLER is elevated, the out-of-level alarm indicates that hull inclination exceeds 0.3\xb0. What should you do?",opa:"Raise the high corner.",opb:"Raise the low corner.",opc:"Raise unit to proper air gap and inspect for damage.",opd:"Confirm operation of out-of-level alarm.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A life preserver or buoyant work vest is required to be worn on a MODU when a person is ____________.",opa:"working on the rig floor",opb:"working over water",opc:"working on the pipe racks",opd:"operating line throwing equipment",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel aground may have negative GM since the ____________.",opa:"decrease in KM is equal to the loss of draft",opb:"virtual rise of G is directly proportional to the remaining draft",opc:"displacement lost acts at the point where the ship is aground",opd:"lost buoyancy method is used to calculate KM, and KB is reduced",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are releasing carbon dioxide gas (CO2) into an engine compartment to extinguish a fire. The CO2 will be most effective if the ____________.",opa:"compartment is closed and ventilators are opened",opb:"compartment is left open to the air",opc:"compartment is closed and airtight",opd:"air flow to the compartment is increased with blowers",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in transit with winds expected to exceed 70 knots, must lower the legs to 60.5 feet below the hull in order to meet the requirements for leg strength and ____________.",opa:"stability",opb:"variable load",opc:"environmental load",opd:"load line",ans:"opa"},{question:"For the DEEP DRILLER, it is recommended that the number of lower hull ballast tanks with free surfaces be less than ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"4",opc:"6",opd:"8",ans:"opc"},{question:"For optimum stability during jacking operations, mat ballast tanks or spud cans should be ____________.",opa:"empty",opb:"fully ballasted",opc:"partially ballasted",opd:"sealed",ans:"opb"},{question:"The transverse distance between draft marks for the DEEP DRILLER is ____________.",opa:"122'-09'",opb:"164'-00'",opc:"217'-01'",opd:"260'-05'",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fire extinguishing agents used on Class C fires must be ____________.",opa:"able to absorb heat",opb:"water based",opc:"nonconducting",opd:"nontoxic",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"444 tons",opb:"644 tons",opc:"1044 tons",opd:"1263 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The stamped full weight of a 100-lb. CO2 bottle is 314 lbs. What is the minimum weight of the bottle before it has to be recharged?",opa:"282 lbs.",opb:"294 lbs.",opc:"300 lbs.",opd:"304 lbs.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which item is NOT required to be marked with the vessel's name?",opa:"Hand-portable fire extinguisher",opb:"Life preserver",opc:"Immersion suit",opd:"Lifeboat oar",ans:"opa"},{question:"The sea painter of a rescue boat should be led ____________.",opa:"forward and outboard of all obstructions",opb:"forward and inboard of all obstructions",opc:"up and down from the main deck",opd:"to the foremost point on the vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement concerning an accidental oil spill in the navigable waters of the U.S. is FALSE?",opa:"The person in charge must report the spill to the Coast Guard.",opb:"Failure to report the spill may result in a fine.",opc:"The company can be fined for the spill.",opd:"The Corps of Engineers is responsible for the clean up of the spill.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Regulations require that access to a cargo pumproom in a tank vessel carrying grade D liquid cargo, shall be ____________.",opa:"away from galleys, living quarters, or navigation spaces",opb:"only from areas equipped with power ventilation systems",opc:"from the open deck",opd:"isolated from sources of vapor ignition",ans:"opc"},{question:"The extinguishing agent most effective for combating wood fires is ____________.",opa:"water",opb:"carbon dioxide",opc:"foam",opd:"dry chemical",ans:"opa"},{question:"After jacking down your liftboat you have an unexpected list. You find that the only cause of this list must be a flooded leg. Your next course of action should be to ____________.",opa:"jack the vessel back up to a safe height",opb:"proceed on to your next destination since the list is unimportant",opc:"pump out all ballast to gain reserve buoyancy",opd:"notify the U. S. Coast Guard",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is an example of a grade B flammable liquid?",opa:"Allyl alcohol",opb:"Phenol",opc:"Acetaldehyde",opd:"Carbon disulfide",ans:"opd"},{question:"The full period of motion of the DEEP DRILLER while in transit is 7 seconds and the maximum pitch angle as seen on the inclinometers is 7\xb0. From the standpoint of critical motion, the motion is ____________.",opa:"satisfactory, keep the unit at transit draft",opb:"satisfactory, put the unit in standby",opc:"unsatisfactory, ballast to survival draft",opd:"unsatisfactory, place unit in standby",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning distress signals in a survival craft?",opa:"Hand held flares and orange smoke signals are required.",opb:"If hand-held rocket-propelled parachute flares are provided, they are the only distress signals required.",opc:"Two hand-held smoke signals shall be provided.",opd:"A Very pistol with twelve flares is required.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The term 'oil' as used in the Oil Pollution Regulations means ____________.",opa:"fuel oil",opb:"sludge",opc:"oil refuse",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When lowering a boat with gravity davits, it will be pulled into the embarkation deck by the ____________.",opa:"falls",opb:"tricing pendants",opc:"frapping lines",opd:"boat hooks",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). How much more variable load in kips can be placed on the unit if winds increase to greater than 70 knots?",opa:"0 kips",opb:"200 kips",opc:"600 kips",opd:"1,000 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"All inlet and discharge fittings below the waterline shall have ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"cast-iron shut-off valves",opb:"a wooden plug with a 36 inch lanyard",opc:"an efficient and accessible means of closing",opd:"a blank-off flange of similar material",ans:"opc"},{question:"For a MODU with transverse inclination, an increase in GMT causes ____________.",opa:"list to stabilize at an angle of loll",opb:"list to decrease",opc:"trim to decrease",opd:"list to increase",ans:"opb"},{question:"The tank barge on which you are preparing to load petroleum is required to have onboard one B-II fire extinguisher. What does NOT meet this requirement?",opa:"2-1/2 gallon foam",opb:"5 gallon water (stored pressure)",opc:"10 pound dry chemical",opd:"15 pound CO2",ans:"opb"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, a fire drill must be conducted at least once a ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"month",opc:"quarter",opd:"year",ans:"opa"},{question:"The device that allows a floating MODU to sway without bending the marine riser system is the ____________.",opa:"yaw joint",opb:"sway joint",opc:"slip joint",opd:"flex or ball joint",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have 590 tons of below deck tonnage. There is no liquid mud aboard. If you have 84 tons of cargo above deck with a VCG above the deck of 2.7 feet, what is the maximum allowed VCG of the remainder of the deck cargo that is permitted? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson)",opa:"2.54 feet",opb:"2.85 feet",opc:"3.11 feet",opd:"3.55 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many type B-II hand portable fire extinguishers are required in the machinery space of an uninspected motor vessel with 1,400 BHP? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"5",ans:"opa"},{question:"On small passenger vessels gasoline tanks must be ____________.",opa:"electrically bonded to a common ground",opb:"fitted with vertical baffle plates if the tank is longer than 30 inches in any horizontal dimension",opc:"built without flanged-up top edges",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A link on an anchor chain should be replaced when wear or grinding of surface cracks has reduced the cross section area by ____________.",opa:"0.04",opb:"0.06",opc:"0.08",opd:"0.1",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are loading in a port subject to the winter load line mark and bound for a port subject to the summer load line mark. You will enter the summer zone after steaming six days. You will consume 32 tons of fuel, water, and stores per day. The hydrometer reading at the loading pier is 1.005, and the average TPI is 65. What is the minimum freeboard required at the start of the voyage?",opa:"93 inches",opb:"90 inches",opc:"81 inches",opd:"70 inches",ans:"opc"},{question:"A crew member suddenly becomes blind in both eyes. Which code should your message contain?",opa:"MNJ",opb:"MNM",opc:"MNO",opd:"MNI",ans:"opc"},{question:"A tankerman who permits or causes oil to go into a navigable waterway may be punished federally by ____________.",opa:"fine",opb:"imprisonment",opc:"suspension or revocation of tankerman's document",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The canvas covering of fire hose is called the ____________.",opa:"casing",opb:"outer hose",opc:"line cover",opd:"jacket",ans:"opd"},{question:"A person on a fixed or floating platform engaged in oil exploration MAY discharge food waste into the sea when the distance from the nearest land is at least ____________.",opa:"3 nautical miles",opb:"5 nautical miles",opc:"12 nautical miles",opd:"25 nautical miles",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Emergency Position Indicating Radio beacon on a cargo vessel must be stowed ____________.",opa:"in an inside passageway",opb:"in an approved bracket",opc:"so that it is accessible from the bridge of the vessel",opd:"so that it will float free if the vessel sinks",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should longitude 116\xb054.9'E be written when preparing an AMVER report?",opa:"Q1169",opb:"116.9E",opc:"11655E",opd:"117E",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #1 (Transit), suffers minor damage which results in flooding in tank 1S. You may pump from ____________.",opa:"2S",opb:"C1S",opc:"1S",opd:"10P",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is an advantage of the 6x19 class of wire rope over the 6x37 class of wire rope of the same diameter?",opa:"Greater holding power",opb:"Better fatigue life",opc:"Resistance to elongation",opd:"Resistance to corrosion",ans:"opd"},{question:"Line throwing apparatus aboard ship must contain ____________.",opa:"two rockets, one of which shall be the buoyant type",opb:"three rockets, one of which shall be the buoyant type",opc:"four rockets, two of which shall be the buoyant type",opd:"five rockets, two of which shall be the buoyant type",ans:"opc"},{question:"Fire protection regulations for towing vessels allow you to use a nonmetallic flexible hose in fuel line installations under all of the following conditions EXCEPT when ____________.",opa:"used in lengths of not more than 30 inches",opb:"reinforced with wire braid",opc:"visible and easily accessible",opd:"fitted with Coast Guard approved garden hose fittings",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of plan is used to outline the vessel\u2019s fire fighting arrangement within the fire control plan?",opa:"Partial",opb:"Inboard profile",opc:"Subdivision and stability",opd:"General arrangement",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which operation should be done when launching an inflatable liferaft by hand?",opa:"Open the liferaft casing.",opb:"Turn the valve on the CO2 cylinder to start inflation.",opc:"Make sure the operating cord is secured to the vessel before throwing it over the side.",opd:"After inflation, detach operating cord from liferaft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged, and there is no list or trim. The rolling period is short. The freeboard before the damage was 12'02' (3.7 meters). It is now reduced to 3'00'(1 meter). Which action would you take FIRST?",opa:"Press up a slack centerline double bottom tank",opb:"Pump out an amidships centerline ballast tank",opc:"Transfer ballast from the peak tanks to an amidships centerline tank",opd:"Pump out the marine potable tank located on the starboard side amidships",ans:"opb"},{question:"Inflatable liferafts must be overhauled and inspected at a U.S. Coast Guard approved service facility every ____________.",opa:"six months",opb:"twelve months",opc:"eighteen months",opd:"twenty-four months",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, while drilling, has a total weight of 15,400 kips. The LCG is 120.00 feet AF0, and the TCG is -0.5 feet to port of the centerline. What is the bow leg reaction?",opa:"4,737 kips",opb:"4,916 kips",opc:"5,063 kips",opd:"5,145 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"While in ocean transit, the COASTAL DRILLER experiences a single amplitude roll of 5 degrees. What is the minimum roll period that does not exceed the design limits of the legs?",opa:"2.7 seconds",opb:"4.0 seconds",opc:"6.5 seconds",opd:"7.2 seconds",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which should NOT be a treatment for a person who has received a head injury and is groggy or unconscious?",opa:"Give a stimulant.",opb:"Elevate his head.",opc:"Stop severe bleeding.",opd:"Treat for shock.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning a motor lifeboat?",opa:"It is propelled by engine or hand-propelling gear.",opb:"It has a sufficient fuel capacity, if motorized, for 48 hours of operation.",opc:"It must be able to maintain a loaded speed of 6 knots.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Structural bulkheads on a MODU are usually ____________.",opa:"continuous",opb:"watertight",opc:"transverse",opd:"non-watertight",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a vessel is inclined at a small angle the center of buoyancy will ____________.",opa:"remain stationary",opb:"move toward the low side",opc:"move toward the high side",opd:"move to the height of the metacenter",ans:"opb"},{question:"The officer responsible for the sanitary condition of the engineering department is the ____________.",opa:"Master",opb:"Chief Mate",opc:"Chief Engineer",opd:"First Assistant",ans:"opc"},{question:"The air spaces in the floor of an inflatable liferaft will provide protection against ____________.",opa:"asphyxiation from CO2",opb:"loss of air in the sides of the raft",opc:"rough seas",opd:"cold water temperatures",ans:"opd"},{question:"The danger of a charged hose left unattended on deck with the nozzle open is ____________.",opa:"the hose could burst",opb:"the nozzle end will whip about causing damage or injury",opc:"water damage to vessel's cargo or structure",opd:"personnel might trip over the hose",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 22'-04', AFT 22'-10'; and the KG is 22.6 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 45\xb0 inclination.",opa:"1.8 feet",opb:"2.6 feet",opc:"2.9 feet",opd:"3.6 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"When electrical equipment is involved in a fire, the stream of dry chemicals should be ____________.",opa:"aimed at the source of the flames",opb:"fogged above the equipment",opc:"shot off a flat surface onto the flames",opd:"used to shield against electrical shock",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of limber holes?",opa:"To allow for air circulation",opb:"To allow for stress and strain in rough waters",opc:"To allow water in the boat to drain overboard",opd:"To allow water in the bilge to get to the boat drain",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 40,301 foot-long tons, TM = 3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons. What is the KG corrected for longitudinal free surface effects?",opa:"53.78 feet",opb:"54.82 feet",opc:"55.47 feet",opd:"56.01 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which single-letter sound signal(s) may only be made in compliance with the Rules of the Road?",opa:"D",opb:"E",opc:"S",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following describes why topside icing, which is usually off-center, decreases vessel stability?",opa:"increases displacement",opb:"it increases the height of the center of gravity",opc:"it increases draft",opd:"reduces the pocketing of free surface",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What is the margin on the maximum allowable KG if winds increase to greater than 70 knots, and the TOC is changed to the recommended value?",opa:"0.0 foot",opb:"1.0 foot",opc:"37.0 feet",opd:"38.0 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The liquid mud tanks on your vessel measure 24'L by 16'B by 8'D. The vessel's displacement in salt water (specific gravity 1.025) is 864 T and the specific gravity of the mud is 1.47. What is the reduction in GM due to 2 of these tanks being slack?",opa:"0.32 foot",opb:"0.78 foot",opc:"0.96 foot",opd:"1.12 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Motor-propelled lifeboats are required to have sufficient fuel to operate continuously at 6 knots for how many hours?",opa:"6",opb:"12",opc:"18",opd:"24",ans:"opd"},{question:"As the displacement of a vessel increases, the detrimental effect of free surface ____________.",opa:"increases",opb:"decreases",opc:"remains the same",opd:"may increase or decrease depending on the fineness of the vessel's form",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which topic is NOT required to be discussed at the pre-transfer conference?",opa:"Identity of the product to be transferred",opb:"Details of transferring and receiving systems",opc:"Emergency shutdown procedures",opd:"Estimated time of finishing cargo",ans:"opd"},{question:"The sails are properly set and trimmed. As a vessel heads up from a beam reach to close hauled the ____________.",opa:"apparent wind moves forward",opb:"heeling moment decreases",opc:"side slip decreases",opd:"speed increases",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each cylinder in a two stroke cycle engine experiences combustion ____________.",opa:"once each crankshaft revolution",opb:"twice each crankshaft revolution",opc:"every other crankshaft revolution",opd:"every fourth stroke",ans:"opa"},{question:"Obstruction lights on mobile offshore drilling units on the waters of the U.S. Outer Continental Shelf must be displayed ____________.",opa:"at all times",opb:"between sunset and sunrise",opc:"whenever visibility is restricted",opd:"whenever vessels approach within one-half mile",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). If weather conditions make it necessary to ballast down to survival, how much ballast would be required?",opa:"3,998.3 long tons",opb:"4,086.5 long tons",opc:"4,188.0 long tons",opd:"5,087.0 long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 14'-11', AFT 16'-01'; and the KG is 24.4 feet. What is the righting moment when the vessel is inclined to 30\xb0? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"24,960 foot-tons",opb:"22,870 foot-tons",opc:"20,360 foot-tons",opd:"18,240 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you see an individual fall overboard, you should ____________.",opa:"throw him/her a life buoy",opb:"hail 'man overboard'",opc:"pass the word to the bridge",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER arrived in port with drafts of: FWD 21'-06.5', AFT 23'-05.4'. Cargo was loaded and discharged as shown. Use sheet 2 in the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts.",opa:"FWD 21'-07.1', AFT23'-08.9'",opb:"FWD 21'-05.9', AFT23'-01.9'",opc:"FWD 21'-03.0', AFT23'-04.8'",opd:"FWD 21'-10.0', AFT23'-06.0'",ans:"opd"},{question:"In how many locations must lifeboats be installed on a mobile offshore drilling unit?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"Fire protection regulations for towing vessels require all crew members to know how to perform each of these tasks EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"start the mechanical ventilation system for the engine room",opb:"operate the fuel shut-off for the engine room",opc:"operate all fire extinguishing equipment aboard the vessel onboard the vessel, including starting the fire pump",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"In how many locations must lifeboats be installed on a mobile offshore drilling unit?",opa:"4",opb:"3",opc:"2",opd:"1",ans:"opc"},{question:"On small passenger vessels cooking and heating equipment ____________.",opa:"shall be suitable for marine use",opb:"may use liquefied petroleum gas",opc:"cannot use gasoline",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which fire control plan symbol(s) represents the agent or device best suited for extinguishing a class 'B' fire?",opa:"16 and 47",opb:"16 and 36",opc:"47",opd:"26",ans:"opb"},{question:"How should signal flares be used after you have abandoned ship and are adrift in a liferaft?",opa:"Immediately use all the signals at once.",opb:"Use all the signals during the first night.",opc:"Employ a signal every hour after abandoning ship until they are gone.",opd:"Use them only when you are aware of a ship or plane in the area.",ans:"opd"},{question:"No outlet on a fire hydrant may point above the horizontal in order to ____________.",opa:"avoid kinking the hose",opb:"avoid personal injury during connection",opc:"make connecting easier",opd:"prevent spray on electrical equipment",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel heading SW is on a course of ____________.",opa:"202.5\xb0",opb:"225.0\xb0",opc:"247.5\xb0",opd:"270.0\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"For a MODU with longitudinal inclination, an increase in GML causes ____________.",opa:"list to stabilize at an angle of loll",opb:"trim to stabilize at an angle of loll",opc:"trim to increase",opd:"trim to decrease",ans:"opd"},{question:"What could be a result of insufficient lubrication of lifeboat winches and davits?",opa:"Moisture accumulation in winch motor damaging the electrical wiring",opb:"Freezing of gears in cold weather",opc:"Corroding of sheaves on the davits so they will not rotate",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER will sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts.",opa:"FWD 27'-01', AFT25'-08'",opb:"FWD 29'-09', AFT25'-09'",opc:"FWD 25'-09', AFT30'-05'",opd:"FWD 25'-06', AFT30'-00'",ans:"opd"},{question:"Damage stability is the stability ____________.",opa:"which exists when the wind speed is less than 50 knots",opb:"before collision",opc:"after flooding",opd:"at the maximum load",ans:"opc"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, the EPIRB onboard is required to be tested ____________.",opa:"daily",opb:"weekly",opc:"monthly",opd:"yearly",ans:"opc"},{question:"If there is unsafe machinery on a mobile offshore drilling unit, who is responsible for reporting the existence of the unsafe condition to the Coast Guard?",opa:"The chief mechanic",opb:"The port engineer",opc:"The rig superintendent",opd:"The designated person in charge",ans:"opd"},{question:"When evacuating the DEEP DRILLER, preparations should include ____________.",opa:"putting the unit at transit draft",opb:"activating the emergency power system",opc:"jettisoning all combustible materials",opd:"removing all tension from the mooring lines",ans:"opb"},{question:"Fire extinguishers of sizes III, IV, and V are designated as ____________.",opa:"portable",opb:"semi-portable",opc:"fixed",opd:"disposable",ans:"opb"},{question:"The required fireman's outfits required for MODU's are not to be used for any other purpose EXCEPT for the ____________.",opa:"oxygen and explosion meter when it is used for detection of flare gases",opb:"self-contained breathing apparatus, when used as protection from gas leaking from a refrigeration unit",opc:"boots and gloves that are made of rubber or electrically non-conductive material, if used when repairing electrical equipment",opd:"lifeline, if used by personnel entering a compartment which might be deficient of oxygen",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vertical shift of weight to a position above the vessel's center of gravity will ____________.",opa:"increase reserve buoyancy",opb:"decrease the righting moments",opc:"decrease KG",opd:"increase KM",ans:"opb"},{question:"The breaking strength of the service lines of the rockets used with an impulse-projected, rocket type line throwing appliances is ____________.",opa:"300 lbs.",opb:"500 lbs.",opc:"1000 lbs.",opd:"1500 lbs.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What does the 'B' on a 'B-II' fire extinguisher refer to? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"Size of the applicator",opb:"Size of the nozzle",opc:"Size of the extinguisher",opd:"Class of fire that the extinguisher should be used on",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is under tow at a 20 foot draft. The rig motions are close to exceeding the limits for critical pitch and roll. The rig is also experiencing occasional pounding on the horizontal braces. In this situation you should ____________.",opa:"ballast down to a 45 foot draft and check vessel motions",opb:"wait until pitch and roll exceed the limits before ballasting down",opc:"ballast up to a 15 foot draft and check vessel motions",opd:"shorten the tow wire for a smoother tow",ans:"opa"},{question:"What should be done after repairing a surface crack on a link of anchor chain by grinding?",opa:"Examine the area by magnetic particle inspection",opb:"Replace the chain in service",opc:"Galvanize the area",opd:"Post heat the area",ans:"opa"},{question:"The number of certificated able seamen and lifeboatmen required on a MODU is determined by the ____________.",opa:"Minerals Management Service",opb:"Corps of Engineers",opc:"Coast Guard",opd:"American Bureau of Shipping",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statements is/are FALSE in regard to Ro-Ro vessels' spaces that are 'specially suitable for vehicles'?",opa:"The spaces shall be fitted with an approved fire or smoke detecting system.",opb:"The spaces shall NOT be fitted with fixed CO2 fire extinguishing systems.",opc:"The Commandant may permit the installation of an approved water sprinkler extinguishing system.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The moment created by a force of 12,000 tons and a moment arm of 0.25 foot is ____________.",opa:"48,000 ft.-tons",opb:"6,000 ft.-tons",opc:"3,000 ft.-tons",opd:"0 ft.-tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the water depth is 500 feet, the length of the pendant wire from the anchor to the buoy is typically ____________.",opa:"400 feet",opb:"500 feet",opc:"600 feet",opd:"1000 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.6 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.3 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.1 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A foam-type portable fire extinguisher would be most useful in combating a fire in ____________.",opa:"solid materials such as wood or bales of fiber",opb:"flammable liquids",opc:"a piece of electrical equipment",opd:"combustible metallic solids",ans:"opb"},{question:"What quality of a diesel fuel is most significant for efficient combustion?",opa:"Volatility",opb:"Viscosity",opc:"Flash point",opd:"Specific heat",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you must jump from a vessel, the correct posture includes ____________.",opa:"holding down the life preserver against the chest with one arm crossing the other, covering the mouth and nose with a hand, and feet together",opb:"knees bent and held close to the body with both arms around legs",opc:"body straight and arms held tightly at the sides for feet first entry into the water",opd:"both hands holding the life preserver below the chin with knees bent and legs crossed",ans:"opa"},{question:"The plans, for use during emergencies aboard the DEEP DRILLER, are readily available in the ____________.",opa:"wheelhouse under glass",opb:"pump room",opc:"OIM's office",opd:"ballast control room",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the entire contents of bulk tanks #2 and #3 are back-loaded to an offshore supply vessel, what would be the new draft?",opa:"11.04 feet",opb:"10.88 feet",opc:"10.72 feet",opd:"9.02 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are fighting a class 'B' fire with a portable dry chemical extinguisher. The discharge should be directed ____________.",opa:"to bank off a bulkhead onto the fire",opb:"at the seat of the fire, starting at the near edge",opc:"over the top of the fire",opd:"at the main body of the fire",ans:"opb"},{question:"In deballasting to survival draft because of extreme wind and wave loads, thrusters or propulsion, if available, should be used to ____________.",opa:"reduce windward mooring line tensions",opb:"reduce leeward mooring line tensions",opc:"increase leeward mooring line tensions",opd:"maintain constant mooring line tensions",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #3 (Preparing to Drill). What is the margin on the maximum allowable KG while drilling?",opa:"4.58 feet",opb:"5.24 feet",opc:"6.27 feet",opd:"6.94 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"What must be mounted at a small passenger vessel's operating station for use by the Master and crew?",opa:"Emergency Instructions",opb:"A tide table for the area",opc:"Instructions on artificial respiration",opd:"The location of the first aid kit",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of the limit switch on gravity davits?",opa:"To cut off the power when the davits hit the track safety stops",opb:"To stop the davits from going too fast",opc:"To cut off the power when the davits are about 12 inches or more from the track safety stops",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are FWD 20'-08', AFT 23'-00'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if 95 tons of cargo are loaded 76 feet forward of amidships.",opa:"FWD 21'-01', AFT22'-11'",opb:"FWD 20'-09', AFT22'-09'",opc:"FWD 20'-09', AFT23'-01'",opd:"FWD 20'-08', AFT23'-00'",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a MODU, hand portable extinguishers are size(s) ____________.",opa:"II only",opb:"II and III",opc:"I and II",opd:"I only",ans:"opc"},{question:"In order to determine the fire and explosion hazard data for naphtha, you would use that information contained in the Chemical Data Guide for which chemical?",opa:"Treacle",opb:"Napthalene",opc:"Tar camphor",opd:"Mineral spirits",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers major damage which results in flooding in tank C1P. Your best countermeasure is to ____________.",opa:"pump from 2P",opb:"pump from C1P",opc:"counter flood in 1P",opd:"counter flood in 10S",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each EPIRB required on a MODU shall be stowed in a manner which will permit ____________.",opa:"easy access to its storage compartment",opb:"replacement of the battery without exposure to the weather",opc:"it to float free if the unit sinks",opd:"it to remain attached to the unit",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to the regulations, to prevent excessive pressure buildup in cargo tanks containing LFG, they are fitted with ____________.",opa:"pressure vacuum relief valves",opb:"excess flow valves",opc:"safety relief valves",opd:"flame screens",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your cargo vessel's Certification of Inspection expires 30 April 2002. One of your inflatable liferafts was last serviced in January 2002. The raft must be reinspected no later than ____________.",opa:"3-Jan",opb:"3-Jun",opc:"4-Apr",opd:"7-Jan",ans:"opa"},{question:"In commercial fishing, 'cold water' means water where the monthly mean low water temperature is normally ____________.",opa:"39\xb0Fahrenheit or less",opb:"44\xb0Fahrenheit or less",opc:"49\xb0Fahrenheit or less",opd:"59\xb0Fahrenheit or less",ans:"opd"},{question:"On the COASTAL DRILLER, a noticeable increase in the level indicator while extracting the legs from the soil indicates ____________.",opa:"the legs are free",opb:"one or two legs are stuck",opc:"a punch-through is occurring",opd:"the legs are being extracted through a punch-through soil layer",ans:"opb"},{question:"When possible, what is the FIRST step in fighting an engine fuel-pump fire which results from a broken fuel line?",opa:"Secure all engine room doors, hatches, and vents.",opb:"Close the fuel line valve.",opc:"Check the spread of the fire with foam.",opd:"Cast the barge off the wharf.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the flash points would indicate a grade D combustible liquid?",opa:"65\xb0F",opb:"87\xb0F",opc:"155\xb0F",opd:"160\xb0F",ans:"opb"},{question:"Inflatable liferafts are provided with ____________.",opa:"a portable radio",opb:"an oil lantern",opc:"canned milk",opd:"a towing connection",ans:"opd"},{question:"What are the additional vertical moments created when P-tank #4 in the DEEP DRILLER sample load form #1 (Transit) is completely filled?",opa:"2,252 foot-tons",opb:"9,413 foot-tons",opc:"11,665 foot-tons",opd:"13,917 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The lubber's line of a magnetic compass ____________.",opa:"always shows true north direction",opb:"indicates the vessel's heading",opc:"is always parallel to the vessel's transom",opd:"is located on the compass card",ans:"opb"},{question:"A jack-up 180 feet in length with the LCF at 120 feet AFO has a draft of 8 feet at the bow and 11 feet at the stern. What is the trim by the stern?",opa:"2.0 feet",opb:"2.4 feet",opc:"3.0 feet",opd:"6.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 3200 tons of cargo, 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 323 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in salt water.",opa:"17'-00'",opb:"16'-10'",opc:"16'-07'",opd:"16'-04'",ans:"opd"},{question:"When must a dry chemical fire extinguisher be recharged?",opa:"After each use",opb:"When the air temperature exceeds 90\xb0F",opc:"Every 6 months",opd:"Every 12 months",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about entry into a space that has been sealed for a long time is TRUE?",opa:"A tank that has been used to carry hazardous liquids should be tested for oxygen content, toxicity, and explosive gases.",opb:"You can safely enter the space without a breathing apparatus if the oxygen content exceeds 14%.",opc:"The natural ventilation through the installed vents is sufficient to provide the proper oxygen content.",opd:"The heat of the sun on upper ballast tanks, such as in a bulk carrier, may generate carbon monoxide.",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a vessel of 10,000 tons displacement, compute the reduction in metacentric height due to free surface in a hold having free water on tank tops. The hold is 50 feet long and 50 feet wide. The reduction in metacentric height is ____________.",opa:"1.2 feet",opb:"1.1 feet",opc:"1.3 feet",opd:"1.5 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"If the hydrostatic release mechanism for an inflatable liferaft is not periodically serviced and becomes inoperable, it will fail to ____________.",opa:"set the water lights on immersion",opb:"release the dye marker from the liferaft",opc:"free the liferaft from the vessel",opd:"break the seal on the carbon dioxide cylinder",ans:"opc"},{question:"When anchoring in an area with a hard bottom, the fluke angle of an anchor should be set at ____________.",opa:"20\xb0",opb:"30\xb0",opc:"40\xb0",opd:"50\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is TRUE concerning frapping lines?",opa:"They are used to steady a lifeboat when lowered.",opb:"They are normally attached to the davit span.",opc:"They are needed only on radial davits.",opd:"They are used to clear the puddings.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What is the new Longitudinal Free Surface Correction (FSCL) if the entire contents of drill water tanks 6 and 7 are discharged?",opa:"2.24 feet",opb:"2.14 feet",opc:"2.10 feet",opd:"1.63 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to 46 CFR Subchapter T the definition of a ferry includes vessels that ____________.",opa:"operate in other than ocean or coastwise service",opb:"have provisions only for deck passengers, vehicles, or both",opc:"operate on a short run on a frequent schedule between two points over the most direct water route",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which flash point would indicate a grade D combustible liquid?",opa:"40\xb0F",opb:"95\xb0F",opc:"79\xb0F",opd:"155\xb0F",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the COASTAL DRILLER, in case the bilge discharge is oily, the bilge water should be discharged through the ____________.",opa:"overboard discharge",opb:"dump valves",opc:"skimmer tank",opd:"sump valves",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a patient has an electrical burn, it is important to ____________.",opa:"look for a second burn, which may have been caused by the current passing through the body",opb:"locate the nearest water source and flood the burn with water for five minutes",opc:"remove any dirt or charred skin from the area of the burn",opd:"apply ointment to the burn area and wrap with clean cloth",ans:"opa"},{question:"An important step in fighting any electrical fire is to ____________.",opa:"stop ventilation",opb:"stop the vessel",opc:"de-energize the circuit",opd:"apply water to extinguish the fire",ans:"opc"},{question:"In order to withstand fluid head pressure on a MODU, stiffeners are often attached to the bulkhead ____________.",opa:"penetrations",opb:"plating",opc:"framing",opd:"brackets",ans:"opb"},{question:"Steam driven pumps are considered, by regulations, sources of vapor ignition if the steam temperature is at least ____________.",opa:"100\xb0C",opb:"212\xb0F",opc:"500\xb0F",opd:"1200\xb0F",ans:"opc"},{question:"The solid arrow in the Crew Mess represents ____________.",opa:"path of forced ventilation",opb:"search and rescue route",opc:"nearest door",opd:"primary means of escape",ans:"opd"},{question:"CO2 extinguishes a fire by ____________.",opa:"cooling",opb:"smothering",opc:"chemical action",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are in a lifeboat when you sight the stars indicated in illustration D005SA. You will be heading due north when you head for Polaris which is indicated by what letter?",opa:"A",opb:"C",opc:"E",opd:"I",ans:"opc"},{question:"The sails are properly set and trimmed. As a vessel heads up from a beam reach to close hauled the ____________.",opa:"speed increases",opb:"side slip decreases",opc:"heeling moment decreases",opd:"apparent wind moves forward",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which equipment is the primary source of generating a locating signal?",opa:"DSC only",opb:"DSC and EPIRB",opc:"SART and DSC",opd:"EPIRB and SART",ans:"opd"},{question:"Heavy fuel oils when spilled are ____________.",opa:"more harmful to sea life than lighter oils",opb:"easier to clean up than lighter refined oils",opc:"less harmful to sea life than lighter oils",opd:"not a real threat to marine life",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many B-II hand portable fire extinguishers are required in the machinery space of a 260 GT tow vessel with 2400 B.H.P.? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"6",opb:"5",opc:"3",opd:"2",ans:"opc"},{question:"When should a fire be ventilated?",opa:"When attacking the fire directly",opb:"When using a steam smothering system",opc:"When using the fixed CO2 system",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each pressure gauge used in an oil transfer operation must be accurate to within ____________.",opa:"1 percent",opb:"3 percent",opc:"5 percent",opd:"10 percent",ans:"opd"},{question:"While the COASTAL DRILLER is in a normal transit, the roll period is 9 seconds. What is the limiting angle of roll which does not exceed the design limits of the legs?",opa:"11\xb0",opb:"9\xb0",opc:"7\xb0",opd:"5\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel must have a B-II fire extinguisher. Which extinguisher fulfills this requirement? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"4 lb. carbon dioxide",opb:"4 lb. dry chemical",opc:"15 lb. carbon dioxide",opd:"12 gallon foam",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should longitude 119\xb056.3'W be written when preparing an AMVER report?",opa:"V19.9",opb:"120\xb0W",opc:"119.9W",opd:"11956W",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the MOST important consideration when determining how to fight an electrical fire?",opa:"Whether the fire is in machinery or passenger spaces",opb:"Danger of shock to personnel",opc:"The amount of toxic fumes created by the extinguisher",opd:"Maintaining electrical power",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are alone and administering CPR to an adult victim. How many chest compressions and how many inflations should you administer in each sequence?",opa:"15 compressions then 2 inflations",opb:"15 compressions then 4 inflations",opc:"30 compressions then 2 inflations",opd:"30 compressions then 4 inflations",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 22.4 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 19'-06', AFT 20'-00'.",opa:"12\xb0",opb:"24\xb0",opc:"48\xb0",opd:"52\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"CO2 cylinders, which protect the small space in which they are stored must ____________.",opa:"NOT contain more than 200 pounds of CO2",opb:"be automatically operated by a heat actuator",opc:"have an audible alarm",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"In storm conditions, with the wind and waves from the port bow of the DEEP DRILLER in 600 feet water depth, the offset is 9%. Completely slacking mooring lines 5 and 6 reduces the offset to ____________.",opa:"0.065",opb:"0.05",opc:"0.025",opd:"0",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you wear extra clothing when entering the water after abandoning a MODU it will ____________.",opa:"weigh you down",opb:"preserve body heat",opc:"reduce your body heat",opd:"make it more difficult to breathe",ans:"opb"},{question:"In the analysis of damaged stability for the DEEP DRILLER, disregarded are the beneficial effects of moorings and ____________.",opa:"horizontal area of the platform",opb:"vertical area of the platform",opc:"countermeasures",opd:"wind strength",ans:"opc"},{question:"Upon release to the atmosphere, LFG readily ____________.",opa:"vaporizes",opb:"attacks caustically",opc:"rises",opd:"attacks corrosively",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you desired to communicate with another station that your navigation lights were not functioning, you would send ____________.",opa:"PB",opb:"PD1",opc:"MJ",opd:"LN1",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act', your radiotelephone log must contain ____________.",opa:"a record of all routine calls",opb:"a record of your transmissions only",opc:"the home address of the vessel's Master or owner",opd:"a summary of all distress calls and messages",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each hand portable fire extinguisher on a MODU must be marked with ____________.",opa:"the name of the unit on which it is located",opb:"the date that it was installed on the unit",opc:"the names of the individuals qualified to use it",opd:"an identification number different from other extinguishers on the unit",ans:"opd"},{question:"If a MODU takes a sudden severe list or trim from an unknown cause, you should FIRST ____________.",opa:"determine the cause before taking countermeasures",opb:"assume the shift is due to off-center loading",opc:"counter flood on the side opposite the list or trim",opd:"assume the cause is environmental forces",ans:"opa"},{question:"The forward draft of your ship is 27'-11' and the after draft is 29'-03'. The draft amidships is 28'-05'. Your vessel is ____________.",opa:"hogged",opb:"sagged",opc:"listed",opd:"trimmed by the head",ans:"opa"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, boat drills must be conducted at least ____________.",opa:"monthly",opb:"quarterly",opc:"daily",opd:"annually",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are operating a liftboat. When jacking down and a leg becomes stuck on the bottom, you should ____________.",opa:"raise the free legs all the way",opb:"use the engines to rotate about the leg that is stuck",opc:"jack the barge down part way to pull the leg free",opd:"submerge the barge completely to give added pull",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Preparing to Drill). If the liquid mud in mud pit #4 (see table 8) is dumped, what would be the new height of the center of gravity corrected for longitudinal free surface effects?",opa:"50.29 feet",opb:"53.55 feet",opc:"53.92 feet",opd:"54.24 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Regulations require that venting for cargo tanks in which only grades D or E liquids are to be transported shall, as a MINIMUM, be of which type? (tank barge constructed on or after July 1, 1951)",opa:"Straight vents open to atmosphere",opb:"Individual pressure vacuum relief valves",opc:"Branch vent lines connected to a vent header system",opd:"Gooseneck vents and flame screens",ans:"opd"},{question:"An emergency check-off list is required on vessels carrying six or fewer passengers for hire. The list must contain information on all of the following EXCEPT ____________. (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"precautions for rough weather",opb:"actions required in the event of accident",opc:"procedures for man overboard emergencies",opd:"emergency procedures for fire at sea",ans:"opb"},{question:"The elevating system of the COASTAL DRILLER is normally limited to ____________.",opa:"14,158 kips",opb:"14,400 kips",opc:"17,280 kips",opd:"21,297 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"In order for the automatic lifeboat drain to operate properly ____________.",opa:"the cap should be removed to drain the boat when it is waterborne",opb:"the cage must be free of rubbish or the ball may not seat properly",opc:"there is an automatic ball check located in a siphon tube",opd:"the small lever to release the rubber ball float must be turned counterclockwise",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 4850 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 279.84 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 267.7 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 268.4 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 269.2 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 270.6 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"After abandoning a vessel, water that is consumed within the first 24 hours will ____________.",opa:"pass through the body with little absorbed by the system",opb:"help to prevent fatigue",opc:"quench thirst for only 2 hours",opd:"help to prevent seasickness",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about the free surface correction is TRUE?",opa:"It is added to the uncorrected GM to arrive at the corrected available GM.",opb:"It is obtained by dividing the free surface moments by 12 times the volume of displacement.",opc:"It is obtained by dividing the total free surface by the total vertical moments.",opd:"It is subtracted from the total longitudinal moments before dividing by displacement to find LCG.",ans:"opb"},{question:"On which vessels is GMDSS required?",opa:"All vessels capable of international voyages",opb:"Vessels operating outside of the range of VHF coastal radio stations",opc:"SOLAS Convention ships of 300 gross tonnage or more.",opd:"Coastal vessels of less than 300 gross tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a commercial fishing vessel 78 feet long. At least one of your ring buoys or throwable flotation devices must have a line of what minimum length attached?",opa:"60 feet",opb:"70 feet",opc:"80 feet",opd:"90 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"A liferaft with a capacity of 8 people used in ocean service is required by regulations to carry ____________.",opa:"8 liters of fresh water",opb:"12 units of provisions",opc:"12 liters of fresh water",opd:"24 units of provisions",ans:"opc"},{question:"Curve A in the Design Limits of Legs Chart of the Coastal Driller Operating Manual, shows the operating limits during severe storm conditions during transit based on ____________.",opa:"stability and leg strength",opb:"variable load",opc:"environmental load",opd:"load line",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each OSV must carry ____________.",opa:"one category I 406 Mhz satellite EPIRB",opb:"at least one life buoy on each side of the vessel fitted with a buoyant life line",opc:"at least 12 rocket parachute flares",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"onboard an OSV, the key to the most rapid and effective response to a man overboard situation is ____________.",opa:"switching to hydraulic steering",opb:"a dedicated crew",opc:"good equipment",opd:"good communication",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the trim of a jack-up with a forward draft of 12 feet and an after draft of 13 feet?",opa:"0.5 foot by the stern",opb:"1.0 foot by the stern",opc:"2.0 feet by the stern",opd:"0.5 feet by the head",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a MODU, a door that is required to be marked 'KEEP CLOSED' is designed to ____________.",opa:"prevent the passage of flammable gases",opb:"prevent the passage of poisonous vapors",opc:"delay the spread of heat and flames",opd:"maintain watertight integrity",ans:"opd"},{question:"The length of the steering oar in a lifeboat is ____________.",opa:"shorter than the rowing oars",opb:"the same length as the rowing oars",opc:"longer than the rowing oars",opd:"unrelated to the length of the rowing oars",ans:"opc"},{question:"Grinding to eliminate shallow surface defects should be done ____________.",opa:"parallel to the longitudinal direction of the chain",opb:"perpendicular to the direction of the anchor chain",opc:"diagonally across the link of the anchor chain",opd:"around the circumference of the chain link",ans:"opa"},{question:"One of the principal dangers inherent in liquefied petroleum gas is ____________.",opa:"as it warms up it becomes heavier than air",opb:"the way it reacts with sea water",opc:"the strong odor it produces",opd:"its low temperature causes frostbite or freezing",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER as currently configured is limited to a maximum water depth of ____________.",opa:"400 feet",opb:"600 feet",opc:"800 feet",opd:"1,000 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the most important characteristic of the extinguishing agent in fighting a class 'C' fire?",opa:"Weight",opb:"Temperature",opc:"Electrical nonconductivity",opd:"Cost",ans:"opc"},{question:"Subtracting FSCT from KGT yields ____________.",opa:"BL",opb:"GMT",opc:"FSCT",opd:"KG",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which single-letter sound signal may be made only in compliance with the International Rules of the Road?",opa:"D",opb:"F",opc:"Q",opd:"U",ans:"opa"},{question:"What emergency equipment is NOT found in the Crew Mess in this view of the vessel\u2019s fire control plan?",opa:"Primary Means of Escape",opb:"Fire Alarm",opc:"Heat Sensor",opd:"Smoke Detector",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are administering chest compressions during CPR. Where on the victim's body should the pressure be applied?",opa:"Lower half of the sternum",opb:"Tip of the sternum",opc:"Top half of the sternum",opd:"Left chest over the heart",ans:"opa"},{question:"With no environmental forces on the DEEP DRILLER, the average of the starboard drafts is 59.0 feet, and the average of the port drafts is 61.0 feet. KGT is 52.84 feet. What is the value of TCG?",opa:"-2.00 feet",opb:"-1.00 foot",opc:"-0.16 foot",opd:"-0.10 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"A B-III foam extinguisher contains ____________.",opa:"2-1/2 gallons of foam",opb:"8 gallons of foam",opc:"10 gallons of foam",opd:"12 gallons of foam",ans:"opd"},{question:"Where do fatigue failures of wire rope mooring lines usually occur?",opa:"In the middle part of the line length",opb:"Near the socketed end fitting adjacent to the anchor",opc:"At the point where the line touches the bottom",opd:"At the place the anchor buoy is attached to the line",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). What is the new height of the center of gravity corrected for transverse free surface effects if the entire contents of Salt Water Ballast Tanks 1P and 1S are discharged?",opa:"65.95 feet",opb:"66.85 feet",opc:"67.66 feet",opd:"68.59 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the best indication of the loading of a diesel engine?",opa:"Oil temperature",opb:"Manifold pressure",opc:"Exhaust gas temperature",opd:"Fuel consumption",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the minimum number of people required to safely handle a 1-1/2 inch fire hose?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"Failure of both port-side ballast pumps on the DEEP DRILLER prevents their use. To dewater from the port forward tanks, you should use the ____________.",opa:"port saltwater service pump",opb:"port drill water pump",opc:"port bilge pumps",opd:"starboard ballast pump and crossover system",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which information are you required to report to the Coast Guard when an accident occurs in which loss of life results? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Location of the occurrence",opb:"Number and name of vessel",opc:"Names of owners",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"To turn over a liferaft that is floating upside down, you should pull on the ____________.",opa:"canopy",opb:"manropes",opc:"sea painter",opd:"righting lines",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What is the value of KML if the entire contents of drill water tanks 6 and 7 are discharged?",opa:"253.90 feet",opb:"253.24 feet",opc:"252.92 feet",opd:"252.24 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 220\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"close hauled on the port tack",opb:"close hauled on the starboard tack",opc:"running before the wind",opd:"on a broad reach",ans:"opd"},{question:"The worst atmospheric condition for dispersion of H2S is ____________.",opa:"heavy rain",opb:"gusty winds with rain",opc:"nearly calm, clear nights or early morning",opd:"full sun with high winds",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which item is of the most use in getting a lifeboat away from a moving vessel?",opa:"The falls",opb:"Sea Painter",opc:"Fleming Gear",opd:"Boat Hook",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are loading in a port subject to the winter load line mark and bound for a port subject to the tropical load line mark. You will enter the summer zone after steaming four days, and you will enter the tropical zone after a total of twelve days. You will consume 31 tons of fuel, water, and stores per day. The hydrometer reading at the loading pier is 1.000, and the average TPI is 46. What is the minimum freeboard required at the start of the voyage?",opa:"78 inches",opb:"74 inches",opc:"70 inches",opd:"68 inches",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 968 tons and measures 158'L x 40'B. You ship a large wave on the after deck. What is the reduction to GM due to free surface before the water drains overboard, if the after deck measures 65'L x 40'B and the weight of the water is 80 tons?",opa:"9.14 feet",opb:"9.45 feet",opc:"9.68 feet",opd:"9.87 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"If, for any reason, it is necessary to abandon ship while far out at sea, it is important that the crew members should ____________.",opa:"separate from each other as this will increase the chances of being rescued",opb:"get away from the area because sharks will be attracted to the vessel",opc:"immediately head for the nearest land",opd:"remain together in the area because rescuers will start searching at the vessel's last known position",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER arrived in port with drafts of: FWD 19'-06.6', AFT 20'-05.6'. Cargo was loaded and discharged as shown. Use sheet 2 in the white pages of The Stability Data Reference book to determine the final drafts.",opa:"FWD 20'-06', AFT21'-02'",opb:"FWD 18'-06', AFT19'-09'",opc:"FWD 18'-10', AFT20'-05'",opd:"FWD 20'-03', AFT21'-05'",ans:"opa"},{question:"You will find a limit switch on a ____________.",opa:"liferaft cradle",opb:"radial davit",opc:"sheath-screw davit",opd:"gravity davit",ans:"opd"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 21.8 feet and the drafts are: FWD 23'-05', AFT 24'-04'.",opa:"37\xb0",opb:"31\xb0",opc:"26\xb0",opd:"21\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the new location of the transverse center of gravity if 200 short tons are discharged from 10 feet to port of the centerline on a MODU with TCG 0.7 foot starboard of the centerline, and the displacement is 9,000 short tons?",opa:"0.94 foot starboard of centerline",opb:"0.90 foot starboard of centerline",opc:"0.47 foot port of centerline",opd:"0.23 foot port of centerline",ans:"opa"},{question:"Aboard a vessel, dividing the sum of the vertical moments by the total weight yields the vessel's ____________.",opa:"height of the center of gravity",opb:"vertical moments",opc:"righting moments",opd:"inclining moments",ans:"opa"},{question:"The signal 'AS' when used in signaling by the International Code of Signals means ' ____________ '.",opa:"Over",opb:"Finished with transmission",opc:"Wait",opd:"Repeat this signal",ans:"opc"},{question:"Any person maintaining a listening watch on a bridge-to-bridge radiotelephone must be able to ____________.",opa:"speak English",opb:"repair the unit",opc:"send Morse Code",opd:"speak a language the vessel's crew will understand",ans:"opa"},{question:"Prior to magnetic particle inspection of anchor chain, the chain should be ____________.",opa:"degaussed",opb:"demagnetized",opc:"soaked",opd:"sandblasted",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you are in urgent need of a helicopter, which signal code should you send?",opa:"BR",opb:"BS",opc:"BT1",opd:"BZ",ans:"opa"},{question:"A mobile offshore drilling unit under tow is approaching a fog bank. When should fog signals be started?",opa:"When the towing vessel enters the fog",opb:"When the drilling rig enters the fog",opc:"When the towing vessel can no longer be seen from the rig",opd:"Immediately",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you send a flag hoist of MAJ 8, what information are you conveying?",opa:"The least depth of water in the channel is 8 meters.",opb:"Derelict dangerous to navigation to the north.",opc:"Navigation is closed. You should navigate with caution.",opd:"I have a male age 8 years.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Dry chemical extinguishers may be used on what class of fires?",opa:"A only",opb:"B only",opc:"B and C only",opd:"A, B or C as marked on the extinguisher",ans:"opd"},{question:"The control panel of a fire detection system must have all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"a power-available light",opb:"an audible alarm to notify the crew and identify the origin of the fire",opc:"a means to silence audible alarms while maintaining visible alarm lights",opd:"a way to bypass the entire panel if it malfunctions",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fires of which class would most likely occur in the engine room of a vessel?",opa:"Classes A and B",opb:"Classes B and C",opc:"Classes C and D",opd:"Classes A and D",ans:"opb"},{question:"What should you do with your emergency position indicating radio beacon if you are in a liferaft in a storm?",opa:"Bring it inside the liferaft and leave it on.",opb:"Bring it inside the liferaft and turn it off until the storm passes.",opc:"Leave it outside the liferaft and leave it on.",opd:"Leave it outside the liferaft but turn it off.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are preparing to load fuel oil on a vessel of 1,600 gross tons constructed after June 30, 1974. Before loading, you must check that the fuel oil tank vents ____________.",opa:"are not obstructed by on-deck cargo",opb:"have a fire extinguisher within the immediate area",opc:"have containment capacity for at least one barrel",opd:"are opened and the flame screen replaced",ans:"opc"},{question:"A 98 GT uninspected towing vessel with a 1500 B.H.P. engine capability would be required to carry how many type B-II hand portable fire extinguishers onboard? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"2",opb:"4",opc:"6",opd:"8",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 17'-05', AFT 19'-07'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"0.62 foot",opb:"0.80 foot",opc:"0.85 foot",opd:"0.99 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"The maximum length allowed between main, transverse bulkheads on a vessel is referred to as the ____________.",opa:"floodable length",opb:"factor of subdivision",opc:"compartment standard",opd:"permissible length",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the principle behind dynamic braking as used on an anchor windlass?",opa:"Electrical loading",opb:"Mechanical distribution",opc:"Compressibility of air",opd:"Mechanical friction",ans:"opa"},{question:"An effective method for moving patients with spinal injuries onto a spine board is known as the ____________.",opa:"pack-strap carry",opb:"two man extremities carry",opc:"fireman's drag",opd:"four man log roll",ans:"opd"},{question:"The sails are properly set and trimmed. As a vessel heads up from a beam reach to close hauled the ____________.",opa:"apparent wind moves aft",opb:"heeling moment increases",opc:"side slip decreases",opd:"mainsheet must be eased",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the most vulnerable part of the fire main system?",opa:"The fire pump",opb:"Exposed hard piping",opc:"The hydrant valve",opd:"The fire hose",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Although winds are less than 70 knots, excessive motion requires ballasting to survival draft. Assume that 4087 long tons of ballast are added at an average VCG of 8.32 feet, and upon arrival at 45 feet, port and starboard ballast tanks 1, 3, and 8 are slack. What will be the new margin on the maximum allowable KG?",opa:"7.08 feet",opb:"8.12 feet",opc:"8.44 feet",opd:"8.96 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the procedure for checking for spinal cord damage in an unconscious patient?",opa:"Beginning at the back of the neck, and proceeding to the buttocks, press the spine to find where it hurts",opb:"Prick the skin of the hands and the soles of the feet with a sharp object to check for reaction",opc:"Selectively raise each arm and each leg and watch patient's face to see if he registers pain",opd:"Roll patient onto his stomach and prick along the length of his spine to check reaction",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER will sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts.",opa:"FWD 26'-06', AFT28'-10'",opb:"FWD 26'-10', AFT28'-05'",opc:"FWD 27'-00', AFT28'-03'",opd:"FWD 27'-03', AFT28'-00'",ans:"opc"},{question:"If another station sent you the signal 'KG', he would be ____________.",opa:"telling you to stay clear",opb:"telling you he has flooded a hold",opc:"asking you if you needed a tug",opd:"telling you he found an aircraft wreckage",ans:"opc"},{question:"A violation of the 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act' may result in a ____________.",opa:"civil penalty of $650 against the Master or person in charge of a vessel",opb:"civil penalty of$1,000 against the vessel itself",opc:"suspension and/or revocation of an operator's FCC license",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is NOT true about the starboard passageway between frames 122-139?",opa:"There is a water tight door",opb:"A push button for halon release is not in the passageway",opc:"A water fog applicator is available",opd:"A primary means of escape is not shown",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel heading SSE is on a course of ____________.",opa:"112.5\xb0",opb:"135.0\xb0",opc:"157.5\xb0",opd:"180.0\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 40,301 foot-long tons, TM = 3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT 18,732 foot-long tons. What is the KG corrected for transverse free surface effects?",opa:"53.78 feet",opb:"54.82 feet",opc:"55.47 feet",opd:"56.01 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to regulations, a cargo hose used for transferring liquefied gases must have a bursting pressure of ____________.",opa:"5 times the maximum working pressure on the hose during cargo transfer",opb:"one half the designed working pressure",opc:"4 times the pressure of the cargo pump used for transferring",opd:"5 times the minimum working pressure on the hose during cargo transfer",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is experiencing a single amplitude roll angle of 1 degree and a roll period of 7 seconds. What is the maximum recommended water depth for elevating?",opa:"50 feet",opb:"100 feet",opc:"150 feet",opd:"200 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Initial stability is indicated by ____________.",opa:"GM",opb:"KM",opc:"Deck load",opd:"Maximum allowed KG",ans:"opa"},{question:"The length of chain between the anchor and the end of the pendant line is called the ____________.",opa:"pigtail chain",opb:"thrash chain",opc:"crown chain",opd:"wear chain",ans:"opc"},{question:"The transfer procedures for oil products are required to be posted ____________.",opa:"in the pilothouse",opb:"in the officer's lounge",opc:"in the upper pumproom flat",opd:"where they can be easily seen or readily available",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is NOT a requirement for testing the line throwing appliance on a vessel?",opa:"A drill should be conducted every three months.",opb:"A regular service line must be used when it's fired.",opc:"A regular projectile must be used when it's fired.",opd:"The actual firing is at the discretion of the Master.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The fire control plan symbol that designates a space or compartment protected by Halon 1301 is ____________.",opa:"10",opb:"11",opc:"12",opd:"44",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel's drafts are FWD 19'-02', AFT 23'-10'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if 98 tons of fuel is pumped 116 feet forward.",opa:"FWD 19'-04', AFT23'-06'",opb:"FWD 19'-07', AFT23'-04'",opc:"FWD 19'-09', AFT23'-01'",opd:"FWD 19'-09', AFT23'-06'",ans:"opb"},{question:"The instructions for launching lifeboats and liferafts on a MODU must be approved by the ____________.",opa:"lease operator",opb:"Minerals Management Service",opc:"Coast Guard",opd:"person-in-charge of the unit",ans:"opc"},{question:"Aboard small passenger vessels the steering gear, signaling whistle, controls, and communication system shall be tested by the Master ____________.",opa:"once a week",opb:"before getting underway for the day's operation",opc:"at every inspection and reinspection",opd:"at least once in every 48 hours",ans:"opb"},{question:"Each EPIRB required on a MODU shall be tested using the integrated test circuit and output indicator every ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"two weeks",opc:"month",opd:"two months",ans:"opc"},{question:"The use of sinking and dispersing chemical agents for removal of surface oil is ____________.",opa:"the most common method used in the United States",opb:"too expensive for common use",opc:"generally safe to sea life",opd:"authorized only with prior approval of the Federal On-Scene Coordinator",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). What is the new metacentric height corrected for longitudinal free surface effects if the entire contents of salt water ballast tanks 1P and 1S are discharged? (Use KML = 348.58)",opa:"261.11 feet",opb:"279.37 feet",opc:"283.37 feet",opd:"301.12 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"You must make a written application to obtain or renew your 'T' boat's Certificate of Inspection ____________.",opa:"on form CG-835",opb:"at the shipyard where you are hauled out",opc:"on form CG-3752",opd:"every time your boat is hauled out",ans:"opc"},{question:"The sounding level of 17 lb. per gallon mud in mud pit 2S of the COASTAL DRILLER is 7.75 feet. What are the transverse moments for this mud?",opa:"896 ft.-kips",opb:"913 ft.-kips",opc:"1139 ft.-kips",opd:"1161 ft.-kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"A wooden small passenger vessel operating on a coastwise route in cold water shall carry sufficient inflatable buoyant apparatus for __________ or meet alternate requirements regarding collision bulkhead standards and the provision of life floats.(small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"all persons aboard",opb:"67% of the total number of persons permitted onboard.",opc:"50% of all persons aboard",opd:"30% of all persons aboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"The transverse free surface correction of a floating MODU displacing 24,000 long tons is 1.0 foot. When the MODU is deballasted by discharging 8,000 long tons of ballast, the FSMT decreases by 4,000 ft.-long tons. What is the new FSCT?",opa:"1.50 feet",opb:"1.25 feet",opc:"1.00 foot",opd:"0.83 foot",ans:"opb"},{question:"The type davits shown are ____________.",opa:"round-bar davits",opb:"radial davits",opc:"gravity davits",opd:"quadrantal davits",ans:"opc"},{question:"When using a hand held smoke signal from a lifeboat, you should activate the signal ____________.",opa:"on the downwind side",opb:"on the upwind side",opc:"inside the boat",opd:"at the stern",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Weather conditions make it necessary to ballast down to survival draft. It is decided to check the stability at the intermediate draft of 32 feet. How much ballast is required to ballast to 32 feet?",opa:"2,094 long tons",opb:"2,194 long tons",opc:"2,294 long tons",opd:"3,294 long tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Radio station logs involving communications during a disaster shall be kept by the station licensee for at least ____________.",opa:"4 years from date of entry",opb:"3 years from date of entry",opc:"2 years from date of entry",opd:"1 year from date of entry",ans:"opb"},{question:"If you reef a marconi mainsail, the sail area ____________.",opa:"becomes less",opb:"becomes larger",opc:"does not change",opd:"moves aft",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fire extinguishers on inspected vessels are numbered by size I through V, with I being ____________.",opa:"used for electrical fires only",opb:"the smallest",opc:"the most accessible",opd:"the most effective",ans:"opb"},{question:"CATEGORY I EPIRB's transmit on frequencies that are monitored by ____________.",opa:"orbiting satellites in space",opb:"commercial radio stations",opc:"private, commercial, and military aircraft",opd:"Both A & C",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are FWD 20'-08', AFT 23'-00'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if 195 tons of cargo are discharged 76 feet aft of amidships.",opa:"FWD 20'-05', AFT21'-11'",opb:"FWD 20'-07', AFT22'-01'",opc:"FWD 20'-11', AFT22'-00'",opd:"FWD 21'-03', AFT22'-04'",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Master of a cargo or tank vessel shall be responsible that each lifeboat, except those free-fall launched, is lowered to the water with crew and maneuvered at least once every ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"month",opc:"three months",opd:"year",ans:"opc"},{question:"A jack-up, while level in transit at 10 feet draft, experiences a wind gust which results in a starboard draft of 11 feet 6 inches. What is the heel?",opa:"1 foot 6 inches to starboard",opb:"3 feet to starboard",opc:"3 feet to port",opd:"1 foot 6 inches to port",ans:"opb"},{question:"Preloading tests the soil to the vertical leg reaction that would be imposed by ____________.",opa:"static forced and drilling loads",opb:"a severe storm",opc:"the design storm",opd:"environmental forces",ans:"opc"},{question:"Before deballasting to survival draft in the event of predicted heavy weather, the DEEP DRILLER Operations Manual recommends that the mooring lines be slacked ____________.",opa:"10 feet",opb:"20 feet",opc:"30 feet",opd:"40 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The fire protection regulations for towing vessels require the crew to be trained for fire fighting with drills and safety orientations ____________.",opa:"only if the vessel is greater than 100 gross tons",opb:"always, as stated in the regulations",opc:"but, only applies to towing vessels constructed after August 27, 2003",opd:"however, drills are not required for those holding a fire fighting certificate",ans:"opb"},{question:"A cabinet or space containing the controls or valves for the fixed firefighting system must be ____________.",opa:"posted with instructions on the operation of the system",opb:"ventilated and equipped with explosion-proof switches",opc:"painted with red and black diagonal stripes",opd:"equipped with a battery powered source of emergency lighting",ans:"opa"},{question:"On an oceangoing vessel, for each person a lifeboat (without desalting kits) is certified to carry, the boat must be supplied with ____________.",opa:"2 pounds of condensed milk",opb:"a signaling whistle",opc:"3 liters of water",opd:"a life preserver",ans:"opc"},{question:"On the COASTAL DRILLER, except when pumping from a tank, the bilge system valves should be ____________.",opa:"cracked open",opb:"in the check-stop position",opc:"opened for draining",opd:"closed",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should you warm up a diesel engine that has not been run for some time?",opa:"Run it at minimum speed until warmed to operating temperature.",opb:"Idle for a brief period of time and then warm up at half speed.",opc:"Bring it up to top speed immediately and run until warmed up.",opd:"Inject ether into the air intake to shorten warm up time.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are loading in a port subject to the tropical load line mark and bound for a port subject to the winter load line mark. You will enter the summer zone after steaming one day, and you will enter the winter zone after a total of eleven days. You will consume 33 tons of fuel, water, and stores per day. The hydrometer reading at the loading pier is 1.004, and the average TPI is 46. What is the minimum freeboard required at the start of the voyage?",opa:"85 inches",opb:"82 inches",opc:"80 inches",opd:"78 inches",ans:"opb"},{question:"A tool consisting of a handle and releasable chain used for turning pipe or fittings of a diameter larger than that which a pipe wrench would fit is called ____________.",opa:"breakout wrench",opb:"makeup tongs",opc:"chain tongs",opd:"pipe spinner",ans:"opc"},{question:"On small passenger vessels a gasoline engine must be fitted with ____________.",opa:"A means of backfire flame control",opb:"A lubricating oil pressure gauge and a tachometer",opc:"Jacket water discharge temperature gauges",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the entire contents of bulk tanks #2 and #3 are back-loaded to an offshore supply vessel, what longitudinal moment would have to be created to level the unit in trim at the new draft?",opa:"25,846 ft.-kips",opb:"17,119 ft.-kips",opc:"8,727 ft.-kips",opd:"1,788 ft.-kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 4.3 ft.",opb:"Available GM 4.1 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.9 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.6 ft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is drilling on location at a 60 foot draft. Waves are approaching within 2 feet of the underside of the spider deck. You should ____________.",opa:"suspend drilling operations and deballast to a 45 foot draft",opb:"continue drilling while ballasting to a 20 foot draft maximum air gap",opc:"deballast when the waves just begin to hit the underside of the spider deck",opd:"reduce tension on all anchor chains to increase draft",ans:"opa"},{question:"How many people onboard a MODU must be trained in the use of the fireman's outfit?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 3900 tons of cargo, 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 359 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in fresh water.",opa:"19'-00'",opb:"18'-07'",opc:"18'-04'",opd:"18'-01'",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Preparing to Drill). If all the liquid mud (see table 8) is dumped, what would be the new height of the transverse metacenter?",opa:"61.19 feet",opb:"62.80 feet",opc:"62.99 feet",opd:"62.94 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Semisubmersibles A and B are identical. However, 'A' is more tender than 'B'. This means that 'A' relative to 'B' has a ____________.",opa:"lower KG",opb:"smaller GM",opc:"smaller roll angle",opd:"larger GZ",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is required by regulations concerning the stowage of lifeboats on cargo vessels?",opa:"Each lifeboat must have a launching appliance.",opb:"Launching appliances must be of the gravity type.",opc:"There may not be more than two launching appliances on the same deck.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Routine radio communications should be no more than ____________.",opa:"one minute",opb:"three minutes",opc:"five minutes",opd:"eight minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"A marine chemist issues gas free certificates and is certified by which organization?",opa:"Mine Safety Appliance Association",opb:"American Chemical Society",opc:"Marine Chemists Association",opd:"National Fire Protection Association",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you are forced to abandon ship in a lifeboat, you should ____________.",opa:"remain in the immediate vicinity",opb:"head for the nearest land",opc:"head for the closest sea-lanes",opd:"vote on what to do, so all hands will have a part in the decision",ans:"opa"},{question:"When launching a lifeboat, the tricing pennants should be released ____________.",opa:"before the boat is lowered from the stowed position",opb:"as the boat-fall blocks break clear of the davit head",opc:"before the boat is lowered from the embarkation level",opd:"after the boat is released into the water",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged, listing to port and on occasion flopping to the same angle to starboard. It has a long, slow, sluggish roll around the angle of list. There is excessive trim by the stern with little freeboard aft. What action should you take FIRST to correct this situation?",opa:"Jettison any off-center topside weights to lower GM and correct the list.",opb:"Pump out any slack after double-bottom tanks to reduce free surface and increase freeboard aft.",opc:"Pump out the after peak and fill the forepeak to change the trim.",opd:"Press up any slack double-bottom tanks forward of the tipping center, then fill the forepeak if empty.",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a magnetic compass is not in use for a prolonged period of time it should ____________.",opa:"be shielded from direct sunlight",opb:"be locked into a constant heading",opc:"have any air bubbles replaced with nitrogen",opd:"have the compensating magnets removed",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is required for a dry exhaust pipe? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Noncombustible hangers and supports",opb:"Insulation from combustible material",opc:"An automatic damper",opd:"A rain spray and spray cap",ans:"opa"},{question:"A 7,000 ton displacement tankship carries two slack tanks of alcohol with a S.G. of 0.8. Each tank is 50 ft. long and 30 ft. wide. What is the reduction in GM due to free surface with the vessel floating in sea water, S.G. is 1.026?",opa:".36 ft.",opb:".46 ft.",opc:".72 ft.",opd:".82 ft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The minimum concentration of H2S which can cause death if a person is exposed for even an instant is ____________.",opa:"200 ppm",opb:"400 ppm",opc:"600 ppm",opd:"1000 ppm",ans:"opd"},{question:"In areas where CO2 piping is installed, such piping may not be used for any other purpose EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"in connection with the fire-detecting system",opb:"in connection with the water sprinkler system",opc:"to ventilate the space",opd:"to run the emergency wiring to the space",ans:"opa"},{question:"Vessels in ocean service shall carry ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"life floats for 50% of all persons onboard",opb:"buoyant apparatus for all persons onboard",opc:"sufficient inflatable buoyant apparatus for all persons onboard",opd:"life jackets for 50% of all persons onboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which list is NOT required to be provided as part of the appendices of the Shipboard Oil Pollution Emergency Plan?",opa:"A list of agencies or officials of Coastal State Administrators responsible for receiving and processing incident reports.",opb:"A list of agencies or officials in regularly visited ports.",opc:"A list specifying who will be responsible for informing the parties listed and the priority in which they must be notified.",opd:"A list of personnel duty assignments.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 27'-06', AFT 28'-02'; and the KG is 23.1 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 60\xb0 inclination.",opa:"0.9 foot",opb:"1.8 feet",opc:"2.7 feet",opd:"4.5 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The most important consideration in the event the Deep Driller suffers damage is ____________.",opa:"preserve reserve buoyancy",opb:"advise authorities",opc:"pump from adjacent undamaged compartments",opd:"counter flood on the opposite corner",ans:"opa"},{question:"A fire starts in a switchboard due to a short circuit. This is which class of fire?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the minimum number of bolts required in a temporary bolted flange oil hose coupling?",opa:"3",opb:"4",opc:"6",opd:"A bolt must be used in every hole.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The appearance of Bunker C and fuel oils are dark colored liquids, and ____________.",opa:"soluble oils",opb:"slop oils",opc:"cutting oils",opd:"viscous oils",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a vessel is required to have a power-driven fire pump, the pump may also be used for ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"the drinking water supply system",opb:"the bilge pump",opc:"engine cooling water",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Cargo hose carried on tank vessels shall be able to withstand a pressure of at least ____________.",opa:"75 psi",opb:"100 psi",opc:"120 psi",opd:"150 psi",ans:"opd"},{question:"Air-cooled gasoline auxiliary engines are allowed on vessels not more than 65 feet in length, carrying not more than 12 passengers if ____________.",opa:"it is not practicable to supply water to the engine",opb:"they have a self-contained fuel system and are installed on an open deck",opc:"they are rated at not more than 4.5 horsepower",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"On surface type offshore drilling units, each survival craft must be capable of being launched to the water at the minimum operating draft, under unfavorable conditions of trim and with the unit listed not less than ____________.",opa:"16\xb0",opb:"20\xb0",opc:"24\xb0",opd:"30\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"The sails are properly set and trimmed. As a vessel heads up from a beam reach to close hauled the ____________.",opa:"true wind velocity increases",opb:"heeling moment decreases",opc:"side slip increases",opd:"jib sheet must be eased",ans:"opc"},{question:"A solution to overcome tripping defects is an arrangement of special plates on either side of the flukes, designed to set them in the correct tripping position. These special plates are called ____________.",opa:"trippers",opb:"stocks",opc:"stabilizers",opd:"palms",ans:"opd"},{question:"On small passenger vessels, cooling water for the exhaust lines from an internal combustion engine must be ____________.",opa:"obtained from the engine's cooling water system or from a separate engine-driven pump",opb:"chemically treated to prevent corrosion",opc:"flushed and changed periodically",opd:"obtained from a fresh water storage tank or an expansion tank",ans:"opa"},{question:"Vertical moment is obtained by multiplying a vessel's weight and its ____________.",opa:"VCG or KG",opb:"LCB",opc:"LCG",opd:"TCG",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are underway in the Gulf of Mexico when you hear a distress message over the VHF radio. The position of the sender is about 20 miles south of Galveston, TX, and you are about 80 miles ESE of Galveston. What action should you take?",opa:"Immediately acknowledge receipt of the distress message",opb:"Defer acknowledgment for a short interval so that a coast station may acknowledge receipt",opc:"Do not acknowledge receipt until other ships nearer to the distress have acknowledged",opd:"Do not acknowledge receipt because you are too far away to take action",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which precaution should be taken when testing a line throwing gun?",opa:"Never remove the line from the rocket.",opb:"Fire it at an angle of approximately 90 degrees to the horizon.",opc:"Wear asbestos gloves.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). While the unit is deballasting, starboard valve 19 fails in the closed position. You may deballast from tank 9S by pumping from tank 8S by opening valves 20 and ____________.",opa:"35",opb:"21",opc:"18",opd:"17",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers major damage which results in flooding in tank C3S. Your best countermeasure is to ____________.",opa:"pump from 9S",opb:"pump from C3S",opc:"counter flood in 1P",opd:"counter flood in 10S",ans:"opa"},{question:"Grade E combustible liquids are those having flash points of ____________.",opa:"80\xb0F or less",opb:"greater than 80\xb0F and less than 115\xb0F",opc:"greater than 115\xb0F and less than 150\xb0F",opd:"150\xb0F or greater",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER has a KGL of 53.16 feet while at a draft of 58.0 feet. Although there are no environmental forces, trim is 2.0 feet by the stern. What is the value of LCG?",opa:"2.16 feet",opb:"2.26 feet",opc:"2.36 feet",opd:"2.46 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a person is in shock, their skin will be ____________.",opa:"warm and dry",opb:"warm and damp",opc:"cold and dry",opd:"cold and damp",ans:"opd"},{question:"In comparison to electric power, hydraulic power for jacking systems has the advantage of ____________.",opa:"better control capabilities",opb:"less maintenance and repair",opc:"fewer personnel needed during jacking",opd:"less preload needed",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about entering into a tank which has been sealed for a long time is TRUE?",opa:"The tank should be tested only once to ensure the oxygen content is at least 14% before entry.",opb:"The tank must be tested at frequent intervals to ensure that hazardous gasses have not regenerated.",opc:"The tank need not be tested for oxygen content if it is ventilated for more than 24 hours.",opd:"If the oxygen content tests at less than 12% you should wear an approved gas mask.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Extended cyclical variations in tensions will cause an anchor chain to break due to ____________.",opa:"fatigue",opb:"corrosion",opc:"distortion",opd:"abrasion",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to the 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act', what is NOT required in the radiotelephone log?",opa:"Distress and alarm signals transmitted or intercepted",opb:"Times of beginning and end of watch period",opc:"Routine navigational traffic",opd:"Daily statement about the condition of the required radiotelephone equipment",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are underway in mid-ocean, when you hear a distress message over the VHF radio. The position of the sender is 20 miles away. What action should you take?",opa:"Immediately acknowledge receipt of the distress message.",opb:"Defer acknowledgment for a short interval so that a coast station may acknowledge receipt.",opc:"Do not acknowledge receipt until other ships nearer to the distress have acknowledged.",opd:"Do not acknowledge because you are too far away to take action.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are preparing for what promises to be a rough ocean passage. Your 120-foot schooner carries a yard on the foremast, about 50 feet above the water. The yard weighs about 1000 pounds. If you take the yard down and stow it on deck for the trip, you will ____________.",opa:"increase your vessel's GM",opb:"decrease the metacentric height",opc:"give the vessel a gentler roll",opd:"increase the reserve buoyancy",ans:"opa"},{question:"Adding the FSCL to KG yields ____________.",opa:"KM",opb:"GM",opc:"KGT",opd:"KGL",ans:"opd"},{question:"This illustration shows the correct method of securing a ____________.",opa:"man-rope",opb:"frapping line",opc:"sea painter",opd:"lifeline",ans:"opc"},{question:"While drilling loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), the DEEP DRILLER suffers a sudden unexpected forward inclination. The wind and waves are light from the starboard bow. Among the possible causes, you should consider ____________.",opa:"failure of mooring lines 2 and 3",opb:"drilling crew has dumped the mud",opc:"the drill string has broken",opd:"ballast tanks equalizing into tank 1P",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 6'-00', AFT 6'-06'. From past experience, you know that the vessel will increase her draft 1 inch for every 6 tons loaded. There is rig water onboard and 17 tons of deck cargo. How many more tons of cargo can be loaded and still maintain the same trim?",opa:"14 tons",opb:"18 tons",opc:"24 tons",opd:"33 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Horizontal subdivision decks forming watertight compartments in the columns of a semisubmersible MODU increase the unit's ____________.",opa:"tank capacities",opb:"stability in the event of damage",opc:"towing speed",opd:"anchor holding ratio",ans:"opb"},{question:"Stretchers are fitted in lifeboats to provide a ____________.",opa:"place for people to lie down",opb:"means for rigging the sail",opc:"place for rowers to brace their feet",opd:"suitable means for water to drain below the footings",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 23'-03', AFT 27'-01'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessels displacement if you are in fresh water.",opa:"12,550 tons",opb:"12,900 tons",opc:"13,200 tons",opd:"13,350 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Where is the keel generally located on a MODU?",opa:"Along the midships axis",opb:"Along the centerline of the lower hulls",opc:"Along the roll axis of the hull",opd:"Along the axis of rotation of the hull",ans:"opb"},{question:"Any extinguishing agent used on a Class 'C' fire must have which important property?",opa:"Cooling ability",opb:"Leaves no residue",opc:"Penetrating power",opd:"Nonconductivity",ans:"opd"},{question:"The water pockets located on the underside of inflatable liferafts ____________.",opa:"stow rainwater; these 4 spaces do not take up valuable space",opb:"act as stabilizers by filling with sea water as soon as the raft is inflated and upright",opc:"hold the freshwater required by regulation to be provided in the raft when packed",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"You may have to give artificial respiration after a/an ____________.",opa:"drowning",opb:"electrocution",opc:"poisoning",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER as currently configured is limited to a maximum drilling depth of ____________.",opa:"18,400 feet",opb:"20,600 feet",opc:"22,800 feet",opd:"25,000 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What does a SART signal sound or look like?",opa:"It transmits 'SOS' and the vessel's name and position in slow speed Morse Code.",opb:"It will appear on a radar unit's PPI as a line of dots radiating outward with the innermost dot indicating the SART's position.",opc:"It will appear on a radar unit's PPI as a line of dots radiating outward with the outermost dot indicating the SART's position.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Each liferaft, which does not have an indicated maximum stowage height indicated on the liferaft, must be ____________.",opa:"limited to carry no more than 10 persons",opb:"stowed not more than 59 feet above the lightest waterline",opc:"stowed in quick release racks",opd:"inspected every six months",ans:"opb"},{question:"The difference between the height of the metacenter and the metacentric height is known as ____________.",opa:"righting arm",opb:"metacentric radius",opc:"height of the center of buoyancy",opd:"height of the center of gravity",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are FWD 24'-02', AFT 24'-04'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if 295 tons of cargo are loaded 122 feet aft of amidships.",opa:"FWD 22'-08', AFT26'-00'",opb:"FWD 22'-10', AFT25'-09'",opc:"FWD 23'-04', AFT26'-03'",opd:"FWD 23'-05', AFT25'-11'",ans:"opc"},{question:"A B-II fire extinguisher has a minimum capacity of ____________.",opa:"3 gallons of foam",opb:"20 pounds of CO2",opc:"10 pounds of dry chemical",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The KG of a vessel is found by dividing the displacement into the ____________.",opa:"height of the center of gravity of the vessel",opb:"sum of the vertical moments of the vessel",opc:"sum of the free surface moments of the vessel",opd:"sum of the longitudinal moments of the vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"The liquid mud tanks on your vessel measure 40'L by 20'B by 8'D. The vessel's displacement is 996 T and the specific gravity of the mud is 1.7. What is the reduction in GM due to 2 of these tanks being slack?",opa:"0.95 foot",opb:"1.26 feet",opc:"2.10 feet",opd:"2.54 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"When retrieving the survival craft, the winch operator should stop the winch and check ____________.",opa:"that all personnel are seated in the craft",opb:"that the cable has not jumped any grooves on the drum",opc:"which way the wind is blowing",opd:"the hydraulic fuel level before lifting",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the height of the metacenter is greater than the height of the center of gravity a vessel has which type of stability?",opa:"Stable",opb:"Neutral",opc:"Unstable",opd:"Negative",ans:"opa"},{question:"A magnetic compass card is marked in how many degrees?",opa:"90",opb:"180",opc:"360",opd:"400",ans:"opc"},{question:"A casing string that is run below the previous casing string, but does not extend to the wellhead is called a ____________.",opa:"production string",opb:"liner",opc:"packer",opd:"squnch joint",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 5486 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 277.84 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 271.2 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 272.1 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 273.6 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 274.6 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged with no list, but down by the stern. There is progressive flooding and trim by the stern is increasing. What is the effect on transverse stability after the deck edge at the stern is submerged?",opa:"KB increases, increasing BM and therefore GM",opb:"KG increases due to the weight of the added water on deck",opc:"BM decreases from loss of waterplane and greater volume.",opd:"There is no effect on transverse stability.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 260\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"on a close reach",opb:"on a broad reach",opc:"on a starboard tack",opd:"running before the wind",ans:"opb"},{question:"Why are symmetric mooring patterns frequently used to keep MODU's on station?",opa:"All lines contribute to the holding power of the mooring system.",opb:"Environmental forces will probably vary in direction during the time the MODU is on station.",opc:"Environmental forces will probably come from the same direction during the time the MODU is on station.",opd:"Governmental regulations require this mooring pattern unless an exemption is issued.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 18'-09', AFT 20'-05'; and the KG is 23.8 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 15\xb0 inclination.",opa:"0.7 foot",opb:"1.0 feet",opc:"1.7 feet",opd:"3.8 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The brickwork surrounding the firebox of a boiler is known as ____________.",opa:"refractory",opb:"the screen wall",opc:"the water wall",opd:"fire plate",ans:"opa"},{question:"After an accident the victim may go into shock and die. What should be done to help prevent shock?",opa:"Slightly elevate the head and feet.",opb:"Keep the person awake.",opc:"Keep the person lying down and at a comfortable temperature.",opd:"Give the person a stimulant to increase blood flow.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What type of gauging is required for a cargo of formic acid?",opa:"Open",opb:"Restricted",opc:"Closed",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following product(s) would be classified as grade E?",opa:"Gasoline",opb:"Bunker C",opc:"Kerosene",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers damage to the port forward column below the waterline. Pumping from tank 2P and 3P is not sufficient to prevent increasing port list and bow down trim. You should consider counter flooding in tank ____________.",opa:"2S",opb:"9S",opc:"C2BS",opd:"10S",ans:"opd"},{question:"On which type davit does the davit head stay at the same height?",opa:"Radial",opb:"Sheath-screw",opc:"Quadrantal",opd:"Gravity",ans:"opa"},{question:"While drilling at 4,000 feet with casing set to 2,000 feet, the well kicks with mud weight in the hole. Mud pumps are shut down and the blowout preventer is closed. Compared to the drilling situation, the pressure on the casing seat will be ____________.",opa:"unchanged",opb:"increased",opc:"reduced",opd:"indeterminable",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is an indication of reserve buoyancy?",opa:"Metacentric height",opb:"Righting moment",opc:"Rolling period",opd:"Freeboard",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the sample load from #2 (preload). All of the preload is dumped with the exception of 50 kips in preload tank #28. What is the new LCG?",opa:"119.11 feet AF0",opb:"119.44 feet AF0",opc:"119.68 feet AF0",opd:"120.11 feet AF0",ans:"opc"},{question:"By regulation, orange smoke distress signals will expire not more than how many months from the date of manufacture?",opa:"24 months",opb:"36 months",opc:"42 months",opd:"54 months",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 14'-04', AFT 18'-08'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.05 feet",opb:"1.15 feet",opc:"1.25 feet",opd:"1.31 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the OCMI has NOT granted an extension, free-fall lifeboats must be lowered into the water and launched with the assigned crew at least once every ____________.",opa:"3 months",opb:"6 months",opc:"year",opd:"2 years",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning GMDSS Radio Operator requirements is FALSE?",opa:"Each compulsory vessel must carry at least two licensed GMDSS Radio Operators at all times while at sea.",opb:"Each compulsory vessel must carry at least two licensed Radio Operators at all times while at sea and may elect to carry a GMDSS Radio Maintainer as well.",opc:"Communications involving safety of life at sea do not have to be logged as long as the compulsory vessel was not involved in such communications.",opd:"While at sea, adjustments to, and the maintaining of, GMDSS equipment may be performed by the GMDSS Radio operator as long as the work is supervised by an onboard licensed GMDSS Radio Maintainer.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The maximum mean draft to which a vessel may be safely loaded is called ____________.",opa:"mean draft",opb:"calculated draft",opc:"deep draft",opd:"load line draft",ans:"opd"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 21.2 feet and the drafts are: FWD 27'-11', AFT 28'-07'.",opa:"72\xb0",opb:"52\xb0",opc:"24\xb0",opd:"19\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, sleeping spaces for the regular personnel employed onboard may not berth more than ____________.",opa:"two persons",opb:"three persons",opc:"four persons",opd:"five persons",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the charted water depth is 200 feet, the limits of service for the COASTAL DRILLER require an air gap of ____________.",opa:"35 feet",opb:"32 feet",opc:"30 feet",opd:"25 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Depending on its concentration, which product(s) can be classified as either grade D or E?",opa:"Sulfuric acid",opb:"Formaldehyde solutions 37% to50%",opc:"1,1,1-trichloroethane",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"A semisubmersible which flops between port and starboard angles of list is likely to have ____________.",opa:"KMT greater than KML",opb:"KMT less than KGT",opc:"an off-center LCG",opd:"TCG greater than level-vessel TCB",ans:"opb"},{question:"In evacuation from a MODU, an individual without the option of a survival craft or liferaft should enter the water on the leeward side, except when ____________.",opa:"there is burning oil on the water",opb:"there is a rescue craft in the area",opc:"water temperature is below 40\xb0F",opd:"a rigid survival craft is in the area",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). While in field transit, the wind speeds are predicted to increase above 70 knots. What would be the new KGL if the legs are lowered to the recommended value?",opa:"50.65 feet",opb:"37.00 feet",opc:"36.53 feet",opd:"13.65 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The most serious effect of air trapped in a non-treated diesel engine jacket water cooling system is that it ____________.",opa:"causes corrosion",opb:"reduces the ability of the system to cool the engine",opc:"can form pockets which block the flow of coolant through the system",opd:"accelerates formation of metal plating",ans:"opa"},{question:"Spaces containing batteries require good ventilation because ____________.",opa:"ventilation avoids CO2 build up",opb:"ventilation supplies extra oxygen for charging the battery",opc:"ventilation avoids flammable gas accumulation",opd:"less electrolyte is required to maintain the batteries' charge",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statements is FALSE concerning the proper procedure in handling a fire hose?",opa:"A 1\xbd inch hose should be deployed with a minimum of a nozzle man and hoseman.",opb:"Back-up hosemen should be placed wherever the hose makes a significant turn.",opc:"Use of a spanner wrench when attaching nozzles or additional lengths of hose is always critical.",opd:"The nozzleman should always hold the nozzle with one hand on top, to prevent kickback.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Structural stress on a MODU can be reduced by ____________.",opa:"lessening the effect of environmental forces",opb:"even and symmetrical variable loading",opc:"local concentration of heavy consumables",opd:"increasing the metacentric height",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 477 tons and measures 116'L x 31'B. You ship a large wave on the after deck. What is the reduction in GM due to free surface before the water drains overboard, if the after deck measures 54'L x 31'B and the weight of the water is 51.5 tons?",opa:"6.43 feet",opb:"6.75 feet",opc:"6.99 feet",opd:"7.25 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"When lifting loads from a boat in heavy weather, the load should be taken when the boat ____________.",opa:"reaches the crest",opb:"begins to fall",opc:"begins to rise",opd:"reaches the trough",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers major damage which results in flooding in tank C1P. Pumping from tanks in the vicinity of the damage has proven ineffective. Your best countermeasure is to ____________.",opa:"counter flood in 1P",opb:"counter flood in 10S",opc:"pump from C1P",opd:"pump from C3S",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which space(s) on your cargo vessel must have a fire detection system?",opa:"Any compartment containing explosives",opb:"Any compartment adjacent to one containing explosives",opc:"Enclosed spaces which are 'specially suitable for vehicles'",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What signal must be sounded by a vessel towing a mobile offshore drilling unit through an area of restricted visibility?",opa:"Two prolonged blasts",opb:"Five or more short blasts",opc:"One prolonged and two short blasts",opd:"One prolonged and three short blasts",ans:"opc"},{question:"The lightweight longitudinal moments for the DEEP DRILLER are ____________.",opa:"680,914 ft.-long tons",opb:"9,733 ft.-long tons",opc:"-5,937 ft.-long tons",opd:"-6,716 ft.-long tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). According to the deck load graph, how much additional deck load could be added on the unit?",opa:"435.59 long tons",opb:"321.59 long tons",opc:"281.59 long tons",opd:"192.59 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the meaning of the signal SA T1035 RQ when sent by the International code of Signals?",opa:"The longitude is 10\xb035'.",opb:"I am altering course to 103.5\xb0T.",opc:"Can you proceed at 1035 local time?",opd:"Is the latitude 10\xb035'?",ans:"opc"},{question:"What does the term 'head' mean when applied to a fire pump?",opa:"Length of the discharge pipe",opb:"Height of the discharge pipe",opc:"Difference between the discharge and suction pressures",opd:"Sum of discharge and suction pressures",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which cargo is considered volatile?",opa:"Bunker C",opb:"Turkey-red oil",opc:"Sweet oil",opd:"iso-Propylamine",ans:"opd"},{question:"The idler sheave which directs and turns the anchor cable from a semisubmersible is known as the ____________.",opa:"swivel fairlead",opb:"windlass wildcat",opc:"chain stopper",opd:"chain director",ans:"opa"},{question:"If there is a possibility of confusion, which signal should be used to send the group 'True Bearing 045 Degrees'?",opa:"45",opb:"B045",opc:"B045T",opd:"A045",ans:"opd"},{question:"Two individuals authorized to serve as a lifeboatman must be assigned to any lifeboat that has a capacity of more than ____________.",opa:"10 persons",opb:"20 persons",opc:"30 persons",opd:"40 persons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a mean draft of 60 feet, has a two-foot trim by the head and a three foot list to starboard. What is the draft at the port aft draft mark?",opa:"57.5 feet",opb:"59.5 feet",opc:"60.5 feet",opd:"62.5 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which substance is NOT considered to be 'Oil' under the pollution prevention regulations?",opa:"Petroleum and fuel oil",opb:"Sludge",opc:"Oil mixed with dredge spoil",opd:"Oil refuse and oil mixed with wastes",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the height of the metacenter is less than the height of the center of gravity, a vessel has which type of stability?",opa:"Stable",opb:"Neutral",opc:"Negative",opd:"Positive",ans:"opc"},{question:"The person-in-charge shall insure that each rescue boat on an OSV is lowered to the water, launched and operated at least once every ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"two months",opc:"three months",opd:"six months",ans:"opc"},{question:"The quantity of fuel required to be carried in a motor lifeboat is ____________.",opa:"the quantity needed for 24 hours continuous operation",opb:"the quantity needed for 48 hours continuous operation",opc:"55 gallons",opd:"90 gallons",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the regulations that apply to small passenger vessels an 'open boat' is a vessel ____________.",opa:"that is used for charter fishing or tours and is open to the public",opb:"on which gambling and consumption of alcoholic beverages is permitted",opc:"that is docked and open for visitors",opd:"that is not protected from entry of water by means of a complete weather tight deck",ans:"opd"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, the lifeboat motors shall be operated in the ahead and astern position at least once each ____________.",opa:"day",opb:"week",opc:"month",opd:"year",ans:"opb"},{question:"Heat exhaustion is caused by excessive ____________.",opa:"loss of body temperature",opb:"loss of water and salt from the body",opc:"gain in body temperature",opd:"intake of water when working or exercising",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 22'-04', AFT 22'-10'; and the KG is 18.4 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 30\xb0 inclination.",opa:"1.6 feet",opb:"2.9 feet",opc:"3.8 feet",opd:"4.6 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"If a vessel takes a sudden, severe list or trim from an unknown cause, you should FIRST ____________.",opa:"determine the cause before taking countermeasures",opb:"assume the shift is due to off-center loading",opc:"counter flood",opd:"assume the cause is environmental forces",ans:"opa"},{question:"A patient in shock should NOT be placed in which position?",opa:"On their side if unconscious",opb:"Head down and feet up, no injuries to face or head",opc:"Flat on their back with head and feet at the same level",opd:"Arms above their head",ans:"opd"},{question:"With an approved combination nozzle, low-velocity fog is produced by ____________.",opa:"inserting an applicator in the nozzle",opb:"putting the handle of the nozzle in the forward position",opc:"directing a straight stream of water against the ship's structure",opd:"the combination nozzle only when the water pressure exceeds 125 psi",ans:"opa"},{question:"Normally, potable water systems are connected directly to the ____________.",opa:"fire-main system",opb:"feed-water system",opc:"freshwater sanitary system",opd:"domestic water tank",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a MODU, the keel is the primary strength member of the lower hull form in which direction?",opa:"transverse",opb:"diagonal",opc:"longitudinal",opd:"vertical",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is planning to operate while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 ( Preparing to Drill). What is the margin between KGT and maximum allowable KG?",opa:"0.66 foot",opb:"2.58 feet",opc:"5.24 feet",opd:"7.87 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). While in field transit, the wind speeds are predicted to increase above 70 knots. What would be the change in KGL if the legs are lowered to the recommended value?",opa:"12.75 feet",opb:"13.65 feet",opc:"59.30 feet",opd:"60.50 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 5.26 ft.",opb:"Available GM 4.24 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.11 ft.",opd:"Available GM 4.01 ft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The preferred type of pollution control for oil spills on the water is (are) ____________.",opa:"straw",opb:"booms",opc:"skimmers",opd:"chemical dispersants",ans:"opb"},{question:"The carriage of a liquefied gas not appearing in table 4 of 46 CFR Part 154 must be approved by the ____________.",opa:"vessel owner",opb:"Commandant (G-MTH)",opc:"American Bureau of Shipping",opd:"Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection",ans:"opb"},{question:"While operating off the coast of Greece, a seaman is injured. What indicator should be in the preamble of a radio telegram asking for medical advice from a Greek station?",opa:"RADIO MEDICAL",opb:"DH MEDICO",opc:"MEDICO ELLAS",opd:"MAYDAY",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is meant by 'CES'?",opa:"Coast Earth Satellite",opb:"Coast Earth Station",opc:"Central Equatorial Station",opd:"Coastal Equivalent Station",ans:"opb"},{question:"A mobile offshore drilling unit will show the day-shape in Diagram 10 to indicate that it is ____________.",opa:"at anchor",opb:"being towed",opc:"aground",opd:"drilling",ans:"opb"},{question:"Small passenger vessels in coastwise service must carry approved ____________.",opa:"life floats",opb:"inflatable buoyant apparatus",opc:"inflatable liferafts",opd:"Any of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Coast Guard inspection required before a Certificate of Inspection can be issued is conducted ____________.",opa:"when deemed necessary by the Regional Inspection Center",opb:"after you apply in writing to the nearest Officer in Charge of Marine Inspection (OCMI)",opc:"at random from a Coast Guard patrol boat",opd:"after a formal complaint is filed with the OCMI",ans:"opb"},{question:"How much drill water is required for transfer between drill water tanks #25 and #26 in order to correct the list of the COASTAL DRILLER with total transverse moments of - 6,800 ft.-kips?",opa:"200 kips from tank#26 to tank #25",opb:"200 kips from tank#25 to tank #26",opc:"100 kips from tank#26 to tank #25",opd:"100 kips from tank#25 to tank #26",ans:"opd"},{question:"Provided every effort is made to preserve body moisture content by avoiding perspiration, how long is it normally possible to survive without water?",opa:"Up to 3 days",opb:"8 to 12 days",opc:"15 to 20 days",opd:"25 to 30 days",ans:"opb"},{question:"A 6,000 BHP, 199 GT tug operating on the Great Lakes is required to carry how many B-II extinguishers? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"6",opd:"9",ans:"opd"},{question:"Coast Guard Regulations permit which of the following systems to be used for fire prevention and the simultaneous inerting of cargo tanks on tank vessels?",opa:"An inert gas system",opb:"The deck foam system",opc:"The fire main system",opd:"A fixed water spray system",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fires which occur in energized electrical equipment, such as switchboard insulation, are class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to the regulations, what fire safety control feature is required in quick-closing shut off valves?",opa:"Electrical cut off switch",opb:"A fusible link",opc:"Manual cut off switch",opd:"A water spray actuator",ans:"opb"},{question:"When floating, the appropriate leg horizontal must be aligned in the center of the ____________.",opa:"center of each lower hull guide",opb:"center of each upper guide structure",opc:"top of the jack house",opd:"bottom of the hull",ans:"opb"},{question:"Each fireman's outfit and its spare equipment on a MODU must be stowed ____________.",opa:"in a locked cabinet in the machinery space",opb:"in an unlocked cabinet in the machinery space",opc:"in a separate and accessible location",opd:"at a fire hydrant location",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a MODU, each EPIRB or SART must be tested at least once ____________.",opa:"each week",opb:"every two weeks",opc:"each month",opd:"every two months",ans:"opc"},{question:"Offshore drilling units that are on an international voyage must have a portable radio apparatus that meets the requirements of the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Minerals Management Service",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"Federal Communications Commission",ans:"opd"},{question:"The helicopter deck of a MODU must be marked with the units identification, appropriate aiming circles, and a continuous line on the perimeter which is ____________.",opa:"8 inches wide",opb:"16 inches wide",opc:"24 inches wide",opd:"32 inches wide",ans:"opb"},{question:"Oil well casing will fail when the external pressure exceeds the internal pressure by a differential equal to the casing's rated ____________.",opa:"tensile strength",opb:"hoop stress",opc:"collapse pressure",opd:"burst pressure",ans:"opc"},{question:"After you have thrown the liferaft and stowage container into the water, you inflate the liferaft by ____________.",opa:"pulling on the painter line",opb:"forcing open the container which operates the CO2",opc:"hitting the hydrostatic release",opd:"using the hand pump provided",ans:"opa"},{question:"A fishing vessel that is required to have a fireman's outfit, must have all of the following in the outfit except a ____________.",opa:"flashlight",opb:"combustible gas indicator",opc:"self-contained breathing apparatus",opd:"fire axe",ans:"opb"},{question:"Lubricating oil should be changed on a heavy duty diesel engine when ____________.",opa:"it gets dark in color",opb:"a sample rubbed between fingers feels thin",opc:"it has been in use for a specified interval",opd:"it no longer supports combustion",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 21'-04', AFT 26'-04'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"0.62 foot",opb:"0.80 foot",opc:"0.85 foot",opd:"0.99 foot",ans:"opa"},{question:"A mobile offshore drilling unit is on the waters of the U.S. Outer Continental Shelf. It has a length of 220 feet and a breadth of 190 feet. Where must the obstruction lights be located?",opa:"At the top of the drill mast",opb:"On each corner of the rig",opc:"At the bow of the rig",opd:"At the bow and stern of the rig",ans:"opb"},{question:"While drilling loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), the DEEP DRILLER suffers an unexpected but slowly increasing port and aft inclination. The wind and waves are light. This inclination could have been caused by ____________.",opa:"the failure of mooring lines 2 and 3",opb:"the drilling crew dumping the mud",opc:"the drill string breaking",opd:"ballast tanks equalizing into tank 10P",ans:"opd"},{question:"The painter of an inflatable liferaft should be ____________.",opa:"free running on the deck",opb:"faked out next to the case",opc:"secured to a permanent object on deck",opd:"stowed near the raft",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the VCG for the cement in P-Tank #1 on the DEEP DRILLER if the ullage is 6.4 feet?",opa:"116.24 feet",opb:"116.44 feet",opc:"119.81 feet",opd:"123.06 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A J-chaser is used to ____________.",opa:"transfer a pennant wire to the anchor handling vessel",opb:"clean chain as it is hauled into the rig",opc:"lower spring buoys into the water",opd:"retrieve an anchor after the buoy has been lost",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, following discharge of preload, should ____________.",opa:"leave dump valves open",opb:"close all dump valves",opc:"remove dump valves",opd:"replace dump valves",ans:"opb"},{question:"A motor lifeboat shall carry sufficient fuel to operate continuously for a period of ____________.",opa:"12 hours",opb:"18 hours",opc:"24 hours",opd:"36 hours",ans:"opc"},{question:"Carbon dioxide cylinders which protect machinery spaces, paint lockers and tanks may be located within those spaces when the amount of carbon dioxide does not exceed ____________.",opa:"150 lbs.",opb:"300 lbs.",opc:"450 lbs.",opd:"600 lbs.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which data is NOT painted on the bow of a lifeboat?",opa:"Number of persons allowed",opb:"Name of the vessel",opc:"Weight of the boat",opd:"Port of registry",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the Captain of the Port or Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection issues an order of suspension to the operator of a vessel concerning oil transfer operations, it ____________.",opa:"is always effective immediately",opb:"includes a statement of each condition requiring corrective action",opc:"must be in writing before it takes effect",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 747 tons and measures 136'L by 34'B. You ship a large wave on the after deck. What is the reduction to GM due to free surface before the water drains overboard, if the after deck measures 56'L x 34'B and the weight of the water is 58.6 tons?",opa:"6.04 feet",opb:"6.23 feet",opc:"6.51 feet",opd:"6.76 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"All personnel onboard a vessel should be familiar with the rescue boat's ____________.",opa:"boarding and operating procedure",opb:"maintenance schedules",opc:"navigational systems",opd:"fuel consumption rates",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 22'-04', AFT 21'-06'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if: (1) 300 tons are loaded 122 feet forward of amidships; (2) 225 tons are loaded 150 feet aft of amidships; and 122 tons of fuel are pumped 72 feet aft.",opa:"FWD 22'-11', AFT22'-09'",opb:"FWD 23'-00', AFT23'-00'",opc:"FWD 23'-02', AFT23'-01'",opd:"FWD 23'-03', AFT23'-05'",ans:"opa"},{question:"How would the exhaust of a properly operating diesel engine appear?",opa:"Light blue haze",opb:"Light brown haze",opc:"Light gray haze",opd:"Perfectly clear",ans:"opd"},{question:"A fire in the radio transmitter would be of what class?",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers major damage which results in flooding in tank C3S. Pumping from tanks in the vicinity of the damage have proven ineffective. Your best countermeasure is to ____________.",opa:"counter flood in 1P",opb:"counter flood in 10S",opc:"pump from C1P",opd:"pump from C3S",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which type of ventilation is required for enclosed spaces containing gasoline, machinery, or fuel tanks? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Natural supply and mechanical exhaust",opb:"Mechanical supply and natural exhaust",opc:"Mechanical supply and mechanical exhaust",opd:"Natural supply and natural exhaust",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is an advantage of diesel over steam turbine propulsion?",opa:"Less fuel consumption per SHP",opb:"Diesel fuel costs less than bunker C or its equivalent",opc:"Less routine maintenance required",opd:"Less weight per SHP",ans:"opa"},{question:"After you activate your emergency position indicating radio beacon, you should ____________.",opa:"turn it off for five minutes every half-hour",opb:"turn it off and on at five-minute intervals",opc:"turn it off during daylight hours",opd:"leave it on continuously",ans:"opd"},{question:"The center of volume of the immersed portion of the hull is called the ____________.",opa:"center of buoyancy",opb:"center of flotation",opc:"center of gravity",opd:"tipping center",ans:"opa"},{question:"When approaching a fire from leeward you should shield fire fighters from the fire by using ____________.",opa:"a straight stream of water",opb:"foam spray",opc:"high-velocity fog",opd:"low-velocity fog",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the change in longitudinal moments for the Coastal Driller if 2.0 feet of drill water is transferred from a full drill water tank #23 to an empty drill water tank #1?",opa:"15,565 foot-kips increase",opb:"7,585 foot-kips increase",opc:"15,565 foot-kips decrease",opd:"16,041 foot-kips decrease",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many bolts are required in a temporarily connected standard ANSI (American National Standards Institute) coupling?",opa:"2",opb:"4",opc:"6",opd:"8",ans:"opb"},{question:"What can be determined about an injury from examining the condition of a victim's pupils?",opa:"The degree of pain being suffered",opb:"The degree of vision impairment",opc:"Whether or not the brain is functioning properly",opd:"Whether or not the victim's blood pressure is normal",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel heading WSW is on a course of ____________.",opa:"202.5\xb0",opb:"225.0\xb0",opc:"247.5\xb0",opd:"271.0\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"What are the maximum vertical moments, including free surface moments, permitted on the DEEP DRILLER at survival draft if the winds are less than 70 knots?",opa:"912,120 foot-tons",opb:"933,124 foot-tons",opc:"996,529 foot-tons",opd:"998,929 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Distress flares and smoke signals for small passenger vessels ____________.",opa:"are not required aboard vessels on runs of less than 30 minutes duration",opb:"must be Coast Guard approved and stowed in a portable, watertight container",opc:"must be marked with an expiration date not more than 42 months from the date of manufacture",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fire protection regulations for towing vessels require that drills be conducted onboard the vessel as if there were an actual emergency. Drills include all of the following, EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"testing all alarm and detection systems",opb:"breaking out and using the vessel's emergency equipment",opc:"participation by selected crew members",opd:"one person putting on protective clothing, if the vessel is so equipped",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which formula can be used to calculate metacentric height?",opa:"KM + GM",opb:"KM -GM",opc:"KM -KG",opd:"KB + BM",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER's ability to meet the damage stability criteria depends on maintaining a watertight integrity, KGL and KGT less than maximum allowed, level attitude, and displacement less than ____________.",opa:"11,777 kips",opb:"13,158 kips",opc:"14,158 kips",opd:"17,280 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"When stability of a vessel is neutral, the value of GM ____________.",opa:"only depends on the height of the center of gravity",opb:"only depends on the height of the metacenter",opc:"is greater when G is low",opd:"is zero",ans:"opd"},{question:"The free surface effects of a partially full liquid tank decrease with increased ____________.",opa:"density of the liquid",opb:"placement of the tank above the keel",opc:"displacement volume of the vessel",opd:"size of the surface area in the tank",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Emergency Position Indicating Radio beacon on an OSV vessel must be stowed ____________.",opa:"in an inside passageway",opb:"in an approved bracket",opc:"so that it is accessible from the pilothouse of the vessel",opd:"so that it will float free if the vessel sinks",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 20'-08', AFT 23'-03'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the MT1.",opa:"1050 foot-tons",opb:"1065 foot-tons",opc:"1090 foot-tons",opd:"1130 foot-tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"Freeboard is measured from the upper edge of the ____________.",opa:"bulwark",opb:"deck line",opc:"gunwale bar",opd:"sheer strake",ans:"opb"},{question:"Flames from small leaks of LFG may be extinguished by ____________.",opa:"utilizing carbon dioxide or dry chemical fire extinguishers",opb:"utilizing soda and acid fire extinguishers",opc:"blowing the flames out",opd:"letting it burn itself out",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the meaning of the signal 'G0325'?",opa:"The distance is 325 miles.",opb:"The longitude is 3\xb025'.",opc:"The course is 325\xb0.",opd:"Change course to 325\xb0.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A shipmate chokes suddenly, cannot speak, and starts to turn blue. You should ____________.",opa:"perform the Heimlich maneuver",opb:"make the victim lie down with the feet elevated to get blood to the brain",opc:"immediately administer CPR",opd:"do nothing until the victim becomes unconscious",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which chemical is used to treat water in order to ensure its safety for drinking?",opa:"Nitrogen",opb:"Chlorine",opc:"Carbon",opd:"Oxygen",ans:"opb"},{question:"Prior to entering a davit-launched liferaft, you should make sure that ____________.",opa:"the liferaft is well ventilated of excess carbon dioxide",opb:"all personnel have removed their life preservers to facilitate boarding",opc:"the door flap has been cut away and stowed inside the raft",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"In order to maintain speed while changing course from a close reach to a broad reach, the sails should be ____________.",opa:"lowered",opb:"reefed",opc:"hauled in",opd:"eased out",ans:"opd"},{question:"While operating off Panama a seaman is injured. What indicator should be included in the preamble of a radio telegram requesting medical advice from a Panamanian station?",opa:"RADIO MEDICAL",opb:"DH MEDICO",opc:"XXX",opd:"MEDRAD",ans:"opb"},{question:"On small passenger vessels which parts of a water-cooled gasoline or diesel engine must be water-jacketed and cooled?",opa:"The engine's head",opb:"The block",opc:"The exhaust manifold",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are loading in a port subject to the winter load line mark and bound for a port subject to the tropical load line mark. You will enter the summer zone after steaming four days, and you will enter the tropical zone after a total of seven days. You will consume 38 tons of fuel, water, and stores per day. The hydrometer reading at the loading pier is 1.004, and the average TPI is 72. What is the minimum freeboard required at the start of the voyage?",opa:"85 inches",opb:"90 inches",opc:"92 inches",opd:"94 inches",ans:"opb"},{question:"When positive stability exists, GZ represents the ____________.",opa:"righting moment",opb:"center of gravity",opc:"righting arm",opd:"metacentric height",ans:"opc"},{question:"The total leg load reactions on an independent leg, self-elevating unit include static and ____________.",opa:"environmental loading",opb:"variable loading",opc:"fixed loading",opd:"basic loading",ans:"opa"},{question:"If an inflatable liferaft is overturned, it may be righted by ____________.",opa:"filling the stabilizers on one side with water",opb:"releasing the CO2 cylinder",opc:"pushing up from under one end",opd:"standing on the inflating cylinder and pulling on the straps on the underside of the raft",ans:"opd"},{question:"On vessels that are required to have fixed carbon dioxide fire extinguishing systems, the controls to operate the system shall be installed in an accessible location ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"outside the space protected",opb:"inside the space protected",opc:"at the carbon dioxide cylinders",opd:"in a padlocked waterproof metal box",ans:"opa"},{question:"How many degrees are there on a compass card?",opa:"360\xb0",opb:"380\xb0",opc:"390\xb0",opd:"420\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"The tricing pendants should be released ____________.",opa:"before the gripes are removed",opb:"before loading the passengers",opc:"after loading the passengers",opd:"after the boat is afloat",ans:"opc"},{question:"A 100-GT vessel, constructed before July 1,1974, is loading diesel fuel. What is the minimum capacity of the drip pans required for placement under or around each fuel tank vent, overflow, and fill pipe?",opa:"1 gallon",opb:"5 gallons",opc:"1 barrel",opd:"2 barrels",ans:"opb"},{question:"The vessel\u2019s fire control plan is laid out on which of the following type of plan?",opa:"General arrangement",opb:"Midship section",opc:"Subdivision",opd:"Lines",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 08'-11.5', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.85 feet",opb:"2.65 feet",opc:"2.36 feet",opd:"2.15 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"When personnel are lifted by a helicopter from an inflatable liferaft, the personnel on the raft should ____________.",opa:"deflate the floor of the raft to reduce the danger of capsizing",opb:"inflate the floor of the raft to provide for additional stability",opc:"remove their lifejackets to prepare for the transfer",opd:"take in the sea anchor to prevent fouling of the rescue sling",ans:"opa"},{question:"An elevated jack-up weighs 17,000 kips. Its center of gravity is located 110 feet aft of frame zero (AFO). What would be the new LCG if the cantilever (weight 900 kips) and drill floor (weight 800 kips) were skidded 70 feet aft?",opa:"103.0 feet AF0",opb:"113.4 feet AF0",opc:"117.0 feet AF0",opd:"180.0 feet AF0",ans:"opc"},{question:"Offshore drilling units that carry twelve or more persons on a voyage of more than three days must have a ____________.",opa:"recreation room",opb:"radar room",opc:"hospital space",opd:"navigation space",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a combination chain and wire rope mooring line is used, the chain is deployed ____________.",opa:"at the anchor end of the line",opb:"at the wildcat end of the line",opc:"midway between the anchor and the wildcat",opd:"through the anchor buoy",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the value of KML for the DEEP DRILLER at a draft of 60 feet?",opa:"59.63 feet",opb:"60.16 feet",opc:"61.68 feet",opd:"61.13 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The purpose of air tanks in a lifeboat is to ____________.",opa:"make the boat float higher",opb:"provide a stowage place for provisions",opc:"add strength to the boat",opd:"keep the boat afloat if flooded",ans:"opd"},{question:"In rough weather, when a ship is able to maneuver, it is best to launch a lifeboat ____________.",opa:"on the lee side",opb:"on the windward side",opc:"with the wind dead ahead",opd:"with the wind from astern",ans:"opa"},{question:"One of the main purposes of the inclining experiment on a vessel is to determine the ____________.",opa:"location of the center of gravity of the light ship",opb:"position of the center of buoyancy",opc:"position of the metacenter",opd:"maximum load line",ans:"opa"},{question:"A fire must be ventilated ____________.",opa:"when using an indirect attack on the fire such as flooding with water",opb:"to prevent the gases of combustion from surrounding the firefighters",opc:"to minimize heat buildup in adjacent compartments",opd:"if compressed gas cylinders are stowed in the compartment on fire",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which hazard probably would NOT be encountered when entering an empty but uncleaned fish hold?",opa:"Lack of oxygen",opb:"Methane gas",opc:"Hydrogen sulfide gas",opd:"Carbon monoxide",ans:"opd"},{question:"What does blowing tubes accomplish?",opa:"Eliminates unburned fuel oil residues from the firebox",opb:"Increases boiler efficiency",opc:"Flushes away mineral deposits inside the water tubes",opd:"Cleans soot deposits from the inside of the stack",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement about firefighting foam is TRUE?",opa:"Foam conducts electricity.",opb:"To be most effective, foam should be directed at the base of the fire.",opc:"Foam is most effective on burning liquids which are flowing.",opd:"Foam can ONLY be used to extinguish class A fires.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which is/are required for engine exhaust pipe installations on small passenger vessels?",opa:"Protection where people or equipment can contact the pipe.",opb:"Piping must be arranged so that water backflow cannot reach the engine exhaust ports",opc:"Dry exhaust pipe ending at the transom should be located as far outboard as possible",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fire axes required on MODU's must be stored in the enclosure for fire hoses with the location marked '__________'.",opa:"Fire Axe Location",opb:"Hose Station No.",opc:"Fire Station No.",opd:"Firefighting Equipment",ans:"opc"},{question:"While going on location in 250 feet water depth when the pitch angle of the COASTAL DRILLER is 2 degrees, the single amplitude pitch period should be longer than ____________.",opa:"0.2 second",opb:"0.4 second",opc:"4.9 seconds",opd:"13.9 seconds",ans:"opd"},{question:"A semisubmersible with displacement of 19,700 long tons and KG of 50.96 feet loads 300 long tons of barite into P-tanks located 120 feet above the keel. What is the change in KG?",opa:"0.79 foot upward",opb:"1.00 foot upward",opc:"1.04 feet upward",opd:"1.83 feet upward",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). Weather conditions require ballasting to survival draft. Assume that upon arrival at 45 feet, port and starboard ballast tanks 2 and 9 will be full and that port and starboard ballast tanks 1, 3, and 8 will be slack. What would be the new value of the total longitudinal free surface moments (FSML)?",opa:"69,658 foot-tons",opb:"56,244 foot-tons",opc:"42,830 foot-tons",opd:"30,168 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master shall insure that the Emergency Position Indicating Radio beacon (EPIRB) is ____________.",opa:"secured inside the wheelhouse",opb:"tested annually",opc:"tested monthly",opd:"secured in the emergency locker",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 24'-09', AFT 27'-02'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessels displacement if you are in salt water.",opa:"13,175 tons",opb:"13,350 tons",opc:"13,490 tons",opd:"13,620 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"A drilling bit which is doughnut shaped to permit recovery of the center portion of the hole drilled is called a ____________.",opa:"diverter bit",opb:"hole reamer",opc:"core bit",opd:"conventional bit",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a cargo of kerosene were considered 'too lean' to explode, then it must be ____________.",opa:"above the 'explosive range'",opb:"within the 'explosive range'",opc:"below the 'explosive range'",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER may remain at operating draft instead of deballasting to survival draft when ____________.",opa:"critical motion limits have been exceeded",opb:"waves approach within two feet of the spider deck",opc:"the maximum wave height is less than 64 feet",opd:"winds are greater than 70 knots",ans:"opc"},{question:"The natural rolling period of a drilling barge increases when ____________.",opa:"GM increases",opb:"the setback is placed in the pipe racks",opc:"free surfaces are reduced",opd:"ice accumulates above deck",ans:"opd"},{question:"Under normal conditions a liferaft is released from its cradle by ____________.",opa:"cutting the restraining strap",opb:"unscrewing the turnbuckle on the back of the cradle",opc:"lifting one end of the raft",opd:"pushing the plunger on the center of the hydrostatic release",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is CORRECT with respect to inserting an airway tube?",opa:"Only a trained person should attempt to insert an airway tube.",opb:"A size 2 airway tube is the correct size for an adult.",opc:"The airway tube will not damage the victim's throat.",opd:"Inserting the airway tube will prevent vomiting.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A fire of escaping liquefied flammable gas is best extinguished by ____________.",opa:"cooling the gas below the ignition point",opb:"cutting off the supply of oxygen",opc:"stopping the flow of gas",opd:"interrupting the chain reaction",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have 12 containers of rig supplies each measuring 10'L by 4'B by 5'H and weighing 2.0 tons each. Each container is stowed on deck. What is the maximum VCG permitted of the remaining cargo if you are carrying rig water and load to maximum capacity?",opa:"0.5 foot",opb:"0.9 foot",opc:"1.1 feet",opd:"1.6 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many fire axes should be carried by a 700 GT cargo vessel, navigating the Great Lakes?",opa:"8",opb:"6",opc:"4",opd:"2",ans:"opb"},{question:"The most detrimental effect on initial stability is a result of liquids ____________.",opa:"flowing from side to side within the vessel",opb:"flowing from fore to aft within a vessel",opc:"flowing in and out of a holed wing tank",opd:"pocketing in a slack tank as a vessel heels",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 869 tons and measures 136'L x 33'B. You ship a large wave on the after deck which measures 52'L x 33'B. The weight of the water is estimated at 52.8 tons. What is the reduction in GM due to free surface before the water drains overboard?",opa:"4.83 feet",opb:"5.12 feet",opc:"5.46 feet",opd:"5.85 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Due to the shape of the sea anchor, the best way to haul it back aboard is by ____________.",opa:"hauling in on the anchor line as you would any anchor",opb:"getting all hands to assist",opc:"its trip line",opd:"cutting the line, as you cannot haul it back in",ans:"opc"},{question:"The three corners of the main sail are called ____________.",opa:"head, fore, and aft",opb:"luff, leech, and spar",opc:"headboard, foot, and tail",opd:"head, tack, and clew",ans:"opd"},{question:"The maximum weight for the COASTAL DRILLER in severe storm conditions is ____________.",opa:"14,158 kips",opb:"14,400 kips",opc:"15,158 kips",opd:"17,280 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"In evacuation from a MODU, an individual without the option of a survival craft or liferaft should enter the water on the leeward side, except when ____________.",opa:"there is a rescue craft in the area",opb:"there is hydrogen sulfide present",opc:"water temperature is below 40\xb0F",opd:"a rigid survival craft is in the area",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER arrived in port with drafts of: FWD 28'-04', AFT 30'-08'. Cargo was loaded and discharged as indicated. Use sheet 2 in the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts.",opa:"FWD 29'-01', AFT30'-01'",opb:"FWD 29'-03', AFT29'-11'",opc:"FWD 29'-05', AFT29'-09'",opd:"FWD 29'-07', AFT29'-07'",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the total number of approved low-velocity spray ('water-fog') applicators required aboard a tankship?",opa:"4",opb:"7",opc:"10",opd:"11",ans:"opb"},{question:"How is a distress message normally initiated through INMARSAT?",opa:"All INMARSAT units have a dedicated key that can be pressed for immediate action.",opb:"By adding the word 'DISTRESS' in the first line of the message's preamble",opc:"Certain INMARSAT units have a dedicated key that can be pressed for immediate action, while other systems provide menu-driven features.",opd:"By transmitting the distress message on the U.S. Coast Guard's dedicated monitoring channel.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning a sailing vessel with the sails properly trimmed?",opa:"The more the sails are sheeted in, the greater your speed will be when sailing downwind.",opb:"As the sails are sheeted in, the vessel will heel less when close hauled.",opc:"As the sails are sheeted in on a close hauled course, speed will increase as the side forces on the vessel decrease.",opd:"Sheeting in the sails will allow the vessel to sail closer to the wind but will decrease speed.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which communications functions must all vessels be capable of performing under GMDSS as defined by the International Maritime Organization?",opa:"Radio direction finding",opb:"Distress alerting to and from vessels, search and rescue coordination, on-scene communications, signals for locating, Maritime Safety Information, general and bridge-to-bridge communications.",opc:"Communications in each of the operational ocean areas",opd:"All communications possible within the International Safety-NET service",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning the application of dry chemical powder is FALSE?",opa:"At temperatures of less than 32\xb0F, the extinguisher must be recharged more often.",opb:"When possible, the fire should be attacked from windward.",opc:"The stream should be directed at the base of the fire.",opd:"Directing the stream into burning flammable liquid may cause splashing.",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a victim is unconscious, you should first look for evidence of ____________.",opa:"high fever",opb:"head injury",opc:"broken limbs",opd:"irregular breathing",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel which violates the 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act' may be charged a civil penalty of ____________.",opa:"100",opb:"650",opc:"1000",opd:"1500",ans:"opb"},{question:"The fire control plan symbol represented by (56) is a ____________.",opa:"water monitor (gun)",opb:"water fog applicator",opc:"space protected by water",opd:"sprinkler head",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT a requirement of cargo piping installed in tank vessels carrying grade D or E cargo ONLY?",opa:"The cargo piping system shall be fixed.",opb:"Flanged joints shall be used for pipe sizes exceeding 2 inches in diameter.",opc:"Piping through bunker spaces may be run through a pipe tunnel.",opd:"Connections at bulkheads must be made so that the plating does not form part of a flanged joint.",ans:"opa"},{question:"If your asphalt barge has operated more than 12 months in saltwater in the 24 month period since it was last dry-docked, when is it required to be hauled out again?",opa:"12 months since last dry-docking",opb:"18 months since last dry-docking",opc:"24 months since last dry-docking",opd:"36 months since last dry-docking",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 08'-11.5', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.20 feet",opb:"2.00 feet",opc:"1.80 feet",opd:"1.65 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are FWD 19'-03', AFT 21'-07'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if 142 tons of fuel are pumped 86 feet aft.",opa:"FWD 18'-09', AFT22'-01'",opb:"FWD 19'-00', AFT21'-01'",opc:"FWD 19'-00', AFT21'-08'",opd:"FWD 19'-01', AFT21'-04'",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 58.0 feet draft in sea water, places 200 long tons onboard. What is the new draft?",opa:"56.55 feet",opb:"59.45 feet",opc:"60.00 feet",opd:"75.41 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A message giving warning of a hurricane should have which prefix when sent by radiotelephone?",opa:"Pan-Pan (3 times)",opb:"Securite Securite Securite",opc:"TTT TTT TTT",opd:"No special prefix",ans:"opb"},{question:"It is generally NOT allowed to clean up an oil spill by using ____________.",opa:"a boom",opb:"suction equipment",opc:"chemical agents",opd:"skimmers",ans:"opc"},{question:"Use the material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the KG is 25.2 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 27'-11', AFT 28'-09'; at what angle will the vessel lose positive stability?",opa:"54\xb0",opb:"59\xb0",opc:"65\xb0",opd:"71\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"The decks of a MODU are supported by transverse members called ____________.",opa:"trusses",opb:"deck longitudinals",opc:"deck beams",opd:"web frames",ans:"opc"},{question:"Under ideal conditions, the DEEP DRILLER can pick up and place pipe in the rack at a rate of about ____________.",opa:"600 feet per hour",opb:"800 feet per hour",opc:"1,000 feet per hour",opd:"1,200 feet per hour",ans:"opc"},{question:"In which Sea Area must a compulsory vessel carry either INMARSAT or HF SITOR equipment?",opa:"This equipment must be carried at all times at sea regardless of where the vessel will be operating.",opb:"This equipment partially satisfies the carriage requirement for vessels operating in Sea Area A3.",opc:"This equipment satisfies in full the carriage requirement for vessels operating in Sea Area A2.",opd:"HF SITOR equipment partially satisfies the carriage requirement for vessels operating in Sea Area A3, but INMARSAT equipment must be carried to satisfy the requirement when the vessel is in Sea Area A4.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which would be considered pollution under the U.S. water pollution laws?",opa:"Garbage",opb:"Hazardous substances",opc:"Oil",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 6'-02', AFT 6'-08'. From past experience, you know that the vessel will increase her draft 1 inch for every 6 tons loaded. There is rig water onboard and 23 tons of deck cargo. How many more tons of cargo can be loaded and still maintain the same trim?",opa:"6 tons",opb:"12 tons",opc:"18 tons",opd:"24 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"All marine low-speed diesels are of what design?",opa:"Four-stroke",opb:"Two-stroke",opc:"Electronic ignition",opd:"Forced exhaust",ans:"opb"},{question:"The remote control for a fixed fire extinguishing system should be ____________. (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"painted red and labeled",opb:"concealed from the crew",opc:"protected by plexiglas",opd:"padlocked",ans:"opa"},{question:"Oily rags stored in a pile that is open to the atmosphere are a hazard because they may ____________.",opa:"deteriorate and give off noxious gasses",opb:"spontaneously heat and catch fire",opc:"attract lice and other vermin and serve as a breeding ground",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (transit). What is the new metacentric height corrected for transverse free surface effects if the entire contents of Salt Water Ballast Tanks 1P and 1S are discharged? (Use KMT = 375.38 feet)",opa:"375.38 feet",opb:"345.23 feet",opc:"319.66 feet",opd:"306.79 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a mean draft of 45 feet, has a three-foot trim by the stern and a two-foot list to port. What is the draft at the starboard forward draft mark?",opa:"42.5 feet",opb:"44.5 feet",opc:"45.5 feet",opd:"47.5 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A moment of 300 ft.-tons is created by a force of 15,000 tons. What is the moment arm?",opa:"50.00 feet",opb:"25.00 feet",opc:"0.04 foot",opd:"0.02 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 140\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"close hauled on the starboard tack",opb:"close hauled on the port tack",opc:"on a broad reach",opd:"running before the wind",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 18'-06', AFT 19'-01'; and the KG is 18.2 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 35\xb0 inclination.",opa:"1.8 feet",opb:"3.0 feet",opc:"4.7 feet",opd:"5.8 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"An aluminum powder fire is classified as class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is considered to be a B-II portable fire extinguisher?",opa:"2-1/2 gallon foam",opb:"4 pound carbon dioxide",opc:"2 pound dry chemical",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The edge of the sail labeled 'A' is called the ____________.",opa:"leech",opb:"clew",opc:"luff",opd:"headboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"The flammable limits of gasoline are 1.3 to 7.6 percent volume of air. You are testing a tank that contained gasoline by using a combustible gas indicator. Under testing, the tank sample caused the needle to move rapidly to 100 on the dial and remain there. What is the concentration of flammable gas?",opa:"0",opb:"1.3 to 7.6%",opc:"over 7.6%",opd:"over 100%",ans:"opb"},{question:"While loaded as shown in the DEEP DRILLER Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), all of the liquid mud is dumped. What is the new uncorrected KG?",opa:"52.09 feet",opb:"52.20 feet",opc:"53.23 feet",opd:"55.36 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 2.4 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.2 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.5 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning lifeboat gripes?",opa:"They must be released by freeing a safety shackle.",opb:"They should not be released until the boat is in lowering position.",opc:"They may be adjusted by a turnbuckle.",opd:"They are normally used only with radial davits.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). How much additional deck load can be placed aboard without exceeding the deck load limit?",opa:"1,335.6 long tons",opb:"1,086.6 long tons",opc:"585.4 long tons",opd:"435.6 long tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"You receive a medical message that contains the code MSJ. This means ' ____________.'",opa:"Place patient in hot bath",opb:"The wound should be stitched",opc:"You should pass a stomach tube",opd:"The wound should not be stitched",ans:"opa"},{question:"Anchor shackles should have a breaking strength that is ____________.",opa:"equal to the chains they are connecting",opb:"25% more than the chains they are connecting",opc:"50% more than the chains they are connecting",opd:"100% more than the chains they are connecting",ans:"opa"},{question:"When H2S is burned (flared) on a MODU, what can you expect to occur?",opa:"All of the H2S will be converted to SO2.",opb:"All of the H2S will be converted to hydrogen and free sulfur.",opc:"Only 80% of the H2S will be converted to SO2 or free sulfur.",opd:"The H2S not converted will not be dangerous.",ans:"opc"},{question:"On every vessel, distress signals must be stowed ____________.",opa:"on or near the navigating bridge",opb:"on the flying bridge not closer than 15 feet to any bulkhead",opc:"above the freeboard deck away from heat",opd:"in an enclosed space below the freeboard deck away from heat",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the primary advantage of a davit-launched liferaft in comparison to an inflatable liferaft?",opa:"The davit-launched liferaft is easier to maintain.",opb:"The davit-launched liferaft is made of fire-retardant material.",opc:"The davit-launched liferaft has a built-in sprinkler system for fire protection.",opd:"The davit-launched liferaft enables personnel to enter the raft without having to enter the water.",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the change in the vertical moments (excluding free surface effects) for the COASTAL DRILLER if 2.0 feet of drill water is transferred from a full drill water tank #23 to an empty drill water tank #6?",opa:"253 foot-kips",opb:"56 foot-kips",opc:"-253 foot-kips",opd:"-411 foot-kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is a treatment for traumatic shock?",opa:"Administer CPR.",opb:"Administer fluids.",opc:"Open clothing to allow cooling of the body.",opd:"Keep the victim in a sitting position.",ans:"opb"},{question:"While in transit, the DEEP DRILLER suffers flooding in the starboard pump room. Both starboard bilge pumps are inadequate to dewater the pump room. You may supplement the performance of the bilge pumps by using the ____________.",opa:"starboard saltwater service pump",opb:"starboard drill water pump",opc:"starboard ballast pump",opd:"port ballast pump and crossover system",ans:"opb"},{question:"The platform that supports the derrickman when tripping pipe is called the ____________.",opa:"Texas deck",opb:"water table",opc:"stabbing board",opd:"monkey board",ans:"opd"},{question:"The difference between the height of the metacenter and the height of the center of gravity is ____________.",opa:"KB",opb:"KG",opc:"KM",opd:"GM",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are standing a radio watch aboard the rig. A crew boat calls you on VHF channel 16. When you reply with your vessel name and call letters, you should request the crew boat to switch to an intership channel such as channel ____________.",opa:"6",opb:"10",opc:"12",opd:"14",ans:"opb"},{question:"When piggybacking anchors, the distance between the primary anchor and the secondary anchor is determined by ____________.",opa:"bottom conditions",opb:"anchor types",opc:"water depth",opd:"workboat winch capacity",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which data is NOT used in the Allowable Wind and Wave Charts for the COASTAL DRILLER?",opa:"Leg penetration",opb:"Wave height",opc:"Total weight",opd:"Current",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the ullage is 6.4 feet in P-Tank #5 for the Deep Driller, what is the value of the longitudinal moment?",opa:"-2,254 foot-tons",opb:"-2,949 foot-tons",opc:"-3,392 foot-tons",opd:"-4,249 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel must have at least two fireman's outfits aboard if she ____________.",opa:"is documented",opb:"is over 100 gross tons",opc:"is under foreign articles",opd:"has more than 49 people aboard",ans:"opd"},{question:"The joint of the riser in a marine riser system that compensates for heave, the up-and-down motion of a floater, is the ____________.",opa:"flex joint",opb:"slip joint",opc:"heave joint",opd:"riser joint",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the regulations for lifeboat falls, which action must be taken with the falls no later than 5-year intervals?",opa:"Proof tested",opb:"End-for-ended",opc:"Renewed",opd:"Weight tested",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should the number '9' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"NEW-MER-AL-NINER",opb:"NUM-BER-NINE",opc:"NO-VAY-NINER",opd:"OK-TOH-NINE",ans:"opc"},{question:"What are the three basic types of engine starters?",opa:"Air, water, electric",opb:"Air, hydraulic, electric",opc:"Metered, hydraulic, automatic",opd:"Air, emergency, hydraulic",ans:"opb"},{question:"The space containing carbon dioxide cylinders shall be properly ventilated and designed to prevent an ambient temperature in excess of ____________.",opa:"75\xb0F",opb:"100\xb0F",opc:"130\xb0F",opd:"165\xb0F",ans:"opc"},{question:"After deploying the anchor, a permanent chain chaser is ____________.",opa:"removed from the anchor chain",opb:"connected to a buoy at the anchor",opc:"stripped back to the rig and secured",opd:"connected to a buoy halfway down the chain",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 58.0 feet draft in sea water, discharges 200 long tons. What is the new draft?",opa:"55.55 feet",opb:"56.55 feet",opc:"57.05 feet",opd:"59.45 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A semisubmersible displacing 17,600 long tons has an LCG 3.2 feet forward of amidships. Bulk, weighing 400 long tons, is loaded into P-tanks located 50.8 feet aft of amidships. What is the new LCG?",opa:"0.80 foot forward of amidships",opb:"1.20 feet forward of amidships",opc:"2.00 feet forward of amidships",opd:"4.40 feet forward of amidships",ans:"opc"},{question:"A person who observes an individual fall overboard from an OSV should ____________.",opa:"immediately jump into the water to assist the individual",opb:"call for help and keep the individual in sight",opc:"run to the radio room to send an emergency message",opd:"go to the control room for the distress flares",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the threshold limit value (TLV) for a product of PHTHALIC ANHYDRIDE?",opa:"1 ppm",opb:"2 ppm",opc:"3 ppm",opd:"4 ppm",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), suffers damage to the starboard forward column below the waterline. Pumping from tank 2S and 3S is not sufficient to prevent increasing starboard list and bow down trim. You should consider counter flooding in tank ____________.",opa:"2P",opb:"9P",opc:"C2BP",opd:"10P",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the primary disadvantage of a permanent chain chaser system?",opa:"It requires anchor handling boats with more horsepower.",opb:"Chain chasers work in shallow water only.",opc:"Chain chasers will not work with piggyback anchors.",opd:"It takes longer to deploy anchors using chain chasers.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the weight of cement in P-tank #1 of the Deep Driller if the ullage is 3.4 feet?",opa:"11.5 long tons",opb:"16.6 long tons",opc:"54.2 long tons",opd:"78.2 long tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the minimum number of bolts required in a permanently connected flange oil hose coupling?",opa:"A bolt must be used in every hole.",opb:"6",opc:"4",opd:"3",ans:"opa"},{question:"The letter G, when sent with a complement, may be followed by ____________.",opa:"two numerals",opb:"two letters",opc:"three or four numerals",opd:"four or five numerals",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which item of the listed survival craft equipment would be the most suitable for night signaling to a ship on the horizon?",opa:"A red parachute flare",opb:"A red handheld flare",opc:"An orange smoke flare",opd:"A flashlight",ans:"opa"},{question:"Inflatable liferafts carried on passenger vessels must be annually ____________.",opa:"overhauled by the ship's crew",opb:"sent to the Coast Guard for servicing",opc:"sent to the steamship company shore repair facility",opd:"sent to a Coast Guard approved service facility",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are operating a liftboat. Before starting jacking operations you should ____________.",opa:"put the crane in a vertical position",opb:"close the wheelhouse doors",opc:"have all personnel don life jackets",opd:"put a watch in the engineroom",ans:"opc"},{question:"If not attached to the nozzle, each low-velocity spray applicator on a MODU must be stowed ____________.",opa:"in a protected area on the main deck",opb:"inside a machinery space near the entrance",opc:"next to the fire hydrant to which the fire hose is attached",opd:"on a rack inside the quarters near the entrance",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a supply run to an offshore drilling rig. onboard is the cargo listed. What is the height above the main deck of the center of gravity of the cargo?",opa:"1.50 feet",opb:"1.96 feet",opc:"2.21 feet",opd:"2.78 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT required to be contained in the oil transfer procedures?",opa:"A line diagram of the vessel's oil transfer piping",opb:"The number of persons on duty during oil transfer operations",opc:"Any special procedures for topping off tanks",opd:"The location and capacity of all fuel and cargo tanks on the vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"In the illustration, the sea anchor is number ____________.",opa:"1",opb:"12",opc:"14",opd:"18",ans:"opd"},{question:"The enclosed area defined as the intersection of the surface of the water and the hull of a vessel is the ____________.",opa:"amidships plane",opb:"longitudinal reference plane",opc:"baseline",opd:"waterplane",ans:"opd"},{question:"A ship that, at any time, operates seaward of the outermost boundary of the territorial sea is required to prepare, submit, and maintain a(n) ____________.",opa:"synthetic plastic discharge plan",opb:"oil discharge plan",opc:"shipboard oil pollution emergency plan",opd:"vapor recovery procedures plan",ans:"opc"},{question:"The angle of maximum righting arm corresponds approximately to the angle of ____________.",opa:"deck edge immersion",opb:"the load line",opc:"downflooding",opd:"loll",ans:"opa"},{question:"A tank vessel transferring non-flammable hazardous cargo in bulk must display warning signs. These signs must ____________.",opa:"be visible from both sides and from forward and aft",opb:"indicate 'NO SMOKING'",opc:"be displayed only while transferring cargo and fast to a dock",opd:"use black lettering on a white background",ans:"opd"},{question:"The effects of free surface on a vessel's initial stability do NOT depend upon the ____________.",opa:"volume of displacement of the vessel",opb:"dimensions of the surface of the liquid",opc:"amount of liquid in slack tanks",opd:"specific gravity of the liquid in the tank",ans:"opc"},{question:"What material is allowed in construction of the hull of a vessel with an integral diesel fuel tank ?",opa:"Steel or aluminum",opb:"Sandwich style fiberglass with a natural rubber core",opc:"Copper-nickel or copper silicon alloys",opd:"Any or all of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Control valves of a CO2 system may be located within the protected space when ____________.",opa:"it is impractical to locate them outside",opb:"there is also a control valve outside",opc:"the CO2 cylinders are also in the space",opd:"an automatic heat-sensing trip is installed",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which flash point would indicate a grade E combustible liquid?",opa:"80\xb0F",opb:"75\xb0F",opc:"140\xb0F",opd:"155\xb0F",ans:"opd"},{question:"A spanner is a ____________.",opa:"cross connection line between two main fire lines",opb:"special wrench for the couplings in a fire hose line",opc:"tackle rigged to support a fire hose",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The parts of the sail shown are correctly labeled EXCEPT the ____________.",opa:"head",opb:"leach",opc:"luff",opd:"tack",ans:"opc"},{question:"The liquid mud tanks on your vessel measure 24'L by 16'B by 8'D. The vessel's displacement in fresh water is 864 tons and the specific gravity of the mud is 1.47. What is the reduction in GM due to 2 of these tanks being slack?",opa:".32 foot",opb:".80 foot",opc:".96 foot",opd:"1.12 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"What agency is responsible for enforcing the rules for obstruction lights on mobile offshore drilling units?",opa:"Minerals Management Service",opb:"Corps of Engineers",opc:"Department of Energy",opd:"U.S. Coast Guard",ans:"opd"},{question:"While drilling loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), the DEEP DRILLER suffers an unexpected but slowly increasing starboard and aft inclination. The wind and waves are light. This inclination could have been caused by ____________.",opa:"the failure of mooring lines 6 and 7",opb:"the drilling crew dumping the mud",opc:"the drill string breaking",opd:"ballast tanks equalizing into tank 10S",ans:"opd"},{question:"Sails may be wing and wing when ____________.",opa:"close hauled",opb:"tacking",opc:"wearing",opd:"sailing with the wind aft",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is equipped with totally enclosed lifeboats. Which statement is TRUE when the boat is enveloped in flames?",opa:"The ventilators will automatically close by the action of fusible links.",opb:"The motor takes its air supply from outside the lifeboat to prevent asphyxiation of the crew.",opc:"A water spray system to cool the outside of the boat is operated by a high-volume manual pump.",opd:"An air tank will provide about ten minutes of air for the survivors and the engine.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on the second deck in the main machinery space. What emergency equipment, if any, is located at frame 107?",opa:"CO2 fire extinguisher and 1 1/2' fire hose",opb:"Fire main valve and 1 1/2' fire hose",opc:"Smoke detector and bell alarm",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"If the metacentric height is small, a vessel will ____________.",opa:"be tender",opb:"have a quick and rapid motion",opc:"be stiff",opd:"have large angles of roll",ans:"opa"},{question:"The person in charge of a mobile offshore drilling unit must insure that ____________.",opa:"the Muster List ('Station Bill') is approved by the Coast Guard",opb:"the date of each fire extinguisher test is recorded",opc:"all personnel are trained to launch the survival craft",opd:"a fire drill is held at least once each day",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is NOT a safety precaution to be observed during the loading of LFG?",opa:"Report any leakage of cargo.",opb:"Make sure the rake ends of the barge are completely dry and mopped.",opc:"Ascertain that the hoses to be used are in good order.",opd:"Be on the lookout for work being accomplished ashore in the vicinity of the barges.",ans:"opb"},{question:"When giving mouth-to-mouth rescue breathing to an adult, you should breathe at the rate of how many breaths per minute?",opa:"4",opb:"8",opc:"12",opd:"20",ans:"opc"},{question:"Automatic fire dampers in ventilation systems are operated by use of ____________.",opa:"heat or smoke detectors",opb:"C02 system pressure switches",opc:"remotely operated valves",opd:"fusible links",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 2.8 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.2 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.5 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"When elevating the COASTAL DRILLER in 200 feet of water, the unit should be placed at an air gap of ____________.",opa:"35 feet",opb:"32 feet",opc:"30 feet",opd:"25 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What is the new LCG if the entire contents of drill water tanks 6 and 7 are discharged?",opa:"118.20 feet",opb:"119.44 feet",opc:"120.10 feet",opd:"121.36 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel heading SE is on a course of ____________.",opa:"112.5\xb0",opb:"135.0\xb0",opc:"157.5\xb0",opd:"180.0\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"Why is carbon dioxide (CO2) better than dry chemical for fighting a class 'C' fire?",opa:"The dry chemical is a conductor.",opb:"The dry chemical leaves a residue.",opc:"CO2 will not dissipate in air.",opd:"It takes smaller amounts of CO2 to cover the same area.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The hinge fitting used to attach the boom to the mast is the ____________.",opa:"gooseneck",opb:"step",opc:"swivel",opd:"pintle",ans:"opa"},{question:"This fire control plan symbol represented by (39) is a space protected by ____________.",opa:"water",opb:"foam",opc:"sprinkler",opd:"none of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"What does a pyrometer measure on a diesel engine?",opa:"Water temperature",opb:"Water pressure",opc:"Exhaust temperature",opd:"Air box pressure",ans:"opc"},{question:"To increase the extent of flooding your vessel can suffer without sinking, you could ____________.",opa:"ballast the vessel",opb:"increase reserve buoyancy",opc:"lower the center of gravity",opd:"raise the center of gravity",ans:"opb"},{question:"A hydraulic accumulator is designed to ____________.",opa:"store fluid under pressure",opb:"act as a fluid reservoir",opc:"provide overpressure relief",opd:"replenish fluid to a system",ans:"opa"},{question:"The sounding level of 17 lb. per gallon mud in mud pit 2S of the COASTAL DRILLER is 7.75 feet. What is the weight of the mud?",opa:"153.16 kips",opb:"156.13 kips",opc:"194.77 kips",opd:"198.54 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"For what purpose may gasoline be used on small passenger vessels?",opa:"Heating",opb:"Lighting",opc:"Cooking",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Severe exposure to chlorine gas can be fatal. Chlorine gas is primarily a ____________.",opa:"respiratory irritant",opb:"skin burning agent",opc:"blood poisoning agent",opd:"nerve paralyzing irritant",ans:"opa"},{question:"CATEGORY I EPIRB's transmit on frequencies that are monitored by ____________.",opa:"orbiting satellites in space",opb:"commercial radio stations",opc:"private, commercial, and military aircraft",opd:"Both A & C",ans:"opa"},{question:"Who completes the Declaration of Inspection before loading a tank vessel?",opa:"The U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"The manager of the shore facility",opc:"The person(s) designated in-charge",opd:"The American Bureau of Shipping",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a severe storm threatens the COASTAL DRILLER while elevated, the setback in the derrick should be lowered and placed in the pipe rack. Its weight should be accounted for as ____________.",opa:"variable loads",opb:"drilling loads",opc:"environmental loads",opd:"fixed weight",ans:"opa"},{question:"A certificated lifeboatman assigned to command the lifeboat should ____________.",opa:"be the first individual to board the craft",opb:"drain the hydraulic pressure before lowering the craft",opc:"have a list of the persons assigned to the lifeboat",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a semisubmersible MODU, reserve buoyancy is increased by the presence of void spaces above the waterline in the ____________.",opa:"submerged hulls",opb:"quarters",opc:"columns and upper structure",opd:"submerged connecting structures",ans:"opc"},{question:"A hydrostatic release mechanism for a liferaft ____________.",opa:"must be wet before it will release",opb:"should be kept in a watertight cover except in an emergency",opc:"will inflate the raft in its cradle if operated manually",opd:"must be submerged to a certain depth to release automatically",ans:"opd"},{question:"While drilling loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), the DEEP DRILLER suffers a sudden unexpected inclination to port and aft. Strong winds and high waves are from the starboard bow. Among the possible causes, you should consider ____________.",opa:"failure of mooring lines 1 or 2",opb:"failure of mooring lines 3 or 4",opc:"leak in ballast tank#9P",opd:"ballast tanks equalizing into tank 10P",ans:"opb"},{question:"The chemicals in sacks aboard MODU's are palletized to reduce ____________.",opa:"labor in loading and handling",opb:"pilferage",opc:"marking and labeling",opd:"contamination",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER may remain at operating draft instead of deballasting to survival draft when ____________.",opa:"critical motion limits have not been exceeded",opb:"waves approach within two feet of the spider deck",opc:"the maximum wave height is greater than 64 feet",opd:"winds are greater than 70 knots",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 23'-03', AFT 24'-01'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessels displacement if you are in fresh water.",opa:"11,650 tons",opb:"11,800 tons",opc:"12,000 tons",opd:"12,250 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"When signaling a course using the International Code of Signals, the signal ____________.",opa:"must be followed by 'T', 'M' or 'C' to indicate if it is true, magnetic or compass",opb:"should be preceded by the letters CSE",opc:"should include the compass deviation if a compass course is signaled",opd:"always indicates a true course unless indicated otherwise in the message",ans:"opd"},{question:"A qualified person must be assigned as the second in command of a lifeboat on a MODU if the lifeboat has a capacity of more than ____________.",opa:"20 persons",opb:"30 persons",opc:"40 persons",opd:"50 persons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #2 (Ballasting to Survival). What is the new height of the longitudinal metacenter if all the bulk materials are discharged?",opa:"61.34 feet",opb:"62.13 feet",opc:"62.35 feet",opd:"64.00 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"If heavy smoke is coming from the paint locker, the FIRST firefighting response should be to ____________.",opa:"release the CO2 flooding system",opb:"open the door to evaluate the extent of the fire",opc:"enter and use a portable extinguisher",opd:"secure the ventilation",ans:"opd"},{question:"Ring life buoys used aboard a small passenger vessels on oceans or coastwise routes are required to be what color?",opa:"White",opb:"White or international orange",opc:"Orange",opd:"Any highly visible color easily seen from the air",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is observed to be level at a draft of 60.0 feet. At the same time, the calculated load form shows the displacement to be 17,845 long tons, total longitudinal moment 51,466 foot-kips, and total transverse moments -10,000 foot-kips. What is the transverse location of the missing load?",opa:"36.67 feet",opb:"0.56 foot",opc:"-0.55 foot",opd:"-36.67 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the international calling and distress channel found on all VHF-FM equipped drilling rigs?",opa:"Channel 1",opb:"Channel 10",opc:"Channel 16",opd:"Channel 68",ans:"opc"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, the minimum number of inclined ladders which must be fitted between each weather deck is ____________.",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opa"},{question:"Besides general arrangement plans, what other mediums may be utilized to provide fire control details to officers during fire and emergencies?",opa:"Microfilm",opb:"Blueprint",opc:"Booklet Form",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The most effective first aid treatment for chemical burns is to immediately ____________.",opa:"apply ointment to the burned area",opb:"flood the affected area with water",opc:"wrap the burn with sterile dressing",opd:"apply an ice pack to the burned area",ans:"opb"},{question:"A Certificate of Financial Responsibility attests that the vessel ____________.",opa:"has financial backing to meet any liability resulting from the discharge of oil",opb:"has the minimum required amount of P& I and hull insurance",opc:"will assume the responsibility for any damage or loss to the shipper",opd:"has financial reserves to meet reasonable expected crew costs of an intended voyage",ans:"opa"},{question:"Limit switches, winches, falls, etc. must be thoroughly inspected at least every ____________.",opa:"2 months",opb:"4 months",opc:"6 months",opd:"year",ans:"opd"},{question:"What information must be available to use the Allowable Wind and Wave Charts for the COASTAL DRILLER?",opa:"Soil conditions",opb:"Overturning moment",opc:"Water depth",opd:"Specific gravity of the sea water",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, discharges 275.8 long tons. What is the new draft?",opa:"56 feet",opb:"58 feet",opc:"60 feet",opd:"62 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is classified as a combustible liquid?",opa:"Acetaldehyde",opb:"Ethyl alcohol",opc:"Carbon tetrachloride",opd:"Tetraethylene glycol",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 7240 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 273.20 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 271.2 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 272.1 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 273.6 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 275.3 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"A fire in a pile of canvas is classified as class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opa"},{question:"A mat-supported jack-up is best suited for drilling in locations with bottom conditions which are ____________.",opa:"soft and level",opb:"firm and uneven",opc:"sloping",opd:"coral",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #3 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of longitudinal moments for the liquid variables if the entire contents of tank #19 are transferred to tank #13?",opa:"12,344 ft.-kips",opb:"173,493 ft.-kips",opc:"181,174 ft.-kips",opd:"1,929,523 ft.-kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"When administering artificial respiration to an adult, the breathing cycle should be repeated about ____________.",opa:"12 to 15 times per minute",opb:"18 to 20 times per minute",opc:"20 to 25 times per minute",opd:"as fast as possible",ans:"opa"},{question:"Determine the free surface constant for a fuel oil tank 30 ft. long by 40 ft. wide by 15 ft. deep. The specific gravity of the fuel oil is .85 and the ship is floating in saltwater (S.G. 1.026).",opa:"0.83",opb:"42.7",opc:"3787",opd:"4571",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the spoken emergency signal for a 'man overboard' on the VHF radio?",opa:"Man Overboard",opb:"Security",opc:"Mayday",opd:"Pan-Pan",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-00', AFT 15'-11'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.82 feet",opb:"2.97 feet",opc:"3.15 feet",opd:"3.24 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"What happens to the efficiency of an anchor when it is moved from sand to mud?",opa:"The efficiency increases.",opb:"The efficiency decreases.",opc:"The efficiency remains the same.",opd:"The efficiency cannot be determined.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A towing vessel is NOT required to be fitted with radar if it is ____________.",opa:"used occasionally to assist vessels in distress",opb:"used solely for pollution response",opc:"less than 49 feet in length",opd:"towing alongside",ans:"opb"},{question:"In using the Allowable Wind and Wave Charts for the COASTAL DRILLER, leg penetration is assumed to be less than ____________.",opa:"55 feet",opb:"45 feet",opc:"35 feet",opd:"25 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"When attempting to enter a compartment containing a fire, which method of applying water is best?",opa:"High-velocity fog stream directed toward the overhead",opb:"Straight stream directed into the center of the fire",opc:"Sweeping the compartment with a fog stream",opd:"Solid stream directed toward the overhead",ans:"opc"},{question:"On the COASTAL DRILLER, the level of water in each of two pump bilge pits is monitored by hydrostatic alarm switches connected to a remote panel located in the ____________.",opa:"OIM's quarters",opb:"OIM's office",opc:"control house",opd:"SCR room",ans:"opb"},{question:"Small quantities of flammable liquids needed at a work site should be ____________.",opa:"used only under the supervision and direction of a ship's officer",opb:"tightly capped and stowed with other tools near the job site when securing at the end of the day",opc:"used only when a pressurized fire hose is laid out ready for immediate use",opd:"in a metal container with a tight cap",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 368 tons and measures 96'L x 28'B. You ship a large wave on the after deck. What is the reduction to GM due to free surface before the water drains overboard, if the after deck measures 42'L x 28'B and the weight of the water is 36 tons?",opa:"4.98 feet",opb:"5.21 feet",opc:"5.43 feet",opd:"5.67 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A documented vessel's name is marked on a clearly visible exterior area of both sides of the bow and on the stern in block letters not less than ____________.",opa:"6 inches in height",opb:"5 inches in height",opc:"4 inches in height",opd:"3 inches in height",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a mobile offshore drilling unit it is required to ____________.",opa:"inspect the lifesaving gear provided in any helicopter landing on the rig",opb:"check the Certificate of Inspection of any support vessel bringing hazardous materials to the rig",opc:"insure that engineering spaces are in a clean and sanitary condition",opd:"record the length of each abandonment drill in the rig's log book",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a small passenger vessel, if an inlet or discharge pipe is not accessible, its shut off valve ____________.",opa:"must be operable from the weather deck",opb:"may be operable from any accessible location above the bulkhead deck",opc:"must be labeled at its operating point to show its identity and direction of closing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Aboard a vessel, multiplying a load's weight by the distance of the load's center of gravity from the centerline results in the load's ____________.",opa:"TCG",opb:"transverse moment",opc:"righting moment",opd:"transverse free surface moment",ans:"opb"},{question:"A person being treated for shock should be wrapped in warm coverings to ____________.",opa:"increase body heat",opb:"preserve body heat",opc:"avoid self-inflicted wounds caused by spastic movement",opd:"protect the person from injury during transportation",ans:"opb"},{question:"A life line must be connected to the liferaft ____________.",opa:"at the bow",opb:"at the stern",opc:"in the middle",opd:"all around",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the TLV of cyclohexanol?",opa:"20 ppm",opb:"30 ppm",opc:"40 ppm",opd:"50 ppm",ans:"opd"},{question:"The amount of freeboard which a ship possesses has a tremendous effect on its ____________.",opa:"initial stability",opb:"free surface",opc:"permeability",opd:"stability at large angles of inclination",ans:"opd"},{question:"In storm conditions, when the DEEP DRILLER is in 600 feet water depth, and the high-line tension (HLT) is 350 kips, completely slacking the two leeward mooring line tensions reduces the HLT to ____________.",opa:"375 kips",opb:"275 kips",opc:"245 kips",opd:"220 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"How long must a 'Declaration of Inspection' be kept onboard?",opa:"One week",opb:"Two weeks",opc:"One month",opd:"Three months",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the weight of barite in P-tank #4 of the DEEP DRILLER if the ullage is 3.4 feet?",opa:"11.5 long tons",opb:"16.6 long tons",opc:"54.2 long tons",opd:"78.2 long tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is anchoring in 600 feet of water. In the absence of environmental forces, the mooring lines should be adjusted to ____________.",opa:"245 kips",opb:"222 kips",opc:"237 kips",opd:"194 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What is the new VCG if the entire contents of drill water tanks 6 and 7 are discharged?",opa:"38.00 feet",opb:"48.38 feet",opc:"49.16 feet",opd:"65.00 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Transit). What is the new height of the center of gravity corrected for longitudinal free surface effects if the entire contents of Salt Water Ballast Tanks 1P and 1S are discharged?",opa:"67.04 feet",opb:"68.02 feet",opc:"68.72 feet",opd:"69.21 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are berthed at a cargo facility where you have just completed discharging a dangerous cargo from your barge. You must complete topside repairs on the barge involving hot work before sailing. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You can make repairs with permission of the facility owner since you are empty and the cargo is on the facility.",opb:"The repair area must be inspected by a marine surveyor to ensure that it can be done safely.",opc:"Hot work repairs at such a facility are prohibited.",opd:"The facility operator must notify the Captain of the Port before conducting welding or hotwork.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 11'-01', AFT 14'-07'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.30 feet",opb:"1.17 foot",opc:"1.06 foot",opd:"0.91 foot",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the height of the metacenter is less than the height of the center of gravity, a vessel has which type of stability?",opa:"Stable",opb:"Neutral",opc:"Unstable",opd:"Positive",ans:"opc"},{question:"The purpose of the inclining experiment is to ____________.",opa:"determine the location of the metacenter",opb:"determine the lightweight center of gravity location",opc:"verify the hydrostatic data",opd:"verify data in the vessel's operating manual",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER suffers minor flooding of the port pump room. If both port bilge pumps fail to dewater the pump room, you should use the ____________.",opa:"port drill water pump",opb:"port saltwater service pump",opc:"port ballast pumps",opd:"starboard ballast pumps and crossover system",ans:"opa"},{question:"After making the required notification that a large oil spill into the water has occurred, the FIRST action should be to ____________.",opa:"apply straw or sawdust on the oil",opb:"contain the spread of the oil",opc:"throw grains of sand into the oil",opd:"have the vessel move out of the spill area",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 17'-06', AFT 20'-04'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.05 feet",opb:"1.15 feet",opc:"1.25 feet",opd:"1.31 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Limit switches are located on the survival craft winch systems for OSVs to ____________.",opa:"stop the winch just before the survival craft reaches final stowage position",opb:"limit the amount of cable on the drum",opc:"limit the ascent rate",opd:"stop the winch in case the craft's weight exceeds the load lift limit",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT a grade E product?",opa:"Dioctyl-phthalate",opb:"Gasoline",opc:"Formic acid",opd:"Creosote coal tar",ans:"opb"},{question:"What are the vessel equipment and personnel requirements for GMDSS?",opa:"Two licensed GMDSS radio operators",opb:"Equipment carriage requirements",opc:"Distress alerting and response",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which system is least likely to be subject to fading or static interference?",opa:"HF SITOR",opb:"INMARSAT",opc:"Digital Selective Calling on channel 70",opd:"VHF ARQ",ans:"opb"},{question:"While reading the muster list you see that '3 short blasts on the whistle and three short rings on the general alarm bell bells' is the signal for ____________.",opa:"abandon ship",opb:"dismissal from fire and emergency stations",opc:"fire and emergency",opd:"man overboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 6'-01', AFT 6'-05'. From past experience, you know that the vessel will increase her draft 1 inch for every 5 tons loaded. There is rig water onboard and 15 tons of deck cargo. How many more tons of cargo can legally be loaded and still maintain the same trim?",opa:"10 tons",opb:"20 tons",opc:"35 tons",opd:"None",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fire hose stations shall be marked in red letters and figures such as Fire Station No. '1', '2', '3', etc. The height of the letters and figures must be at least ____________.",opa:"1/2 inch",opb:"1 inch",opc:"1-1/2 inches",opd:"2 inches",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fueling results in the collection of waste oil in drip pans and containers. Which is an approved method of disposing of the waste oil?",opa:"Draining it overboard when the vessel gets underway",opb:"Placing it in proper disposal facilities",opc:"Adding sinking agents and discharging it into the water",opd:"Mixing it with dispersants before draining it overboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel is 'listed' when it is ____________.",opa:"down by the head",opb:"down by the stern",opc:"inclined due to off-center weight",opd:"inclined due to wind",ans:"opc"},{question:"A flooded leg on a liftboat would adversely affect the vessel's stability underway by ____________.",opa:"increasing the righting moment",opb:"decreasing the vessel's displacement",opc:"increasing the reserve buoyancy",opd:"shifting the CG (center of gravity) off center",ans:"opd"},{question:"At what rate would you render mouth to mouth or mouth to nose artificial respiration to an adult?",opa:"4 to 6 times per minute",opb:"12 to 15 times per minute",opc:"20 to 30 times per minute",opd:"At least 30 times per minute",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a floating MODU inclines to an angle slightly greater than the angle of loll, she will ____________.",opa:"capsize",opb:"incline further",opc:"flop to the other side",opd:"return to the angle of loll",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of vessel shall be required to have an emergency towing arrangement fitted at both ends?",opa:"A 30,000 dwt ton oil barge",opb:"An 18,000 dwt ton tanker constructed in 1998",opc:"A 5,000 dwt ton coastal tanker",opd:"A 22,000 dwt ton tanker operated after Jan. 1, 1999",ans:"opd"},{question:"On all mobile offshore drilling units, the deckhead of each accommodation space must be located above ____________.",opa:"the operating draft",opb:"the survival draft",opc:"the transit draft",opd:"the deepest load line",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a Mariner class cargo vessel. Your drafts are: FWD 21'-04', AFT 23'-04'. You wish to increase the calculated GM of 4.8' to 5.8'. What tanks should you ballast? (Use the white pages in the Stability Data Reference Book.)",opa:"Tanks: DB2, DB6",opb:"Tanks: DB6, DT7",opc:"Tanks: DB4, DB7",opd:"Tanks: DB2, DB5",ans:"opc"},{question:"Regulations require that approved buoyant work vests ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"may not be carried on inspected vessels",opb:"may be substituted for 10% of the required life jackets",opc:"shall be stowed in a place inaccessible to passengers",opd:"shall be stowed separately from the required life jackets",ans:"opd"},{question:"The full period of motion of the DEEP DRILLER while in transit is 7 seconds and the maximum pitch angle as seen on the inclinometers is 4 degrees. From the standpoint of critical motion, the motion is ____________.",opa:"unsatisfactory, change course and speed",opb:"satisfactory, continue transit",opc:"unsatisfactory, ballast to survival draft",opd:"unsatisfactory, place unit in standby",ans:"opb"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 260\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"on a close reach",opb:"on a broad reach",opc:"on a starboard tack",opd:"running before the wind",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the COASTAL DRILLER, the level of water in each of two pump bilge pits is monitored by ____________.",opa:"visual sight gages",opb:"low and high level alarms",opc:"hydrostatic alarm switches",opd:"OSS units (overflow sequence selector units)",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a vessel of 34,000 tons displacement, a tank 80 ft. long, 60 ft. wide and 30 ft. deep is half filled with fresh water (SG 1.000) while the vessel is floating in saltwater (SG 1.026). What is the free surface constant for this tank?",opa:"2661",opb:"2819",opc:"40100",opd:"42213",ans:"opc"},{question:"The hinge fitting used to attach the boom to the mast is the ____________.",opa:"gooseneck",opb:"step",opc:"swivel",opd:"pintle",ans:"opa"},{question:"What precaution should be taken when treating burns caused by contact with dry lime?",opa:"Water should be applied in a fine spray.",opb:"The burned area should be immersed in water.",opc:"The entire burn area should be covered with ointment.",opd:"Before washing, the lime should be brushed away gently.",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a supply run to an offshore drilling rig. onboard is the cargo listed. What is the height above the main deck of the center of gravity of the cargo?",opa:"0.96 foot",opb:"1.45 feet",opc:"1.96 feet",opd:"2.96 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The bottom of the mast rests on the ____________.",opa:"foot plate",opb:"sole plate",opc:"hounds",opd:"mast step",ans:"opd"},{question:"A MODU floating in sea water while displacing 20,000 long tons has transverse free surface moments of 7,500 ft.-long tons and longitudinal free surface moments of 10,000 ft.-long tons. The maximum virtual rise in the height of the center of gravity due to free surfaces is ____________.",opa:"0.35 foot",opb:"0.50 foot",opc:"0.88 foot",opd:"2.00 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Use the material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the KG is 25.2 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 22'-03', AFT 23'-01'; at what angle will the vessel lose positive stability?",opa:"92\xb0",opb:"77\xb0",opc:"68\xb0",opd:"61\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"Individuals who have consumed alcohol within 24 hours of exposure to H2S can tolerate ____________.",opa:"unusually large concentrations of H2S",opb:"smaller than normal concentrations of H2S",opc:"moderate concentrations of H2S without the usual reactions",opd:"longer exposure to H2S concentrations",ans:"opb"},{question:"Fires in combustible metals, such as sodium or magnesium, are classified as class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opd"},{question:"The sailing drafts are: FWD 24'-03', AFT 25'-03' and the GM is 5.5 feet. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book, to determine the available righting arm at 30\xb0 inclination.",opa:"2.6 feet",opb:"2.9 feet",opc:"3.2 feet",opd:"3.5 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are loading at port A, governed by the summer load line mark, for a voyage to port B, governed by the winter mark. The fresh water allowance is 10', and the hydrometer reads 1.020. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You may not load beyond the winter mark except for 2 inches brackish water allowance.",opb:"You may not load beyond the summer mark and must be at the winter mark upon arrival at port B.",opc:"You may not load beyond the summer mark plus 8 inches brackish water allowance.",opd:"You may load to the summer mark plus 2 inches if you will be at the winter mark when entering the winter zone.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is carrying 84,000 barrels of oil for discharge. The cargo hoses have an inside diameter of 14 inches. When four hoses are connected to the manifold, the container around the manifold must hold a total of how many barrels?",opa:"Three",opb:"Four",opc:"Twelve",opd:"Sixteen",ans:"opb"},{question:"A permanent chain chasing system is used to ____________.",opa:"clean anchor chain as it's hauled in",opb:"recover anchors which have lost their buoys",opc:"run and retrieve anchors",opd:"prepare anchor chain for inspection",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel heading NE is on a course of ____________.",opa:"022.5\xb0",opb:"045.0\xb0",opc:"067.5\xb0",opd:"090.0\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master or person-in-charge of an OSV shall insure that each deck from which rescue boats are launched is ____________.",opa:"surfaced with a nonskid texture",opb:"roped off to prevent unnecessary access",opc:"kept clear of any obstructions that would interfere with launching",opd:"posted with a list of persons assigned to the rescue boat",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the maximum amount of variables that may be taken aboard the COASTAL DRILLER while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (drilling)?",opa:"1000 kips",opb:"681 kips",opc:"89 kips",opd:"0 kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"When lowering lifeboats in heavy seas, a good practice is to rig frapping lines ____________.",opa:"on only the forward falls",opb:"on only the after falls",opc:"with a lead of about 45 degrees to the boat",opd:"from the falls to the main deck of the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Lifeboat winches on a MODU are required to be inspected and an entry made in the logbook. What should this entry include?",opa:"The time required to lower a lifeboat",opb:"The time required to raise a lifeboat",opc:"The date of inspection and condition of the winch",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, which reactive group(s) is/are not compatible with the products polybutene and o-xylene?",opa:"Nitric acid",opb:"Amides",opc:"Alcohols, glycols",opd:"Phenols, cresols",ans:"opa"},{question:"Locations on a MODU where flammable hydrocarbon gas or vapors may accumulate due to drilling operations are defined as ____________.",opa:"gaseous locations",opb:"hazardous locations",opc:"classified locations",opd:"designated locations",ans:"opc"},{question:"The unit used to measure anchor line tensions in the offshore drilling industry is the ____________.",opa:"long ton",opb:"short ton",opc:"metric ton",opd:"Kip",ans:"opd"},{question:"While drilling loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), the DEEP DRILLER suffers a sudden unexpected inclination to port and forward. Strong wind and high waves are from the starboard quarter. Among the possible causes, you should consider ____________.",opa:"failure of mooring lines 1 or 2",opb:"failure of mooring lines 5 or 6",opc:"leak in ballast tank#2P",opd:"ballast tanks are equalizing into tank 1P",ans:"opb"},{question:"What condition will result in the automatic shutdown of a diesel engine?",opa:"High jacket water pressure",opb:"High lube oil pressure",opc:"Low lube oil pressure",opd:"Excessive turbo charger speed",ans:"opc"},{question:"A hurricane has recurved to the northeast and its forward speed is 20 knots. Your MODU is located 600 miles northeast of the hurricane's center. How long will it take for the hurricane center to reach your position if it holds its present course and speed?",opa:"10 hours",opb:"30 hours",opc:"50 hours",opd:"80 hours",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER arrived in port with drafts of: FWD 18'-06', AFT 21'-10'. Cargo was loaded and discharged as indicated. Use sheet 2 in the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts.",opa:"FWD 18'-06', AFT21'-06'",opb:"FWD 18'-08', AFT21'-04'",opc:"FWD 18'-10', AFT21'-02'",opd:"FWD 19'-00', AFT21'-00'",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the best method to overcome the effects of shadowing when attempting to place an INMARSAT-B call?",opa:"A small course change should work.",opb:"Select a CES that serves the INMARSAT satellite that will handle the call.",opc:"Installing a shadow correction filter will compensate in fringe areas.",opd:"Turning on compensators will work in all but extreme cases of shadowing.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Line throwing apparatus aboard ship must contain ____________.",opa:"two rockets, one of which shall be the buoyant type",opb:"three rockets, one of which shall be the buoyant type",opc:"four rockets, two of which shall be the buoyant type",opd:"five rockets, two of which shall be the buoyant type",ans:"opc"},{question:"Each EPIRB required on an OSV shall be tested using the integrated test circuit and output indicator every ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"two weeks",opc:"month",opd:"two months",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should the number '3' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"TAY-RAH-TREE",opb:"BEES-SOH-THREE",opc:"NUM-ERL-THREE",opd:"TRIC-THREE",ans:"opa"},{question:"How often must the impulse-projected line throwing appliance be test fired?",opa:"Monthly",opb:"At the Master's discretion",opc:"Semiannually",opd:"Annually",ans:"opb"},{question:"In MODU construction, beam brackets are triangular plates that join the deck beam to a ____________.",opa:"bulkhead",opb:"frame",opc:"stanchion",opd:"deck longitudinal",ans:"opb"},{question:"The major cause of anchor buoy pendant wire failures is ____________.",opa:"corrosion",opb:"rough weather",opc:"defective sockets",opd:"mishandling",ans:"opb"},{question:"In storm conditions, with the wind and waves from the port bow of the DEEP DRILLER in 600 feet water depth, the tensions in mooring line 1 and 2 are 400 kips. Completely slacking the mooring lines 5 and 6 reduces the tension in mooring lines 1 and 2 to about ____________.",opa:"375 kips",opb:"330 kips",opc:"275 kips",opd:"220 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"If the maximum leg penetration of the COASTAL DRILLER is 75 feet, the water depth value in the Allowable Wind and Wave Charts must be increased by ____________.",opa:"75 feet",opb:"50 feet",opc:"25 feet",opd:"0 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A jack-up level at 12.5 feet draft transfers 100 kips of drill water from a tank with a TCG of -30 feet to a starboard tank with a TCG of 70 feet. The resulting starboard draft is 13 feet. The moment required to change list one inch (MCL1') is ____________.",opa:"667 foot-kips",opb:"833 foot-kips",opc:"1,400 foot-kips",opd:"1,667 foot-kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"Although KG for a MODU in lightweight is relatively high, the vessel is stiff because ____________.",opa:"KM is small",opb:"KM is high",opc:"BL is small",opd:"KB is large",ans:"opb"},{question:"While drilling ahead with 60 foot draft, the DEEP DRILLER encounters lost circulation and loses 900 bbls. of 16 pounds per gallon mud to the hole. How much ballast must be taken on to maintain 60 foot draft?",opa:"220 long tons",opb:"270 long tons",opc:"330 long tons",opd:"440 long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"A small fuel spillage has occurred during helicopter refueling. After the leak has been stopped and fire-control personnel have been notified and are standing by, the next step is to ____________.",opa:"proceed with fueling operation",opb:"have helicopter move to a safer location",opc:"wash spilled fuel away with a flood of water",opd:"clean spilled fuel with rags",ans:"opc"},{question:"To keep injured survivors warm in the water after abandoning a MODU, they should ____________.",opa:"be placed in the middle of a small circle formed by the other survivors in the water",opb:"float on their backs with their arms extended for maximum exposure to the air",opc:"remove their life preservers and hold on to the uninjured survivors",opd:"sip seawater at intervals of fifteen minutes",ans:"opa"},{question:"On small passenger vessels, which material must not be used in a valve or fitting for a hull penetration?",opa:"Cast bronze",opb:"Plastic",opc:"Cast iron",opd:"Stainless steel",ans:"opc"},{question:"The vessel motion that can significantly affect mooring line tensions on a MODU is ____________.",opa:"roll",opb:"yaw",opc:"surge",opd:"pitch",ans:"opc"},{question:"The ship's tanks most effective for trimming are the ____________.",opa:"deeps",opb:"domestics",opc:"peaks",opd:"settlers",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel has lifeboats on both sides. Lifeboat No. 2 is located ____________.",opa:"forward of lifeboat No. 4 on the starboard side",opb:"forward of lifeboat No. 4 on the port side",opc:"aft of lifeboat No. 1 on the starboard side",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the longitudinal shift in the center of gravity if 200 short tons is moved ten feet to port and 30 feet forward on a MODU with a displacement of 8,960 long tons?",opa:"0.20 foot",opb:"0.22 foot",opc:"0.67 foot",opd:"0.84 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"Water pockets on the underside of an inflatable liferaft are for ____________.",opa:"catching rain water",opb:"stability",opc:"easy drainage",opd:"maneuverability",ans:"opb"},{question:"The waiting signal in code for all forms of signaling is ____________.",opa:"AR",opb:"AS",opc:"C",opd:"RQ",ans:"opb"},{question:"A SOLAS passenger ship safety certificate is required on all ____________.",opa:"T-Boats carrying more than 49 passengers for hire",opb:"T-Boats that carry more than 12 passengers on an international voyage",opc:"T-Boats carrying more than 150 passengers for hire",opd:"large excursion vessels on lakes, bays, sounds, and river routes",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is correct with respect to required watertight bulkheads on small passenger vessels less than 100 GT?",opa:"Penetrations are prohibited.",opb:"Sluice valves are not permitted.",opc:"Each bulkhead must be stepped at its midpoint.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The lifeline of a life float or buoyant apparatus shall ____________.",opa:"be at least 3/8 inch diameter and properly secured around the sides and ends of the device",opb:"be festooned in bights not longer than three feet long",opc:"have a seine float in each bight unless the line is an inherently buoyant material",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The rotary of the COASTAL DRILLER is located 36 feet aft of the transom and 6 feet to starboard of the centerline. The hook load is 300 kips. Considering the changes to lightweight shown in the Operating Manual, the maximum amount of setback is ____________.",opa:"545 kips",opb:"450 kips",opc:"245 kips",opd:"224 kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"The three conditions which cause engine shutdown are overspeed, low lube oil pressure, and ____________.",opa:"high lube oil pressure",opb:"high jacket water pressure",opc:"high jacket water temperature",opd:"low jacket water pressure",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the metacentric height is large, a vessel will ____________.",opa:"be tender",opb:"have a slow and easy motion",opc:"be stiff",opd:"have a tendency to yaw",ans:"opc"},{question:"While on a normal tow, the COASTAL DRILLER is threatened with the approach of a severe storm. Including the time required to place the generators on-line, the approximate time required to lower the legs from a TOC (tip-of-can) position of 1.20 feet to 60.50 feet is ____________.",opa:"8 minutes",opb:"32 minutes",opc:"47 minutes",opd:"55 minutes",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your liferaft is to leeward of a fire on the water and riding to its sea anchor. You should FIRST ____________.",opa:"boat the sea anchor",opb:"paddle away from the fire",opc:"splash water over the liferaft to cool it",opd:"get out of the raft and swim to safety",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the presence of external forces, the center of buoyancy of an inclined vessel is vertically aligned with the ____________.",opa:"center of gravity",opb:"metacenter",opc:"center of flotation",opd:"keel",ans:"opb"},{question:"After jacking down your liftboat you have an unexpected list. You find that the only cause of this list must be a flooded leg. Raising the flooded leg further would adversely affect the boats stability by ____________.",opa:"raising the KG and increasing the draft which may put you in an unsafe operating condition",opb:"increasing GM and causing a fast roll",opc:"increasing the righting arm on the high side",opd:"causing the vessel to yaw when underway",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have an AB who has become violently ill, and you are requesting urgent medical advice. Your message should contain which code?",opa:"MAB",opb:"MAD",opc:"MAA",opd:"MAF",ans:"opc"},{question:"What prevents water running along the shaft of a leaking centrifugal pump from entering the shaft bearing?",opa:"Shaft seal",opb:"Water flinger",opc:"Drain hole",opd:"Lantern ring",ans:"opb"},{question:"Use the material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the KG is 23.0 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 15'-03', AFT 15'-09'; at what angle will the vessel lose positive stability?",opa:"57\xb0",opb:"72\xb0",opc:"81\xb0",opd:"90\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"The sounding level of 12 lb. per gallon mud in mud pit 1S of the COASTAL DRILLER is 5.5 feet. What is the weight of the mud?",opa:"104.53 kips",opb:"114.37 kips",opc:"116.45 kips",opd:"127.41 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have carbon tetrachloride as part of the cargo. If a fire breaks out in the general area, what is the major danger from the carbon tetrachloride?",opa:"It will explode if exposed to a flame.",opb:"Phosgene gas may be formed if it comes in contact with hot metal.",opc:"It will burn rapidly once ignited.",opd:"You cannot use water to fight the fire because it will react with the carbon tetrachloride.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 19 feet, has a KGL of 59.91 feet and an LCG of 1.57 feet. What is the trim angle?",opa:"0.2\xb0 by the stern",opb:"0.3\xb0 by the stern",opc:"0.4\xb0 by the stern",opd:"0.5\xb0 by the stern",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which vessel is NOT required to have a radiotelephone?",opa:"A 34-foot vessel engaged in towing",opb:"A dredge operating in a channel",opc:"A vessel of 100 GT carrying 50 passengers for hire",opd:"A 12-meter private yacht",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel is 'listed' when it is ____________.",opa:"inclined due to an off-center weight",opb:"inclined due to the wind",opc:"down by the head",opd:"down by the stern",ans:"opa"},{question:"The deck plating on a MODU is supported primarily by deck longitudinals and deck ____________.",opa:"girders",opb:"stanchions",opc:"frames",opd:"beams",ans:"opd"},{question:"What are the vertical moments for the cement contents of P-tank #1 of the DEEP DRILLER if the ullage is 2.3 feet?",opa:"4,198 ft.-tons",opb:"7,067 ft.-tons",opc:"7,096 ft.-tons",opd:"14,921 ft.-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"A fire in the galley ALWAYS poses the additional threat of ____________.",opa:"contaminating food with extinguishing agent",opb:"spreading through the engineering space",opc:"causing loss of stability",opd:"a grease fire in the ventilation system",ans:"opd"},{question:"An advantage of a dry chemical over a carbon dioxide fire extinguisher is its ____________.",opa:"greater range",opb:"cooling ability",opc:"cleanliness",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 23'-03', AFT 27'-01'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessels displacement if you are in salt water.",opa:"12,750 tons",opb:"12,900 tons",opc:"13,150 tons",opd:"13,250 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The center of gravity of a freely swinging load suspended from a pedestal crane acts as if it were located at the ____________.",opa:"counterweight",opb:"pedestal",opc:"longitudinal centerline",opd:"point of suspension",ans:"opa"},{question:"The type of davit on which you must turn a crank in order to swing the lifeboat out over the ship's side is a ____________.",opa:"sheath-screw davit",opb:"gravity davit",opc:"radial davit",opd:"bruckner davit",ans:"opa"},{question:"The 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act' applies to ____________.",opa:"every towing vessel of 16 feet or over in length while navigating",opb:"every vessel of 50 GT and upward, carrying one or more persons for hire",opc:"all aircraft operating on the water",opd:"every power-driven vessel of 20 meters and upward while navigating",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to regulations, a Master or person in charge of a MODU is required to submit a report of a loss of life ____________.",opa:"only when it happens while underway",opb:"to the next of kin",opc:"to the nearest Marine Safety or Marine Inspection Office",opd:"to the nearest coroner",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the subchapter for Cargo and Miscellaneous Vessels of the Federal Code of Regulations, what is the maximum number of sleeping accommodations a barge may have before it is required to have fire pumps, hydrants, hose, and nozzles installed?",opa:"5",opb:"8",opc:"12",opd:"15",ans:"opc"},{question:"During a long ocean tow of a jack-up the clearance in the upper guide should be reduced to zero to restrain the leg and eliminate the impact loads from dynamic responses. This is best done by ____________.",opa:"lowering the spud cans below the hull",opb:"raising the spud cans into hull recesses",opc:"tapering the upper guides and building up the teeth",opd:"remove certain lengths of leg",ans:"opc"},{question:"Name one major advantage of transporting gas under refrigeration.",opa:"It increases its volume.",opb:"It reduces its volume.",opc:"It has less product per volume.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which vessel is required to carry an efficient daylight signaling lamp? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"99 GT towing vessel on Inland Waters",opb:"199 GT towing vessel on a coastwise voyage",opc:"299 GT towing vessel on a coastwise voyage",opd:"199 GT towing vessel on an international voyage",ans:"opd"},{question:"The sails are properly set and trimmed. As a vessel heads up from a beam reach to close-hauled the ____________.",opa:"apparent wind remains steady",opb:"heeling moment decreases",opc:"side slip decreases",opd:"speed decreases",ans:"opd"},{question:"Overspeed of the diesel engine driving an electric generator could cause ____________.",opa:"low voltage trip",opb:"reverse power trip",opc:"damage to windings",opd:"excessive exhaust temperatures",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the percentage of oxygen in a typical sample of uncontaminated air?",opa:"12 percent",opb:"15 percent",opc:"18 percent",opd:"21 percent",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which vessel is NOT required to have a Pollution Placard posted onboard?",opa:"215-foot naval auxiliary vessel",opb:"75-foot towing vessel",opc:"50-foot cabin cruiser used for pleasure only",opd:"150-foot unmanned tank barge",ans:"opa"},{question:"How should cargo tank hatches be protected when the ullage opening is open and the tank NOT gas free?",opa:"With gooseneck vents",opb:"With warning signs",opc:"With flame screens",opd:"With pressure-vacuum relief valves",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a lifeline is required to be attached to a ring life buoy it must be at least ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"30 feet long",opb:"60 feet long",opc:"90 feet long",opd:"120 feet long",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel\u2019s fire control plan shall be ____________.",opa:"posted every 150 feet along the most continuous deck on the vessel.",opb:"permanently posted for the guidance of ship\u2019s officers.",opc:"given to each crewmember in booklet form.",opd:"translated into three languages: English, French and Spanish.",ans:"opb"},{question:"How often is a drill on the use of the line throwing appliance required to be held on a mobile offshore drilling unit?",opa:"Once a month",opb:"Once a year",opc:"Once a week",opd:"Once every three months",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning spare charges for portable fire extinguishers on unmanned tank barges?",opa:"Spare charges shall be carried for at least 50 percent of each size and variety required onboard.",opb:"If the unit cannot be charged by the vessel's personnel, one spare unit shall be carried in lieu of spare charges.",opc:"Spare charges shall be stowed in watertight containers on deck.",opd:"Regulations concerning spare charges do not apply to unmanned barges.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Master or person in charge of a vessel subject to the 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Act' who fails to comply with the Act or the regulations thereunder may be charged a civil penalty of ____________.",opa:"2000",opb:"1500",opc:"1000",opd:"650",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have 8 containers of steward's supplies each measuring 6'L by 6'B by 6'H and weighing 1.5 tons each. Each container is stowed on deck. What is the maximum VCG permitted of the remaining cargo if you are carrying rig water and load to maximum capacity? (Refer to trim and stability letter for M.V. Surveyor.)",opa:"1.00 foot",opb:"1.33 feet",opc:"1.48 feet",opd:"2.00 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"What does NOT affect the value of the free surface correction?",opa:"Width of the tank",opb:"Length of the tank",opc:"Registered tonnage",opd:"Specific gravity of the liquid in the tank",ans:"opc"},{question:"The bilge pump on a fishing vessel ____________.",opa:"must be fixed if the vessel exceeds 12 meters in length",opb:"may be used as a fire pump",opc:"must be portable if there are more than 4 watertight compartments",opd:"must be capable of pumping at least 450 gpm",ans:"opa"},{question:"Lifeboat hatchets should be ____________.",opa:"kept in a locker",opb:"secured at each end of the boat with a lanyard",opc:"kept next to the boat coxswain",opd:"kept in the emergency locker on the ship and brought to the lifeboat when needed",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel heading NNE is on a course of ____________.",opa:"022.5\xb0",opb:"045.0\xb0",opc:"067.5\xb0",opd:"090.0\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"Explosive and flammable gasses are most likely to be encountered on a MODU ____________.",opa:"at any location",opb:"on the drill floor and liquid mud handling areas",opc:"in bulk storage tanks",opd:"in machinery spaces",ans:"opb"},{question:"One of the limitations of foam as an extinguishing agent is that foam ____________.",opa:"cannot be made with salt water",opb:"is heavier than oil and sinks below its surface",opc:"is corrosive and a hazard to fire fighters",opd:"conducts electricity",ans:"opd"},{question:"Once the daily ration of drinking water in a survival situation has been established, the drinking routine should include ____________.",opa:"small sips at regular intervals during the day",opb:"a complete daily ration at one time during the day",opc:"one-third the daily ration three times during the day",opd:"small sips only after sunset",ans:"opc"},{question:"How long shall the operator of a vessel employed in the transferring of oil to other vessels keep the Declaration of Inspection of those transfers?",opa:"1 week from date of signature",opb:"2 weeks from date of signature",opc:"1 month from date of signature",opd:"6 months from date of signature",ans:"opc"},{question:"Among the equipment included in the DEEP DRILLER lightweight are the loading hoses, derrick, traveling block in the lowest position, mooring chain, all machinery with liquids to normal operating level, and ____________.",opa:"normal food supplies for 79 persons",opb:"eight anchor buoys",opc:"anchors",opd:"lower hull fuel",ans:"opc"},{question:"Portable CO2 fire extinguishers should NOT be used to inert a space containing flammable liquids due to the danger of ____________.",opa:"the CO2 being inhaled by personnel",opb:"reflash of burning liquids",opc:"vapor condensation on the extinguisher",opd:"the discharge causing a static spark",ans:"opd"},{question:"A fire in a pile of dunnage would be classified as class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the decrease in vertical moments for the Coastal Driller if 2.5 feet of drill water is discharged from a full drill water tank #23?",opa:"3,464 ft.-kips",opb:"2,982 ft.-kips",opc:"482 ft.-kips",opd:"161 ft.-kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"An LWT anchor often has difficulty tripping in ____________.",opa:"sand",opb:"soft soil",opc:"stiff clay",opd:"heterogeneous soil",ans:"opb"},{question:"What pressure must a spring buoy, moored at a 500 foot depth, withstand?",opa:"100 psig",opb:"150 psig",opc:"225 psig",opd:"300 psig",ans:"opc"},{question:"Small oil spills on deck can be kept from going overboard by ____________.",opa:"driving wooden plugs into the vents",opb:"closing the lids on the vents",opc:"plugging the scuppers",opd:"plugging the sounding pipes",ans:"opc"},{question:"A complete recharge for a self-contained breathing apparatus can be found in what location designated by this symbol on the ship\u2019s fire control plan?",opa:"58",opb:"59",opc:"60",opd:"30",ans:"opa"},{question:"Distress flares and smoke signals are not required on vessels operating on short runs. A 'short run' is limited to ____________. (small passenger vessel regulation)",opa:"water of less than 20 feet in depth",opb:"where land is always in sight",opc:"no more than 5 miles",opd:"about 30 minutes away from the dock",ans:"opd"},{question:"With the air supply on, the air pressure in an enclosed lifeboat will be ____________.",opa:"changing in relation to the speed of the craft",opb:"less than outside air pressure",opc:"greater than outside air pressure",opd:"equal to outside air pressure",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which instrument may a towing vessel, engaged in towing exclusively on the Western Rivers, use in place of a magnetic compass?",opa:"Gyrocompass",opb:"Illuminated Swing Meter",opc:"A VHF Radio",opd:"GPS Receiver",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 14,500 tons, with a longitudinal CG 247.5 ft. aft of the FP. If you pump 80 tons of ballast from forward to aft through a distance of 480 feet, your new CG will be ____________.",opa:"244.85 feet aft of FP",opb:"246.22 feet aft of FP",opc:"248.87 feet aft of FP",opd:"250.15 feet aft of FP",ans:"opd"},{question:"To safely enter a compartment where CO2 has been released from a fixed extinguishing system, you should ____________.",opa:"wear a canister type gas mask",opb:"test the air with an Orsat apparatus",opc:"test the air with a pure air indicator",opd:"wear a self-contained breathing apparatus",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 3245 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 272.20 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 267.7 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 268.4 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 269.2 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 270.6 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to Coast Guard Regulations (CFR 33), the shipboard Oil Pollution Emergency Plan must include ____________.",opa:"all information ordinarily provided in the Oil Record Book",opb:"an explanation and purpose of the plan",opc:"a one-line schematic of the plan to be implemented",opd:"the operating instructions for any and all oily-water separators installed aboard the vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"In using the Allowable Wind and Wave Charts for the COASTAL DRILLER, which of the three leg reactions is required?",opa:"Minimum",opb:"Average",opc:"Highest",opd:"Preloaded value",ans:"opc"},{question:"A semisubmersible, 200 feet in length between draft marks with the LCF 10 feet aft of amidships, records the following drafts: Port Forward 64'-9'; Port Aft 68'-9'; Starboard Forward 59'-9'; and Starboard Aft 63'-9'. What is the true mean draft?",opa:"64.25 feet",opb:"64.45 feet",opc:"64.75 feet",opd:"64.90 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"In the absence of external forces, adding weight on one side of a floating vessel causes the vessel to ____________.",opa:"heel until the angle of loll is reached",opb:"list until the center of buoyancy is aligned vertically with the center of gravity",opc:"trim to the side opposite TCG until all moments are equal",opd:"decrease draft at the center of flotation",ans:"opb"},{question:"When two fire hose teams are attacking a fire they should ____________.",opa:"use different fire hose pressures",opb:"use fire hoses of different sizes",opc:"not attack the fire from opposite sides",opd:"not wear protective clothing",ans:"opc"},{question:"The holding power of an anchor is the ____________.",opa:"maximum sustained vertical load an anchor will resist before dragging",opb:"maximum sustained horizontal load an anchor will resist before dragging",opc:"maximum sustained vertical load an anchor will resist before the mooring line breaks",opd:"maximum sustained horizontal load an anchor will resist before the mooring line breaks",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which system is most likely to be affected by atmospheric disturbances?",opa:"MF/HF radiotelephony",opb:"VHF DSC",opc:"INMARSAT",opd:"SafetyNET",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which grade of anchor chain is generally used on floating drilling vessels?",opa:"Grade 1",opb:"Grade 2",opc:"Oil Rig Quality (stud link)",opd:"303S",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 19'-00', AFT 24'-00'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"0.62 foot",opb:"0.80 foot",opc:"0.85 foot",opd:"0.99 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"A drill must be conducted in the use of the line throwing appliance at least once in every ____________.",opa:"2 months",opb:"3 months",opc:"4 months",opd:"5 months",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 60 feet, has a KGT of 57.11 feet and TCG of 0.5 foot to port. What is the list angle?",opa:"2\xb0 port",opb:"3\xb0 port",opc:"4\xb0 port",opd:"5\xb0 port",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are FWD 19'-02', AFT 23'-10'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if 98 tons of fuel is loaded 116 feet forward of amidships.",opa:"FWD 19'-04', AFT23'-06'",opb:"FWD 19'-07', AFT23'-04'",opc:"FWD 19'-09', AFT23'-01'",opd:"FWD 19'-09', AFT23'-06'",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have abandoned ship and are in an inflatable raft that has just inflated. You hear a continuous hissing coming from a fitting in a buoyancy tube. What is the cause of this?",opa:"The saltwater is activating the batteries of the marker lights on the canopy.",opb:"The inflation pump is in automatic operation to keep the tubes fully inflated.",opc:"A deflation plug is partially open allowing the escape of CO2.",opd:"Excess inflation pressure is bleeding off and should soon stop.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER has sufficient reserve stability to overcome damage due to flooding of any one watertight compartment in winds to ____________.",opa:"36 knots",opb:"50 knots",opc:"70 knots",opd:"100 knots",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning locating signals in the GMDSS is FALSE?",opa:"Locating signals are transmitted by survival craft VHF transceivers.",opb:"Locating signals are transmitted by SARTs.",opc:"Locating signals are intended to facilitate the finding of a distressed vessel or its survivors",opd:"Locating signals are not transmitted by autoalarm generators.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A sailing vessel with the wind coming from 090\xb0 relative would be ____________.",opa:"close hauled on the starboard tack",opb:"reaching on the starboard tack",opc:"on a broad reach on the starboard tack",opd:"close hauled on the port tack",ans:"opb"},{question:"The edge of a hurricane has overtaken your MODU in the Gulf of Mexico and the northwest wind of a few hours ago has shifted to the west. This is an indication that you are located in the ____________.",opa:"navigable semicircle",opb:"dangerous semicircle",opc:"low pressure area",opd:"eye of the storm",ans:"opa"},{question:"Paints and solvents on a vessel should be ____________.",opa:"stored safely at the work site until work is completed",opb:"returned to the paint locker after each use",opc:"covered at all times to protect from ignition sources",opd:"stored in a suitable gear locker",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-00', AFT 15'-11'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.62 feet",opb:"2.82 feet",opc:"2.97 feet",opd:"3.15 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each ventilation system for an enclosed classified location on a MODU must provide a complete change of air every ____________.",opa:"3 minutes",opb:"5 minutes",opc:"7 minutes",opd:"10 minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"What fitting on the mast works in conjunction with the shrouds to control side bend of the mast?",opa:"Chainplate",opb:"Hound",opc:"Crowfoot",opd:"Spreader",ans:"opd"},{question:"The normal equipment of every rescue boat shall include ____________.",opa:"buoyant oars",opb:"one 50 meter line",opc:"one first aid kit",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A crew member is unconscious and the face is flushed. You should ____________.",opa:"lay the crew member down with the head and shoulders slightly raised",opb:"administer a liquid stimulant",opc:"lay the crew member down with the head lower than the feet",opd:"attempt to stand the crew member upright to restore consciousness",ans:"opa"},{question:"When using the rainwater collection tubes of a liferaft, the FIRST collection should be ____________.",opa:"passed around so all can drink",opb:"poured overboard because of salt washed off the canopy",opc:"saved to be used at a later time",opd:"used to boil food",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are under sail on a close reach, and the wind is steady. While steady on course, you reef the mainsail and your speed slows. The apparent wind ____________.",opa:"is unchanged",opb:"increases and draws aft",opc:"increases and draws forward",opd:"decreases and draws aft",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What is the new transverse free surface correction (FSCT) if the entire contents of drill water tanks 6 and 7 are discharged?",opa:"2.24 feet",opb:"2.14 feet",opc:"2.10 feet",opd:"1.67 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are transferring fuel from a supply vessel to your MODU. If you close off one tank in the line of tanks being filled, the rate of flow to other open tanks on the same line will ____________.",opa:"increase",opb:"decrease",opc:"stop",opd:"stabilize",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER suffers minor flooding of the starboard pump room. If both starboard bilge pumps fail to dewater the pump room, you should use the ____________.",opa:"starboard drill water pump",opb:"starboard saltwater service pump",opc:"starboard ballast pumps",opd:"port ballast pumps and crossover system",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is level at a draft of 58 feet when there are no environmental forces. What is the value of LCG?",opa:"0.00 (amidships)",opb:"2.23 feet forward of amidships",opc:"2.26 feet forward of amidships",opd:"2.31 feet forward of amidships",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 55 feet, has a KGT of 53.05 feet and TCG of 0.5 foot to starboard. What is the list angle?",opa:"2.0\xb0Starboard",opb:"2.9\xb0Starboard",opc:"3.2\xb0Starboard",opd:"3.5\xb0 starboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"The stamped full weight of a 100 lb. CO2 bottle is 314 lbs. What is the minimum weight of the bottle before it has to be recharged?",opa:"282 lbs.",opb:"294 lbs.",opc:"300 lbs.",opd:"304 lbs.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which fire detection system is actuated by sensing a heat rise in a compartment?",opa:"Manual fire detection system",opb:"Automatic fire detection system",opc:"Smoke detection system",opd:"Watchman's supervisory system",ans:"opb"},{question:"onboard small passenger vessels, fill lines and sounding pipes of gasoline tanks must extend directly ____________.",opa:"to within one-half of their diameter from the bottom of the tank",opb:"To within one-half foot from the bottom of the tank",opc:"To the tank top",opd:"Midway between the top and bottom of the tank",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #2 (Ballasting to Survival). What is the shift in LCG if 100.76 long tons of ballast are added to Ballast Tank #8S to replace the discharge of all bulk materials?",opa:"0.06 foot aft",opb:"0.14 foot aft",opc:"0.27 foot aft",opd:"0.40 foot aft",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a MODU, an obvious indicator of lost circulation of drilling fluid is ____________.",opa:"fluid level in the mud pits increases rapidly",opb:"fluid level in the mud pits decreases rapidly",opc:"increased cuttings on the shale shaker",opd:"decreased cuttings on the shale shaker",ans:"opb"},{question:"Pollution regulations require that each scupper in an enclosed deck area have a ____________.",opa:"wooden plug",opb:"soft rubber plug",opc:"two-piece soft patch",opd:"mechanical means of closing",ans:"opd"},{question:"The preferred agent used in fighting a helicopter crash fire is ____________.",opa:"CO2",opb:"dry chemical",opc:"water",opd:"foam",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is a pinion in a jacking system?",opa:"Flexible coupling",opb:"Flexible shaft",opc:"Flexible joint",opd:"Gearwheel",ans:"opd"},{question:"A MODU helicopter landing deck on which fueling operations are conducted must have a fire protection system that is capable of discharging at 100 psi pressure a foam spray of at least ____________.",opa:"30 gallons per minute",opb:"40 gallons per minute",opc:"50 gallons per minute",opd:"60 gallons per minute",ans:"opc"},{question:"The signal T 0735 means ____________.",opa:"The Greenwich mean time is 0735",opb:"The zone time is 0735",opc:"The latitude is 7\xb0 35'",opd:"The longitude is 7\xb0 35'",ans:"opb"},{question:"How should the number '1' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"OO-NO",opb:"OO-NAH-WUN",opc:"NUM-EV-WUN",opd:"NEW-MAL-WON",ans:"opb"},{question:"The two points that act together to trim a ship are the ____________.",opa:"LCF and LCB",opb:"LCG and LCB",opc:"metacenter and LCG",opd:"VCG and LCG",ans:"opb"},{question:"The tension on an anchor cable increases so that the angle of the catenary to the seabed at the anchor reaches 10 degrees. How will this affect the anchor in sandy soil?",opa:"It will have no effect.",opb:"It will increase the holding power.",opc:"It will reduce the holding power.",opd:"It will cause the anchor to snag.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You must evacuate crewmembers from a space filling with smoke. The primary means of escape is blocked by the fire. What fire control plan symbol designates the secondary means of escape?",opa:"61",opb:"62",opc:"63",opd:"19",ans:"opb"},{question:"In storm conditions, with the wind and waves from the starboard bow of the DEEP DRILLER in 400 feet water depth, the offset is 7%. Completely slacking mooring lines 7 and 8 reduces the offset to ____________.",opa:"0.065",opb:"0.05",opc:"0.04",opd:"0.025",ans:"opc"},{question:"Where must the draft marks be placed on a small passenger vessel?",opa:"On each side of the stem",opb:"Near the stern post or rudder post",opc:"At each end of the vessel",opd:"On each side, amidships",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a man who has fallen overboard is being picked up by a rescue boat, the boat should normally approach with the wind ____________.",opa:"astern and the victim just off the bow",opb:"ahead and the victim just off the bow",opc:"just off the bow and the victim to windward",opd:"just off the bow and the victim to leeward",ans:"opd"},{question:"What must ocean going vessels of 100 GT to 400 GT be fitted with for oily mixtures?",opa:"A fixed system to discharge the slops overboard",opb:"A fixed system to discharge oily mixtures to a reception facility",opc:"A portable system to discharge the slops overboard",opd:"A portable system to discharge oily mixtures to a reception facility",ans:"opb"},{question:"Storage batteries on 'T-Boats' must be located ____________.",opa:"in sight of the main engine(s)",opb:"in a tray lined with suitable material that resists damage from the electrolyte",opc:"in locked closets with restricted ventilation",opd:"near the bilge to lower the center of gravity and improve stability",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is in distress and you have made radiotelephone contact with a U.S. Coast Guard vessel. The Coast Guard vessel requests that you give him a long count. This indicates that ____________.",opa:"your radio transmitter is not working properly",opb:"the Coast Guard vessel is testing its receiver",opc:"the Coast Guard vessel is taking a radio direction finder bearing on your vessel",opd:"the Coast Guard vessel is requesting your position in latitude and longitude",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are involved in an emergency landing of a helicopter on the water. You should inflate your life jacket ____________.",opa:"upon entering the helicopter",opb:"prior to reaching the water",opc:"after reaching the water, but prior to exiting the helicopter",opd:"after exiting clear of the helicopter",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is a major disadvantage of Di-Lok chain compared with Oil Rig Quality (stud link) chain in floating drilling rig operations?",opa:"Shorter fatigue life",opb:"Higher weight",opc:"Lower strength",opd:"Greater expense",ans:"opa"},{question:"The deck loads on a MODU are distributed through the deck beams to the ____________.",opa:"frames",opb:"hull",opc:"stringers",opd:"plates",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 18'-09', AFT 20'-03'. How much more cargo can be loaded to have the vessel down to the freeboard draft? (Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"4521 tons",opb:"5349 tons",opc:"7242 tons",opd:"9750 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Since electrical burn victims may be in shock, the FIRST medical response is to check for ____________.",opa:"indication of broken bones",opb:"breathing and heartbeat",opc:"symptoms of concussion",opd:"bleeding injuries",ans:"opb"},{question:"There is a fire in the crew's quarters of your vessel. You should ____________.",opa:"ventilate the quarters as much as possible",opb:"prepare to abandon ship",opc:"close all ventilation to the quarters if possible",opd:"attempt to put the fire out yourself before sounding the alarm",ans:"opc"},{question:"A MODU lists and trims about the ____________.",opa:"center of gravity",opb:"center of buoyancy",opc:"center of flotation",opd:"centroid of the underwater volume",ans:"opc"},{question:"As an extinguishing agent, foam ____________.",opa:"conducts electricity",opb:"should be directed at the base of the fire",opc:"is most effective on burning gases which are flowing",opd:"extinguishes by cooling oil fires below ignition temperature",ans:"opa"},{question:"What additional precautions should be taken when making temporary repairs to a MODU that is operating when hydrogen sulfide is present?",opa:"Seal off all tank and compartment ventilation.",opb:"Remove all bulk materials from the P-tanks.",opc:"Provide respiratory protection and monitoring.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The date and time kept in the radiotelephone log shall commence at ____________.",opa:"midnight",opb:"noon",opc:"beginning of the watch",opd:"any convenient time",ans:"opa"},{question:"An extinguisher with 15 lbs. of CO2 or 10 lbs. of dry chemical is a size ____________.",opa:"I",opb:"II",opc:"III",opd:"IV",ans:"opb"},{question:"In launching a covered lifeboat, what would safely lower the lifeboat from inside the lifeboat cabin?",opa:"Frapping line",opb:"Tricing line",opc:"Rottmer release",opd:"Winch remote control wire",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which kind(s) of broadcasts are available through Safety NET?",opa:"MSI and messages to pre-defined groups of subscribers",opb:"MSI and vessel traffic lists",opc:"Hourly NOAA weather broadcasts from the NWS",opd:"Coastal weather broadcasts",ans:"opa"},{question:"While drilling loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), the DEEP DRILLER suffers a sudden unexpected inclination to starboard and forward. Strong winds and high waves are from the port quarter. Among the possible causes, you should consider ____________.",opa:"failure of mooring lines 3 or 4",opb:"failure of mooring lines 7 or 8",opc:"leak in ballast tank#2S",opd:"ballast tanks equalizing into tank 1S",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are loading propanolamine and spill a small quantity on deck. According to the Chemical Data Guide, you would expect its odor to be ____________.",opa:"sweet",opb:"similar to turpentine",opc:"fishy",opd:"similar to ammonia",ans:"opc"},{question:"The transfer procedures required to be followed on tankships shall contain ____________.",opa:"a list of each port of discharge",opb:"a line diagram of the vessel's transfer piping",opc:"a current crew list",opd:"the duties by name of each person in charge required for each transfer operation",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-00', AFT 15'-11'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.62 feet",opb:"2.82 feet",opc:"2.97 feet",opd:"3.15 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Drilling), dumps all the mud in pits 1, 2, 3, and 4. What is the new TCG?",opa:"-0.36 foot",opb:"-0.26 foot",opc:"0.31 foot",opd:"0.36 foot",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER's ability to meet the damage stability criteria depends on maintaining watertight integrity, displacement less than 14,158 kips, level attitude, and KGT and KGL less than ____________.",opa:"the height of the righting arm",opb:"the maximum allowed",opc:"GMT and GML",opd:"BMT and BML",ans:"opb"},{question:"All portable fire extinguishers must be capable of being ____________.",opa:"carried by hand to a fire",opb:"carried or rolled to a fire",opc:"recharged in the field",opd:"used on class 'B' fires",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel's KG is determined by ____________.",opa:"dividing the total longitudinal moment summation by displacement",opb:"dividing the total vertical moment summation by displacement",opc:"multiplying the MT1 by the longitudinal moments",opd:"subtracting LCF from LCB",ans:"opb"},{question:"The wooden plug fitted tightly in the vent of a damaged tank may prevent the tank from ____________.",opa:"filling completely",opb:"developing free surfaces",opc:"developing free surface moments",opd:"collapsing",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the definition of transverse metacenter?",opa:"The distance between the actual center of gravity and the maximum center of gravity that will still allow a positive stability.",opb:"The point to which G may rise and still permit the vessel to possess positive stability.",opc:"The sum of the center of buoyancy and the center of gravity.",opd:"The transverse shift of the center of buoyancy as a vessel rolls.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The signal given to commence lowering the lifeboats is ____________.",opa:"3 short blasts of the ship's whistle",opb:"specified on the muster list (station bill)",opc:"3 long blasts of the ship's whistle",opd:"1 long blast of the ship's whistle",ans:"opb"},{question:"The original equilibrium position is stable when ____________.",opa:"metacentric height is positive",opb:"metacentric radius is positive",opc:"KG exceeds maximum allowable limits",opd:"free surfaces are excessive",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is observed to be level at a draft of 10 feet 6 inches. At the same time, the calculated load form shows the displacement to be 13,445 kips, total longitudinal moments 1,613,466 foot-kips, and total transverse moments -10,000 foot-kips. What is the longitudinal location of the missing load?",opa:"46 feet AFO",opb:"84 feet AFO",opc:"189 feet AFO",opd:"217 feet AFO",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are loading in a port governed by the tropical load line mark for a voyage to a port governed by the winter mark. The fresh water allowance is 5 inches, and the hydrometer reads 1.005. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You may load to the tropical mark plus 1 inch brackish water allowance.",opb:"You must load so that each zone mark will not be submerged upon entering the zone.",opc:"Your draft must not exceed the winter mark plus the fresh water allowance upon arrival off the discharge port.",opd:"You may only load to the winter mark plus a brackish water allowance of 4 inches.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Spaces containing gasoline-powered machinery or gasoline storage tanks on small passenger vessels should have ventilator ducts that extend to the bilges because ____________.",opa:"air is heavier than gas fumes",opb:"oil and water mix there",opc:"it prevents air from entering or leaving the space",opd:"Gasoline vapors are heavier than air, tend to settle in the bilges, and create an explosion hazard",ans:"opd"},{question:"The self-contained breathing device should not be used in which situation?",opa:"Oxygen deficient spaces",opb:"Compartments containing poisonous vapors",opc:"Fighting fires that produce heavy smoke",opd:"Underwater search",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which casualty involving a mobile offshore drilling unit would require a report to be filed?",opa:"Damage to property of $20,000",opb:"An injury treated by first aid",opc:"An occurrence materially and adversely affecting the vessel's fitness for service",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"An elevated jack-up weighs 14,000 kips. Its TCG is located 1.0 foot to starboard of the centerline. What would be the new TCG for the jack-up if the drill floor, weighing 700 kips, is skidded 10 feet to port?",opa:"9.00 feet port",opb:"0.50 foot starboard",opc:"0.50 foot port",opd:"1.00 foot port",ans:"opb"},{question:"When landing a lifeboat through heavy surf with a strong current running parallel to the beach (from right to left when facing from seaward) the recommended procedure is to ____________.",opa:"approach while coming to the left to take advantage of the current",opb:"drop an anchor outside the surf line, then pay out anchor line over the bow while the seas carry the boat toward the beach",opc:"approach slow enough so that the boat can be brought around to meet breaking seas on the bow",opd:"rig a drogue with tripping line over the bow, back ashore with drogue tripped between breakers",ans:"opd"},{question:"Adding the transverse free surface correction to the uncorrected height of the center of gravity of a MODU yields ____________.",opa:"FSCT",opb:"KG",opc:"KGT",opd:"GMT",ans:"opc"},{question:"The emergency power system for the DEEP DRILLER should be placed in operation when the weather forecast predicts winds greater than 90 knots and when ____________.",opa:"evacuating the unit",opb:"ballasting",opc:"deballasting",opd:"unexpected list and trim exist",ans:"opa"},{question:"During the passage of a severe storm, the DEEP DRILLER is at survival draft. Strong winds are blowing from the starboard. A careful load form calculation determined that, although the unit is level, the TCG is 2.0 feet to starboard. The value of the wind heeling moment is ____________.",opa:"40,402 ft.-long tons",opb:"32,099 ft.-long tons",opc:"21,343 ft.-long tons",opd:"19,982 ft.-long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER's lightweight is the condition prior to loading ____________.",opa:"deck load",opb:"deck load and lower-hull liquids",opc:"deck load, lower-hull liquids, and external loads",opd:"deck load, lower-hull liquids, external loads, and deploying anchors",ans:"opd"},{question:"To check stability, a weight of 35 tons is lifted with the jumbo boom, whose head is 35 feet from the ship's centerline. The clinometer shows a list of 7.0\xb0 with the weight suspended. Displacement including the weight is 14,000 tons. The GM in this condition is ____________.",opa:"0.71 foot",opb:"0.95 foot",opc:"1.26 feet",opd:"2.01 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER will sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts.",opa:"FWD 22'-02', AFT25'-08'",opb:"FWD 21'-07', AFT26'-03'",opc:"FWD 20'-11', AFT26'-09'",opd:"FWD 20'-09', AFT26'-11'",ans:"opc"},{question:"If an engine shuts down due to high jacket water temperature, what action should be taken?",opa:"Open crankcase explosion covers",opb:"Allow engine to cool gradually",opc:"Slowly add cool water to the expansion tank",opd:"Back flush the cooling water system",ans:"opb"},{question:"What fitting on the mast works in conjunction with the shrouds to control side bend of the mast?",opa:"Chainplate",opb:"Hound",opc:"Crowfoot",opd:"Spreader",ans:"opd"},{question:"Regulations define the bulkhead deck as ____________. (subdivision and stability regulations)",opa:"any deck extending from stem to stern",opb:"the uppermost deck to which transverse watertight bulkheads extend",opc:"the lowermost deck to which transverse watertight bulkheads extend",opd:"the uppermost complete deck",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a MODU, a CO2 extinguisher is checked by ____________.",opa:"reading the gage pressure",opb:"weighing the extinguisher",opc:"discharging a small amount of CO2",opd:"seeing if the seal has been broken",ans:"opb"},{question:"Lost circulation can cause a kick or blowout by ____________.",opa:"creating a flow channel outside the casing and back to the surface",opb:"lowering the density of the drilling fluid",opc:"reducing the mud level in the well",opd:"contaminating the drilling fluid",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a vessel of 7000 tons displacement, a tank 35 ft. long, 30 ft. wide and 46 ft. deep is half filled with liquid cargo (S.G. 0.923) while the vessel is floating in saltwater (S.G. 1.026). What is the free surface constant for this tank?",opa:"3240",opb:"2731",opc:"2390",opd:"2024",ans:"opd"},{question:"If help has not arrived in 10-12 hours after abandoning a vessel in a rescue boat, you should ____________.",opa:"go in one direction until the fuel runs out",opb:"steer a course for the nearest land",opc:"steer a course for the nearest sea lane",opd:"shut down the engines if installed and put out the sea anchor",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has 3 lifeboats on each side. The aftermost boat on the starboard side is designated as boat number ____________.",opa:"6",opb:"5",opc:"3",opd:"3 STARBOARD",ans:"opb"},{question:"While you are working in a space, the fixed CO2 system is accidentally activated. You should ____________.",opa:"secure the applicators to preserve the charge in the cylinders",opb:"continue with your work as there is nothing you can do to stop the flow of CO2",opc:"retreat to fresh air and ventilate the compartment before returning",opd:"make sure all doors and vents are secured",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the DEEP DRILLER, VCG is obtained from the sum of the vertical moments by ____________.",opa:"adding displacement",opb:"subtracting displacement",opc:"multiplying by displacement",opd:"dividing by displacement",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has a midships engine room and the cargo is concentrated in the end holds. The vessel is ____________.",opa:"sagging with tensile stress on main deck",opb:"sagging with compressive stress on main deck",opc:"hogging with tensile stress on main deck",opd:"hogging with compressive stress on main deck",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which radiotelephone signal indicates receipt of a distress message?",opa:"Received mayday",opb:"Roger wilco",opc:"SOS acknowledged",opd:"Mayday, roger",ans:"opa"},{question:"Liquefied flammable gas is defined as any flammable gas having a Reid vapor pressure exceeding how many pounds?",opa:"14",opb:"30",opc:"40",opd:"50",ans:"opc"},{question:"In storm conditions, with the wind and waves from the starboard bow of the DEEP DRILLER in 600 feet water depth, the offset is 8%. Completely slacking mooring lines 7 and 8 reduces the offset to ____________.",opa:"0.065",opb:"0.05",opc:"0.025",opd:"0",ans:"opb"},{question:"A chemical additive to LPG gives it a characteristic ____________.",opa:"odor",opb:"color",opc:"pressure",opd:"density",ans:"opa"},{question:"The rescuer can best provide an airtight seal during mouth to mouth ventilation by pinching the victim's nostrils and ____________.",opa:"cupping a hand around the patient's mouth",opb:"keeping the head elevated",opc:"applying his mouth tightly over the victim's mouth",opd:"holding the jaw down firmly",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER arrived in port with drafts of: FWD 19'-10.5', AFT 22'-11.6'. Cargo was loaded and discharged as shown. Use sheet 2 in the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts.",opa:"FWD 20'-01.4', AFT23'-00.6'",opb:"FWD 19'-07.6', AFT22'-10.4'",opc:"FWD 19'-09.3', AFT22'-08.7'",opd:"FWD 19'-11.7', AFT23'-02.5'",ans:"opb"},{question:"The person on a MODU who is responsible for maintaining the engineering spaces in a clean and sanitary condition is the ____________.",opa:"Master, or person in charge",opb:"Chief Engineer, or engineer in charge if no chief engineer is required",opc:"senior mechanic, or mechanic on duty if no senior mechanic designated",opd:"senior electrician, or electrician on duty if no senior electrician designated",ans:"opb"},{question:"A fire is discovered in the forepeak of a vessel at sea. The wind is from ahead at 35 knots. You should ____________.",opa:"remain on course and hold speed",opb:"change course and put the stern to the wind",opc:"change course to put the wind on either beam and increase speed",opd:"remain on course but slack the speed",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are on a supply run to an offshore drilling rig. onboard is the cargo listed. What is the height above the main deck of the center of gravity of the cargo?",opa:"3.75 feet",opb:"3.02 feet",opc:"2.22 feet",opd:"0.83 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a vessel is sagging, what kind of stress is placed on the sheer strake?",opa:"Compression",opb:"Tension",opc:"Thrust",opd:"Racking",ans:"opa"},{question:"A negative metacentric height ____________.",opa:"will always cause a vessel to capsize",opb:"always results from off-center weights",opc:"should always be immediately corrected",opd:"All of the above are correct",ans:"opc"},{question:"When applying chest compressions on an adult victim during CPR, the sternum should be depressed about ____________.",opa:"1/2 inch or less",opb:"1/2 to 1 inch",opc:"1 to 1-1/2 inches",opd:"1-1/2 to 2 inches",ans:"opd"},{question:"The national distress, safety, and calling frequency is channel ____________.",opa:"13",opb:"16",opc:"18",opd:"22",ans:"opb"},{question:"Use the material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the KG is 24.2 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 23'-04', AFT 24'-05'; at what angle will the vessel lose positive stability?",opa:"67\xb0",opb:"71\xb0",opc:"75\xb0",opd:"79\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"In reviving a person who has been overcome by gas fumes, what would you AVOID doing?",opa:"Giving stimulants",opb:"Prompt removal of the patient from the suffocating atmosphere",opc:"Applying artificial respiration and massage",opd:"Keeping the patient warm and comfortable",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"338 tons",opb:"309 tons",opc:"281 tons",opd:"263 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about free surface is TRUE?",opa:"A partially filled space with 40% surface permeability will have greater free surface effect than one with 60% surface permeability.",opb:"Pocketing increases the loss of GM due to free surface effect.",opc:"Cargo with a specific gravity of 1.05 has less free surface effect than a cargo with a specific gravity of 0.98.",opd:"Pocketing occurs at small angles of inclination when a tank is 98% full.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A schooner is a fore-and-aft rigged vessel with ____________.",opa:"a single mast",opb:"two masts: with the mizzen stepped abaft the rudder post",opc:"two masts: with the mizzen stepped forward of the rudder post",opd:"at least two masts: a foremast and a mainmast",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are operating a ship greater than 400 gross tons. You are NOT permitted to carry oil or hazardous materials in a(n) ____________.",opa:"forepeak tank",opb:"after peak tank",opc:"deep tank",opd:"on-deck portable tank",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel rolls slowly and sluggishly. This indicates that the vessel ____________.",opa:"has off-center weights",opb:"is taking on water",opc:"has a greater draft forward than aft",opd:"has poor stability",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Preparing to Drill). According to the deck load graph, how much additional deck load could be added to the unit?",opa:"526.87 long tons",opb:"276.87 long tons",opc:"241.50 long tons",opd:"189.51 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"If your vessel is certificated to carry 10 persons, including both adults and children, how many life jackets are you required to carry onboard? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"11 adult",opb:"10 adult and 1 child",opc:"10 adult and 5 child",opd:"10 adult",ans:"opb"},{question:"A fill pipe for a gasoline tank onboard a small passenger vessel must be ____________.",opa:"arranged so neither liquid gasoline nor its vapors can overflow or escape inside the vessel",opb:"terminated on the weather deck and extend to within one half of its diameter from the bottom of the tank",opc:"fitted with a suitably marked watertight deck plate or screw cap",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Drilling loads on the COASTAL DRILLER are the combined loads arising from conductor tension, rotary, hook, and ____________.",opa:"fixed loads",opb:"setback loads",opc:"basic loads",opd:"variable loads",ans:"opb"},{question:"All life jackets carried onboard small passenger vessels are required to be marked ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"with the vessel's name",opb:"with the vessel's official number",opc:"with the maximum weight to be held by the life preserver",opd:"with the maximum serviceable life of the life preserver",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel operating outside of coastal waters must carry an automatically activated Emergency Position Indicating Radio Beacon (EPIRB) if she ____________.",opa:"does not have berthing facilities",opb:"has berthing and galley facilities",opc:"is a workboat and her mother ship carries an EPIRB",opd:"None of the above are correct.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is partially loaded with a GM of 3.1 feet and drafts of: FWD 19'-06', AFT 21'-04'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine what tank(s) you should ballast to increase the GM to 3.7 feet.",opa:"Tanks: DT1",opb:"Tanks: DB3, DT8",opc:"Tanks: DB2, DB7",opd:"Tanks: DB5",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has 3 lifeboats on each side. The aftermost boat on the port side is designated as boat number ____________.",opa:"6",opb:"5",opc:"3",opd:"3 PORT",ans:"opa"},{question:"If your vessel has a list to port due to negative GM and off-center weight, the first corrective measure you should take is to ____________.",opa:"move port-side main-deck cargo to the starboard side",opb:"fill the starboard double-bottom",opc:"pump water from the port double-bottom to the starboard double-bottom",opd:"pump water from the port double-bottom over the side",ans:"opb"},{question:"Air gap is the vertical distance between the bottom of the hull and the ____________.",opa:"still water level",opb:"wave crest",opc:"wave crest plus the charted water depth and tidal corrections",opd:"wave crest plus the charted water depth and tidal correction and storm surge",ans:"opa"},{question:"Puncture leaks in the lower tubes or bottom of an inflatable liferaft should FIRST be stopped by using ____________.",opa:"sealing clamps",opb:"repair tape",opc:"a tube patch",opd:"sail twine and vulcanizing kit",ans:"opa"},{question:"For GMDSS, which statement concerning compulsory vessels is TRUE?",opa:"Vessels over 500 gross tons must carry at least three licensed GMDSS Radio Operators.",opb:"Passenger vessels between 300-500 gross tons need to carry only one licensed GMDSS Radio Operator, but passenger vessels larger than 500 must carry two licensed Operators.",opc:"Vessels larger than 500 gross tons must carry certain additional GMDSS equipment than what a vessel between 300-500 gross tons must carry.",opd:"Vessels between 300-500 gross tons need to carry no more than one EPIRB, SART and survival craft transceiver, but vessels larger than 500 gross tons must carry two of each unit.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The sounding in fuel oil tank 4P on the DEEP DRILLER is 8.75 feet. What are the transverse moments for this amount of fuel?",opa:"-17,416 ft.-long tons",opb:"-874 ft.-long tons",opc:"3,992 ft.-long tons",opd:"17,416 ft.-long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"How many means of escape must be provided from passenger areas on a passenger vessel of 500 GT?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Two, unless there is an elevator provided",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is standing rigging?",opa:"Halyards",opb:"Stays",opc:"Sheets",opd:"Downhauls",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's existing draft is FWD 14'-00', AFT 16'-00'. Using the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN, determine the new draft if 350 long tons are discharged from No. 13 hatch.",opa:"FWD 13'-03 5/8',AFT 15'-03 1/8'",opb:"FWD 13'-04 3/4',AFT 15'-03 1/4'",opc:"FWD 13'-05 1/5',AFT 15'-04 3/5'",opd:"FWD 13'-08 4/5',AFT 15'-08 4/5'",ans:"opd"},{question:"A squeeze-grip type carbon dioxide portable fire extinguisher has been partially discharged. It should be ____________.",opa:"labeled empty and recharged as soon as possible",opb:"replaced in its proper location if weight loss is no more than 25%",opc:"replaced in its proper location regardless of weight",opd:"replaced in its proper location if weight loss is no more than 15%",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 25'-09', AFT 28'-03'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the location of the center of flotation relative to amidships.",opa:"2.6 feet forward",opb:"2.1 feet forward",opc:"at the longitudinal center",opd:"0.8 foot aft",ans:"opc"},{question:"All personnel should be familiar with the lifeboats ____________.",opa:"boarding and operating procedures",opb:"maintenance schedule",opc:"navigational systems",opd:"fuel consumption rates",ans:"opa"},{question:"The lightweight vertical moments for the DEEP DRILLER are ____________.",opa:"680,914 ft.-long tons",opb:"9,733 ft.-long tons",opc:"-5,937 ft.-long tons",opd:"-6,716 ft.-long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"Those ship's tanks that are particularly important for trimming the ship are the ____________.",opa:"domestics",opb:"settlers",opc:"deeps",opd:"peaks",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged and partially flooded. It is listing 12\xb0 to port and trimmed 8 feet down by the head. It has a long, slow, sluggish roll. Which action should you take FIRST?",opa:"Press up an after, slack, centerline double bottom tank",opb:"Pump out the forepeak tank",opc:"Jettison the anchors and anchor cables",opd:"Jettison deck cargo from the port side",ans:"opa"},{question:"When water pressure of 100 psi is used in conjunction with an inline proportioner for the production of the mechanical foam, a 5-gallon can of liquid foam will last ____________.",opa:"1-1/2 minutes",opb:"2-1/2 minutes",opc:"5 minutes",opd:"15 minutes",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each EPIRB and SART for lifeboats shall be tested ____________.",opa:"weekly",opb:"every 2 weeks",opc:"monthly",opd:"every 3 months",ans:"opc"},{question:"Portable Halon extinguishers used on MODU's may use ____________.",opa:"HALON 1301 only",opb:"HALON 22 only",opc:"HALON 1211 only",opd:"HALON 1301 or1211",ans:"opc"},{question:"Weights added or discharged at the center of flotation on the COASTAL DRILLER while floating will change the ____________.",opa:"list",opb:"trim",opc:"true mean draft",opd:"TPI",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. Grand Haven, determine the amount of ballast required in tank No.1 (P&S) to maintain drafts of 17'-00' forward and 22'-06' aft for a vessel loaded with grain which has a test weight of 39.5 lbs.",opa:"155 tons each",opb:"170 tons each",opc:"190 tons each",opd:"200 tons each",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of the following best describes the requirement of the emergency pump control when used as the emergency shutdown on tank vessels?",opa:"stop the flow of oil at the main deck manifold",opb:"prevent the oil from leaving the shore facility",opc:"prevent the oil from siphoning through the pump",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is moored in 600 feet of water. The tension on anchor line #8 is 190 kips. What is the vertical component of chain tension for that line?",opa:"53.6 long tons",opb:"55.3 long tons",opc:"84.8 long tons",opd:"442.4 long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Operation of the valve control release on a fixed CO2 system must immediately ____________.",opa:"release CO2 to the protected space",opb:"secure all mechanical ventilation in the protected space",opc:"sound the rig's general alarm signal for a fire",opd:"sound an alarm in the ballast control room",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which commodity would be regulated by subchapter D, Rules and Regulations for Tank Vessels?",opa:"Asphalt",opb:"Vinyl Chloride",opc:"Benzene",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"How should latitude 54\xb018.9'N be written when preparing an AMVER report?",opa:"54.3N",opb:"0543N",opc:"5419N",opd:"54\xb0N",ans:"opc"},{question:"Before taking drinking water onboard in the U.S. or its possessions, the responsible person from the vessel should determine that the source ____________.",opa:"is used by a city",opb:"has been treated with chlorine",opc:"is approved by the Public Health Service",opd:"is not from surface water",ans:"opc"},{question:"The requirements for special welding procedures on a MODU must be contained in the ____________.",opa:"vessel plans",opb:"Coast Guard file",opc:"construction portfolio",opd:"construction plans",ans:"opc"},{question:"For a MODU with trim, an increase in GMT will cause the inclination to ____________.",opa:"stabilize at an angle of loll",opb:"decrease",opc:"increase",opd:"remain constant",ans:"opb"},{question:"The rescue boat on an OSV shall carry a tow line strong enough to tow the vessel's largest loaded liferaft at a speed of at least ____________.",opa:"1 knot",opb:"2 knot",opc:"5 knot",opd:"10 knot",ans:"opb"},{question:"A semisubmersible, 200 feet in length between draft marks with the LCF 10 feet aft of amidships, records the following drafts: Port Forward 64'-09'; Port Aft 68'-09'; Starboard Forward 59'-09'; and Starboard Aft 63'-09'. What is the list?",opa:"10 feet to port",opb:"5 feet to port",opc:"2.5 feet to port",opd:"5 feet to starboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #5 (Survival) when an unexpected slowly increasing starboard list and bow down trim occurs. A leak in 1S is found. By deballasting from ballast tanks 2S and 3S, the inclination slowly decreases. The increase in the longitudinal free surface correction is ____________.",opa:"1.25 feet",opb:"0.90 foot",opc:"0.83 foot",opd:"0.34 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has drafts of: FWD 25'-11', AFT 26'-11'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts if you ballast the forepeak with 83 tons of seawater.",opa:"FWD 26'-05.6', AFT26'-07.5'",opb:"FWD 26'-04.3', AFT26'-06.1'",opc:"FWD 26'-06.8', AFT26'-06.3'",opd:"FWD 26'-07.7', AFT26'-05.4'",ans:"opc"},{question:"To treat a person suffering from heat exhaustion, you should ____________.",opa:"administer artificial respiration",opb:"put him in a tub of ice water",opc:"give him sips of cool water",opd:"cover him with a light cloth",ans:"opc"},{question:"The most doubtful and unpredictable factor in a mooring system is the ____________.",opa:"ability of the anchors to hold in a seabed",opb:"anchor chain catenary length",opc:"variability of the fairlead",opd:"angle of the flukes",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which part of the inert gas system is designed to relieve sudden large overpressures that exceed the capacity of the mechanical P/V valves?",opa:"Pressure control valve",opb:"Deck water seal",opc:"Liquid filled P/V breaker",opd:"Isolation valve",ans:"opc"},{question:"While in 150 feet water depth when the pitch angle of the COASTAL DRILLER is 1 degree, the platform pitch period for going on location should be longer than ____________.",opa:"0.2 second",opb:"3.2 seconds",opc:"7.0 seconds",opd:"9.2 seconds",ans:"opc"},{question:"The main advantage of a steady stream of water on a class 'A' fire is that it ____________.",opa:"breaks up and cools the fire",opb:"protects the firefighting crew",opc:"removes the oxygen",opd:"washes the fire away",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a GMDSS radio operator initiates a DSC distress transmission but does not insert a message, what happens?",opa:"The transmission is aborted and an alarm sounds to indicate this data must be provided by the operator.",opb:"The transmission is not initiated and 'ERROR' is indicated on the display readout.",opc:"The transmission will be made with 'default' information provided automatically.",opd:"The receiving station will poll the DSC unit of the vessel in distress to download the necessary information",ans:"opc"},{question:"To reduce mild fever the MOST useful drug is ____________.",opa:"bicarbonate of soda",opb:"paregoric",opc:"aspirin",opd:"aromatic spirits of ammonia",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a MODU is involved in a casualty, the cost of property damage includes ____________.",opa:"the cost of labor and material to restore the property to the service condition which existed prior to the casualty",opb:"the loss of revenues while the unit is being repaired, up to a maximum of$50,000",opc:"the damage claims awarded to individuals or companies involved in the casualty, up to a maximum of$50,000",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about sailing close-hauled is TRUE?",opa:"If you ease the sheets and change heading, you can sail faster but not so close to the wind.",opb:"If you ease the sheets you will be in irons.",opc:"If you sheet your sails closer to the centerline, you can sail closer to the wind and decrease leeway.",opd:"If you sheet your sails closer to the centerline, you will luff.",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to the regulations for lifeboat falls, which action must be taken at 30-month intervals?",opa:"End-for-ended",opb:"Renewed",opc:"Inspected",opd:"Weight tested",ans:"opa"},{question:"How do you operate a portable CO2 fire extinguisher?",opa:"Point the horn down.",opb:"Turn cylinder upside-down.",opc:"Break the rupture disc.",opd:"Pull pin, squeeze grip.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which piece(s) of equipment represented by these Fire Control Plan symbols can be found on the exterior of the vessel?",opa:"1",opb:"53",opc:"55",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 14'-11', AFT 16'-01'; and the KG is 23.2 feet. What is the righting moment when the vessel is inclined to 15\xb0? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"5,800 foot-tons",opb:"7,600 foot-tons",opc:"9,272 foot-tons",opd:"11,200 foot-tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 3315 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 27.0 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 26.2 feet",opb:"KG 27.4 feet",opc:"KG 28.6 feet",opd:"KG 30.1 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"While operating your oceangoing vessel you must keep a record of any discharge or disposal of garbage. These entries shall be made ____________.",opa:"before the end of the voyage",opb:"before arriving at your next port",opc:"no later than 24 hours after disposal of the garbage",opd:"at the time the garbage was disposed",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which task is NOT the responsibility of the GMDSS Radio Operator?",opa:"Inspecting and cleaning the SART's container, and clearing the immediate storage area of any debris or obstacles.",opb:"Measuring the SART's transmitted frequency.",opc:"Placing the SART in the test mode and verifying that the nearby PPI shows concentric circles.",opd:"Ensuring the SART's batteries are replaced before their expiration date.",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many B-II fire extinguishers must be in the machinery space of a 175-foot long fishing vessel propelled by engines with 2300 brake horsepower?",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"5",ans:"opb"},{question:"The notice of casualty to a MODU must include ____________.",opa:"a request for assistance",opb:"the location of the unit at the time of the casualty",opc:"an estimate of the cost to repair damages",opd:"the amount of fuel remaining",ans:"opb"},{question:"The maximum allowable KG for the COASTAL DRILLER in normal transit at a draft of 10.5 feet is ____________.",opa:"40 feet",opb:"45 feet",opc:"55 feet",opd:"65 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, with a draft of 10 feet 3 inches in seawater, has a displacement of ____________.",opa:"13,011 kips",opb:"13,336 kips",opc:"13,445 kips",opd:"14,637 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"The first AMVER position report must be sent within how many hours of departure?",opa:"12",opb:"24",opc:"36",opd:"48",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 13'-10', AFT 16'-04'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.30 feet",opb:"1.17 foot",opc:"1.01 foot",opd:"0.91 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the DEEP DRILLER, the longitudinal free surface correction (FSCL) is obtained from the total of the longitudinal free surface moments (FSML) by ____________.",opa:"adding the LCG",opb:"subtracting the LCG",opc:"multiplying by displacement",opd:"dividing by displacement",ans:"opd"},{question:"The straight stream capability of an all-purpose nozzle is used in fighting a class A fire to ____________.",opa:"shield fire fighters from radiant heat",opb:"break up burning material",opc:"get the most water possible on the fire",opd:"drive heat and smoke ahead of the fire fighters",ans:"opb"},{question:"The gross weight of a fully charged CO2 bottle in a fixed CO2 system is 220 lbs. When the bottle is empty it weighs 120 lbs. What is the minimum acceptable gross weight of the CO2 bottle before it should be recharged by the manufacturer?",opa:"200 lbs.",opb:"205 lbs.",opc:"210 lbs.",opd:"220 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Foam extinguishes a fire by ____________.",opa:"smothering the burning material",opb:"chemical combination with burning material",opc:"absorbing the burning material",opd:"organic destruction of the burning material",ans:"opa"},{question:"Where there are multiple accident victims, which condition should be the first to receive emergency treatment?",opa:"Back injuries",opb:"Major multiple fractures",opc:"Suspension of breathing",opd:"Burns",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the Guidance Manual for Loading the M.V. Grand Haven, determine the amount of ballast required in tank No. 3 (P & S) to maintain drafts of 17'-00' forward and 22'-06' aft for a vessel loaded with grain which has a test weight of 34 lbs.",opa:"1150 tons each",opb:"1180 tons each",opc:"1220 tons each",opd:"1250 tons each",ans:"opc"},{question:"The change in trim of a vessel may be found by ____________.",opa:"dividing the trim moments by MT1",opb:"subtracting the LCF from the LCB",opc:"looking at the Hydrostatic Properties Table for the draft of the vessel",opd:"dividing longitudinal moments by the displacement",ans:"opa"},{question:"If the cause of severe list or trim is off-center ballast, counter flooding into empty tanks will ____________.",opa:"increase the righting moment",opb:"increase the righting arm",opc:"increase list or trim",opd:"decrease list or trim",ans:"opd"},{question:"Repair of structures on a MODU in the vicinity of liquid mud handling areas presents what possible hazard?",opa:"Toxic gasses may be present.",opb:"Flammable gasses may be present.",opc:"Liquid muds may flood adjoining spaces.",opd:"An oxygen-deficient atmosphere may be present.",ans:"opb"},{question:"During the towing of a survival craft, a lookout should be on station to ____________.",opa:"release the towline in an emergency",opb:"help the helmsman steer",opc:"look for food and water",opd:"check the water level in the bilge",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE of a stiff vessel?",opa:"She will have a large metacentric height.",opb:"Her period of roll will be large due to her large metacentric height.",opc:"She will have an unusually high center of gravity.",opd:"She will pitch heavily.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Visual inspections of survival craft on offshore drilling units, to ensure operational readiness, must be conducted at least once a ____________.",opa:"week",opb:"month",opc:"quarter",opd:"year",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are ordering ships' stores. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Aerosol cans of engine starting fluid must be stowed in either the paint locker or portable magazine after receipt.",opb:"Drugs and medicines must be stowed in accordance with the directives of the Food and Drug Administration.",opc:"Flammable ship's stores must be certified for use on inspected vessels by Underwriter's Laboratories.",opd:"Properly labeled consumer commodities need not be labeled in accordance with Title 46 CFR.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 16'-08', AFT 17'-06'; and the KG is 23.8 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the remaining righting arm at 60\xb0 inclination if the center of gravity is 1.7 feet off the centerline.",opa:"1.8 feet",opb:"2.1 feet",opc:"3.0 feet",opd:"3.8 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A carbon dioxide fire extinguisher should be recharged ____________.",opa:"at least annually",opb:"whenever it is below its required weight",opc:"only if the extinguisher has been used",opd:"before every safety inspection",ans:"opb"},{question:"At all angles of inclination, the metacenter is ____________.",opa:"vertically above the center of buoyancy",opb:"vertically above the center of gravity",opc:"at the intersection of the upright vertical centerline and the line of action of the buoyant force",opd:"at the geometric center of the underwater volume",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a davit-launched liferaft aboard a MODU cannot be launched because of damage to the davit, you should ____________.",opa:"inflate the liferaft on deck",opb:"roll the liferaft over the side",opc:"go to another liferaft station",opd:"get a saw and cut the liferaft free",ans:"opb"},{question:"An ideal mooring system would be ____________.",opa:"symmetrical and in equilibrium",opb:"asymmetrical and in flux",opc:"distorted and in equilibrium",opd:"concentric and in flux",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are being directed to a fire in the lower engine room, portside, frame 127. What machinery is found in that exact location?",opa:"Emergency fire pumps",opb:"Generator",opc:"Bilge pump(s)",opd:"Lube Oil Purifier",ans:"opc"},{question:"The grab rail of a metal lifeboat is normally located ____________.",opa:"along the turn of the bilge",opb:"along each side of the keel",opc:"near the top of the gunwale",opd:"at the bow and at the stern",ans:"opa"},{question:"When initial stability applies, the height of the center of gravity plus the metacentric height equals the ____________.",opa:"free surface moments",opb:"righting arm",opc:"height of the metacenter",opd:"corrected height of the center of gravity",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which signal must you display at night on a docked tank barge to show that it is loading or discharging flammable liquid cargo?",opa:"Red light",opb:"Flashing amber light",opc:"ICC yellow light",opd:"Two orange lights",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the flash point of iso-Hexane?",opa:"-10\xb0Fahrenheit",opb:"20\xb0Centigrade",opc:"68\xb0Fahrenheit",opd:"152\xb0Centigrade",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel heading WNW is on a course of ____________.",opa:"270.0\xb0",opb:"292.5\xb0",opc:"315.0\xb0",opd:"337.5\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the normal operating power for ship-to-ship communications on channel 13?",opa:"1 watt or less",opb:"5 watts",opc:"10 watts",opd:"20 watts",ans:"opa"},{question:"After extinguishing a fire with CO2, it is advisable to ____________.",opa:"use all CO2 available to cool the surrounding area",opb:"stand by with water or other agents",opc:"thoroughly ventilate the space of CO2",opd:"jettison all burning materials",ans:"opb"},{question:"Unless otherwise stated, the term 'approved' applied to a vessel's equipment, means approved by the ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"Congress of the United States",opc:"Commandant of the Coast Guard",opd:"Board of Fire Underwriters",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1171.5 tons",opb:"1311.0 tons",opc:"1503.0 tons",opd:"1710.5 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, the number of industrial personnel permitted to be onboard during drilling operations is found on the ____________.",opa:"Classification Certificate",opb:"Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Owner's Operation Manual",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1920 tons",opb:"1280 tons",opc:"895 tons",opd:"720 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel has a displacement of 10,000 tons. It is 350 feet long and has a beam of 55 feet. You have timed its rolling period to be 15.0 seconds. What is your vessel's approximate GM?",opa:"1.18 feet",opb:"1.83 feet",opc:"2.60 feet",opd:"3.36 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have abandoned ship in tropical waters. Which procedure should be used during a prolonged period in a liferaft?",opa:"Wet clothes during the day to decrease perspiration.",opb:"Get plenty of rest.",opc:"Keep the entrance curtains open.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to regulations, access to a cargo pumproom in a tank vessel carrying grades C or D liquid cargo shall be ____________.",opa:"from areas equipped with power ventilation",opb:"only from enclosed areas free from sources of vapor ignition",opc:"from the open deck",opd:"from within the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"When inclined to an angle of list, the value of the righting arm is ____________.",opa:"negative",opb:"zero",opc:"positive",opd:"maximum",ans:"opb"},{question:"At a refueling area or fuel facility, smoking or any flame or spark is prohibited ____________.",opa:"within 50 feet",opb:"anywhere on the helodeck",opc:"during refueling operations",opd:"within 100 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"In a semisubmersible MODU, the columns contain void spaces above the waterline that used principally for ____________.",opa:"equipment storage",opb:"machinery",opc:"elevators",opd:"reserve buoyancy",ans:"opd"},{question:"You wish to communicate by radiotelephone with a foreign vessel using the International Code of Signals. This is indicated by the signal ____________.",opa:"'Charlie Quebec'",opb:"'Code'",opc:"'Kilo'",opd:"'Interco'",ans:"opd"},{question:"A deck-stowed 40-foot container is giving off smoke, and one end is discolored from heat. The cargo is valuable and easily damaged by water. You want to extinguish the fire without further damage if possible. What action should you take?",opa:"Connect a portable line from the ship's fixed system and discharge CO2 into the container.",opb:"Flood the container with water and disregard any cargo damage as the fire threatens the entire vessel.",opc:"Pierce the container and discharge 6 or more portable CO2's then add more CO2 hourly.",opd:"Cool the exterior of the container with water and close all vents; then keep it cooled until it can be off-loaded.",ans:"opc"},{question:"While operating off the coast of Portugal, a seaman is injured. What indicator should be used in a message requesting medical advice from a Portuguese station?",opa:"MEDICAL RADIO",opb:"DH MEDICO",opc:"XXX RADIOMEDICAL",opd:"PORT HEALTH",ans:"opc"},{question:"Due to the hazards involved with Halon extinguishers on a MODU, the size II extinguisher may only be used ____________.",opa:"outside",opb:"on class C fires",opc:"in an emergency",opd:"on class B fires",ans:"opa"},{question:"Outlets in gasoline fuel lines are ____________.",opa:"permitted for drawing fuel samples",opb:"permitted for draining fuel from lines",opc:"permitted for bleeding air from lines",opd:"prohibited",ans:"opd"},{question:"The height of the metacenter above the keel will vary depending on the ____________.",opa:"draft and beam of the drilling unit",opb:"displacement and deadweight of the drilling unit",opc:"buoyancy and trim of the drilling unit",opd:"tonnage and deadweight of the drilling unit",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 4700 tons of cargo, 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 323 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in fresh water.",opa:"19'-00'",opb:"19'-03'",opc:"19'-07'",opd:"20'-01'",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning an inflatable liferaft?",opa:"The floor may be inflated for insulation from cold water.",opb:"Crew members may jump into the raft without damaging it.",opc:"The raft may be boarded before it is fully inflated.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The best treatment for preventing traumatic shock after an accident is to ____________.",opa:"have the victim exercise to increase circulation",opb:"keep the victim from electrical equipment",opc:"keep the victim warm and dry while lying down",opd:"apply ice packs and avoid excitement",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the meter needle of the oxygen indicator cannot be set to zero, what should be done?",opa:"Replace the batteries.",opb:"Check the sampling tube for blockage.",opc:"Adjust the final reading by the amount the needle is displaced from zero.",opd:"Replace the platinum filament.",ans:"opa"},{question:"After a report of casualty to a mobile offshore drilling unit, what record must be kept onboard?",opa:"The Oil Record Book",opb:"The crane record book",opc:"All chart catalogs",opd:"The machinery maintenance logbook",ans:"opb"},{question:"For a floating MODU, the center of buoyancy and the metacenter are in the line of action of the buoyant force ____________.",opa:"only when there is positive stability",opb:"only when there is negative stability",opc:"only when there is neutral stability",opd:"at all times",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is part of a vessel's standing rigging?",opa:"Sheet",opb:"Backstay",opc:"Topping lift",opd:"Downhaul",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the DEEP DRILLER, among the starboard-side valves to open when deballasting from ballast tank 2S is valve ____________.",opa:"3",opb:"5",opc:"6",opd:"7",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are operating a liftboat. When beginning to jack down you should ____________.",opa:"jack down one leg at a time",opb:"jack up first, then down",opc:"undog doors to the engine room",opd:"assemble all personnel on the main deck",ans:"opb"},{question:"Diesel engines are considered safer than gasoline engines because ____________.",opa:"they are more heavily built",opb:"the fuel used is less volatile",opc:"they can be easily reversed",opd:"they operate at a lower speed",ans:"opb"},{question:"Of the required ring life buoys for a MODU, how many must be equipped with a water light?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"4",opd:"8",ans:"opc"},{question:"Who is responsible for lowering the survival craft?",opa:"Roustabout",opb:"First man aboard",opc:"Last man aboard",opd:"Helmsman",ans:"opd"},{question:"The water in which a vessel floats provides vertical upward support. The point through which this support is assumed to act is known as the center of ____________.",opa:"effort",opb:"flotation",opc:"gravity",opd:"buoyancy",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which maintenance functions can a GMDSS Radio Operator perform?",opa:"The Operator can make fine internal adjustments to the transmitter as long as the output power does not change by more than one percent.",opb:"The Operator is responsible for ensuring that INMARSAT antennas are free of built-up soot and clear of obstacles.",opc:"All levels of maintenance must be performed by a licensed GMDSS Radio Maintainer.",opd:"The Operator may install an EPROM in order to ensure that the equipment continues to operate within legal constraints.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Increasing free surfaces has the effect of raising the ____________.",opa:"uncorrected KG",opb:"virtual height of the center of gravity",opc:"metacenter",opd:"metacentric height",ans:"opb"},{question:"On inspected cargo vessels, each fire station is required to be fitted with a hose which has a nominal diameter of ____________.",opa:"1-1/2 or 2-1/2 inches",opb:"2 or 3 inches",opc:"2-1/2 or 3-1/2 inches",opd:"3 or 4 inches",ans:"opa"},{question:"Regulations require that pumprooms on tank vessels carrying grade C liquid cargo with machinery spaces below the freeboard deck be ventilated with ____________.",opa:"power ventilation",opb:"gooseneck vents and flame screens",opc:"at least two ducts extending to the weather deck",opd:"a vent header system",ans:"opa"},{question:"A continual worsening of the list or trim of any floating MODU indicates ____________.",opa:"negative GM",opb:"progressive flooding",opc:"structural failure",opd:"an immediate need to counter flood",ans:"opb"},{question:"Sixty (60) tons of cargo are raised with a heavy lift boom 45 feet from the centerline. The vessel's displacement including the weight lifted is 18,400 tons. The angle of list caused by the suspended weight is 1.5\xb0, KM is 28.75 ft., and BM is 17.25 ft. What is the KG?",opa:"11.65 feet",opb:"22.85 feet",opc:"23.15 feet",opd:"23.82 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Every U.S. crude oil tankship with a keel laying date on or after 1/1/75, shall be equipped with an inert gas system if the tonnage is more than ____________.",opa:"100,000 DWT (long tons)",opb:"100,000 DWT(metric tons)",opc:"50,000 DWT (long tons)",opd:"50,000 DWT (metric tons)",ans:"opb"},{question:"When giving first aid, you should understand how to conduct primary and secondary surveys and know ____________.",opa:"which medications to prescribe",opb:"how to diagnose an illness from symptoms",opc:"the limits of your capabilities",opd:"how to set broken bones",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel's drafts are: FWD 16'-03', AFT 16'-09'; and the KG is 21.3 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the angle of list if the center of gravity is shifted 2 feet off the centerline.",opa:"12\xb0",opb:"14\xb0",opc:"20\xb0",opd:"22\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"What type of stern tube bearing has the least friction?",opa:"Oil-lubricated bearings",opb:"Lignum vitae",opc:"Hard rubber",opd:"Bronze bushings",ans:"opa"},{question:"How many adult life jackets are required onboard a MODU?",opa:"Enough for 100 percent of the persons allowed onboard",opb:"One for each work station and industrial work site",opc:"Enough for 150 percent of the persons allowed onboard",opd:"Both A & B above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The gross weight of a fully charged CO2 cylinder is 80 lbs. When the bottle is empty it weighs 60 lbs. What is the minimum acceptable gross weight of the CO2 bottle before it should be recharged by the manufacturer?",opa:"55 lbs.",opb:"68 lbs.",opc:"78 lbs.",opd:"82 lbs.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Corrosive liquids and acids should have what kind of label?",opa:"Skull and crossbones",opb:"Yellow",opc:"Red",opd:"White",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which extinguishing agent is most likely to allow reflash as a result of not cooling the fuel below its ignition temperature?",opa:"CO2",opb:"Water stream",opc:"Water spray",opd:"Foam",ans:"opa"},{question:"As shown, the line indicated by number 4 is connected to the ____________.",opa:"releasing gear",opb:"sea painter",opc:"McCluny hook",opd:"Fleming gear",ans:"opc"},{question:"What weight is added when P-tank #4 in the DEEP DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Transit) is completely filled?",opa:"19.54 long tons",opb:"55.71 long tons",opc:"75.25 long tons",opd:"94.79 long tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"While preparing for a storm when elevated, the total weight of the COASTAL DRILLER is 14,150 kips, LM are 1,712,150 ft.-kips, and TM are -9,905 ft.-kips. The starboard leg reaction is ____________.",opa:"4,536 kips",opb:"4,698 kips",opc:"4,725 kips",opd:"4,890 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"After the initial cleaning of flue gas in an inert gas system the gas is passed through what device for final cleaning?",opa:"Scrubber",opb:"Demister",opc:"Deck water seal",opd:"Final filter",ans:"opb"},{question:"The canopy of an inflatable liferaft should ____________.",opa:"go into place as the raft is inflated",opb:"be put up after everyone is aboard",opc:"be put up only in severe weather",opd:"be used as a sail if the wind is blowing",ans:"opa"},{question:"While going on location in 200 feet water depth when the roll angle of the COASTAL DRILLER is 2.5 degrees, the roll period should be longer than ____________.",opa:"0.8 second",opb:"6.2 seconds",opc:"13.0 seconds",opd:"17.0 seconds",ans:"opc"},{question:"Compared to the amount of concentrated foam liquid used, the amount of low expansion mechanical foam produced is ____________.",opa:"97 times greater",opb:"94 times greater",opc:"10 times greater",opd:"2 times greater",ans:"opc"},{question:"The upward pressure of displaced water is called ____________.",opa:"buoyancy",opb:"deadweight",opc:"draft",opd:"freeboard",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 24'-07', AFT 25'-09'; and the KG is 24.0 feet. What is the righting moment when the vessel is inclined to 15\xb0? (Use the selected stability curves in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"5,202 foot-tons",opb:"8,666 foot-tons",opc:"10,876 foot-tons",opd:"11,424 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has 3 lifeboats on each side. The middle boat on the starboard side is designated as boat number ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"2 STARBOARD",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER in transit is level at 23.0 feet draft. Strong winds are blowing from the starboard. A careful load form calculation determines that the TCG is 2.0 feet to starboard. What is the value of the wind heeling moment?",opa:"4,339 foot-long tons",opb:"26,033 foot-long tons",opc:"39,050 foot-long tons",opd:"78,099 foot-long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel heading ESE is on a course of ____________.",opa:"112.5\xb0",opb:"135.0\xb0",opc:"157.5\xb0",opd:"180.0\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which channel has been designated for on-scene communications in GMDSS?",opa:"24",opb:"2187.5",opc:"70",opd:"16 and 2174.5",ans:"opd"},{question:"A MODU displacing 10,000 tons uses its crane to lift a 20 ton load, already aboard, to a height of 5 feet above the deck. When lifting, the head of the crane boom is 50 feet above the load. What is the change in KG?",opa:"No change",opb:"0.1 foot",opc:"0.2 foot",opd:"1.0 foot",ans:"opb"},{question:"On small passenger vessels, shut-off valves must be installed on both gasoline and diesel fuel supply lines ____________.",opa:"at the tank and the engine end of the fuel line",opb:"outside the engineroom on the fill and vent lines",opc:"only at the tank end of the fuel line",opd:"only at the engine end of the fuel line",ans:"opa"},{question:"The muster list shows each rig hand's muster station, his duties during abandonment, basic instructions, and ____________.",opa:"all emergency signals",opb:"instructions for lowering the survival craft",opc:"the time each weekly drill will be held",opd:"work schedule",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on the SS American Mariner and involved in a collision. Your draft has increased uniformly and there is about 4 feet of freeboard remaining. The vessel is on an even keel and has a long rolling period. The roll is sluggish, and the vessel hangs at the ends of a roll. Which of the following actions would you take first to correct the situation?",opa:"Pump out a slack double bottom tank to reduce free surface.",opb:"Flood any empty double bottom tanks to decrease KG.",opc:"Jettison topside weights to increase freeboard.",opd:"Pump out flooding water in the cargo holds to reduce free surface.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The hoist line primarily used for lifting personnel on MODU cranes is called the ____________.",opa:"personnel line",opb:"whip line",opc:"main hoist line",opd:"pendant",ans:"opb"},{question:"The lightweight transverse free surface moments for the DEEP DRILLER are ____________.",opa:"680,914 ft.-long tons",opb:"000 ft.-long tons",opc:"-5,937 ft.-long tons",opd:"-6,716 ft.-long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents a fire alarm panel?",opa:"68",opb:"58",opc:"37",opd:"30",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, elevated in 200 feet of water with 2 knots current, 30 foot waves, and wind speeds of 60 knots may continue drilling if the maximum leg reaction is less than ____________.",opa:"5,700 kips",opb:"5,790 kips",opc:"5,870 kips",opd:"5,990 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which fire control plan symbol will NOT be found in your stateroom?",opa:"30",opb:"39",opc:"59",opd:"60",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 4184 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 27.8 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 25.8 feet",opb:"KG 26.6 feet",opc:"KG 27.2 feet",opd:"KG 28.0 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"During an abandonment or drill, the first person to arrive at the survival craft should ____________.",opa:"pass out food and water to personnel",opb:"open the doors and start the sprinkler system",opc:"activate the emergency release handle",opd:"open the doors and prepare the craft for boarding",ans:"opd"},{question:"In continuous operation, the effective range of the 15 pound CO2 extinguisher is limited to ____________.",opa:"2 to 4 feet",opb:"3 to 8 feet",opc:"9 to 12 feet",opd:"10 to 15 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have abandoned ship and are in charge of a liferaft. How much water per day should you permit each occupant to drink after the first 24 hours?",opa:"1 can",opb:"1 pint",opc:"1 quart",opd:"1 gallon",ans:"opb"},{question:"While preloading, the COASTAL DRILLER has a total weight of 21,401 kips. The LM are 2,560,416 ft.-kips, and the TM are -6,206 ft.-kips. What is the port leg reaction?",opa:"7,099 kips",opb:"7,134 kips",opc:"7,151 kips",opd:"7,203 kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each emergency light on a MODU must be marked with ____________.",opa:"the letter 'E'",opb:"an arrow pointing to the nearest exit",opc:"a no-smoking symbol",opd:"the word 'DANGER'",ans:"opa"},{question:"When discharging a portable CO2 fire extinguisher, you should NOT hold the horn of the extinguisher because the horn ____________.",opa:"becomes extremely hot",opb:"becomes extremely cold",opc:"could come off in your hands",opd:"is placed directly in the flames",ans:"opb"},{question:"Where can GMDSS regulations pertaining specifically to U.S.-flag vessels be found?",opa:"These are located in CCIR #476.",opb:"These are located in FCC Part 83.",opc:"These are published only by the U.S. Coast Guard.",opd:"These are located in 47 CFR Part 80.",ans:"opd"},{question:"When displacement increases, the free surface corrections for slack tanks ____________.",opa:"increase",opb:"decrease",opc:"are directly proportional",opd:"remain unchanged",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the sample load form #3 (drilling), the hook load is placed in the pipe racks. What would be the new variable load?",opa:"2,381.0 kips",opb:"3,381.0 kips",opc:"3,658.8 kips",opd:"4,381.0 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"While preparing for a storm when elevated, the total weight of the COASTAL DRILLER is 14,150 kips, LM are 1,712,150 ft.-kips, and TM are -9,905 ft.-kips. The bow leg reaction is ____________.",opa:"4,536 kips",opb:"4,716 kips",opc:"4,748 kips",opd:"4,866 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"Upon hearing the abandon ship signal, you put on your life jacket and report to your station. After the cover is removed you board your open lifeboat. The FIRST thing to do is to ____________.",opa:"release the gripes",opb:"release tricing pendants",opc:"put the cap on the drain",opd:"lift the brake handle",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your voyage planning indicates you will arrive at a waypoint in longitude 149\xb016.3'W at 0947 ZT on 3 March 1988. How should this date be entered into an AMVER report?",opa:"030947W",opb:"031947Z",opc:"031947 88",opd:"03MAR1947Z",ans:"opb"},{question:"Lifeboat winches on mobile offshore drilling units are required to be inspected and an entry made in the logbook. How often should this entry be made?",opa:"Every 3 months",opb:"Every 6 months",opc:"Every year",opd:"Only after conducting a boat drill",ans:"opa"},{question:"The painter which is to be attached to the thwart of a lifeboat should ____________.",opa:"be fitted at the end with an approved safety shackle",opb:"have a long eye splice at the end, and a shackle and pin should be attached to the painter with a lanyard",opc:"have a long eye splice at the end, and a hardwood toggle should be attached to the thwart with a lanyard",opd:"be fitted with a swivel and quick-releasing pelican hook",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 560 tons. The existing deck cargo has a center of gravity of 4.5 feet above the deck and weighs 34 tons. If you load 10 tons of ground tackle with an estimated center of gravity of 2.8 feet above the deck, what is the final height of the CG of the deck cargo?",opa:"4.11 feet",opb:"4.36 feet",opc:"4.57 feet",opd:"4.78 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the COASTAL DRILLER is properly preloaded, each of the leg reactions should be ____________.",opa:"7,200 kips",opb:"7,099 kips",opc:"4,720 kips",opd:"3,381 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is on a voyage of three months duration. The number of sanitary inspections required is ____________.",opa:"one",opb:"three",opc:"six",opd:"twelve",ans:"opa"},{question:"Using a sea anchor will ____________.",opa:"reduce the drift rate of the liferaft",opb:"keep the liferaft from turning over",opc:"aid in recovering the liferaft",opd:"increase your visibility",ans:"opa"},{question:"If there are no alternatives for escape, what is the maximum height that the survival craft could be dropped into the water?",opa:"2 ft.",opb:"6 ft.",opc:"10 ft.",opd:"14 ft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Compliance with the terms of the load line certificate on a MODU is the responsibility of the ____________.",opa:"Ballast Control Operator",opb:"Barge Supervisor",opc:"Master or Offshore Installation Manager",opd:"operators representative",ans:"opc"},{question:"Use the floodable length curve in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the curve represents 45 percent permeability and number 1 hold floods, the vessel will sink if the permeability exceeds what percent?",opa:"63",opb:"66",opc:"71",opd:"77",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which procedure should be followed when individuals are rescued in cold climates and suffer from hypothermia?",opa:"Give them brandy or other alcoholic stimulation to promote a return to an acceptable body temperature.",opb:"Move them to a warm room to gradually raise their body temperature.",opc:"Keep them moving to stimulate circulation to raise their body temperature.",opd:"Warm them under an electric blanket to rapidly regain normal body temperature.",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the regulations, cargo pumprooms on tank vessels (constructed in 1965) handling grade C liquid cargo shall have power ventilation systems which can completely change the air in ____________.",opa:"1 minute",opb:"3 minutes",opc:"5 minutes",opd:"10 minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, 1,3 -pentadiene possesses which characteristic?",opa:"Colorless liquid, mild aromatic odor",opb:"Pale yellow liquid, strong odor",opc:"Colorless liquid, faint odor",opd:"Straw-colored liquid, sweet-odor",ans:"opc"},{question:"To turn over an inflatable liferaft that is upside down, you should pull on the ____________.",opa:"canopy",opb:"manropes",opc:"sea painter",opd:"righting strap",ans:"opd"},{question:"If your vessel has a GM of one foot and a breadth of 50 feet, what is your vessel's estimated rolling period?",opa:"11 seconds",opb:"15 seconds",opc:"20 seconds",opd:"22 seconds",ans:"opd"},{question:"It is proposed to moor the DEEP DRILLER in 600 feet of water in a region in which the effective wind velocity could reach 80 knots, significant wave height could reach 30 feet, and the current could be 1.5 knots. If these conditions occurred at the same time from the beam, the total environmental force would be ____________.",opa:"620 kips",opb:"595 kips",opc:"475 kips",opd:"425 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 4700 tons of cargo 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 323 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in salt water.",opa:"19'-00'",opb:"19'-04'",opc:"19'-09'",opd:"20'-01'",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement concerning GMDSS distress alerts is TRUE?",opa:"Information contained in a distress alert includes the name and position of the distressed vessel, and may include additional information such as the nature of the situation and what kind of assistance that may be required.",opb:"Distress alerts may be used to alert other vessels, including those in port, of existing navigational hazards.",opc:"Distress alerts may be used to alert other vessels, including those in port, of existing weather warnings.",opd:"A vessel in the vicinity of a distress situation may leave the area without notifying the RCC that is overseeing the operation.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 6422 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 26.6 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 24.9 feet",opb:"KG 25.5 feet",opc:"KG 26.1 feet",opd:"KG 28.9 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"While loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #5 (Survival), an estimated 250 long tons of snow and ice accumulates on the DEEP DRILLER at an estimated height of 127 feet. Assuming no corrective ballasting, what is the new height of the center of gravity corrected for longitudinal free surface effects?",opa:"58.78 feet",opb:"60.68 feet",opc:"61.53 feet",opd:"62.78 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"On small passenger vessels, when may a flexible hose be used in gasoline or diesel fuel lines?",opa:"In diesel installations only",opb:"In gasoline installations only",opc:"In both diesel and gasoline installations",opd:"In neither diesel nor gasoline installations",ans:"opc"},{question:"Assuming that the recommended hatch loading sequence is followed, how many long tons of iron ore may be loaded through hatch No. 20 while using a single belt loader to arrive at a desired mean keel draft of 24'-10'? (Use the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN.)",opa:"1540 tons",opb:"1590 tons",opc:"1645 tons",opd:"1670 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using high working tensions in the mooring system reduces the ____________.",opa:"hook load at drilling depths over 10,000 feet",opb:"possibility of dragging anchors",opc:"allowable deck load at operating draft",opd:"margin between working tension and breaking strength",ans:"opd"},{question:"The quickest method to stop a small diesel engine whose throttle or governor has become stuck open is to ____________.",opa:"drain the fuel tank",opb:"turn off the ignition switch",opc:"close the fuel supply valve",opd:"apply the shaft brake",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a davit-launched raft is lowered from a MODU, upon becoming waterborne, the raft is released by ____________.",opa:"activating the release lock of the hook",opb:"pulling smartly on the knobbed cocking lanyard",opc:"the effects of buoyancy removing the weight of the raft from the hook",opd:"releasing the boarding flap and the bowsing lines",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your tow includes a loaded chlorine barge. After inspecting the tow, the mate reports that he hears a hissing sound coming from the safety valves. Where will you find information on emergency procedures concerning the uncontrolled release of cargo?",opa:"Barge's Certificate of Inspection",opb:"Cargo Information Card on your towboat",opc:"Cargo Manifest or loading paper",opd:"Dangerous Cargo Regulations",ans:"opb"},{question:"A shepherd's crook is used to ____________.",opa:"lower spring buoys into the water",opb:"find an anchor after the buoy has been lost",opc:"transfer a pennant wire to the anchor handling boat",opd:"clean chain as it is hauled into the rig",ans:"opb"},{question:"What represents the center of gravity?",opa:"GZ",opb:"M",opc:"B",opd:"G",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should the number '7' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"SAY-TAY-SEVEN",opb:"SEE-ETA-SEVEN",opc:"NUM-BER-SEVEN",opd:"NEW-MER-AL-SEVEN",ans:"opa"},{question:"Physical exertion on the part of a person who has fallen into cold water would ____________.",opa:"be the best thing to try if there was no rescue in sight",opb:"increase survival time in the water",opc:"increase the rate of heat loss from the body",opd:"not affect the heat loss from the body",ans:"opc"},{question:"While in ocean transit at a draft of 10 feet, the Coastal Driller has a maximum allowed KG of ____________.",opa:"42 feet",opb:"44 feet",opc:"65 feet",opd:"70 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Why is it necessary to extend ventilators of gasoline powered vessels to the bilges?",opa:"To keep them dry, and thus easier to clean",opb:"To remove fuel vapors which are heavier than air",opc:"To provide adequate air to the engines",opd:"To cool the machinery areas",ans:"opb"},{question:"A semisubmersible, 200 feet in length between draft marks with the LCF 10 feet aft of amidships, records the following drafts: Port Forward 74'-09'; Port Aft 78'-09'; Starboard Forward 69'-09'; and Starboard Aft 73'-09'. What is the list?",opa:"-1.0 foot",opb:"-2.5 feet",opc:"-5.0 feet",opd:"-10.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The term, 'cargo tank length', as used in part 157 of the Pollution Regulations, means the ____________.",opa:"length of any individual cargo space, from bulkhead to bulkhead",opb:"greatest distance between two opposite cargo tank bulkheads",opc:"diagonal measurement of a cargo tank",opd:"length from the forward bulkhead of the forward most cargo tanks to the after bulkhead of the aftermost cargo tanks",ans:"opd"},{question:"What publication/s should a GMDSS Operator consult regarding the proper set-up and operation of vessel equipment?",opa:"ITU Publications",opb:"The manufacturers instruction manuals",opc:"Part 90 of the FCC Rules and Regulations",opd:"Code of Federal Regulations, Title 47, Part 80, Subpart W`",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has a displacement of 24,500 tons. It is 529 feet long and has a beam of 71 feet. You have timed your vessel's rolling period to be 25.0 seconds. What is your vessel's approximate GM?",opa:"1.25 feet",opb:"1.56 feet",opc:"1.98 feet",opd:"2.43 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which is TRUE of a 'stiff' vessel?",opa:"It has a small GM.",opb:"It pitches heavily.",opc:"It has an unusually high center of gravity.",opd:"Its period of roll is short.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The 'trimming arm' of a vessel is the horizontal distance between the ____________.",opa:"LCB and LCF",opb:"LCF and LCG",opc:"LHA and LCG",opd:"LCB and LCG",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are at sea and have received a General Emergency message announcing the outbreak of war in Europe. You are directed to comply with the instructions in NGA (NIMA) PUB 117, Chapter eight. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"If on a coastwise voyage along the east coast of the U.S., you should put into the nearest port.",opb:"You should only enter a port in the danger zone during hours of darkness.",opc:"When over 200 hundred miles from a port in the danger zone, you should not darken ship.",opd:"You should attempt to submit an AMVER report to NSA.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement concerning immersion suits is TRUE?",opa:"Immersion suits should be worn while performing routine work on deck.",opb:"After purchasing, the suit should be stowed in the storage bag in which it was received.",opc:"During the annual maintenance, the front zipper should be lubricated using light machine oil or mineral oil.",opd:"Any tear or leak will render the suit unserviceable and it must be replaced.",ans:"opb"},{question:"You can slow or stop a sailing vessel by ____________.",opa:"put the wind off the beam and sheet in",opb:"put the wind off the stern and ease all sheets",opc:"bring the vessel's head into the wind and let the sails luff",opd:"raise the centerboard when running before the wind",ans:"opc"},{question:"A ship is inclined by moving a weight of 30 tons a distance of 30 ft. from the centerline. A 28-foot pendulum shows a deflection of 12 inches. Displacement including weight moved is 4,000 tons. KM is 27.64 feet. What is the KG?",opa:"21.34 feet",opb:"22.06 feet",opc:"22.76 feet",opd:"23.21 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Where would you find a list of the lifesaving equipment onboard your supply boat?",opa:"Ship's Articles",opb:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"U.S. Coast Guard Regulations",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a mobile offshore drilling rig has four hand portable fire extinguishers that can be recharged by personnel on the unit, how many spare charges must be carried?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"A report of casualty to a mobile offshore drilling unit must include ____________.",opa:"the estimated cost of damage to the unit",opb:"an evaluation of who was at fault",opc:"the amount of ballast onboard",opd:"the name of the owner or agent of the unit",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 3.2 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.9 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.8 ft.",opd:"Available GM 5.3 ft.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 40,301 foot-long tons, TM = 3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons. What is TCG?",opa:"0.00 feet",opb:"1.03 feet",opc:"2.22 feet",opd:"3.91 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"After launching, an inflatable raft should be kept dry inside by ____________.",opa:"opening the automatic drain plugs",opb:"draining the water pockets",opc:"using the electric bilge pump",opd:"using the bailers and cellulose sponge",ans:"opd"},{question:"In the DEEP DRILLER, the transverse free surface correction (FSCT) is obtained from the total of transverse free surface moments (FSMT) by ____________.",opa:"adding the TCG",opb:"subtracting the TCG",opc:"multiplying by displacement",opd:"dividing by displacement",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are approaching another vessel and see that it has the signal flag 'O' hoisted. What is your next action?",opa:"Proceed on present course and speed since the vessel is requesting a pilot.",opb:"Attempt to call the vessel on VHF radiotelephone and begin a search because the vessel has a man overboard.",opc:"Attempt to call the vessel on VHF radiotelephone because it is disabled.",opd:"Approach with caution because the vessel is stopped and making no way through the water.",ans:"opb"},{question:"When filling fuel-oil tank 6P on the DEEP DRILLER, it is necessary to open valve ____________.",opa:"9",opb:"10",opc:"11",opd:"12",ans:"opd"},{question:"On the DEEP DRILLER, among the valves to open when transferring ballast from Tank 1S to Tank 10P using the #1 ballast pump is valve ____________.",opa:"33 Starboard",opb:"44 Starboard",opc:"33 Port",opd:"44 Port",ans:"opc"},{question:"Longitudinal moment is obtained by multiplying a vessel's weight and its ____________.",opa:"VCG or KG",opb:"LCB",opc:"LCG",opd:"TCG",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which fire control plan symbol represents the agent or device best suited for extinguishing a class 'A' fire?",opa:"56",opb:"47",opc:"36",opd:"26",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, to what chemical family does 1,3 -pentadiene belong?",opa:"Unsaturated hydrocarbons",opb:"Esters",opc:"Phosphorus",opd:"Olefins",ans:"opd"},{question:"The abandon ship signal on the ship's whistle is ____________.",opa:"6 short blasts and 1 long blast",opb:"more than 6 short blasts",opc:"more than 6 short blasts and 1 long blast",opd:"1 long blast of at least 10 seconds",ans:"opc"},{question:"What equipment must be on a life float? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Two paddles, a light, painter, lifeline and pendants",opb:"Water-light, painter, and signal mirror",opc:"Water-light and painter only",opd:"Two paddles, painter, and six red flares",ans:"opa"},{question:"Provided every effort is used to produce, as well as preserve body moisture content by avoiding perspiration, how long is it normally possible to survive without stored quantities of water?",opa:"Up to 3 days",opb:"8 to 14 days",opc:"15 to 20 days",opd:"25 to 30 days",ans:"opb"},{question:"In the small passenger vessel regulations a coastwise route is defined as one that is ____________.",opa:"not more than 50 statute miles from shore in the Gulf of Mexico",opb:"on ocean waters more than 200 nautical miles from shore in the Gulf of Alaska",opc:"not more than 20 statute miles from the nearest safe harbor in the Pacific Ocean",opd:"not more than 20 nautical miles offshore in the ocean",ans:"opd"},{question:"The deck water seal of the inert gas system ____________.",opa:"cools the inert gas and prevents soot from entering the cargo tanks",opb:"acts as an emergency system shutdown when the inlet pressures exceed the safe working pressure in the hazardous zone",opc:"prevents the backflow of hydrocarbon gasses into nonhazardous areas",opd:"relieves sudden large overpressures in the system",ans:"opc"},{question:"While loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #5 (Survival), an estimated 250 long tons of snow and ice accumulates on the DEEP DRILLER at an estimated height of 127 feet. Assuming no corrective ballasting, what is the new draft?",opa:"48'-06'",opb:"47'-03 1/2'",opc:"46'-09 3/4'",opd:"44'-06'",ans:"opc"},{question:"Using the Guidance Manual for Loading the M.V. Grand Haven, determine the amount of ballast required in tank No. 1 (P&S) to maintain drafts of 17'-00' forward and 22'-06' aft for a vessel loaded with grain which has a test weight of 43 lbs.",opa:"23 tons each",opb:"50 tons each",opc:"75 tons each",opd:"150 tons each",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the penalty for failure to enforce, or comply with, the vessel bridge-to-bridge radiotelephone regulations?",opa:"Civil penalty of no more than $650",opb:"Civil penalty of no more than $5,000",opc:"$5,000 fine and imprisonment for not more than one year, or both",opd:"$1,000 fine or imprisonment for not more than two years",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged and is listing to port. The rolling period is short. There is sufficient freeboard so that deck edge submersion is not a problem. What corrective action should be taken FIRST in regard to the vessel's stability?",opa:"Press up any slack double-bottom tanks to eliminate free surface",opb:"Flood any empty double-bottom tanks to add weight low and down",opc:"Jettison topside weights to reduce KG and KB",opd:"Shift any off-center weights from port to starboard",ans:"opd"},{question:"If your bridge-to-bridge radiotelephone ceases to operate, you must ____________.",opa:"immediately anchor your vessel and arrange for repairs to the system",opb:"moor your vessel at the nearest dock available and arrange for repairs to the system",opc:"arrange for the repair of the system to be completed within 48 hours",opd:"exercise due diligence to restore the system at the earliest practicable time",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you use obscene, indecent, or profane language over the radiotelephone, you can be ____________.",opa:"assessed a fine of up to $5,000, imprisonment of up to three years, or both",opb:"assessed a fine not to exceed $11,000, imprisonment of not more than two years, or both",opc:"assessed a fine not to exceed $20,000",opd:"imprisoned up to five years",ans:"opb"},{question:"Most large anchors are manufactured with a ____________.",opa:"bow type shackle",opb:"D-type shackle",opc:"U-type shackle",opd:"Kenter shackle",ans:"opb"},{question:"Where should a tank barge's Certificate of Inspection be kept?",opa:"In the owner's office",opb:"In the operator's office",opc:"On the barge",opd:"On the towboat",ans:"opc"},{question:"Fusible-link fire dampers are operated by ____________.",opa:"a mechanical arm outside the vent duct",opb:"the heat of a fire melting the link",opc:"electrical controls on the bridge",opd:"a break-glass and pull-cable system",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is in transit at the load line draft. It discharges 279.93 kips of weight. The new draft is ____________.",opa:"10.88 feet",opb:"10.8 feet",opc:"10.0 feet",opd:"10 feet 8 inches",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the minimum required number of ring life buoys on a MODU?",opa:"4",opb:"8",opc:"12",opd:"16",ans:"opb"},{question:"The pollution prevention regulations in MARPOL apply to U. S. flag vessels ____________.",opa:"only on the Great Lakes and international waters",opb:"only on the western rivers and international waters",opc:"only on international voyages outside U.S. territorial waters",opd:"on all international and inland waters",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are communicating by radiotelephone using the International Code of Signals. What is the correct method of sending the group 1.3?",opa:"'Wun point tree'",opb:"'Unaone point tercetree'",opc:"'Unaone decimal terrathree'",opd:"'One decimal three'",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement about AMVER reports is TRUE?",opa:"The sailing plan may be sent in any reasonable time before departure, but not later than 12 hours after departure.",opb:"Distress messages should be sent to the AMVER center.",opc:"In the body of the sailing plan report, the letter G is used to indicate a great circle course.",opd:"There are four different message reports in the AMVER system.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 27'-06', AFT 28'-02'; and the KG is 23.1 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 37\xb0 inclination if the center of gravity is 1.8 feet off center.",opa:"0.4 foot",opb:"1.4 feet",opc:"1.8 feet",opd:"2.6 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a vessel carrying grades A, B, C or D cargoes, enclosed spaces where sources of vapor ignition are normally present shall NOT be segregated from cargo tanks by ____________. (vessel constructed after 1970)",opa:"cofferdams",opb:"galleys",opc:"pump rooms",opd:"tanks used to carry liquids having a flash point of 150\xb0F or above",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many B-II fire extinguishers must be in the machinery space of a 75-foot long fishing vessel propelled by engines with 1200 brake horsepower?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are reading the draft marks in illustration D032DG. The water level is at the top of number 8. What is the draft?",opa:"7'-09'",opb:"8'-00'",opc:"8'-03'",opd:"8'-06'",ans:"opd"},{question:"The sails are properly set and trimmed. As a vessel heads up from a beam reach to close hauled the ____________.",opa:"true wind velocity increases",opb:"heeling moment decreases",opc:"side slip decreases",opd:"jib sheet must be hardened up",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel has a strong wind on the port beam. This has the same effect on stability as ____________.",opa:"weight that is off-center to starboard",opb:"increasing the draft",opc:"reducing the freeboard",opd:"increasing the trim",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are reading the draft marks as shown. The water level forward leaves about 4 inches of the 11 visible, and the water level aft is at the top of the 10. What is the mean draft?",opa:"10'-06'",opb:"10'-08'",opc:"10'-10'",opd:"11'-02'",ans:"opc"},{question:"Yawing can be described as ____________.",opa:"jumping on the tow line as the rig pitches",opb:"jumping on the tow line as the rig slams into waves",opc:"veering from side to side on the end of the tow line",opd:"corkscrew motion due to wave action",ans:"opc"},{question:"If your passenger vessel is fitted with a loudspeaker system, it must be tested at least once ____________.",opa:"every week",opb:"a day",opc:"every trip",opd:"a watch or once a trip, whichever is shorter",ans:"opa"},{question:"Refer to the illustration D001SA. Which represents the righting arm?",opa:"GM",opb:"GZ",opc:"BM",opd:"Angle MGZ",ans:"opb"},{question:"The most effective extinguishing action of dry chemical is ____________.",opa:"breaking the chain reaction",opb:"the CO2 that is formed by heat",opc:"smothering",opd:"shielding of radiant heat",ans:"opa"},{question:"A vessel is inclined at an angle of loll. In the absence of external forces, the righting arm (GZ) is ____________.",opa:"positive",opb:"negative",opc:"zero",opd:"vertical",ans:"opc"},{question:"As shown, a frapping line is indicated by number ____________.",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a tank vessel, each high level alarm and tank overfill alarm must be tested ____________.",opa:"no earlier than 24 hours prior to loading",opb:"no later than 24 hours prior to loading",opc:"anytime prior to loading",opd:"weekly",ans:"opa"},{question:"The authority to grant an alternate procedure for oil transfer operations rests with the ____________.",opa:"nearest Coast Guard office",opb:"Officer-in-Charge, Marine Inspection",opc:"Area Commander",opd:"Captain of the Port",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 60 feet, has 50,000 ft.-tons of longitudinal moments. How much ballast should be transferred between tanks 1P and 10P to level the unit longitudinally?",opa:"45.3 long tons",opb:"90.6 long tons",opc:"118.1 long tons",opd:"236.1 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"All life jackets and life buoys shall be marked with the vessel's name in letters at least ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"1/2 inch high",opb:"1 inch high",opc:"Height not specified",opd:"1-1/2 inches high",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to 46 CFR Subchapter T, where practicable carburetor drip collectors should drain to ____________.",opa:"the engine air intakes",opb:"the fuel tanks",opc:"a separate pipe leading to the bilges",opd:"a suitable absorbent material",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which U.S. agency issues a Certificate of Financial Responsibility?",opa:"Environmental Protection Agency",opb:"Coast Guard",opc:"Corps of Engineers",opd:"Maritime Administration",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 24'-09', AFT 27'-02'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessels displacement if you are in fresh water.",opa:"13,075 tons",opb:"13,350 tons",opc:"13,590 tons",opd:"13,700 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"What must be provided on a MODU helicopter deck that is equipped with fueling facilities?",opa:"Fuel testing station",opb:"Foam testing station",opc:"Foam fire protection system",opd:"Fire alarm",ans:"opc"},{question:"At the required fire drill conducted aboard a MODU, all persons must report to their stations and demonstrate their ability to perform the duties assigned to them ____________.",opa:"by the toolpusher",opb:"in the Muster List ('Station Bill')",opc:"by the person conducting the drill",opd:"at the previous safety meeting",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning life jackets which are severely damaged?",opa:"They should be replaced.",opb:"They must be tested for buoyancy before being continued in use.",opc:"They can be repaired by a reliable seamstress.",opd:"They can be used for children.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which vessel(s) is(are) required to comply with the 'Vessel Bridge-to-Bridge Radiotelephone Regulations' while navigating?",opa:"Towing vessels 25 feet or less in length, engaged in towing operations",opb:"Passenger vessel 50 gross tons or less, carrying passengers for hire",opc:"Dredges engaged in operations likely to restrict navigation of other vessels in or near a channel or fairway",opd:"An intermittently manned floating plant under the control of a dredge",ans:"opc"},{question:"The edge of the sail labeled 'A' is called the ____________.",opa:"leech",opb:"clew",opc:"luff",opd:"headboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement about the use of portable electric lights in petroleum product tanks is TRUE?",opa:"The fixture must be explosion-proof and the line must have a ground wire.",opb:"They can be used only when the compartment is gas free.",opc:"They must be explosion-proof, self-contained, battery-fed lamps.",opd:"No portable electric equipment of any type is allowed.",ans:"opc"},{question:"After using a CO2 extinguisher on a MODU, it should be ____________.",opa:"put back in service if some CO2 remains",opb:"hydrostatically tested",opc:"retagged",opd:"recharged",ans:"opd"},{question:"CO2 cylinders forming part of a fixed fire extinguishing system must be pressure tested at least every ____________.",opa:"year",opb:"2 years",opc:"6 years",opd:"12 years",ans:"opd"},{question:"An uncontrolled flow of gas, oil, or other well fluids into the atmosphere is called a ____________.",opa:"flow",opb:"breakout",opc:"kick",opd:"blowout",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the minimum number of deck officers, able seaman or certificated persons required to command each lifeboat on a vessel in ocean service?",opa:"Two",opb:"Three",opc:"Four",opd:"Five",ans:"opa"},{question:"One gallon of low expansion foam solution will produce about ____________.",opa:"10 gallons of foam",opb:"25 gallons of foam",opc:"100 gallons of foam",opd:"500 gallons of foam",ans:"opa"},{question:"An inclined semisubmersible with a very short rolling period about a constant angle of list is likely to have ____________.",opa:"an off-center TCG",opb:"an LCG greater than level vessel LCB",opc:"a negative GM",opd:"excessive free surfaces",ans:"opa"},{question:"Towing vessel fire protection regulations require that all fuel tank vent pipes comply with all of the following provisions EXCEPT that the vent ____________.",opa:"connects to the highest point of the tank",opb:"system discharges on a weather deck through a U-shaped 180 degree pipe bend",opc:"be fitted with a 30-by-30 corrosion resistant flame screen",opd:"must have a positive-acting shut-off valve to prevent water from entering the tank in heavy weather",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your voyage planning indicates you will arrive at a waypoint in longitude 49\xb016.3 W at 0947 ZT on 3 March 1988. How should this date be entered into an AMVER report?",opa:"031247Z",opb:"030947P",opc:"124733 MAR",opd:"309473",ans:"opa"},{question:"An immersion suit must be equipped with a/an ____________.",opa:"air bottle for breathing",opb:"orange smoke canister",opc:"whistle, light and retro reflective material",opd:"sea dye marker",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should the number '4' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"QUAD-ROS-FOOR",opb:"NUM-ERL-FOUR",opc:"NUMB-ER-FOWER",opd:"KAR-TAY-FOWER",ans:"opd"},{question:"An inflatable liferaft is floating in its container, attached to the ship by its painter, as the ship is sinking rapidly. Which action should be taken with respect to the liferaft container?",opa:"Cut the painter line so that it will not pull the liferaft container down.",opb:"Swim away from the container so that you will not be in danger as it goes down.",opc:"Take no action as the pull on the painter will cause the liferaft to inflate and open the container.",opd:"Manually open the container and inflate the liferaft with the hand pump.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel measures 125 feet long by 17 feet in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 7'-09' is 6 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"0.95 foot",opb:"1.25 feet",opc:"1.55 feet",opd:"1.78 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"7.9 feet",opb:"7.3 feet",opc:"6.4 feet",opd:"4.3 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A locker with additional protective clothing can be found in what location designated by this symbol on the ship\u2019s fire control plan?",opa:"30",opb:"58",opc:"59",opd:"60",ans:"opd"},{question:"Flammable liquids should have what kind of label?",opa:"Skull and crossbones",opb:"Yellow",opc:"Red",opd:"White",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a vessel violates the oil pollution laws, who may be held responsible?",opa:"Master only",opb:"Owners only",opc:"Licensed officers only",opd:"Any individual connected with the vessel involved in the operation",ans:"opd"},{question:"All of the following are recognized distress signals under the Navigation Rules EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"a green star signal",opb:"orange-colored smoke",opc:"red flares",opd:"the repeated raising and lowering of outstretched arms",ans:"opa"},{question:"Use the material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the KG is 24.0 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 28'-01', AFT 28'-06'; at what angle will the vessel lose positive stability?",opa:"64\xb0",opb:"71\xb0",opc:"77\xb0",opd:"82\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"Among the valves that must be opened on the DEEP DRILLER to pump bilge water out of the port pump room using the #1 bilge pump is valve ____________.",opa:"28",opb:"36",opc:"41",opd:"42",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a vessel's LCG is aft of her LCB, the vessel will ____________.",opa:"trim by the stern",opb:"trim by the head",opc:"be on an even keel",opd:"be tender",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the most vulnerable part of the fire main system onboard an offshore rig?",opa:"The fire pump",opb:"Exposed hard piping",opc:"The hydrant valve",opd:"The fire hose",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to the regulations for small passenger vessels, fuses and circuit breakers are used in electrical circuits to ____________.",opa:"keep equipment from shutting off unexpectedly",opb:"prevent voltage fluctuations",opc:"keep the circuit from becoming overloaded or overheated",opd:"make the operator inspect his wiring periodically after the fuses blow",ans:"opc"},{question:"In setting the valves on a steam-smothering system on a tank vessel, the master control valve to cargo tanks should be ____________.",opa:"open and individual tank valves open",opb:"open and the individual tank valves closed",opc:"closed and the individual tank valves closed",opd:"closed and the individual tank valves open",ans:"opd"},{question:"Kevlar sails, when not in use, may be damaged if ____________.",opa:"left in the sunlight",opb:"washed with water and bleach",opc:"folded frequently",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a MODU, the possibility of a blowout makes which type of diesel engine shutdown desirable?",opa:"Overspeed trip",opb:"Air inlet shut-off valve",opc:"Water injector",opd:"Fuel cutoff valve",ans:"opb"},{question:"How much non-liquid deck load can the DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), accept if the weight is placed at a VCG of 130 feet? Ballast added or discharged to maintain draft at 60 feet is done so at 10 feet.",opa:"461.9 long tons",opb:"457.5 long tons",opc:"388.8 long tons",opd:"323.1 long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"On cargo and miscellaneous vessels what is NOT a required part of the fireman's outfit?",opa:"Self-contained breathing apparatus with a lifeline attached",opb:"Combustible gas indicator",opc:"Rigid helmet, boots, and gloves",opd:"Flame safety lamp",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 6.8 ft.",opb:"Available GM 5.4 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.1 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.6 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The most effective fire extinguishing agent to use on burning linen is ____________.",opa:"water",opb:"carbon dioxide",opc:"dry chemical",opd:"foam",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the case of an injury causing a person to be incapacitated, the Master or person in charge of a mobile offshore drilling unit must submit a report to the ____________.",opa:"nearest Marine Safety or Marine Inspection Office",opb:"nearest hospital",opc:"Department of Energy",opd:"American Bureau of Shipping",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have just tried calling another vessel on the VHF and they have not replied. How long should you wait before calling that station again?",opa:"One minute",opb:"Two minutes",opc:"Five minutes",opd:"Seven minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"If a crew member is exposed to phenol by way of skin or eye contact, you should IMMEDIATELY ____________.",opa:"administer oxygen",opb:"treat victim for shock",opc:"flush skin and eyes with water",opd:"give victim stimulant",ans:"opc"},{question:"While taking on fuel oil from an offshore supply vessel, the transfer hose leaks, causing a sheen in the water. You should ____________.",opa:"continue transfer operations",opb:"repair the leak with duct tape",opc:"reduce the rate of transfer",opd:"immediately shut down operations",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a MODU, when may a work vest be substituted for a required life preserver?",opa:"To replace a damaged life preserver",opb:"For use during fire drills",opc:"For use during boat drills",opd:"At no time",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER has a change of trim by the head of 2.0 feet. What is the change of draft at the forward draft marks?",opa:"0.66 feet",opb:"1.00 feet",opc:"1.33 feet",opd:"2.00 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"During an annual FCC inspection ____________.",opa:"all required documents and publications may have to be produced",opb:"licensed GMDSS radio operators may be required to demonstrate equipment competencies",opc:"all required equipment must be fully operational",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What can cause a lack of oxygen in a chain locker?",opa:"Absorption",opb:"Osmosis",opc:"Evaporation",opd:"Oxidation",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a passenger vessel's plans must be permanently exhibited, they are NOT required to show information on the ____________.",opa:"fire detection system",opb:"portable fire extinguishers",opc:"lifeboats, liferafts, and life preservers",opd:"ventilation systems",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many liters of water per person must be carried in lifeboats on a tankship sailing a coastwise route?",opa:"None",opb:"One",opc:"Two",opd:"Three",ans:"opd"},{question:"Generally, what is used to inflate liferafts?",opa:"non-toxic gas",opb:"Oxygen",opc:"Hydrogen",opd:"Helium",ans:"opa"},{question:"How many low-velocity spray applicators are required on the weather decks of a tankship?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are approaching another vessel and see that she has the signal flag 'A' hoisted. What should you do?",opa:"Give the vessel a wide berth as she is carrying dangerous goods.",opb:"Attempt to call the vessel on VHF radiotelephone because she is disabled.",opc:"Stop your vessel instantly.",opd:"Slow your vessel and keep well clear because she has a diver down.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Records which must be retained onboard after report of casualty to a MODU include the ____________.",opa:"tour reports",opb:"hull reports",opc:"machinery repair record book",opd:"deck equipment log",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents a fire station?",opa:"1",opb:"30",opc:"51",opd:"58",ans:"opb"},{question:"While in 150 feet water depth when the single amplitude roll angle of the COASTAL DRILLER is 2 degrees, the safe platform roll period for going on location should be longer than ____________.",opa:"0.5 second",opb:"5.0 seconds",opc:"10.0 seconds",opd:"13.5 seconds",ans:"opa"},{question:"All lifeboats, rescue boats, and rigid-type liferafts shall be stripped, cleaned, and thoroughly overhauled at least once every ____________.",opa:"6 months",opb:"year",opc:"18 months",opd:"two years",ans:"opb"},{question:"Repairing damage to the hull of a MODU at or above the waterline reduces the threat of ____________.",opa:"free surface effects",opb:"capsizing the MODU",opc:"continued progressive flooding",opd:"wind overturning moments",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which category of NAVTEX messages may be rejected in some receivers, BUT SHOULD NOT?",opa:"Category L navigational warnings",opb:"Category A navigational warnings",opc:"SAR and distress alert information",opd:"Weather warnings",ans:"opa"},{question:"The lightweight longitudinal free surface moments for the DEEP DRILLER are ____________.",opa:"680,914 ft.-long tons",opb:"000 ft.-long tons",opc:"-5,937 ft.-long tons",opd:"-6,716 ft.-long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, all lifeboats are required to be marked with the ____________.",opa:"name and port of the unit",opb:"owner and port of the unit",opc:"drilling location",opd:"builder",ans:"opa"},{question:"When elevated, placing the LCG and TCG at the leg centroid provides ____________.",opa:"reduced scour rates",opb:"higher variable loading during preloading",opc:"higher drilling loads",opd:"equal leg reactions",ans:"opd"},{question:"Generally, the first action in extinguishing an LFG fire caused by escaping gas is to ____________.",opa:"sweep flames away with water spray",opb:"shut off the leak",opc:"use a chemical foam fire extinguisher",opd:"call the local fire department",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the DEEP DRILLER, among the valves to open when transferring ballast from Tank 10P to Tank 1S using the #2 ballast pump is valve ____________.",opa:"33 Starboard",opb:"36 Starboard",opc:"33 Port",opd:"36 Port",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement(s) is(are) TRUE?",opa:"Polyester sailcloth, such as Dacron, is resistant to rot due to moisture but susceptible to UV degradation and should be kept covered as much as possible.",opb:"Canvas sailcloth is susceptible to rot due to moisture and should never be covered when wet.",opc:"Kevlar sail cloth is susceptible to weakening due to repeated folding and therefore should be draped loosely over the boom when stowed.",opd:"All of the above are true.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The LCG of a vessel may be found by dividing displacement into the ____________.",opa:"longitudinal center of gravity of the vessel",opb:"sum of the vertical moments of the vessel",opc:"sum of the longitudinal moments of the vessel",opd:"longitudinal baseline of the vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"In general, how often are sanitary inspections of passenger and crew quarters made aboard passenger vessels in river service?",opa:"Once each day",opb:"Once each week",opc:"Once each month",opd:"Once each trip",ans:"opc"},{question:"During an abandonment or drill, the first person to arrive at the survival craft should ____________.",opa:"pass out food and water to personnel",opb:"open the doors and start the sprinkler system",opc:"activate the emergency release handle",opd:"open the doors and prepare the craft for boarding",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about sailing close-hauled is TRUE?",opa:"If you ease the sheets, you can sail faster and closer to the wind.",opb:"If you ease the sheets, you can sail faster on the same course.",opc:"If you steer closer to the wind, you will slow down.",opd:"If you sheet your sails closer to the centerline, you must bear away from the wind.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the function of an air receiver in the compressed air system on a MODU?",opa:"Condenses moisture",opb:"Provides overpressure protection",opc:"Purifies the air",opd:"Acts as an accumulator",ans:"opd"},{question:"During preloading or elevating the COASTAL DRILLER, jacking-up may continue if the total weight is less than ____________.",opa:"21,497 kips",opb:"21,297 kips",opc:"17,700 kips",opd:"14,400 kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel measures 128 feet long by 21 feet in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 7'-06' is 6 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"1.56 feet",opb:"2.37 feet",opc:"2.55 feet",opd:"2.74 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The size of fire hydrant hose connections on a cargo vessel must be either 1-1/2 inches or ____________.",opa:"1 inch",opb:"2-1/2 inches",opc:"3 inches",opd:"3-1/2 inches",ans:"opb"},{question:"Regulations require that cargo pumprooms handling grades D and/or E liquid cargo only shall be fitted with at LEAST how many ducts extended to the weather deck?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 15'-05', AFT 21'-03'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.05 feet",opb:"1.15 feet",opc:"1.25 feet",opd:"1.31 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A CO2 extinguisher which has lost 10% of its charge must be ____________.",opa:"used at the earliest opportunity",opb:"hydro tested",opc:"recharged",opd:"weighed again in one month",ans:"opc"},{question:"A vessel is signaling to you by flag hoist, and the answer pennant is hoisted close-up. You should ____________.",opa:"hoist flag 'C'",opb:"wait for further signals after a short delay",opc:"hoist flag 'R'",opd:"expect no further flag hoists",ans:"opd"},{question:"A large oil fire on the deck of a ship can be fought most effectively with ____________.",opa:"dry chemical",opb:"foam",opc:"high-velocity fog",opd:"Water (cartridge-operated)",ans:"opb"},{question:"Before you start an engine in a compartment, it's MOST important to ____________.",opa:"check the flame arrester",opb:"check the fuel tank",opc:"check the battery",opd:"ventilate the bilges",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is a functional or carriage requirement for compulsory vessels?",opa:"A compulsory vessel must carry at least two FCC licensed GMDSS Radio Operators.",opb:"A compulsory vessel must satisfy certain equipment carriage requirements that are determined by where the vessel sails.",opc:"A compulsory vessel must be able to transmit and respond to Distress alerts.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"How should the number '2' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"NUM-BER-TOO",opb:"BEES-SOH-TOO",opc:"DOS-SOH-TU",opd:"NEM-MARL-TWO",ans:"opb"},{question:"The full period of motion of the DEEP DRILLER while tripping is 10 seconds and the maximum pitch angle as seen on the inclinometers is 8 degrees. From the standpoint of critical motion, the motion is ____________.",opa:"unsatisfactory, place setback in the pipe racks",opb:"satisfactory, continue tripping",opc:"unsatisfactory, deballast to survival draft",opd:"satisfactory, place unit in standby",ans:"opc"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, emergency lighting and each emergency power system must be tested at least once a ____________.",opa:"day",opb:"week",opc:"month",opd:"year",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which of these approved lifesaving devices must a small passenger vessel carrying passengers for hire carry for each person onboard? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Buoyant cushion",opb:"Life jacket",opc:"Ring buoy",opd:"Buoyant vest",ans:"opb"},{question:"A safe fuel system must ____________.",opa:"prevent engine overheating",opb:"have proper air/gasoline fuel mixture ratio",opc:"be liquid-and vapor-tight",opd:"supply sufficient air to the intake manifold",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which fire extinguishing agent can NOT be used on an ethylenediamine?",opa:"Water foam",opb:"Dry chemical powder",opc:"Water fog",opd:"Alcohol foam",ans:"opa"},{question:"A crew member suffering from hypothermia should be given ____________.",opa:"a small dose of alcohol",opb:"treatment for shock",opc:"a large meal",opd:"a brisk rub down",ans:"opb"},{question:"In the event of damage to the DEEP DRILLER which results in flooding to one of the lower-hull tanks, pump from ____________.",opa:"nearby damaged tanks",opb:"nearby undamaged tanks containing ballast",opc:"tanks on the opposite corner",opd:"the opposite trim tank",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which fire control plan symbol represents the agent or device best suited for extinguishing a class 'C' fire?",opa:"47",opb:"56",opc:"26",opd:"36",ans:"opc"},{question:"Forces within a vessel have caused a difference between the starboard and port drafts. This difference is called ____________.",opa:"list",opb:"heel",opc:"trim",opd:"flotation",ans:"opa"},{question:"Among the valves that must be opened on the DEEP DRILLER to pump bilge water out of the port pump room using both bilge pumps is valve ____________.",opa:"26",opb:"28",opc:"36",opd:"41",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has a metacentric height of 1.12 feet and a beam of 60 feet. Your average rolling period will be ____________.",opa:"20 seconds",opb:"23 seconds",opc:"25 seconds",opd:"35 seconds",ans:"opc"},{question:"If you fail to notify the Coast Guard of an oil spill, you may be imprisoned up to ____________.",opa:"1 year",opb:"2 years",opc:"3 years",opd:"5 years",ans:"opd"},{question:"When transferring survivors from a survival craft to a rescue vessel, personnel onboard the craft should ____________.",opa:"remove their lifejackets to make it easier to climb onboard the rescue vessel",opb:"climb on top of the survival craft while waiting their turn to transfer to the rescue vessel",opc:"remain seated inside the survival craft and make the transfer one person at a time",opd:"enter the water and swim over to the rescue vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are reading the draft marks in illustration D032DG. The water level is about 4 inches below the bottom of 10. What is the draft?",opa:"10'-04'",opb:"10'-02'",opc:"9'-08'",opd:"9'-04'",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the piping systems of a MODU, what type of valve gives the least resistance to fluid flow when fully open?",opa:"Globe valve",opb:"Butterfly valve",opc:"Gate valve",opd:"Packless valve",ans:"opc"},{question:"What would be considered a vessel under the International Rules of the Road?",opa:"A jack-up rig under tow",opb:"A semisubmersible drilling rig under tow",opc:"A semisubmersible drilling rig drifting after breaking a tow line",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"How many B-II fire extinguishers must be in the machinery space of a 175-foot long fishing vessel propelled by engines with 3300 brake horsepower?",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"5",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1292 tons",opb:"1248 tons",opc:"1211 tons",opd:"1172 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"To find the cause of a gasoline engine's failure to start, you should ____________.",opa:"break the joint in the fuel line at the engine and let the gas run in the bilges",opb:"disconnect the wires at the spark plugs and make the spark jump the gap",opc:"prime the engine with ether through spark plug openings",opd:"ventilate the space, then check the battery, spark plugs, carburetor, and fuel line",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel aground may have negative GM since the ____________.",opa:"decrease in KM is equal to the loss of draft",opb:"virtual rise of G is directly proportional to the remaining draft",opc:"lost buoyancy method is used to calculate KM, and KB is reduced",opd:"displacement lost acts at the point where the ship is aground",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE of a tender vessel?",opa:"It has a large GM.",opb:"Its period of roll is long.",opc:"It has a very low center of gravity.",opd:"It has a good transverse stability.",ans:"opb"},{question:"While in 150 feet water depth when the single amplitude roll angle of the COASTAL DRILLER is 1 degree, the safe platform roll period for going on location should be longer than ____________.",opa:"0.2 second",opb:"3.2 seconds",opc:"7.0 seconds",opd:"9.2 seconds",ans:"opc"},{question:"The primary danger in helicopter fires on a MODU is ____________.",opa:"burning jet fuel running on to quarters or other areas",opb:"loss of the mooring system",opc:"rotating and flying debris",opd:"heat damage to helicopter structure",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 18'-09', AFT 20'-05'; and the KG is 23.8 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 26\xb0 inclination if the center of gravity is 1.0 foot off center.",opa:"0.0 feet",opb:"0.4 foot",opc:"0.8 foot",opd:"1.7 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Life jackets should be marked with the ____________.",opa:"maximum weight allowed",opb:"stowage space assigned",opc:"vessel's home port",opd:"vessel's name",ans:"opd"},{question:"Under federal regulations, what minimum level of Blood Alcohol Content (BAC) constitutes a violation of the laws prohibiting Boating Under the Influence of Alcohol (BUI) on commercial vessels?",opa:".18% BAC",opb:".10% BAC",opc:".06% BAC",opd:".04% BAC",ans:"opd"},{question:"An entry of water, gas, oil, or other formation fluid into the wellbore is called a ____________.",opa:"blowout",opb:"kick",opc:"gusher",opd:"flow",ans:"opb"},{question:"A semisubmersible in transit is at a draft of 19 feet. The depth of the lower hulls is 21 feet. How much bunker fuel at 54.0 lbs./cu ft. could be taken on and still provide one foot of freeboard if the TPI is 52.3?",opa:"627.6 long tons",opb:"648.0 long tons",opc:"843.9 long tons",opd:"255.2 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fusible-link fire dampers are operated by ____________.",opa:"a break-glass and pull-cable system",opb:"electrical controls on the bridge",opc:"a mechanical arm outside the vent duct",opd:"the heat of a fire melting the link",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a semisubmersible drilling unit, increasing riser tension increases ____________.",opa:"KG",opb:"GM",opc:"KM",opd:"free surface moments",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the function of the bypass valve on the self-contained breathing apparatus?",opa:"The valve opens in excessive heat to release the oxygen in the bottle and prevent the bottle from exploding.",opb:"In the event of a malfunction in the equipment, the valve can be operated manually to give the wearer air.",opc:"When pressure in the apparatus exceeds 7 psi above atmospheric pressure, the valve opens to release pressure.",opd:"The valve reduces the high pressure in the bottle to about 3 psi above atmospheric pressure.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Each buoyant work vest on an OSV must be ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard Approved",opb:"marked with the name of the unit",opc:"equipped with a water light",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 15'-09', AFT 16'-08'; and the KG is 23.6 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the angle of list if the center of gravity is shifted 0.9 foot off the centerline.",opa:"15\xb0",opb:"18\xb0",opc:"21\xb0",opd:"24\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have approximately 6 tons of fish on deck. What will be the shift in the center of gravity after you shift the fish to the fish hold, a vertical distance of 7 feet? (total displacement is 422 tons)",opa:"0.1 foot",opb:"0.3 foot",opc:"0.5 foot",opd:"0.9 foot",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each life float on an inspected vessel shall be fitted and equipped with ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"a lifeline, a painter, and one paddle",opb:"a lifeline, a painter, and a water light",opc:"two paddles, a light, and a lifeline",opd:"two paddles, a light, a lifeline, a painter and pendants",ans:"opd"},{question:"A tanker's mean draft is 32'-05'. At this draft, the TPI is 178. The mean draft after loading 1200 tons will be ____________.",opa:"33'-00'",opb:"33'-04'",opc:"33'-08'",opd:"33'-11'",ans:"opa"},{question:"While loaded as shown in the COASTAL DRILLER sample load form #3 (drilling), all of the casing is discharged. What is the change in LCG?",opa:"1.98 feet forward",opb:"1.95 feet forward",opc:"0.02 foot forward",opd:"0.02 foot aft",ans:"opc"},{question:"To what chemical family does chlorallylene belong?",opa:"Alcohols",opb:"Esters",opc:"Glycol ethers",opd:"Substituted allyl",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the minimum permit or license requirement of a GMDSS Radio Maintainer?",opa:"Holding the Marine Radio Operator Permit is a pre-requisite before the GMDSS Maintainer Endorsement can be obtained",opb:"Holding a valid GMDSS Radio Operator license is sufficient",opc:"Holding the GMDSS Radio Maintainer license is sufficient",opd:"Holding the GMDSS Radio Operator license for at least one year is a prerequisite to holding the GMDSS Radio Maintainer license",ans:"opc"},{question:"A liferaft which has inflated bottom-up on the water ____________.",opa:"should be righted by standing on the carbon dioxide cylinder, holding the righting straps and leaning backwards",opb:"should be righted by standing on the life line, holding the righting straps leaning backwards",opc:"will right itself when the canopy tube inflates",opd:"must be cleared of the buoyant equipment before it will right itself",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a small passenger vessel, backfire flame arrestors are installed on a/an ____________.",opa:"oil fired turbine or reciprocating steam engine",opb:"turbocharged diesel engine",opc:"natural gas (propane) engine",opd:"gasoline powered engine",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a MODU is inclined at a small angle, the center of buoyancy will ____________.",opa:"remain stationary",opb:"move toward the low side",opc:"move toward the high side",opd:"move to the height of the metacenter",ans:"opb"},{question:"When inspecting a survival craft, you should check to make sure that the ____________.",opa:"sea anchor is deployed",opb:"hydraulic starting system has been drained",opc:"hydraulic pressure is within the specified range",opd:"steering controls are locked",ans:"opc"},{question:"Where must you record the date of each emergency training drill conducted on a MODU?",opa:"In the logbook",opb:"In the Operations Manual",opc:"On the Certificate of Inspection",opd:"On the muster list",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER will sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts.",opa:"FWD 26'-02', AFT26'-08'",opb:"FWD 25'-09', AFT27'-02'",opc:"FWD 25'-03', AFT28'-09'",opd:"FWD 24'-11', AFT29'-11'",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which vessels must comply with the vessel bridge-to-bridge radiotelephone regulations while navigating?",opa:"Towing vessels 25 feet in length or less",opb:"Passenger vessels of 100 gross tons or greater, carrying one or more passengers for hire",opc:"Power-driven vessels 12 meters or less in length",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, all lifeboats are required to be marked with the ____________.",opa:"name of the owner of the unit",opb:"number of persons allowed in the boat",opc:"drilling location of the unit",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"You used a carbon dioxide (CO2) fire extinguisher but did not empty the extinguisher. You must have it recharged if the weight loss exceeds ____________.",opa:"one percent of the weight of the charge",opb:"five percent of the weight of the charge",opc:"seven percent of the weight of the charge",opd:"ten percent of the weight of the charge",ans:"opd"},{question:"When crossing a bar in rough weather, you should enter on a(n) ____________.",opa:"tidal bore",opb:"ebbing current",opc:"flood current",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The regulations that were passed to implement MARPOL 73/78 concerning oil pollution apply to a U.S. flag vessel that sails on which waters?",opa:"Inland waters only",opb:"Great Lakes only",opc:"International waters",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the COASTAL DRILLER, LCG is obtained from the sum of the longitudinal moments by ____________.",opa:"adding the sum of the weights",opb:"subtracting the sum of the weights",opc:"multiplying by the sum of the weights",opd:"dividing by the sum of the weights",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are reading the draft marks in illustration D032DG. The water level forward is at the top of the 8, and the mean water level aft is at the top of the 8. What is the mean draft?",opa:"8'06'",opb:"8'03'",opc:"8'00'",opd:"7'06'",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your rescue craft is broken down and rolling in heavy seas. You can reduce the possibility of capsizing by ____________.",opa:"shifting the rudder constantly",opb:"moving all personnel forward and low",opc:"moving all personnel aft",opd:"rigging a sea anchor",ans:"opd"},{question:"One gallon of high expansion foam solution will produce ____________.",opa:"8 to 10 gallons of foam",opb:"25 to 50 gallons of foam",opc:"100 to 200 gallons of foam",opd:"500 to 1000 gallons of foam",ans:"opd"},{question:"The initial tension set in the mooring system of a MODU establishes the ____________.",opa:"maximum water depth at which drilling operations can be conducted",opb:"distance the unit can be offset from the wellbore before the restoring forces oppose the environmental forces",opc:"maximum time it will take to disconnect the riser package in the event of a storm",opd:"minimum amount of ballast needed to keep the vessel at operating draft during normal drilling operations",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT a responsibility of the tankerman in charge of loading an unmanned tank barge?",opa:"Enforcement of smoking restrictions",opb:"Restricting vessels from coming alongside the barge",opc:"Insuring that a combustible gas indicator is aboard",opd:"Protecting cargo hose with chafing gear",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 14'-04', AFT 17'-06'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.15 feet",opb:"1.25 feet",opc:"1.31 feet",opd:"1.48 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"To enable tying down a helicopter on the landing area of a MODU, the landing deck must be fitted with ____________.",opa:"recessed tie down points",opb:"hydraulically lifted bitts",opc:"air tuggers",opd:"fixed cleats",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 6.9 ft.",opb:"Available GM 5.3 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.1 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"In general, batteries aboard small passenger vessels should be ____________.",opa:"as high above the bilge as practicable",opb:"stowed in well-ventilated spaces to allow dissipation of any gases generated",opc:"accessible for maintenance and removal",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fixed carbon dioxide extinguishing systems, for machinery spaces that are normally manned, are actuated by one control to open the stop valve in the line leading to the space, and ____________.",opa:"the same control releasing the CO2",opb:"a separate control to release the CO2",opc:"two separate controls to release the CO2",opd:"three separate controls to release the CO2",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have approximately 15 tons of fish on deck. What will be the shift in the center of gravity after you shift the fish to the fish hold, a vertical distance of 8 feet? (total displacement is 300 tons)",opa:"0.1 foot",opb:"0.2 foot",opc:"0.3 foot",opd:"0.4 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"If a person is unconscious from electric shock, you should first remove him from the electrical source and then ____________.",opa:"administer ammonia smelling salts",opb:"check for serious burns on the body",opc:"determine if he is breathing",opd:"massage vigorously to restore circulation",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-00', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.49 feet",opb:"2.38 feet",opc:"2.27 feet",opd:"2.05 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which spaces are required to be segregated from cargo tanks carrying grades A, B, C, or D cargoes?",opa:"Pump rooms",opb:"Enclosed deck spaces",opc:"Cofferdams",opd:"Navigation spaces",ans:"opd"},{question:"Why is electrical power preferred over mechanical power for driving heavy machinery on drilling rigs?",opa:"More fuel efficient",opb:"More flexible",opc:"Lighter",opd:"Less maintenance",ans:"opb"},{question:"If a MODU under tow starts jumping on its tow line, the most appropriate action to alleviate the condition is to ____________.",opa:"change course",opb:"slow down",opc:"heave to",opd:"adjust tow line length",ans:"opd"},{question:"An offshore drilling unit must be equipped with a first aid kit approved by the ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"Minerals Management Service",opd:"Mine Safety and Health Administration",ans:"opd"},{question:"What must Inland vessels of 100 GT and over be fitted with for oily mixtures?",opa:"A fixed system to discharge the slops overboard",opb:"A fixed system to discharge oily mixtures to a reception facility",opc:"A portable system to discharge the slops overboard",opd:"A portable system to discharge oily mixtures to a reception facility",ans:"opb"},{question:"While loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), all of the liquid mud is dumped. What would be the new draft?",opa:"56.69 feet",opb:"58.14 feet",opc:"59.14 feet",opd:"63.31 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"When anchoring a small sailing vessel in rough weather, the best anchor line would be composed of ____________.",opa:"chain-wire",opb:"chain-manila",opc:"chain-nylon",opd:"all chain",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"6.1 feet",opb:"5.8 feet",opc:"5.4 feet",opd:"4.9 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The function of the bypass valve on the self-contained breathing apparatus is to ____________.",opa:"control the pressure of the oxygen as it enters the body",opb:"allow the wearer to manually give himself oxygen",opc:"release excess heat which would otherwise cause the bottle to explode",opd:"allow exhaled gases to pass outside the bottle",ans:"opb"},{question:"The pneumatic containers which store bulk dry mud additives and cement on a MODU are called ____________.",opa:"mud hoppers",opb:"bulk bins",opc:"P-tanks",opd:"mud tanks",ans:"opc"},{question:"On small passenger vessels, backfire flame arrestors are installed on ____________.",opa:"all electric motors",opb:"turbocharged diesel engines",opc:"gasoline engines",opd:"both A and C",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the lifesaving signal for 'You are seen -Assistance will be given as soon as possible'?",opa:"Green star rocket",opb:"Red star rocket",opc:"Orange smoke signal",opd:"Horizontal motion of a flag",ans:"opc"},{question:"A semisubmersible rig under tow should be ballasted down if ____________.",opa:"motion begins to be excessive",opb:"water begins to break over the pontoons",opc:"period of roll exceeds 12 seconds",opd:"forward progress is halted by head wind",ans:"opa"},{question:"What do the small passenger vessel regulations require when installing a hydraulic accumulator or other unfired pressure vessel?",opa:"It be operated at one and one half times normal operating pressure for ten minutes.",opb:"Safety and/or relief valves settings be checked at two and one half times normal operating pressures.",opc:"It be installed to the satisfaction of the cognizant OCMI",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your sailing drafts are: FWD 17'-07', AFT 18'-05' and the GM is 3.4 feet. What will be the angle of list if #4 port double bottom (capacity 140 tons, VCG 2.6 feet, and 26 feet off the centerline) is filled with saltwater? (Use the data in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"Less than 1\xb0",opb:"3\xb0",opc:"6\xb0",opd:"9\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), discharges all the cement in the P-Tanks. See Table 7. What is the change in KG?",opa:"0.24 foot downward",opb:"0.49 foot downward",opc:"0.88 foot downward",opd:"1.02 feet downward",ans:"opb"},{question:"The only wire rope termination which may be made in the field is ____________.",opa:"swaged socket",opb:"thimbled mechanical splice",opc:"hand splice",opd:"spelter poured and resin sockets",ans:"opd"},{question:"A floating MODU with an initial negative metacentric height ____________.",opa:"will capsize",opb:"will incline further",opc:"may lie at an angle of loll",opd:"may be initially level",ans:"opc"},{question:"Aboard a survival craft, ether can be used to ____________.",opa:"start the engine in cold weather",opb:"aid in helping personnel breathe",opc:"prime the sprinkler system",opd:"prime the air supply",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the port leg reaction for the COASTAL DRILLER if the total weight is 15,000 kips, LCG is 120 feet, and TCG is 1.0?",opa:"4,909 kips",opb:"4,931 kips",opc:"4,950 kips",opd:"5,160 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the boiling point of carbon disulfide?",opa:"167\xb0F",opb:"115\xb0F",opc:"111\xb0F",opd:"46\xb0F",ans:"opb"},{question:"On offshore drilling units each ring life buoy must be marked, in a contrasting color, with the unit's ____________.",opa:"name and port of registry",opb:"owner and port of registry",opc:"port of registry and identification number",opd:"name and owner",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a gasoline engine turns over freely but will not start, the cause is generally ____________.",opa:"a defective ignition system",opb:"low lube oil level",opc:"weak valve springs",opd:"too heavy a load",ans:"opa"},{question:"Paint and oil lockers on small passenger vessels must be constructed of or lined with ____________.",opa:"steel or equivalent material",opb:"fiberglass",opc:"sheetrock, asbestos, or other material that retards the spread of fire",opd:"marine plywood",ans:"opa"},{question:"A man aboard a vessel, signaling by raising and lowering his outstretched arms to each side, is indicating ____________.",opa:"danger, stay away",opb:"all is clear, it is safe to pass",opc:"all is clear, it is safe to approach",opd:"a distress signal",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 3900 tons of cargo, 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 259 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in fresh water.",opa:"18'-06'",opb:"18'-02'",opc:"17'-11'",opd:"17'-08'",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are reading the draft marks. The top 2 inches of number '9' are visible above the waterline. What is the draft?",opa:"8'-10'",opb:"9'-02'",opc:"9'-04'",opd:"9'-08'",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a semisubmersible drilling unit, decreasing riser tension increases ____________.",opa:"free surface moments",opb:"KM",opc:"GM",opd:"KG",ans:"opc"},{question:"Before inserting a low-velocity fog applicator into an all-purpose nozzle, you must ____________.",opa:"install the high-velocity nozzle tip",opb:"move the handle to position 2",opc:"move the handle to position 1",opd:"remove the high-velocity nozzle tip",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the Reid vapor pressure of allyl chloride?",opa:"16.5 (psia)",opb:"14.0 (psia)",opc:"12.9 (psia)",opd:"10.3 (psia)",ans:"opd"},{question:"On the DEEP DRILLER, among the starboard-side valves to open when deballasting from ballast tank 8S is valve ____________.",opa:"7",opb:"8",opc:"17",opd:"18",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which shipboard equipment will detect a signal from a SART?",opa:"S-Band Radar",opb:"A DSC receiver",opc:"X-Band Radar",opd:"The autoalarm",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should longitude 116\xb024.3'W be written when preparing an AMVER report?",opa:"116\xb024.3W",opb:"11624W",opc:"116.4W",opd:"116W",ans:"opb"},{question:"The intact volume above the waterline of a floating MODU is ____________.",opa:"displacement volume",opb:"reserve buoyancy",opc:"gross tonnage",opd:"net tonnage",ans:"opb"},{question:"Reinforcing frames attached to a bulkhead on a MODU are called ____________.",opa:"side longitudinals",opb:"intercostals",opc:"stiffeners",opd:"brackets",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have been carrying a liquid with flammable limits of 1% to 7% mixture with air. If your instructions say that no one shall enter the tank if the vapor concentration is over 15% of the LEL, what is the maximum allowable percentage of vapors for men to enter?",opa:"0.0015",opb:"0.0085",opc:"0.0105",opd:"0.07",ans:"opa"},{question:"When flooding occurs in a damaged vessel, reserve buoyancy ____________.",opa:"decreases",opb:"remains the same",opc:"increases",opd:"shifts to the low side",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the length of the catenary when the DEEP DRILLER is anchored in 600 feet of water and the anchor line tension is 170 kips?",opa:"891 feet",opb:"1348 feet",opc:"1493 feet",opd:"1657 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A jack-up 180 feet in length with the LCF at 120 feet AFO has a draft of 8 feet at the bow and 11 feet at the stern. What is the true mean draft (draft at the center of flotation)?",opa:"8.0 feet",opb:"9.0 feet",opc:"10.0 feet",opd:"11.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Automatic fire dampers in ventilation systems are operated by use of a ____________.",opa:"remote operated valve",opb:"C02 system pressure switch",opc:"fusible link",opd:"heat or smoke detector",ans:"opc"},{question:"Changing direction by bringing the stern of the vessel through the eye of the wind is known as ____________.",opa:"jibing",opb:"running before the wind",opc:"tacking",opd:"reefing",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 60 feet, has 35,000 ft.-tons of longitudinal moments. How much ballast should be transferred between tanks 1P and 10P to level the unit longitudinally?",opa:"25.5 long tons",opb:"50.2 long tons",opc:"165.3 long tons",opd:"330.2 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"What entry would NOT be shown on the V line of an AMVER report?",opa:"MED TECH",opb:"MD",opc:"NONE",opd:"NURSE",ans:"opa"},{question:"Regulations require that cargo pumps in tank vessels carrying grade D liquid cargo shall be isolated from sources of vapor ignition by ____________.",opa:"cofferdams",opb:"gastight bulkheads",opc:"passageways or living quarters",opd:"general cargo spaces",ans:"opb"},{question:"The most effective cooling agent among those normally used to fight fires is ____________.",opa:"water fog or spray",opb:"chemical foam",opc:"mechanical foam",opd:"carbon dioxide",ans:"opa"},{question:"Stability is determined principally by the location of the point of application of two forces: the upward-acting buoyant force and the ____________.",opa:"upward-acting weight force",opb:"downward-acting weight force",opc:"downward-acting buoyant force",opd:"environmental force",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 17'-09', AFT 18'-03'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the location of the center of flotation relative to amidships.",opa:"5.6 feet forward",opb:"5.1 feet forward",opc:"at the center of flotation",opd:"0.8 foot aft",ans:"opb"},{question:"If your vessel will list with equal readiness to either side, the list is most likely caused by ____________.",opa:"negative GM",opb:"off-center weight",opc:"pocketing of free surface",opd:"excessive freeboard",ans:"opa"},{question:"After the initial AMVER Position Report, sent by a vessel sailing foreign, subsequent Position Reports must be sent no less frequently than every ____________.",opa:"24 hours",opb:"36 hours",opc:"48 hours",opd:"Monday, Wednesday, and Friday",ans:"opc"},{question:"Except in rare cases, it is impossible to extinguish a shipboard fire by ____________.",opa:"removing the fuel",opb:"interrupting the chain reaction",opc:"removing the oxygen",opd:"removing the heat",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement(s) is(are) TRUE concerning the use of dry chemical extinguishers?",opa:"You should direct the spray at the base of the fire.",opb:"You should direct the spray directly into the fire.",opc:"You should direct the spray at a vertical bulkhead and allow it to flow over the fire.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following would be of immediate concern after discovering a large fire in the ship's galley?",opa:"An adjacent storeroom, containing spare parts",opb:"A storeroom directly above, containing combustible fluids",opc:"An adjacent storeroom, containing mattresses and linen",opd:"An adjacent storeroom, marked 'Stewards Stores'",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning life jackets?",opa:"Buoyant vests may be substituted for life jackets.",opb:"Life jackets are designed to turn an unconscious person's face clear of the water.",opc:"Life jackets must always be worn with the same side facing outwards to float properly.",opd:"Lightly stained or faded life jackets will fail in the water and should not be used.",ans:"opb"},{question:"A life float on a fishing vessel must be equipped with ____________.",opa:"a painter",opb:"red smoke flares",opc:"a jackknife",opd:"a signal mirror",ans:"opa"},{question:"By regulation, cargo tank atmosphere must be inert before and during which operation?",opa:"Stripping",opb:"Loading",opc:"crude oil washing",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Regulations require certain records to be retained onboard a MODU for how long after the report of a casualty?",opa:"1 month",opb:"3 months",opc:"6 months",opd:"12 months",ans:"opb"},{question:"In the COASTAL DRILLER, VCG is obtained from the sum of the vertical moments by ____________.",opa:"adding the sum of the weights",opb:"subtracting the sum of the weights",opc:"multiplying by the sum of the weights",opd:"dividing by the sum of the weights",ans:"opd"},{question:"Safety is increased if ____________.",opa:"extra line and wire are laid out on deck for emergency use",opb:"all lashings are made up, and the decks are clean and clear",opc:"power tools are kept plugged in for immediate use",opd:"spare parts are kept on deck for ready access",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 2865 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 27.8 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 26.2 feet",opb:"KG 27.4 feet",opc:"KG 28.5 feet",opd:"KG 29.5 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a vessel of 125,000 GT on an international voyage, how many international shore connection flange(s) must be provided?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opa"},{question:"The principal action in changing from transit to survival draft in the event heavy weather threatens is ____________.",opa:"ballasting",opb:"deballasting",opc:"disconnecting",opd:"hanging off",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is an advantage of a dry chemical extinguisher as compared to a carbon dioxide extinguisher?",opa:"It has a greater duration.",opb:"It provides a heat shield for the operator.",opc:"It is nontoxic.",opd:"It offers lasting, effective protection against burn-back.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Marine Operators, when calling a ship on VHF-FM radiotelephone, normally call on channel ____________.",opa:"13",opb:"16",opc:"19",opd:"23",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which visual distress signal is acceptable for daylight use only?",opa:"Hand-held red flare",opb:"Self-contained rocket-propelled parachute red flare",opc:"Hand-held orange smoke distress flare",opd:"Red aerial pyrotechnic flare",ans:"opc"},{question:"An obstruction on a helo deck is any object that might present a hazard to the ____________.",opa:"rotor blades and landing gear",opb:"unloading of passengers",opc:"loading of cargo",opd:"pilot's visibility",ans:"opa"},{question:"It is desirable to have screens on the vents of potable water tanks to ____________.",opa:"filter the incoming air",opb:"prevent explosions",opc:"prevent backups",opd:"stop insects from entering",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in the Baltic Sea which is a special area listed in ANNEX V of MARPOL. How many miles from land must you be to discharge ground rags, glass, and bottles into the sea?",opa:"3",opb:"12",opc:"25",opd:"Must be retained aboard",ans:"opd"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, notification shall be given to the Coast Guard of a casualty if a person is injured and unable to perform routine duties for ____________.",opa:"any amount of time",opb:"more than 24 hours",opc:"more than 36 hours",opd:"more than 72 hours",ans:"opa"},{question:"To ensure receipt of all relevant MSI, a NAVTEX receiver should be turned on at least how many hours prior to departure from port?",opa:"10",opb:"8",opc:"6",opd:"4",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are attempting to recover a mooring buoy. If you approach the object on the port tack, how would you slow the vessel as you draw near?",opa:"Quickly change to a starboard tack as you reach the object.",opb:"Shift the rudder from port to starboard several times as you reach the object.",opc:"Bring the wind so that it comes over the stern and ease all the sheets.",opd:"Bring the wind directly over the bow and allow the sails to luff.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Aboard small passenger vessels the number of children's' life jackets carried must be at least what percentage of the total number of persons aboard?",opa:"0.04",opb:"0.075",opc:"0.1",opd:"0.15",ans:"opc"},{question:"For a floating MODU, true mean draft is always the ____________.",opa:"average of the observed drafts",opb:"draft at the center of flotation",opc:"draft corresponding to the calculated displacement",opd:"mean of the calculated drafts",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the sounding in drill water tank #1 for the COASTAL DRILLER, if the weight of drill water in the tank is 388.32 kips?",opa:"14.5 feet",opb:"15.0 feet",opc:"15.5 feet",opd:"16.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"On the DEEP DRILLER, among the starboard-side valves to open when flooding through the overboard discharge into ballast tank 1S is valve ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"7",opd:"37",ans:"opa"},{question:"In MODU construction, a greater number of watertight bulkheads results in ____________.",opa:"increased capacity to set flooding boundaries",opb:"decreased capacity to set flooding boundaries",opc:"reduced compartmentation",opd:"greater deck load capacity",ans:"opa"},{question:"Before starting any diesel or gasoline engine, which of the following must be checked?",opa:"Oil level",opb:"Flow of cooling water",opc:"Exhaust discharge",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What class of bulkhead is required around the galley on a MODU?",opa:"Class A",opb:"Class B",opc:"Class C",opd:"Class D",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-00', AFT 15'-11'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.62 feet",opb:"2.82 feet",opc:"2.97 feet",opd:"3.15 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the proper first aid for LPG in the eye?",opa:"Apply an ice pack to the eye.",opb:"Keep the eyelid closed.",opc:"Flush the eye with plenty of water.",opd:"Rub the eye area clean.",ans:"opc"},{question:"All lifeboats, rescue boats, and rigid-type liferafts shall be stripped, cleaned, and thoroughly overhauled at least once every ____________.",opa:"year",opb:"18 months",opc:"two years",opd:"30 months",ans:"opa"},{question:"After having thrown the liferaft and stowage container into the water, the liferaft is inflated by ____________.",opa:"pulling on the painter line",opb:"forcing open the container which operates the CO2",opc:"hitting the hydrostatic release",opd:"using the hand pump provided",ans:"opa"},{question:"A towing vessel's fire detection system may be certified to comply with the Coast Guard's towing vessel fire protection regulations by ____________.",opa:"a Coast Guard inspector",opb:"a registered professional engineer",opc:"the owner or Master of the vessel",opd:"a licensed electrician",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the lightweight of the DEEP DRILLER?",opa:"680,914 long tons",opb:"9,733 long tons",opc:"5,937 long tons",opd:"6,716 long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"A jack-up 180 feet in length with the LCF at 120 feet AFO has a draft of 8 feet at the bow and 11 feet at the stern. What is the mean draft?",opa:"8.0 feet",opb:"9.0 feet",opc:"9.5 feet",opd:"12.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The geometric center of the underwater volume is known as the ____________.",opa:"center of flotation",opb:"tipping center",opc:"center of gravity",opd:"center of buoyancy",ans:"opd"},{question:"A semisubmersible which flops between forward and aft angles of trim is likely to have ____________.",opa:"KML less than KGL",opb:"an off-center LCG",opc:"LCG greater than LCB",opd:"KML greater than KMT",ans:"opa"},{question:"A bulk freighter 680 ft. in length, 60 ft. beam, with a waterplane coefficient of .84, is floating in salt water at a draft of 21'. How many long tons would it take to increase the mean draft by 1'?",opa:"64.3 tons",opb:"69.6 tons",opc:"81.6 tons",opd:"116 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The signal used with shore lifesaving equipment to indicate, 'Affirmative' is ____________.",opa:"vertical motion of the arms",opb:"code signal 'C' sent by light or sound signaling apparatus",opc:"firing of a red star signal",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel has a displacement of 19,800 tons. It is 464 feet long, and has a beam of 64 feet. You have timed its rolling period to be 21.0 seconds in still water. What is your vessel's approximate GM?",opa:"1.1 ft.",opb:"1.3 ft.",opc:"1.6 ft.",opd:"1.8 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A spark arrestor ____________.",opa:"keeps sparks from falling into an open tank",opb:"secures covers on ullage openings",opc:"prevents sparks from getting out of an engine's exhaust system",opd:"grounds static electricity",ans:"opc"},{question:"For the purposes of the International Rules of the Road, a jack-up drilling rig under tow is considered to be a ____________.",opa:"vessel",opb:"non-displacement vessel",opc:"power-driven vessel",opd:"limited vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fire dampers prevent the spread of fire by ____________.",opa:"convection",opb:"conduction",opc:"radiation",opd:"direct contact",ans:"opa"},{question:"Inflatable liferafts on vessels on an international voyage must be able to carry at least ____________.",opa:"2 persons",opb:"4 persons",opc:"6 persons",opd:"8 persons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the weight of the mud in pit #4 if the sounding level changed to 6 feet and the mud weight decreased from 16 to 14 pounds/gallon?",opa:"70.00 long tons",opb:"84.17 long tons",opc:"93.34 long tons",opd:"106.67 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the transverse shift in the center of gravity if 200 short tons are placed 10 feet to port of the centerline on a MODU with TCG 0.7 foot starboard of the centerline, and the displacement is 9,000 short tons?",opa:"0.03 foot",opb:"0.20 foot",opc:"0.23 foot",opd:"0.62 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"The final inspection responsibility for seeing that a tank barge is provided with the required equipment and fittings in good and serviceable condition prior to loading cargo rests with the ____________.",opa:"terminal operator",opb:"owner of the barge",opc:"tankerman or person in charge of loading",opd:"charterer through the Master of the towing vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"On the vessel\u2019s fire control plan, which symbol helps to control the spread of fire?",opa:"68",opb:"34",opc:"33",opd:"32",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, elevated in 150 feet of water with 0 knots current, 10 foot waves, and wind speeds of 70 knots may continue drilling if the maximum leg reaction is less than ____________.",opa:"5,940 kips",opb:"6,020 kips",opc:"6,080 kips",opd:"6,520 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"The component in an inert gas system used for cleaning the gas of solid and sulfur combustion products, while simultaneously cooling the inert gas, is called the ____________.",opa:"filter",opb:"cooler",opc:"scrubber",opd:"purifier",ans:"opc"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, each storage battery for emergency lighting and power systems must be tested every six months under actual connected load for a period of at least ____________.",opa:"1 hour",opb:"2 hours",opc:"3 hours",opd:"4 hours",ans:"opb"},{question:"Use the material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book. If the KG is 22.0 feet, and the drafts are: FWD 23'-06', AFT 24'-03'; at what angle will the vessel lose positive stability?",opa:"76\xb0",opb:"84\xb0",opc:"89\xb0",opd:"98\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"At the instant when a string of casing being run from a MODU is landed in the well head, ____________.",opa:"the total weight in air of the casing string is removed from the MODU",opb:"the hook load (weight of the casing string) is removed from the MODU",opc:"the weight of the casing inside the riser is removed from the MODU",opd:"the weight of the casing string added to the weight of the fill-up mud is removed from the MODU",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are ordering ship's stores. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"Stores such as line, rags, mattresses, linens, etc. must be treated to be fire retardant.",opb:"Stores certified for use on uninspected vessels may be identified by the certification number used by Underwriter's Laboratories.",opc:"A portable container of a flammable liquid used as fuel for portable auxiliary equipment must be stowed in a paint locker or at a designated open location.",opd:"Acetylene may be in a ship's storeroom in quantities not exceeding 6000 cubic feet.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which distress signal is required for a liferaft in ocean service and could be effectively used to attract the attention of aircraft at night?",opa:"The water light",opb:"Smoke marker",opc:"Red flares",opd:"Orange dye marker",ans:"opc"},{question:"The type of shackle used in making up tow lines to a MODU should be ____________.",opa:"screw pin",opb:"chain",opc:"anchor",opd:"safety",ans:"opd"},{question:"If water is rising in the bilge of a lifeboat, you should FIRST ____________.",opa:"abandon the survival craft",opb:"check for cracks in the hull",opc:"shift all personnel to the stern",opd:"check the bilge drain plug",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 564 tons. The existing deck cargo has a center of gravity of 1.5 feet above the deck and weighs 41 tons. If you load 22 tons of ground tackle with an estimated center of gravity of 2.5 feet above the deck, what is the final height of the CG of the deck cargo?",opa:"1.62 feet",opb:"1.85 feet",opc:"2.10 feet",opd:"2.46 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The fire control plan symbol represented by (16) is a ____________.",opa:"foam station",opb:"foam monitor (gun)",opc:"foam nozzle",opd:"space protected by foam",ans:"opd"},{question:"When compared to low-expansion foam, a high-expansion foam will ____________.",opa:"be drier",opb:"be heavier",opc:"be more heat resistant",opd:"not cling to vertical surfaces",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). If port valves 24 and 2 are mistakenly opened, the change in inclination will be increasing trim by the ____________.",opa:"bow with port list",opb:"bow",opc:"stern",opd:"stern with starboard list",ans:"opa"},{question:"When should you use distress flares and rockets?",opa:"Only when there is a chance of their being seen by rescue vessels",opb:"At half-hour intervals",opc:"At one-hour intervals",opd:"Immediately upon abandoning the vessel",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the action that a GMDSS Radio Operator should take when a DSC distress alert is received?",opa:"No action is necessary, as the DSC control unit will automatically switch to the NBDP follow-on communications frequency.",opb:"The operator should immediately set continuous watch on the radiotelephone frequency that is associated with the frequency band on which the distress alert was received.",opc:"The Operator should immediately set continuous watch on VHF channel 70.",opd:"The Operator should immediately set continuous watch on the NBDP frequency that is associated with the frequency band on which the distress alert was received.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Mechanical gearing of deck machinery such as the windlass or boat hoists should ____________.",opa:"be open to view so, if a foreign object gets in the gearing, the operator can immediately stop the machinery",opb:"have a guard over the gearing",opc:"be painted a contrasting color from the base color in order to call attention to the gearing",opd:"not be operated if there is any crew within 10 feet of the machinery",ans:"opb"},{question:"When launching an open lifeboat by falls, the boathooks should be ____________.",opa:"secured forward and aft where readily available",opb:"secured amidships where they will not hinder the personnel",opc:"used for fending off",opd:"used for picking up survivors in the water",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 17'-05', AFT 20'-01'; and the KG is 25.6 feet. What is the righting moment when the vessel is inclined to 45\xb0? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"18,294 foot-tons",opb:"19,709 foot-tons",opc:"21,137 foot-tons",opd:"22,002 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master or person in charge of a MODU is required to log ____________.",opa:"the names of all persons onboard",opb:"only the names of the crew members onboard",opc:"only the names of passengers onboard",opd:"information on emergency training drills",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 26'-03', AFT 30'-08'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the location of the center of flotation relative to amidships.",opa:"2.8 feet aft",opb:"2.3 feet aft",opc:"1.9 feet aft",opd:"1.5 feet aft",ans:"opd"},{question:"The external inflation bladder on an immersion suit should be inflated ____________.",opa:"before you enter the water",opb:"after you enter the water",opc:"after one hour in the water",opd:"after you notice that your suit is losing buoyancy",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"2.8 feet",opb:"4.6 feet",opc:"6.8 feet",opd:"7.1 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Access to a cargo pumproom on a tank vessel carrying grades A, B, C or D liquid cargoes shall be ____________.",opa:"at least 13.1 feet away from the galleys, living quarters or navigation spaces",opb:"from the open deck",opc:"only from areas equipped with power ventilation systems",opd:"isolated from any part of the vessel which normally contains sources of vapor ignition",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, what is NOT a characteristic of allyl chloride?",opa:"It has a Reid vapor pressure of 10.3 (psig).",opb:"It is a clear to strawberry colored liquid.",opc:"It has sour odor.",opd:"It is classified as a grade B poison.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"395 tons",opb:"530 tons",opc:"750 tons",opd:"990 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The maximum variable load for the COASTAL DRILLER while elevated in a severe storm is ____________.",opa:"2,381 kips",opb:"3,381 kips",opc:"7,099 kips",opd:"21,297 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"As compared to carbon dioxide, dry chemical has which advantage?",opa:"Cleaner",opb:"Effective on metal fires",opc:"Greater range",opd:"More cooling effect",ans:"opc"},{question:"Blocking open or removing fire dampers can cause ____________.",opa:"fixed foam systems to be ineffective",opb:"faster cooling of the fire",opc:"the accumulation of explosive gases",opd:"the fire to spread through the ventilation system",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, while in normal transit, experiences a single amplitude roll of 6 degrees. What is the minimum roll period which does not exceed design limits of the legs?",opa:"10.5 seconds",opb:"8.0 seconds",opc:"4.5 seconds",opd:"1.0 second",ans:"opb"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, the lifeboats' fuel tanks must be emptied and the fuel changed at least once every ____________.",opa:"12 months",opb:"24 months",opc:"36 months",opd:"48 months",ans:"opa"},{question:"The wooden plug inserted in the vent of a damaged tank of a MODU should be removed in case it is decided to ____________.",opa:"pump from the damaged tank",opb:"fight a fire",opc:"abandon the rig",opd:"use the crossover system",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the event of a casualty to a MODU, who is responsible to make records available to the Coast Guard official authorized to investigate the casualty?",opa:"Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection",opb:"The person who caused the casualty",opc:"The company man",opd:"The owner",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are making a heavy lift with the jumbo boom. Your vessel displaces 8530 T. The 40-ton weight is on the pier and its center is 65' to starboard of the centerline. The head of the boom is 115' above the base line and the center of gravity of the lift when stowed on deck will be 50' above the base line. As the jumbo boom takes the strain the ship lists to 5\xb0. What is the GM with the cargo stowed?",opa:"2.96 ft.",opb:"3.18 ft.",opc:"3.46 ft.",opd:"3.77 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Life jackets should be stowed in ____________.",opa:"survival craft",opb:"messrooms",opc:"readily accessible locations",opd:"locked watertight containers",ans:"opc"},{question:"Most drill ships and barges have a walled opening below the derrick, open to the water's surface and through which various drilling tools can pass down to the sea floor called a ____________.",opa:"moon pool",opb:"spider deck opening",opc:"pontoon",opd:"keyway",ans:"opa"},{question:"Epilepsy is a chronic nervous disorder characterized by ____________.",opa:"severe nausea and cramps",opb:"muscular convulsions with partial or complete loss of consciousness",opc:"sudden thirst and craving for candy",opd:"severe agitation and desire to get out of closed spaces",ans:"opb"},{question:"Vessels 'A' and 'B' are identical; however, 'A' is more tender than 'B'. This means that 'A' relative to 'B' has a ____________.",opa:"lower KG",opb:"smaller GM",opc:"larger roll angle",opd:"larger GZ",ans:"opb"},{question:"The geometric center of the underwater volume of a floating vessel is the center of ____________.",opa:"hydrodynamic forces",opb:"flotation",opc:"gravity",opd:"buoyancy",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which extinguishing agent will cool down a heated bulkhead in the least amount of time?",opa:"Water stream",opb:"Water fog or spray",opc:"Steam",opd:"Dry chemical",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is sailing on a port tack when a sudden gust of wind heels the vessel sharply to starboard. Which action will reduce the heeling of the vessel?",opa:"Attempt to sail the vessel closer to the wind",opb:"Ease the sheets to allow air flow to spill off the sail",opc:"Shift weight to the port side of the vessel",opd:"Any of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"How wide must the safety net be that is required on the unprotected perimeter of the helicopter landing deck on a MODU?",opa:"1.0 meter",opb:"1.5 meters",opc:"2.0 meters",opd:"2.5 meters",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which extinguishing agent is recommended in the Chemical Data Guide for use on a carbon disulfide fire?",opa:"Alcohol foam",opb:"Dry chemical",opc:"Chemical foam",opd:"Water fog",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 18'-06', AFT 20'-06'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.10 feet",opb:"0.91 foot",opc:"0.72 foot",opd:"0.68 foot",ans:"opb"},{question:"How long must GMDSS Radio Logs be retained onboard the ship in original form?",opa:"30 days",opb:"3 months",opc:"6 months",opd:"1 year",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have approximately 29 tons of fish on deck. What will be the shift in the center of gravity after you shift the fish to the fish hold, a vertical distance of 5 feet? (total displacement is 483 tons)",opa:"0.3 foot",opb:"0.4 foot",opc:"0.5 foot",opd:"0.6 foot",ans:"opa"},{question:"The radiotelephone safety signal is ____________.",opa:"'Securite' repeated 3 times",opb:"'Safety' repeated 3 times",opc:"'Pan Pan' repeated 3 times",opd:"'Securite Securite' repeated 3 times",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a severe storm threatens the COASTAL DRILLER while elevated as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Drilling), the variable loads would have to be reduced by ____________.",opa:"3,282.5 kips",opb:"2,381.0 kips",opc:"1,000.0 kips",opd:"901.5 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"All electrical appliances aboard a vessel should be grounded to ____________.",opa:"prevent them from falling when the vessel rolls",opb:"protect personnel from electrical shock",opc:"increase their operating efficiency",opd:"prevent unauthorized personnel from operating them",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel continually lists to one side and has a normal rolling period. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"The vessel has negative GM.",opb:"The center of gravity is on the centerline.",opc:"The list can be corrected by reducing KM.",opd:"The vessel has asymmetrical weight distribution.",ans:"opd"},{question:"If help has not arrived in 10-12 hours after having abandoned an OSV in a survival craft, you should ____________.",opa:"go in one direction until the fuel runs out",opb:"plot course for the nearest land",opc:"take a vote on the direction in which to go",opd:"shutdown the engines and put out the sea anchor",ans:"opd"},{question:"The firing of a red star signal may mean ____________.",opa:"'This is the best place to land'",opb:"'You are seen -assistance will be given as soon as possible'",opc:"'Tail block is made fast'",opd:"'Slack away'",ans:"opd"},{question:"If an inflatable liferaft is overturned, it may be righted by ____________.",opa:"filling the stabilizers on one side with water",opb:"releasing the CO2 cylinder",opc:"pushing up from under one end",opd:"standing on the inflating cylinder and pulling on the straps on the underside of the raft",ans:"opd"},{question:"BOTH INTERNATIONAL & INLAND You are proceeding under sail with the auxiliary engine running and the propeller engaged. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"If most of the propelling power comes from the sails, your vessel is considered a sailing vessel.",opb:"You must display a red light over a green light at the masthead.",opc:"In fog you must sound one prolonged blast at two-minute intervals when making way.",opd:"By day, you must display a black diamond shape forward.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, while drilling, has a total weight of 15,400 kips. The LCG is 120.00 feet AF0, and the TCG is -0.5 feet to port of the centerline. What is the port leg reaction?",opa:"5,063 kips",opb:"5,104 kips",opc:"5,233 kips",opd:"5,345 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a self-elevating drilling unit, draft marks must be located ____________.",opa:"near each corner of the hull",opb:"at frame O, port and starboard",opc:"at bow and stern on the centerline",opd:"on each leg",ans:"opa"},{question:"The number of approved adult life jackets that shall be carried is equal to ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"120% of the number of persons listed in the vessel's Certificate of Inspection",opb:"90% of the number of persons listed in the vessel's Certificate of Inspection",opc:"90% of the number of persons onboard at the time",opd:"the number of persons onboard at the time",ans:"opd"},{question:"You can indicate that your vessel is in distress by ____________.",opa:"displaying a large red flag",opb:"displaying three black balls in a vertical line",opc:"sounding five or more short and rapid blasts on the whistle",opd:"continuously sounding the fog whistle",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-10', AFT 15'-08'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1.91 feet",opb:"2.09 feet",opc:"2.21 feet",opd:"2.48 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are communicating on the radiotelephone using plain English. Which procedural word (proword) indicates that you have received another vessel's transmission?",opa:"Out",opb:"Over",opc:"Roger",opd:"Wilco",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Drilling), discharges the bulk in Bulk Tanks 1 and 2. What is the new TCG?",opa:"-1.61 feet",opb:"-1.58 feet",opc:"0.43 feet",opd:"0.99 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Production of mechanical foam by a portable in-line foam proportioner ____________.",opa:"increases the size of foam bubbles formed",opb:"increases the rate of foam production",opc:"improves the extinguishing properties of foam",opd:"gives the nozzle man more freedom of movement, since it can be placed anywhere in the hose line",ans:"opd"},{question:"All vessels not limited to daylight service shall be fitted with a ring life buoy ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"on the stern of the vessel",opb:"with a twenty fathom line attached",opc:"with no line attached",opd:"with a water light to be attached during nighttime operation",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the purpose of a fire control plan aboard passenger ships?",opa:"guidance for the officer-in-charge in the event of fire",opb:"facilitate shore-side fire fighters in fighting fire aboard the vessel",opc:"show passengers where to evacuate in event of fire",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel measures 127 feet long by 17 feet in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 7'-10' is 5 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"1.96 feet",opb:"2.24 feet",opc:"2.45 feet",opd:"2.68 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 684 tons and measures 132'L by 31'B. What is the reduction in GM due to free surface if the fish hold (32'L by 29'B by 9'D) is filled with 2 feet of water? (Each foot of water weighs 26.5 tons)",opa:"2.17 feet",opb:"2.32 feet",opc:"2.52 feet",opd:"3.01 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statements is/are TRUE in regard to Ro-Ro vessels' spaces that are 'specially suitable for vehicles'?",opa:"The spaces shall be fitted with an approved fire or smoke detecting system.",opb:"The spaces shall have designated smoking areas.",opc:"The spaces are prohibited from being fitted with fixed CO2 fire extinguishing systems.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"A U.S. merchant vessel in ocean service is NOT subject to the requirements of Annex V to MARPOL 73/78 ____________.",opa:"outside of 25 nautical miles from nearest land",opb:"outside of the navigable waters of the United States",opc:"in the waters of those countries not signatory to MARPOL",opd:"A U.S. vessel in ocean service is ALWAYS subject to MARPOL.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Metacentric height is a measure of ____________.",opa:"initial stability only",opb:"stability through all angles",opc:"maximum righting arm",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"A semisubmersible with a negative GM flops to an angle of ____________.",opa:"heel",opb:"trim",opc:"list",opd:"loll",ans:"opd"},{question:"When providing first aid to a victim of gas poisoning, the MOST important symptom to check for is ____________.",opa:"suspension of breathing",opb:"unconsciousness",opc:"slow and weak pulse",opd:"cold and moist skin",ans:"opa"},{question:"How many fire extinguishers, and what type, are required on an unmanned oil barge during transfer operations, if the barge has no cargo pumps aboard?",opa:"One B-II",opb:"Two B-II",opc:"One B-V",opd:"Two A-II",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a Mariner class cargo vessel. Your drafts are: FWD 22'-06', AFT 25'-06'. You wish to increase the calculated GM of 4.8' to 5.9'. What tanks should you ballast? (Use the white pages in the Stability Data Reference Book.)",opa:"Tanks: DB3, DB4",opb:"Tanks: DB5, DT6",opc:"Tanks: DB2, DB5",opd:"Tanks: DB2, DB6, DB7",ans:"opc"},{question:"Plastic material may be thrown overboard from a vessel which is ____________.",opa:"25 miles from shore",opb:"12 miles from shore",opc:"3 miles from shore",opd:"None of the above are correct.",ans:"opd"},{question:"An inland oil barge must have equipment available to remove an on-deck oil spill of at least ____________.",opa:"one barrel",opb:"two barrels",opc:"five barrels",opd:"ten barrels",ans:"opa"},{question:"In this view of the bridge deck on the fire control plan, what is represented by the symbol on the aft bulkhead, port side of the wheelhouse?",opa:"Fire Alarm Panel",opb:"Water Tight Door(s) Switch",opc:"Emergency Lighting Board",opd:"Copy of Fire Control Plan",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's existing draft is FWD 19'-08', AFT 20'-04'. Using the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN, determine the new draft if 840 long tons are loaded in No. 1 hatch.",opa:"FWD 18'-08', AFT21'-06'",opb:"FWD 18'-09', AFT21'-07'",opc:"FWD 18'-11', AFT21'-09'",opd:"FWD 22'-00', AFT19'-02'",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in transit during a severe storm while at a draft of 9 feet 6 inches, has a KGT of 39.1 feet and a KGL of 39.9 feet. The margin on the maximum allowable KG is ____________.",opa:"2.6 feet",opb:"3.4 feet",opc:"25.1 feet",opd:"25.9 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The international shore connection required on a MODU is designed to ____________.",opa:"permit discharge of waste oil",opb:"allow hook up of fire fighting water from a dock or another vessel",opc:"satisfy pollution prevention requirements",opd:"allow emergency use of the fire main for deballasting",ans:"opb"},{question:"A carburetor is required to have a safety device called a(n) ____________.",opa:"pressure release",opb:"backfire flame arrestor",opc:"automatic shut off",opd:"flow valve",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 24'-07', AFT 25'-09'; and the KG is 23.2 feet. What is the righting moment when the vessel is inclined to 45\xb0? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"27,008 foot-tons",opb:"29,778 foot-tons",opc:"32,428 foot-tons",opd:"34,663 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, while elevated in 200 feet of water, has 2 knots of current, 50 knots of wind, and 30 foot seas. What is the maximum leg reaction for drilling?",opa:"6,090 kips",opb:"5,980 kips",opc:"5,540 kips",opd:"5,320 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, when underway was loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). It is now preloaded at minimum air gap waiting for all settling to take place. The preload, weighing 7,191.7 kips, has LM 870,196 ft.-kips and TM 2,158 ft.-kips. What is the bow leg reaction?",opa:"7,026 kips",opb:"7,099 kips",opc:"7,144 kips",opd:"7,180 kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"Aboard the DEEP DRILLER, the bilge pumps take suction from the pump rooms, cofferdam, void area, access trunk, and ____________.",opa:"center column chain lockers",opb:"backup drill water tank",opc:"primary salt-water service tank",opd:"forward and after column chain lockers",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"395 tons",opb:"530 tons",opc:"750 tons",opd:"990 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 11'-01', AFT 15'-01'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"0.87 foot",opb:"0.98 foot",opc:"1.14 feet",opd:"1.25 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"On small passenger vessels bunks installed in overnight passenger accommodation spaces ____________.",opa:"must be no less than 74' long and 24' wide with 24' of clear space above",opb:"must not be located more than 3 high, fitted with a suitable aid to access bunks more than 5' above deck with suitable aids to access bunks more than 5' above deck",opc:"must be immediately adjacent to an aisle leading to a means of escape",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The stability of a semisubmersible MODU would be seriously reduced if flooding occurred in the ____________.",opa:"submerged hulls",opb:"column void spaces",opc:"dry mud tanks",opd:"ballast tanks",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who shall insure that all records required by regulations are retained onboard a mobile offshore drilling unit involved in a casualty?",opa:"Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection",opb:"Owner",opc:"Pilot",opd:"Engineer",ans:"opb"},{question:"Extra chemicals for producing chemical foam should be stored ____________.",opa:"in a freezer",opb:"in a cool dry place",opc:"at a temperature not less than 80\xb0F",opd:"in open bins",ans:"opb"},{question:"For each person it is certified to carry, a lifeboat on an oceangoing passenger vessel must be provided with all of the following EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"3 liters of water",opb:"1 unit of provisions",opc:"1 seasickness kit",opd:"1 life preserver",ans:"opd"},{question:"For the DEEP DRILLER, what are the transverse moments for a sounding of 5 feet in tank C3P?",opa:"1,005 foot-tons",opb:"2,139 foot-tons",opc:"-7,130 foot-tons",opd:"-10,797 foot-tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"After putting on a self-contained breathing apparatus, you open the air supply and hear a continuous ringing of a bell. What does this mean?",opa:"The unit is working properly.",opb:"The face mask is not sealed properly.",opc:"The air bottle needs to be refilled.",opd:"The air supply hose has a leak.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Annual inspection of MODU cranes shall be conducted by ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard",opb:"the person in charge",opc:"a qualified inspector",opd:"the crane operator",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which of the following statements is true concerning the control activators, i.e., pull-handles, push-buttons or levers, for a space protected by a CO2 fixed fire extinguishing system?",opa:"Only one control activator is required for discharge piping systems designed without a stop valve.",opb:"Two control activators are required when a stop valve is installed in the main discharge line to a space.",opc:"An alarm must sound for at least 20 seconds before CO2 is released into a space that is likely to be occupied.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The rescuer can best provide an airtight seal during mouth-to-mouth resuscitation by pinching the victim's nostrils and ____________.",opa:"cupping a hand around the patient's mouth",opb:"keeping the head elevated",opc:"applying his mouth tightly over the victim's mouth",opd:"holding the jaw down firmly",ans:"opc"},{question:"When retrieving the survival craft, the winch operator should stop the winch and check ____________.",opa:"that all personnel are seated in the craft",opb:"that the cable has not jumped any grooves on the drum",opc:"which way the wind is blowing",opd:"the hydraulic fluid level before lifting",ans:"opb"},{question:"The free surface effects of a partially full liquid tank decrease with increased ____________.",opa:"density of the liquid",opb:"placement of the tank above the keel",opc:"displacement volume of the MODU",opd:"size of the surface area in the tank",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 20'-08', AFT 25'-03'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the MT1.",opa:"1130 foot-tons",opb:"1095 foot-tons",opc:"1070 foot-tons",opd:"1025 foot-tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Regulations require certain records to be retained onboard for at least 3 months after a MODU is involved in a casualty or until advised that they are no longer needed onboard by the ____________.",opa:"owner",opb:"Master",opc:"person in charge",opd:"Officer in Charge, Marine Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is operating as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). Assume ballast added or discharged to remain at a constant draft is at a VCG of 10 feet. How much non-liquid load would have to be removed from an average height of 130 feet above the keel to meet the maximum allowable KG at a draft of 60 feet for winds greater than 70 knots?",opa:"373 long tons",opb:"457 long tons",opc:"484 long tons",opd:"524 long tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the proper treatment for frostbite?",opa:"rubbing affected area with ice or snow",opb:"rubbing affected area briskly to restore circulation",opc:"wrapping area tightly in warm cloths",opd:"warming exposed parts rapidly",ans:"opd"},{question:"What statement about immersion suits is TRUE?",opa:"Immersion suits should be worn while performing routine work on deck.",opb:"No stowage container for immersion suits may be capable of being locked.",opc:"During the annual maintenance, the front zipper should be lubricated using light machine oil or mineral oil.",opd:"Any tear or leak will render the suit unserviceable and it must be replaced.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is used to test a tank for oxygen content?",opa:"Combustible gas indicator",opb:"Vapor indicator",opc:"Atmosphere analyzer kit",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The stability which remains after a compartment is flooded is called ____________.",opa:"intact stability",opb:"initial stability",opc:"immersion stability",opd:"damage stability",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 40,301 foot-long tons, TM =3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons. What is the metacentric height corrected for longitudinal free surface effects?",opa:"5.66 feet",opb:"6.31 feet",opc:"7.37 feet",opd:"55.47 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A tank which is NOT completely full or empty is called ____________.",opa:"pressed",opb:"slack",opc:"inertial",opd:"elemental",ans:"opb"},{question:"On offshore drilling units when two means of escape are provided from a space above the main deck, one means of escape must be required for rapid escape to ____________.",opa:"a weather deck",opb:"the main deck",opc:"the control house",opd:"the escape capsules",ans:"opa"},{question:"Gasoline fuel tank vents should terminate ____________.",opa:"in the engine compartment",opb:"in the fuel tank space",opc:"above or outside the hull",opd:"at the most convenient location",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement concerning immersion suits is TRUE?",opa:"Immersion suits should be worn during routine work on deck to provide maximum protection.",opb:"After purchasing, the suit should be removed from its storage bag and hung on a hanger where readily accessible.",opc:"Immersion suits must have a PFD light attached to the front shoulder area.",opd:"Small leaks or tears may be repaired using the repair kit packed with the suit.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your 80-ton schooner is hove to on the starboard tack under storm trysail and fore-staysail in 45 knots of wind. Your heading is averaging about 000\xb0 true and the wind is from the northeast. There is a dangerous shoal bearing 270\xb0 true, range 5 miles. Which action would be appropriate?",opa:"You need only stay alert for changes, as your present drift will carry you away from the danger.",opb:"You should strike all sails and get underway under bare poles, making as much way as possible to the north.",opc:"You should set a reefed foresail and strike the jib.",opd:"You should tack or jibe to the port tack and make all possible headway to the south.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A passenger vessel of 600 GT is required to have how many fire axes?",opa:"6",opb:"4",opc:"2",opd:"1",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which fire control plan symbol represents a dry chemical delivery method for small scale fires?",opa:"16",opb:"47",opc:"26",opd:"48",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a life float or buoyant apparatus, the life line is ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"secured around the sides and ends in bights of not longer than three feet",opb:"woven into a net and secured in the center of the float",opc:"used for securing unconscious persons to the sides",opd:"the lanyard for securing provisions",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are making a telephone call ship-to-shore using the VHF-FM service. You can tell that the working channel is busy if you hear ____________.",opa:"speech",opb:"signaling tones",opc:"a busy signal",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement pertaining to log keeping is TRUE?",opa:"Entries relating to pre-voyage, pre-departure and daily tests are required",opb:"Both A and C",opc:"All Distress, Urgent and Safety communications that affect the station's own ship must be logged",opd:"Routine daily MF-HF and INMARSAT-C transmissions do not have to be logged",ans:"opb"},{question:"No person onboard any vessel to which Annex V to MARPOL 73/78 applies may discharge garbage of any type when ____________.",opa:"less than 12 nautical miles from the United States",opb:"less than 12 nautical miles from nearest land",opc:"in the navigable waters of the United States",opd:"less than 25 nautical miles from nearest land",ans:"opc"},{question:"The only type of helicopter that may be refueled with the engine running and the blades turning is ____________.",opa:"a helicopter carrying cargo only",opb:"a turbine-equipped helicopter",opc:"a Sikorsky",opd:"a helicopter carrying injured personnel in an emergency situation",ans:"opb"},{question:"Many vessels are provided with flume tanks, which also have a dump tank located under the flume tanks. In the event the ship is damaged, you could dump the flume tanks into the dump tank which would ____________.",opa:"reduce the free surface effect and raise the KG",opb:"not have any effect on free surface and raise the KG",opc:"reduce the free surface effect and lower the KG",opd:"not have any effect on free surface and lower the KG",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a vessel lists to port, the center of buoyancy will ____________.",opa:"move to port",opb:"move to starboard",opc:"move directly down",opd:"stay in the same position",ans:"opa"},{question:"The central longitudinal structural hull strength member of the lower hulls of semisubmersible MODU's is called the ____________.",opa:"stress plate",opb:"keel",opc:"rider plate",opd:"main beam",ans:"opb"},{question:"An emergency sea anchor may be constructed by using ____________.",opa:"a boat bucket",opb:"an air tank filled with water",opc:"an oar and canvas weighted down",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 3684 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 28.4 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 27.0 feet",opb:"KG 27.6 feet",opc:"KG 28.2 feet",opd:"KG 28.8 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are in a lifeboat when you sight the stars as shown. You will be heading due north when you head for Polaris which is indicated by which letter?",opa:"E",opb:"F",opc:"G",opd:"H",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to regulations, how many B-II hand portable fire extinguishers are required in the cargo tank area of an unmanned, cargo pump-equipped tank barge engaged in transferring grade B flammable liquids?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"None",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who is responsible for reporting a casualty to a mobile offshore drilling unit?",opa:"The pilot",opb:"The owner",opc:"The surveyor",opd:"The engineer",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1171.5 tons",opb:"1311.0 tons",opc:"1503.0 tons",opd:"1710.5 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the event the motion of the DEEP DRILLER is such that critical motion limits are exceeded, you should ____________.",opa:"place the unit at 65 foot draft",opb:"place the unit at 45 foot draft",opc:"shift loads to increase KG",opd:"place the unit in standby",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the new location of the transverse center of gravity if 200 short tons are placed 10 feet to port of the centerline on a MODU with TCG 0.7 foot starboard of the centerline, and displacement 9,000 short tons?",opa:"0.47 foot starboard of centerline",opb:"0.40 foot starboard of centerline",opc:"0.23 foot port of centerline",opd:"0.20 foot port of centerline",ans:"opa"},{question:"When you are firing a pyrotechnic distress signal, it should be aimed ____________.",opa:"horizontally and directly abeam of your vessel",opb:"at the vessel whose attention you want to attract",opc:"into the wind",opd:"at greater than 60 degrees above the horizon",ans:"opd"},{question:"The required amount of water for each person in a lifeboat on an oceangoing vessel, on an international voyage, is ____________.",opa:"1 liter",opb:"2 liters",opc:"3 liters",opd:"4 liters",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), discharges a non-liquid load of 275.8 long tons from a position 130 feet above the keel, 40 feet forward of amidships, and 30 feet to port of the centerline. What is the new LCG?",opa:"0.59 foot",opb:"1.64 feet",opc:"2.23 feet",opd:"2.82 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The only portable electrical equipment permitted in a compartment which is not gas free is a lamp that is ____________.",opa:"battery fed",opb:"self-contained",opc:"approved explosion proof",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"An inflatable liferaft is thrown into the water from a sinking vessel. Which action occurs automatically after the painter trips the CO2 bottles to inflate the raft?",opa:"The sea anchor is deployed.",opb:"The floor inflates.",opc:"If upside down, the raft will right itself.",opd:"The painter detaches from the raft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The draft of the DEEP DRILLER in the lightweight condition is ____________.",opa:"16.19 feet",opb:"17.71 feet",opc:"17.96 feet",opd:"18.35 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of a striker plate?",opa:"Provides surface for applying force on machinery",opb:"Provides landing surface for the sounding bob",opc:"Absorbs machinery vibration",opd:"Prevents valve stem over-travel",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are underway when a fire breaks out in the forward part of your vessel. If possible, you should ____________.",opa:"put the vessel's stern into the wind",opb:"abandon ship to windward",opc:"call for assistance",opd:"keep going at half speed",ans:"opa"},{question:"For the purposes of the International Rules of the Road, a non-self-propelled, semisubmersible drilling unit under tow is considered to be a ____________.",opa:"power-driven vessel",opb:"limited vessel",opc:"non-displacement vessel",opd:"vessel",ans:"opd"},{question:"When the remote push button located in the wheelhouse, starboard side, frame 122, is actuated, what is the result?",opa:"Engine room water tight doors are secured",opb:"Ventilation ducts are secured",opc:"CO2 or Halon extinguishing systems will be energized",opd:"The general alarm will sound the fire and emergency signal",ans:"opb"},{question:"46 CFR Subchapter T requires that rigid plastic or other nonmetallic piping ____________.",opa:"only be used in non-vital systems",opb:"not be used in gasoline or diesel fuel systems",opc:"have approved metallic fittings and cutoff valves where it penetrates a watertight deck or bulkhead",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 23'-03', AFT 27'-01'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the MT1.",opa:"1050 foot-tons",opb:"1065 foot-tons",opc:"1090 foot-tons",opd:"1130 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is used as an indicator of initial stability?",opa:"GM",opb:"KG",opc:"KM",opd:"GZ",ans:"opa"},{question:"A fire pump may be used for other purposes if ____________.",opa:"the other services are run off a reducing station with a pressure gage",opb:"one of the required pumps is kept available for use on the fire main system at all times",opc:"no relief valves are installed",opd:"all of the above conditions are met",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the purpose of a vent header?",opa:"Prevents entry of water into vent systems",opb:"Prevents passage of flame into fuel tanks",opc:"Catches overflow",opd:"Combines individual vent lines into a main",ans:"opd"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, any reports of a casualty that are made are required to be retained onboard for a period of at least ____________.",opa:"3 months",opb:"6 months",opc:"12 months",opd:"24 months",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have approximately 34 tons of fish on deck. What will be the shift in the center of gravity after you shift the fish to the fish hold, a vertical distance of 7.5 feet? (total displacement is 638 tons)",opa:"0.1 foot",opb:"0.2 foot",opc:"0.3 foot",opd:"0.4 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"The center of buoyancy is located at the ____________.",opa:"geometric center of the waterplane area",opb:"intersection of the vertical centerline and line of action of the buoyant force",opc:"center of gravity of the vessel corrected for free surface effects",opd:"geometric center of the displaced volume",ans:"opd"},{question:"The center of buoyancy and the metacenter are in the line of action of the buoyant force ____________.",opa:"only when there is positive stability",opb:"only when there is negative stability",opc:"only when there is neutral stability",opd:"at all times",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a sail is reefed, the sail area is ____________.",opa:"reduced",opb:"increased",opc:"widened",opd:"unchanged",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Master or person in charge of a MODU is required to submit a casualty report of an intentional grounding when it ____________.",opa:"creates a hazard to the vessel",opb:"will last longer than 24 hours",opc:"will last longer than 48 hours",opd:"occurs in international waters",ans:"opa"},{question:"At all angles of inclination, the true measure of a vessel's stability is the ____________.",opa:"metacentric height",opb:"displacement",opc:"righting moment",opd:"inclining moment",ans:"opc"},{question:"What best describes for how long a gas-free test is good?",opa:"For as long as is indicated on the gas-free certificate",opb:"For the instant that it is made",opc:"Until valves in line with the tank or compartment are reopened",opd:"Until changes in temperature or pressure affect the vapor content in the space",ans:"opb"},{question:"Among the valves on the DEEP DRILLER which may be opened when using the Salt-Water Service Pump to pump water into Tank 1P is ____________.",opa:"33",opb:"36",opc:"46",opd:"48",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the spoken emergency signal for a distress signal over a VHF radio?",opa:"Red Alert",opb:"Security",opc:"Mayday",opd:"Pan",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the air temperature is just below 32\xb0F, snow FIRST adheres to ____________.",opa:"surfaces near the waterline",opb:"vertical surfaces",opc:"horizontal surfaces",opd:"leeward surfaces",ans:"opc"},{question:"Channel 13 (156.65 MHz), the designated bridge-to-bridge channel, may NOT be used to ____________.",opa:"exchange navigational information between vessels",opb:"exchange navigational information between a vessel and a shore station",opc:"conduct necessary tests",opd:"exchange operating schedules with company dispatcher",ans:"opd"},{question:"A person has suffered a laceration of the arm. Severe bleeding has been controlled by using a sterile dressing and direct pressure. What should you do next?",opa:"Apply a tourniquet to prevent the bleeding from restarting.",opb:"Apply a pressure bandage over the dressing.",opc:"Remove any small foreign matter and apply antiseptic.",opd:"Administer fluids to assist the body in replacing the lost blood.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which fire-fighting agent is most effective at removing heat?",opa:"Water spray",opb:"Foam",opc:"Carbon dioxide",opd:"Dry chemical",ans:"opa"},{question:"A 50-foot passenger vessel not limited to daylight operation is required to be equipped with at least ____________.",opa:"1 ring life buoy with a water light",opb:"2 ring life buoys with a water light",opc:"2 ring life buoys with 2 water lights",opd:"3 ring life buoys with 2 water lights",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 17'-07', AFT 16'-09'; and the KG is 24.8 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 15\xb0 inclination.",opa:"0.7 foot",opb:"1.2 feet",opc:"1.9 feet",opd:"4.8 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A fire pump on a MODU requires 175 psi discharge pressure to maintain the required 50 psi pitot tube pressure at the two highest hydrants. The maximum setting for the relief valve is ____________.",opa:"125 psi",opb:"175 psi",opc:"200 psi",opd:"225 psi",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which license or document enable a person to serve as person in charge of a tank barge which is transferring cargo?",opa:"Operator of Uninspected Towing Vessels",opb:"Certified Tankerman",opc:"Able Seaman",opd:"Ordinary Seaman/Wiper",ans:"opb"},{question:"A cargo of 100 tons is to be loaded on deck 20 feet from the ship's centerline. The ship's displacement including the 100 tons of cargo will be 10,000 tons and the GM two feet. The list of the vessel after loading this cargo will be ____________.",opa:"5.4\xb0",opb:"5.7\xb0",opc:"5.9\xb0",opd:"6.1\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your sailing drafts are: FWD 19'-06', AFT 20'-10' and the GM is 3.3 feet. What will be the angle of list if the #2 starboard deep tank (capacity 100 tons, VCG 19.1 feet, and 24 feet off the centerline) is filled? (Use the data in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"Less than 1\xb0",opb:"2\xb0",opc:"4\xb0",opd:"6\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"What would NOT be a good extinguishing agent for a grade B product of 1,3-Pentadiene?",opa:"Dry chemical",opb:"CO2",opc:"Foam",opd:"Water",ans:"opd"},{question:"What would be an example of a B-I extinguisher? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"2.5 gallon foam",opb:"10 pound carbon dioxide",opc:"2 pound dry chemical",opd:"5 pound foam",ans:"opc"},{question:"The symbol 5 as shown represents ____________.",opa:"displacement",opb:"leverage center",opc:"centerline",opd:"counter flood limits",ans:"opc"},{question:"When abandoning a MODU, after launching the survival craft you should ____________.",opa:"plot a course for the nearest land",opb:"take a vote on which direction you should go",opc:"stay in the immediate area",opd:"go in one direction until fuel runs out",ans:"opc"},{question:"During loading and discharging operations, in addition to when the cargo tanks have been properly filled, each inert gas system must be capable of maintaining a minimum gas pressure of ____________.",opa:"150 millimeters of water pressure",opb:"125 millimeters of water pressure",opc:"100 millimeters of water pressure",opd:"75 millimeters of water pressure",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel measures 131 feet long by 20 feet in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 8'-03' is 6 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"1.26 feet",opb:"1.74 feet",opc:"1.93 feet",opd:"2.15 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"When retrieving the survival craft, the helmsman should instruct the crewman to ____________.",opa:"check the fuel level",opb:"open the doors",opc:"take the life preservers off",opd:"check that hooks are fully locked in place",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning distress signals in a lifeboat?",opa:"Hand held flares and orange smoke signals are required.",opb:"If hand-held rocket-propelled parachute flares are provided, they are the only distress signals required.",opc:"Two hand-held smoke signals shall be provided.",opd:"A Very pistol with twelve flares is required.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The free surface effects of a partially-full tank in a floating MODU increase with the ____________.",opa:"surface area of the fluid in the tank",opb:"displacement volume of the MODU",opc:"draft of the MODU",opd:"height of the tank above the keel",ans:"opa"},{question:"Foam is a very effective smothering agent and ____________.",opa:"it provides cooling as a secondary effect",opb:"works well on extinguishing electrical fires",opc:"can be used to combat combustible metal fires",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Viewing the bridge level of your vessel\u2019s fire control plan, what do the two symbols within the machinery casing represent?",opa:"CO2 and Halon bell alarms",opb:"CO2 and Halon remote pull stations",opc:"CO2 and Halon bottle room",opd:"CO2 and Halon protected spaces",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a vessel\u2019s fire control plan, the symbol( 64) refers to a ____________.",opa:"infrared gas detector",opb:"dry chemical installation",opc:"inertial gauge",opd:"inert gas installation",ans:"opd"},{question:"In order for combustion to occur inside a piping system such as a vapor collection header in a marine emission control system, there must be ____________.",opa:"fuel",opb:"oxygen",opc:"ignition",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the proper method to fix running rigging to a cleat?",opa:"Half-hitches then a round turn",opb:"One round turn",opc:"A series of half-hitches",opd:"A round turn, figure eights, and a half-hitch",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about the hospital space on a cargo ship is TRUE?",opa:"The hospital may be used for disciplinary confinement if it is not being used for treatment.",opb:"The hospital space must have both a bathtub and shower.",opc:"A hospital is required on all vessels with a crew of 12 or more if it makes overnight voyages.",opd:"If a ship has a crew of forty-five who do not have their own room, the hospital must have four berths.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement describes the primary process by which fires are extinguished by dry chemical?",opa:"The stream of dry chemical powder cools the fire.",opb:"The dry chemical powder attacks the fuel and oxygen chain reaction.",opc:"The powder forms a solid coating over the surface.",opd:"The dry chemical smothers the fire.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the weight of the mud in pit #4 if the sounding level changed from 8 to 6 feet?",opa:"80.00 long tons",opb:"77.75 long tons",opc:"83.34 long tons",opd:"106.67 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 750 tons and measures 151'L by 35'B. What is the reduction in GM due to free surface if the fish hold (60'L by 31'B by 10'D) is filled with 3.5 feet of water? (Each foot of water weighs 53.1 tons)",opa:"4.14 feet",opb:"4.38 feet",opc:"4.55 feet",opd:"4.94 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"4.0 feet",opb:"5.6 feet",opc:"6.0 feet",opd:"6.8 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is a B-II fire extinguisher? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"A 2-1/2 gallon water (stored pressure) extinguisher",opb:"A 15 lb. CO2extinguisher",opc:"A 2 lb. dry chemical extinguisher",opd:"A 1-1/4 gallon foam extinguisher",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's existing draft is FWD 25'-04', AFT 24'-08'. Using the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN, determine the new draft if 634 long tons are discharged from NO. 19 hatch.",opa:"FWD 25'-00 1/4',AFT 25'-04 1/8'",opb:"FWD 25'-02 3/4',AFT 23'-08 5/8'",opc:"FWD 25'-05 1/4',AFT 23'-08 5/8'",opd:"FWD 25'-10 1/4',AFT 23'-11 3/4'",ans:"opc"},{question:"BOTH INTERNATIONAL & INLAND Unless the rules require otherwise, a sailing vessel must keep out of the way of ____________.",opa:"an overtaking vessel",opb:"a pilot vessel on station",opc:"another sailing vessel on a crossing course",opd:"a vessel trawling",ans:"opd"},{question:"Before CPR is started, you should ____________.",opa:"establish an open airway",opb:"treat any bleeding wounds",opc:"insure the victim is conscious",opd:"make the victim comfortable",ans:"opa"},{question:"Regulations require that cargo pumprooms on tank barges (constructed in 1965) carrying grades B or C liquid cargoes have power ventilation systems which can completely change the air in ____________.",opa:"1 minute",opb:"3 minutes",opc:"5 minutes",opd:"10 minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"In the case of a casualty involving a MODU, the Master, owner, agent or person in charge shall make the records required by regulation available upon request to ____________.",opa:"anyone involved in the casualty",opb:"any Coast Guard official authorized to investigate the casualty",opc:"the local Captain of the Port",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"For the DEEP DRILLER, What are the vertical moments for a sounding of 10 feet in tank C3P?",opa:"1,055 foot-tons",opb:"4,754 foot-tons",opc:"14,621 foot-tons",opd:"17,113 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"3.9 feet",opb:"4.3 feet",opc:"4.7 feet",opd:"5.1 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER suffers minor flooding of the starboard pump room while in transit. If both starboard bilge pumps fail to dewater the pump room, you may use ____________.",opa:"starboard drill water pump",opb:"starboard saltwater service pump",opc:"starboard ballast pumps",opd:"port ballast pumps and crossover system",ans:"opa"},{question:"Lines or gear NOT in use should be ____________.",opa:"conspicuously marked",opb:"stowed anywhere",opc:"left on deck",opd:"secured or stowed out of the way",ans:"opd"},{question:"A small passenger vessel of not more than 65 feet in length must have a collision bulkhead if it ____________.",opa:"operates on exposed waters",opb:"carries more than 49 passengers",opc:"is more than 40 feet in length and operates on partially exposed waters",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The number of kips necessary to change the true mean draft of a MODU one inch is known as ____________.",opa:"MT1 inch",opb:"MH1 inch",opc:"KPI",opd:"KMD",ans:"opc"},{question:"Progressive flooding on a MODU is controlled by securing watertight boundaries and ____________.",opa:"transferring drill water",opb:"dumping bulk materials",opc:"pumping out flooded compartments",opd:"evacuating the unit",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel has just finished bunkering and has a small list due to improper distribution of the fuel oil. This list will cause ____________.",opa:"a decrease in reserve buoyancy",opb:"a decrease in the maximum draft",opc:"the vessel to flop to port and starboard",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is a grooved pulley?",opa:"Sheave",opb:"Slip",opc:"Block",opd:"Reeve",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which of the following statements is/are FALSE in regard to Ro-Ro vessels' spaces that are 'specially suitable for vehicles'?",opa:"The spaces shall NOT be fitted with a flame detecting system.",opb:"The spaces shall be fitted with an approved fixed CO2 fire extinguishing system.",opc:"As an alternative to a fixed CO2 system, the Commandant may permit a water sprinkler system.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the bypass valve of a self-contained breathing device is opened, the air flows ____________.",opa:"directly to the face piece",opb:"directly to the air supply bottle",opc:"through the regulator",opd:"from the bottle into the atmosphere",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 10'-04', AFT 14'-08'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1.91 feet",opb:"2.09 feet",opc:"2.21 feet",opd:"2.48 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A crew member is having an epileptic convulsion. You should ____________.",opa:"give the victim artificial respiration",opb:"completely restrain the victim",opc:"give the victim one 30 mg. tablet of phenobarbital",opd:"keep the victim from injuring him or herself",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which of the following statements is/are FALSE in regard to Ro-Ro vessels' spaces that are 'specially suitable for vehicles'?",opa:"The spaces shall be fitted with an approved fire or smoke detecting system.",opb:"The spaces shall be fitted with an approved fixed fire extinguishing system.",opc:"The installation of a water sprinkler extinguishing system is prohibited.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Repair of vital machinery and services on a MODU should be accomplished ____________.",opa:"after control of fire, flooding, and structural repairs",opb:"immediately",opc:"after control of fire, but before control of flooding",opd:"after stability is restored",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Sailing Plan, required by vessels participating in AMVER, must be sent ____________.",opa:"within a few hours before or after departure",opb:"prior to departure",opc:"within 24 hours of departure",opd:"within 12 hours of departure",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are in the process of righting an inflatable liferaft that has inflated in an upside down position. Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"As the raft flips to the upright position, you will be thrown clear.",opb:"After the raft is in the upright position on top of you, dive down to prevent your life preservers from fouling as you come out.",opc:"Swim out from under the raft in a face up position to keep your life preservers clear of the raft.",opd:"You should remove your life preservers before attempting to right an inflatable raft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"The limit switches on a MODUs survival-craft winch system ____________.",opa:"stop the winch just before the craft reaches the final stowage position",opb:"limit the amount of cable on the drum",opc:"limit the ascent rate",opd:"stop the winch in case the craft weighs too much",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, what is NOT a recommended extinguishing agent for an ethyl chloride fire?",opa:"CO2",opb:"Alcohol foam",opc:"Dry chemical",opd:"Water fog",ans:"opb"},{question:"The signal to guide vessels in distress, which indicates, 'This is the best place to land' is the ____________.",opa:"horizontal motion of a white flag",opb:"letter K in Morse code given by light",opc:"code flag S as a hoist",opd:"firing of a white star signal",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You must keep a record of garbage discharged in port to a shore facility.",opb:"You need not keep a record of dumping ground garbage in to the sea more than 25 miles offshore.",opc:"You must keep a record of the approximate weight of the garbage dumped.",opd:"You need not keep a record of garbage incinerated on the ship.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Licenses are issued for ____________.",opa:"3 years",opb:"5 years",opc:"1 year",opd:"2 years",ans:"opb"},{question:"A MODU crane which has been idle for a period of over six months shall be inspected to the same standards as a ____________.",opa:"yearly inspection",opb:"quarterly inspection",opc:"monthly inspection",opd:"weekly inspection",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1171.5 tons",opb:"1311.0 tons",opc:"1503.0 tons",opd:"1710.5 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a sail is reefed, the sail area is ____________.",opa:"reduced",opb:"increased",opc:"widened",opd:"unchanged",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel measures 126 feet (38.41 meters) long by 21 feet (6.4 meters) in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 8 feet (2.44 meters) is 6 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"2.4 feet (0.70 meters)",opb:"2.8 feet (0.85 meters)",opc:"3.0 feet (0.90 meters)",opd:"3.2 feet (0.98 meters)",ans:"opa"},{question:"After conducting a boat drill on a mobile offshore drilling unit, what must the Master or person in charge enter in the in the logbook?",opa:"Any inoperative equipment and the corrective action taken",opb:"The name of the lifeboatman in charge of each lifeboat",opc:"The location of the vessel at the time of the drill",opd:"The time it took to lower the boat",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel has been holed in #1 hold and partially flooded. The hole is plugged against further flooding. In calculating the effect of the flooding on your transverse stability, you should use which method?",opa:"Compartment standard method",opb:"Lost buoyancy method",opc:"Factor of subdivision method",opd:"Added weight method",ans:"opd"},{question:"Hand held red flares expire 42 months from the date of manufacture. Floating orange smoke distress signals expire after how many months?",opa:"18 months",opb:"24 months",opc:"42 months",opd:"60 months",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the liferaft capsizes, all personnel should leave the raft and ____________.",opa:"climb onto the bottom",opb:"swim away from the raft",opc:"right the raft using the righting strap",opd:"inflate the righting bag",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is one of the FIRST things you would do onboarding an inflatable liferaft?",opa:"Open equipment pack.",opb:"Post a lookout.",opc:"Issue anti-seasickness medicine.",opd:"Pick up other survivors.",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a small passenger vessel, 58 feet in length, carrying 52 passengers the fire pump shall have a minimum pumping capacity of ____________.",opa:"10 gallons per minute",opb:"25 gallons per minute",opc:"50 gallons per minute",opd:"100 gallons per minute",ans:"opc"},{question:"In illustration D041DG, the symbol for amidships is ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"5",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Drilling), dumps all the mud in pits 1, 2, 3, and 4. What is the new LCG?",opa:"122.02 feet AFO",opb:"125.03 feet AFO",opc:"125.63 feet AFO",opd:"131.46 feet AFO",ans:"opc"},{question:"If there's a fire aboard your vessel, you should FIRST ____________.",opa:"notify the Coast Guard",opb:"sound the alarm",opc:"have passengers put on life preservers",opd:"cut off air supply to the fire",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning gasoline vapors onboard a vessel?",opa:"They are heavier than air and will settle in the lowest part of the vessel.",opb:"They are lighter than air and will settle in the highest part of the vessel.",opc:"They should be vented into the engine to improve combustion.",opd:"They should be vented into the wheelhouse.",ans:"opa"},{question:"How often does a coast radio station that regularly broadcasts traffic lists transmit the list?",opa:"As often as is deemed necessary to effect delivery",opb:"No less often than every four hours",opc:"Only on an as-needed basis",opd:"Once per 24-hour period",ans:"opb"},{question:"What must be carried out in order to launch and inflate an inflatable liferaft?",opa:"Pull on the hydrostatic release, pull on the sea painter.",opb:"Push on the hydrostatic release, pull on the sea painter.",opc:"Push on the hydrostatic release, push on the sea painter.",opd:"Pull on the hydrostatic release, push on the sea painter.",ans:"opb"},{question:"To determine the number of Able Seamen required on a mobile offshore drilling unit, you should check the ____________.",opa:"load line certificate",opb:"Operations Manual",opc:"Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opd:"Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4, (Drilling). In preparing for approaching heavy weather, the four leeward mooring lines are slacked. These actions reduce the ____________.",opa:"natural pitch period",opb:"metacentric height",opc:"height of the righting arm",opd:"righting moment",ans:"opa"},{question:"The Master or person in charge of a MODU is required to log ____________.",opa:"the date and hour of each fire drill",opb:"the names of all persons onboard",opc:"only casualties which occur while underway",opd:"every event occurring onboard",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the height of the metacenter has the same value as the height of the center of gravity, the metacentric height is equal to ____________.",opa:"the height of the metacenter",opb:"the height of the center of gravity",opc:"the same as half the height of the metacenter",opd:"zero",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about immersion suits is TRUE?",opa:"Prior to abandonment, the suit allows body movement such as walking, climbing a ladder and picking up small objects.",opb:"The immersion suit seals in body heat and provides protection against hypothermia for weeks.",opc:"The suit is flameproof and provides protection to the wearer while swimming through burning oil.",opd:"The wearer of the suit is severely restricted and requires twice the time to climb a ladder than without the suit",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 60 feet, has a KGL of 55.4 feet and an LCG of 2.37 feet. What is the trim in feet?",opa:"2.0 feet by the head",opb:"4.0 feet by the head",opc:"4.0 feet by the stern",opd:"8.0 feet by the stern",ans:"opb"},{question:"BOTH INTERNATIONAL & INLAND You are under sail and overtaking a tug and tow. Which action is correct?",opa:"The power-driven tug must maneuver to avoid collision.",opb:"You must maneuver to avoid the tug and tow.",opc:"You must maneuver to avoid collision only if the tug is to leeward and the wind is on your port side.",opd:"Both vessels are required to maneuver to avoid collision.",ans:"opb"},{question:"In storm conditions, when the environmental conditions are such that the DEEP DRILLER has disconnected the marine riser, the two leeward mooring lines should be ____________.",opa:"tightened",opb:"slacked slightly",opc:"completely slacked",opd:"adjusted to give the same line tensions as the windward lines",ans:"opc"},{question:"Introducing inert gas into a tank already inert with the object of further reducing the oxygen or hydrocarbon content to prevent combustion if air enters the tank is called ____________.",opa:"purging",opb:"gas freeing",opc:"gas dispersion",opd:"bonding",ans:"opa"},{question:"The height of the transverse metacenter for a MODU is 62.44 feet. The height of the center of gravity is 56.10 feet, and the transverse free surface correction is 1.21 feet. What is the value of the metacentric height corrected for transverse free surface effects?",opa:"5.13 feet",opb:"6.34 feet",opc:"8.76 feet",opd:"12.10 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A barge displaying a 2' X 3' white sign with the word 'WARNING' followed by 'DANGEROUS CARGO' in black letters ____________.",opa:"would require that a cargo information card be carried in the pilothouse of the towboat",opb:"may not be spotted next to the towboat while under tow",opc:"may not be in the same tow as a barge carrying gasoline",opd:"must be located as a lead barge in a tow",ans:"opa"},{question:"Before welding in a tank that has carried petroleum products, the tank must be certified by ____________.",opa:"the Coast Guard",opb:"the American Bureau of Shipping",opc:"the shipyard fire department",opd:"a certified marine chemist",ans:"opd"},{question:"To what distance below the hull must the legs of the COASTAL DRILLER be lowered in order to meet the stability and leg strength requirements during the wind speeds greater than 70 knots?",opa:"0.0 feet",opb:"1.2 feet",opc:"25.0 feet",opd:"60.5 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #5 (Survival) when an unexpected slowly increasing port list and bow down trim occurs. A leak in C1P is found. By deballasting from ballast tanks 2P and 3P, the inclination slowly decreases. The increase in the transverse free surface correction is ____________.",opa:"1.25 feet",opb:"0.82 foot",opc:"0.34 foot",opd:"0.18 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"A non-symmetrical tank aboard a MODU contains 390 tons of ballast at a VCG of 9.85 feet. Ballast weighing 250 tons and a VCG of 12.0 feet is discharged. The vertical moments for the remaining ballast is ____________.",opa:"842 ft.-long tons",opb:"3,000 ft.-long tons",opc:"3,842 ft.-long tons",opd:"6,842 ft.-long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"The VHF radiotelephone frequency designated to be used only to transmit or receive information pertaining to the safe navigation of a vessel is ____________.",opa:"156.8 MHz (channel 16)",opb:"156.7 MHz (channel 14)",opc:"156.65 MHz (channel 13)",opd:"156.6 MHz (channel 12)",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the fundamental purpose for imposing radio silence?",opa:"To ensure that interference to proprietary communications is minimized",opb:"To ensure that only voice communications can be effected on the distress frequency or channel",opc:"To ensure that a distressed vessel will have a 'window' twice each hour for transmitting routine messages",opd:"To ensure that interference on a particular frequency or channel to communications concerning emergency traffic is minimized",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which statement about pneumatic chipping tools is TRUE?",opa:"The equipment shall be secured to the hose by a quick-disconnect coupling to prevent the tool from becoming accidentally disconnected.",opb:"The equipment must be grounded to prevent shock hazard.",opc:"The chipping mechanism is made of non-sparking material that is safe to use near explosive atmospheres.",opd:"The needles of the needle-type chipping gun must be replaced when they have been blunted more than \xbd of their diameter.",ans:"opa"},{question:"A tank which carries liquid is dangerous to the stability of a vessel when it is ____________.",opa:"low in the vessel",opb:"completely empty",opc:"completely full",opd:"slack",ans:"opd"},{question:"The immersion suit requirements for OSV apply to units operating in the Atlantic Ocean ____________.",opa:"above 20 degrees North and below 20 degrees South",opb:"above 25 degrees North and below 25 degrees South",opc:"above 30 degrees North and below 30 degrees South",opd:"above 32 degrees North and below 32 degrees South",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which system has the least effective radius of operation?",opa:"HF SITOR",opb:"MF NBDP",opc:"VHF DSC",opd:"NAVTEX",ans:"opc"},{question:"Consideration should be given in planning for the mooring orientation in a new location so that in adverse weather a crane is available to off-load the supply vessel on what side of the unit?",opa:"Weather side",opb:"Leeward side",opc:"Upwind side",opd:"Crosswind side",ans:"opb"},{question:"A MODU displacing 28,000 long tons has a KG of 60 feet. A weight of 500 long tons is discharged from a VCG of 150 feet. To maintain draft, ballast is added at a VCG of 10 feet. What is the change in KG?",opa:"2.5 feet downward",opb:"2.0 feet downward",opc:"1.5 feet downward",opd:"1.0 foot downward",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), discharges a non-liquid load of 275.8 long tons from a position 130 feet above the keel, 40 feet forward of amidships, and 30 feet to port of the centerline. What is the new GMT?",opa:"5.98 feet",opb:"6.84 feet",opc:"7.11 feet",opd:"9.24 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The effects of free surface on initial stability depend upon the dimensions of the surface of the free liquids and the ____________.",opa:"volume of liquid in the tank",opb:"volume of displacement of the MODU",opc:"location of the tank in the MODU",opd:"height of the center of gravity of the MODU",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is elevated in 192 feet of water. Leg penetration is 83 feet. The maximum leg reaction is 5,940 kips. The waves are 30 feet and the current is 2 knots. What is the maximum wind for drilling?",opa:"45 knots",opb:"50 knots",opc:"57 knots",opd:"62 knots",ans:"opb"},{question:"When properly set and drawing, a fore-and-aft sail has a cross-section that ____________.",opa:"is a uniform curve",opb:"is a curve with more curve at the luff",opc:"is a curve with more curve at the leach",opd:"approximates a straight line",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the DEEP DRILLER, when using the starboard #2 ballast pump to provide water to the main deck from the sea, it is necessary to open valves ____________.",opa:"37, 35, 36, 45",opb:"37, 36, 46, 47",opc:"38, 47",opd:"38, 47, 45, 46",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), discharges a non-liquid load of 275.8 long tons from a position 130 feet above the keel, 40 feet forward of amidships, and 30 feet to port of the centerline. What is the resulting list angle?",opa:"2.11 degrees to port",opb:"1.43 degrees to starboard",opc:"2.87 degrees to starboard",opd:"3.02 degrees to starboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"Backfire flame arrestors are installed on ____________.",opa:"fuel tanks",opb:"spark plugs",opc:"carburetors",opd:"distributors",ans:"opc"},{question:"All vessels not required to have a power driven fire pump shall carry ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"a suitable, detachable pump usable for fire fighting purposes",opb:"at least three 2-1/2 gallon fire buckets",opc:"an emergency hand fire and bilge pump",opd:"not less than three hand fire pumps",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the change in longitudinal moments for the DEEP DRILLER if 103.48 long tons of ballast is discharged from a full ballast tank 1P?",opa:"10,944 foot-tons decrease",opb:"7,761 foot-tons decrease",opc:"6,707 foot-tons decrease",opd:"155 foot-tons decrease",ans:"opa"},{question:"Fire protection regulations for towing vessels require training in all of the following, EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"putting on a fireman's outfit, if the vessel is so equipped",opb:"donning a self-contained breathing apparatus, if the vessel is so equipped",opc:"activating the general alarm and reporting inoperative alarm systems and fire-detection systems",opd:"refilling and servicing all expended fire extinguishing equipment",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a commercial fishing vessel, a wearable personal flotation device must be marked with the name of the ____________.",opa:"vessel",opb:"assigned individual",opc:"owner of the device",opd:"Any of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 22'-03', AFT 22'-09'; and the KG is 24.4 feet. What is the righting moment when the vessel is inclined to 15\xb0? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"4,176 foot-tons",opb:"5,916 foot-tons",opc:"7,076 foot-tons",opd:"9,003 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"A device used to enlarge the size of an existing bore hole, having teeth arranged on its outside circumference to cut the formation as it rotates is a(n) ____________.",opa:"enlarger bit",opb:"casing bit",opc:"hole opener",opd:"casing opener",ans:"opc"},{question:"To determine the number of certificated Lifeboatmen required on a mobile offshore drilling unit, you should check the ____________.",opa:"load line certificate",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opd:"Operations Manual",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a vessel\u2019s fire control plan, the symbol (30) refers to a ____________.",opa:"foam station",opb:"fuel shutoff",opc:"fire station",opd:"none of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"When must a MODU display navigation lights while underway?",opa:"Only between sunrise and sunset",opb:"At all times while being towed",opc:"Only when other vessels are in sight",opd:"Whenever visibility is restricted",ans:"opd"},{question:"A small passenger vessel operating on exposed or partially protected waters may not have a port light below the weather deck unless ____________.",opa:"its sill is at least 30 inches above the deepest load waterline",opb:"it opens and has a solid, inside, hinged cover",opc:"it is made of thick transparent plastic",opd:"it is sealed shut",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"4.0 feet",opb:"5.6 feet",opc:"6.0 feet",opd:"6.8 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Unstable equilibrium exists at small angles of inclination when ____________.",opa:"G is above M",opb:"G is off the centerline",opc:"B is off the centerline",opd:"B is above G",ans:"opa"},{question:"A fixed carbon dioxide extinguishing system for a machinery space, designed WITHOUT a stop valve in the line leading to the protected space, is actuated by ____________.",opa:"one control",opb:"two controls",opc:"three controls",opd:"none of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"A 'fifteen-pound' CO2 extinguisher is so called because ____________.",opa:"there are fifteen pounds of CO2 in the container",opb:"the container, when full, weighs fifteen pounds",opc:"the pressure at the discharge nozzle is l5 psi",opd:"the empty container weighs fifteen pounds",ans:"opa"},{question:"BOTH INTERNATIONAL & INLAND A sailing vessel must keep course and speed when ____________.",opa:"being overtaken",opb:"to windward of another sailing vessel",opc:"to leeward of another sailing vessel",opd:"crossing a vessel engaged in fishing",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the first 24 hours after abandoning a vessel, water should be given only to personnel who are ____________.",opa:"thirsty",opb:"sick or injured",opc:"wet",opd:"awake",ans:"opb"},{question:"Using the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, determine the danger angle for permanent list if the KG is 22.2 feet and the drafts are: FWD 23'-06', AFT 24'-03'.",opa:"26\xb0",opb:"30\xb0",opc:"34\xb0",opd:"53\xb0",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in ocean transit at a draft of 10 feet 0 inches with winds greater than 70 knots, has a KGT of 39.0 feet and a KGL of 38.6 feet. The margin on the maximum allowable KG is ____________.",opa:"2.6 feet",opb:"4.1 feet",opc:"26.3 feet",opd:"26.8 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, when underway was loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). It is now preloaded at minimum air gap waiting for all settling to take place. The preload, weighing 7,191.7 kips, has LM 870,196 ft.-kips and TM 2,158 ft.-kips. What is the port leg reaction?",opa:"7,026 kips",opb:"7,099 kips",opc:"7,144 kips",opd:"7,180 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE?",opa:"You need not keep a record of ground garbage dumped into the sea more than 25 miles offshore.",opb:"You must keep a record of garbage discharged in port to a shore facility.",opc:"You need not keep a record of garbage incinerated on the ship.",opd:"You must keep a record of the approximate weight of the garbage dumped.",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to regulations, a Master or person in charge of a MODU is required to submit a report of a loss of life ____________.",opa:"only when it happens while underway",opb:"to the next of kin",opc:"to the nearest OCMI",opd:"to the nearest coroner",ans:"opc"},{question:"As shown, number 1 operates the ____________.",opa:"releasing gear",opb:"McCluny hook",opc:"sea painter",opd:"Fleming gear",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, elevated in 100 feet of water with 0 knots current, 30 foot waves, and wind speeds of 50 knots may continue drilling if the maximum leg reaction is less than ____________.",opa:"6,180 kips",opb:"6,320 kips",opc:"6,440 kips",opd:"6,520 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), discharges a non-liquid load of 275.8 long tons from a position 130 feet above the keel, 40 feet forward of amidships, and 30 feet to port of the centerline. What is the resulting trim angle?",opa:"3.49 degrees to the stern",opb:"4.69 degrees to the stern",opc:"5.18 degrees to the stern",opd:"5.68 degrees to the stern",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning combustible gas indicators?",opa:"One sample of air is adequate to test a tank.",opb:"They do not work properly where there is a lack of oxygen.",opc:"They will detect a lack of oxygen.",opd:"They are calibrated to read the percentage chance of explosion.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which barge in your tow would require a cargo information card to be carried in the pilothouse?",opa:"A tank barge with a sign reading 'No Visitors, No Smoking, No Open Lights'",opb:"An open hopper barge carrying coal",opc:"A gas-free chlorine barge",opd:"An empty (not gas-free) barge that last carried benzene",ans:"opd"},{question:"An extinguishing agent which effectively cools, dilutes combustible vapors, removes oxygen, and provides a heat and smoke screen is ____________.",opa:"carbon dioxide",opb:"Halon 1301",opc:"dry chemical",opd:"water fog",ans:"opd"},{question:"What are the conditions, under GMDSS, whereby a ship is NOT allowed to depart from any port?",opa:"The vessel is not capable of performing all required distress and safety functions.",opb:"The vessel is carrying more than the required number of qualified GMDSS radio operators.",opc:"The vessel has a temporary waiver of its radio license and Safety Certificate.",opd:"The vessel is not carrying a GMDSS radio maintainer, but has provided for shoreside maintenance plus duplication of equipment if required.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your sailing vessel is docked during a storm and is in continuous motion. If a mooring line parts due to vessel motion, it will most likely do so ____________.",opa:"where it is made fast on the vessel",opb:"midway between the vessel and the dock",opc:"at the eye",opd:"at the chock",ans:"opd"},{question:"Outlets in gasoline fuel lines are ____________.",opa:"prohibited",opb:"permitted for draining fuel from lines",opc:"permitted for drawing fuel samples",opd:"permitted for bleeding air from lines",ans:"opa"},{question:"Shipboard Oil Pollution Emergency Plans must be reviewed ____________.",opa:"annually by the owner, with a letter submitted six months before expiration",opb:"only once every five years, with a letter submitted six months before expiration",opc:"and the entire plan resubmitted for approval once every five years, six months before expiration",opd:"annually by the owner, with a letter submitted to the Coast Guard within one month of the anniversary date of the plan approval",ans:"opd"},{question:"Dry chemical fire extinguishers are effective on which type(s) of fire?",opa:"Burning oil",opb:"Electrical",opc:"Paint",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Among the equipment included in the DEEP DRILLER lightweight are the derrick, traveling block in the lowest position, anchors, mooring chain, all machinery with liquids to normal operating level, and ____________.",opa:"normal food supplies for 79 persons",opb:"eight anchor buoys",opc:"lower-hull fuel",opd:"loading hoses",ans:"opd"},{question:"An inflatable liferaft can be launched by ____________.",opa:"the float-free method ONLY",opb:"breaking the weak link on the painter",opc:"throwing the entire container overboard and then pulling on the operating cord to inflate the raft",opd:"removing the securing straps",ans:"opc"},{question:"If an inflatable liferaft inflates upside down, you can right it by ____________.",opa:"pushing up on one side",opb:"standing on the CO2 bottle, holding the bottom straps, and throwing your weight backwards",opc:"getting at least three or four men to push down on the side containing the CO2 cylinder",opd:"doing nothing; it will right itself after the canopy supports inflate",ans:"opb"},{question:"The number of certificated able seamen and lifeboatmen required on a MODU is stated in the ____________.",opa:"Certificate of Inspection",opb:"American Bureau of Shipping code",opc:"Minerals Management Service regulations",opd:"Safety of Life at Sea Convention",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged and on an even keel. There is no trim. The freeboard is reduced to less than 1 foot. The rolling period is very long, and the vessel is sluggish in returning from a roll. Which action would you take FIRST to improve stability?",opa:"In calm seas lower the lifeboats to the water and keep them alongside.",opb:"Rig the jumbo boom and use it to jettison heavy deck cargo.",opc:"Press up a centerline double bottom that is now filled to 15% capacity.",opd:"Pump out the peak tanks simultaneously.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is partially loaded with a GM of 3.1 feet and drafts of: FWD 16'-00', AFT 18'-04'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine what tank(s) you should ballast to increase the GM to 3.6 feet.",opa:"Tanks: DB1, DT1A",opb:"Tanks: DT6, DT7",opc:"Tank: DT8",opd:"Tank: DB3",ans:"opd"},{question:"A jack-up, while level in transit at 10 feet draft, experiences a wind gust which results in a port draft of 11 feet. What is the heel?",opa:"1 foot to starboard",opb:"2 feet to starboard",opc:"2 feet to port",opd:"1 foot to port",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which type of power may a towing vessel use to drive the cargo pumps of a tank barge?",opa:"Only air",opb:"Only steam",opc:"Air or steam only",opd:"Steam, air, or electricity",ans:"opd"},{question:"All MODU personnel should be familiar with the survival craft's ____________.",opa:"boarding and operating procedures",opb:"maintenance schedule",opc:"navigational systems",opd:"fuel consumption rates",ans:"opa"},{question:"If there are a number of survivors in the water after abandoning a MODU, they should ____________.",opa:"tie themselves to the unit so they won't drift with the current",opb:"form a small circular group to create a warmer pocket of water in the center of the circle",opc:"send the strongest swimmer to shore for assistance",opd:"form a raft by lashing their life preservers together",ans:"opb"},{question:"When can a work vest be substituted for a lifejacket in the total count of the required lifesaving gear?",opa:"When it is approved by the Coast Guard",opb:"When working near or over the water",opc:"When stowed away from the ring buoys",opd:"A work vest may never be counted as a lifejacket.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Aboard damaged vessels, the MOST important consideration is preserving ____________.",opa:"bilge pumping capacity",opb:"reserve buoyancy",opc:"level attitude",opd:"instability",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the wave period and the apparent rolling period of the MODU are the same ____________.",opa:"synchronous rolling occurs",opb:"roll period decreases",opc:"roll period increases",opd:"roll amplitude is dampened",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 12'-07', AFT 16'-01'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.30 feet",opb:"1.07 foot",opc:"0.96 foot",opd:"0.82 foot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your tankship has 40 gallons of 6% foam concentrate aboard. Approximately how much foam solution can be produced from this supply?",opa:"200 gallons",opb:"420 gallons",opc:"667 gallons",opd:"986 gallons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Regulations require that cargo tanks in which grades B or C liquids are carried must be vented with which of the following?",opa:"Gooseneck vents",opb:"Flame screens",opc:"Pressure vacuum relief valves",opd:"Forced draft blowers",ans:"opc"},{question:"The accumulation of dangerous fumes generated by the storage batteries is best prevented by ____________.",opa:"covering the batteries in a nonconducting, solid enclosure",opb:"mounting the batteries in a position as high as possible",opc:"natural or mechanical ventilation",opd:"securing the batteries to vibration reducing mounting brackets",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 3700 tons of cargo, 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 427 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in fresh water.",opa:"17'-01'",opb:"17'-00'",opc:"17'-10'",opd:"18'-00'",ans:"opc"},{question:"The Master has ordered you to pull the remote ventilation shut down which is found in what location?",opa:"Port side fan room, frame 138",opb:"Port side of the wheelhouse, frame 122",opc:"Starboard side exterior, frame 132",opd:"Starboard side of the wheelhouse, frame 122",ans:"opd"},{question:"Given the same water depth and line tension, the catenary length of a 90 pound/foot mooring chain in comparison to the catenary length of a 19 pound/foot wire rope mooring line will be ____________.",opa:"longer",opb:"identical",opc:"shorter",opd:"indeterminable",ans:"opc"},{question:"A mobile offshore drilling unit crane certificate is required to be maintained ____________.",opa:"on the unit",opb:"in the company office",opc:"on file with the OCMI",opd:"on file with the American Bureau of Shipping",ans:"opa"},{question:"If a leak occurred while loading diethylenetriamine, the chemical data guide indicates you would smell an odor similar to ____________.",opa:"ammonia",opb:"rotten eggs",opc:"gasoline",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is elevated to an air gap of 25 feet in 250 feet of water. The current is 2 knots and the waves are 30 feet. The maximum leg reaction is 6,120 kips. What is the maximum wind for drilling operations?",opa:"100 knots",opb:"70 knots",opc:"60 knots",opd:"40 knots",ans:"opd"},{question:"The static stability curve for a given vessel peaks at 34\xb0. For this ship, the danger angle for a permanent list would be about ____________.",opa:"8.5\xb0",opb:"17\xb0",opc:"34\xb0",opd:"51\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"How should latitude 51\xb048.7'S be written when preparing an AMVER report?",opa:"5149S",opb:"51.8S",opc:"0578S",opd:"52S",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the mainline valve of a self-contained breathing apparatus is open, the bypass valve should be ____________.",opa:"completely open",opb:"completely closed",opc:"disconnected",opd:"partially opened",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents a fire pump?",opa:"19",opb:"21",opc:"22",opd:"54",ans:"opd"},{question:"According to regulations, which grade(s) of cargo may be carried in tanks that are vented only with gooseneck vents and flame screens?",opa:"B only",opb:"B or C",opc:"C or D",opd:"D or E",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 6.9 ft.",opb:"Available GM 5.3 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.1 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"If you are on the beach and are signaling to a small boat in distress that your present location is dangerous and they should land to the left, you would ____________.",opa:"fire a green star to the left",opb:"send the letter K by light and point to the left",opc:"place an orange signal to your left as you signal with a white light",opd:"send the code signal S followed by L",ans:"opd"},{question:"The color of the signal flare sent up by a submarine to indicate an emergency is ____________.",opa:"white",opb:"yellow",opc:"red",opd:"green",ans:"opc"},{question:"The boom stops are installed on an offshore crane to ____________.",opa:"prevent the boom from being raised too high",opb:"prevent the boom from swinging",opc:"support the boom when not in use",opd:"prevent the boom from being lowered",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which frequencies and modes are allocated for distress alerting in GMDSS?",opa:"406 MHz via EPIRB",opb:"1626.5-1645.5 MHz via INMARSAT",opc:"Channel 70 DSC plus six (6) MF/HF DSC frequencies",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The service use of pyrotechnic distress signals measured from the date of manufacture shall be limited to a period of ____________.",opa:"24 months",opb:"36 months",opc:"42 months",opd:"60 months",ans:"opc"},{question:"The vertical distance between G and M of a MODU is used as a measure of ____________.",opa:"stability at all angles of inclination",opb:"initial stability",opc:"stability at angles less than the limit of positive stability",opd:"stability at angles less than the downflooding angle",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of FSML for Fresh Water if the entire contents of Drill Water Tank #5P are transferred to Tank #5S?",opa:"3,645 ft.-tons",opb:"3,328 ft.-tons",opc:"317 ft.-tons",opd:"0 ft.-tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your ship is sinking rapidly. A container containing an inflatable liferaft has bobbed to the surface upon functioning of the hydrostatic release. Which action should you take?",opa:"Cut the painter line so it will not pull the liferaft container down.",opb:"Swim away from the container so you will not be in danger as it goes down.",opc:"Take no action because the painter will cause the liferaft to inflate and open the container.",opd:"Manually open the container and inflate the liferaft with the hand pump.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Small wooden hull passenger vessels, whose routes are limited to coastwise warm water routes on the high seas, must carry approved life floats or buoyant apparatus ____________.",opa:"for all persons onboard",opb:"for not less than 67% of all persons permitted onboard",opc:"for not less than 100% of all persons permitted onboard",opd:"in place of ring life buoys",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel measures 122 feet long by 18 feet in beam. If the natural rolling period at a draft of 6'-09' is 5 seconds, what is the GM?",opa:"1.4 feet",opb:"2.1 feet",opc:"2.5 feet",opd:"2.9 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A weight of 1,000 kips is equivalent to ____________.",opa:"1,000 pounds",opb:"2,000 short tons",opc:"2,240 pounds",opd:"500 short tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"In case of major damage to column C1P while the DEEP DRILLER is on location, you should pump from port-forward lower-hull tanks using ____________.",opa:"all four ballast pumps",opb:"both port-side ballast pumps",opc:"saltwater service pump to supplement port-side ballast pumps",opd:"drill water pump to supplement port-side ballast pumps",ans:"opb"},{question:"When administering artificial respiration, it is MOST important to ____________.",opa:"monitor blood pressure",opb:"clear airways",opc:"use the rhythmic pressure method",opd:"know all approved methods",ans:"opb"},{question:"What are the most important reasons for using water fog to fight fires?",opa:"Smothers burning surfaces, organically destroys fuel",opb:"Cools fire and adjacent surfaces, provides protective barrier",opc:"Reaches areas not protected by steam or CO2 smothering systems",opd:"Allows fire to be attacked from leeward, saturates liquid surfaces",ans:"opb"},{question:"To assess the potential for progressive flooding aboard a damaged MODU, you must know the ____________.",opa:"integrity of the watertight boundaries",opb:"capacity of the water sprinkler systems",opc:"operation of the machinery space bilge level alarms",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the meaning of the signal QU RQ when sent by the International Code of Signals?",opa:"This is the call sign of a vessel registered in Latvia.",opb:"Is anchoring prohibited?",opc:"Will you lead me to a safe anchorage?",opd:"Interrogative",ans:"opb"},{question:"The certificate of inspection of a MODU will specify the ____________.",opa:"number of licensed personnel required onboard",opb:"maximum load line draft",opc:"maximum water depth for drilling",opd:"next date for an inclining experiment",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER at a draft of 10.5 feet, transfers a portion of the onboard liquids from full drill water tank #23 to empty drill water tank #24. What is the change in the free surface correction?",opa:"0.69 foot",opb:"0.44 foot",opc:"0.34 foot",opd:"0.22 foot",ans:"opb"},{question:"Coast Guard Regulations (46 CFR) require that life jackets shall be ____________.",opa:"provided for each person onboard",opb:"provided for all personnel of watch",opc:"readily accessible to persons in the engine room",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"BOTH INTERNATIONAL & INLAND Your 18-meter vessel is propelled by sail and power. What action is required when the engine is stopped?",opa:"Display a black diamond shape forward.",opb:"Remove the black cone shape from forward.",opc:"Remove the black balls (one at the masthead and one on each spreader).",opd:"Display a black cylindrical shape at the masthead.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel is damaged and listing to port. The rolling period is long, and the vessel will occasionally assume a starboard list. Which action should you take FIRST?",opa:"Fill an empty double bottom tank on the starboard side",opb:"Transfer all possible movable weights from port to starboard",opc:"Pump out ballast from the port and starboard double bottom tanks",opd:"Press up a slack centerline double bottom tank",ans:"opd"},{question:"The holding power of an anchor increases when the ____________.",opa:"amount of chain lying along the bottom increases",opb:"length of the catenary is reduced",opc:"mooring line tension is increased",opd:"amount of chain lying along the bottom decreases",ans:"opa"},{question:"In an electro-hydraulic steering system, rudder movement is maintained in close synchronization with the steering wheel position by means of the ____________.",opa:"trick wheel",opb:"follow-up control",opc:"six-way valve",opd:"Rapson slide",ans:"opb"},{question:"When whistle signals are used for launching lifeboats, one short blast means ____________.",opa:"'use the float-free method only'",opb:"'lower all boats'",opc:"'raise all boats'",opd:"'drill is over, secure all boats'",ans:"opb"},{question:"With the sprinkler system and air system on and all hatches shut, the survival craft will provide protection from a ____________.",opa:"nuclear environment",opb:"fire and toxic environment",opc:"hurricane",opd:"drop greater than 10 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the change in vertical moments for the DEEP DRILLER if 103.48 long tons of ballast is discharged from a full ballast tank 1P?",opa:"6,707 foot-tons decrease",opb:"4,984 foot-tons decrease",opc:"1,914 foot-tons decrease",opd:"155 foot-tons decrease",ans:"opc"},{question:"Reserve buoyancy is ____________.",opa:"also called GM",opb:"the void portion of the ship below the waterline which is enclosed and watertight",opc:"affected by the number of transverse watertight bulkheads",opd:"the watertight portion of a vessel above the waterline",ans:"opd"},{question:"On offshore drilling units fitted with CO2 systems, each space that contains a cylinder must be vented and designed to keep temperature in the space at not more than ____________.",opa:"130\xb0F",opb:"150\xb0F",opc:"180\xb0F",opd:"200\xb0F",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning inert gas systems on tank vessels?",opa:"Flue gases from the ship's boilers are used in some systems.",opb:"Helium is the preferred inert gas.",opc:"Using the system accelerates the rusting of the tanks.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What size bilge pump is required for a lifeboat which has a capacity of 675 cubic feet?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"What effect is achieved from soaking an anchor?",opa:"It allows the bottom soil to consolidate.",opb:"It gives the palms time to trip the anchor.",opc:"It stabilizes the mooring system.",opd:"It lubricates the anchor for better tripping.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which portable fire extinguisher is required just outside the exit of the propulsion machinery space of a 75-ton passenger vessel?",opa:"2-1/2 gallon foam extinguisher",opb:"15 lb. CO2extinguisher",opc:"2 lb. dry chemical extinguisher",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons. What is the transverse free surface correction to KG?",opa:"0.00 feet",opb:"1.03 feet",opc:"1.69 feet",opd:"2.22 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"On small passenger vessels each inlet or discharge pipe penetrating the hull less than six inches above the deepest load waterline ____________.",opa:"must have a check valve to prevent water from entering",opb:"except for engine exhausts must have a means to prevent water from entering the vessel if the pipe fails",opc:"must be fitted with a gate valve",opd:"must be sealed",ans:"opb"},{question:"The bypass valve on a self-contained breathing device should be opened if ____________.",opa:"you are entering a space containing poisonous vapors",opb:"you are entering a space containing explosive gases",opc:"the regulator of the breathing apparatus malfunctions",opd:"the face piece of the breathing device is too tight",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 17'-07', AFT 16'-09'; and the KG is 21.5 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 30\xb0 inclination.",opa:"0.8 foot",opb:"1.5 feet",opc:"2.7 feet",opd:"3.6 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in a survival craft broadcasting a distress message. What information would be essential to your rescuers?",opa:"The nature of the distress",opb:"The time of day",opc:"Your radio call sign",opd:"Your position by latitude and longitude",ans:"opd"},{question:"In illustration D041DG, the symbol for the vertical plane midway between the fore and aft perpendiculars is ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"3",opc:"4",opd:"5",ans:"opb"},{question:"The international shore connection ____________.",opa:"allows hook up of fire fighting water from shore facilities",opb:"satisfies pollution prevention requirements",opc:"allows emergency use of the fire main for deballasting",opd:"permits discharge of waste oil to shore facilities",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's existing draft is FWD 19'-02', AFT 20'-10'. Using the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN, determine the new draft if 170 long tons are discharged from No. 8 hatch.",opa:"FWD 19'-00.4', AFT20'-08.6'",opb:"FWD 18'-10.8', AFT20'-10.4'",opc:"FWD 19'-03.4', AFT20'-05.6'",opd:"FWD 19'-05.4', AFT20'-03.4'",ans:"opb"},{question:"No person whose license has been revoked shall be issued another license except upon ____________.",opa:"approval of the Commandant",opb:"taking a new examination",opc:"approval of the Officer-in-Charge, Marine Inspection",opd:"approval of an administrative law judge",ans:"opa"},{question:"The most important reason for taking anti-seasickness pills as soon as possible after entering a liferaft is to ____________.",opa:"assist in sleeping",opb:"reduce appetite by decreasing nausea",opc:"prevent loss of body moisture by vomiting",opd:"prevent impaired judgment due to motion-induced deliriousness",ans:"opc"},{question:"The largest crew a cargo vessel may carry without having a hospital space is ____________.",opa:"6",opb:"11",opc:"12",opd:"16",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 8'-04', AFT 15'-08'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1.77 feet",opb:"1.91 feet",opc:"2.09 feet",opd:"2.21 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A jack-up, while level in transit at 10 feet draft, experiences a wind gust which results in a port draft of 11 feet. What is the new starboard draft?",opa:"12 feet",opb:"11 feet",opc:"10 feet",opd:"9 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"An immersion suit should be equipped with a/an ____________.",opa:"air bottle for breathing",opb:"whistle and hand held flare",opc:"whistle, strobe light and reflective tape",opd:"whistle, hand held flare and sea dye marker",ans:"opc"},{question:"As shown, the symbol for the reference from which transverse measurements are made is ____________.",opa:"5",opb:"4",opc:"3",opd:"1",ans:"opa"},{question:"Radar reflectors are required for ____________.",opa:"all fishing vessels over 39 feet in length",opb:"sail-propelled fishing vessels",opc:"all fishing vessels of less than 200 GT",opd:"wooden hull fishing vessels with a poor radar echo",ans:"opd"},{question:"When do you use your FCC call sign when transmitting on channel 16?",opa:"Only at the beginning of a transmission",opb:"Only in an emergency",opc:"Only if asked by the U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"Always at the beginning and ending of a transmission",ans:"opd"},{question:"A Coast Guard radiotelephone message about an aid to navigation that is off station is preceded by the word ____________.",opa:"'PAN-PAN'",opb:"'MAYDAY'",opc:"'SOS'",opd:"'SECURITY'",ans:"opd"},{question:"The difference between the starboard and port drafts caused by shifting a weight transversely is ____________.",opa:"list",opb:"heel",opc:"trim",opd:"flotation",ans:"opa"},{question:"A load line for a MODU is assigned by the ____________.",opa:"Minerals Management Service",opb:"Department of Energy",opc:"Corps of Engineers",opd:"A recognized classification society approved by the Coast Guard",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is partially loaded with a GM of 2.6 feet and drafts of: FWD 13'-07', AFT 15'-01'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine what tanks you should ballast to increase the GM to 3.4 feet.",opa:"Tanks: DB1, DB3",opb:"Tanks: DB5, DT1A",opc:"Tanks: DB6, DB7, DT7",opd:"Tanks: DB4, DT8",ans:"opc"},{question:"Camphor oil is classified as a ____________.",opa:"Grade A flammable liquid",opb:"Grade C flammable liquid",opc:"Grade D combustible liquid",opd:"Grade E combustible liquid",ans:"opc"},{question:"Ventilation systems connected to a compartment in which a fire is burning are normally closed to prevent the rapid spread of the fire by ____________.",opa:"convection",opb:"conduction",opc:"radiation",opd:"spontaneous combustion",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, which extinguishing agent is NOT recommended for use in fighting an ethylamine fire?",opa:"Alcohol foam",opb:"Carbon dioxide",opc:"Dry chemical",opd:"Water fog",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents a heat detector?",opa:"18",opb:"31",opc:"49",opd:"63",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which line would NOT be used in handling a mainsail?",opa:"Halyard",opb:"Downhaul",opc:"Uphaul",opd:"Sheet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1171.5 tons",opb:"1311.0 tons",opc:"1503.0 tons",opd:"1710.5 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each distress signal and self-activated smoke signal must be replaced not later than the marked date of expiration, or, from the date of manufacture, not later than ____________.",opa:"6 months",opb:"12 months",opc:"24 months",opd:"42 months",ans:"opd"},{question:"If your JP-5 barge has operated in saltwater for less than 1 month in the 12 month period since it was last dry-docked, when is it required to be hauled out again?",opa:"60 months since last dry-docking",opb:"36 months since last dry-docking",opc:"24 months since last dry-docking",opd:"12 months since last dry-docking",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a floating MODU inclines to an angle slightly less than the angle of loll, she will ____________.",opa:"capsize",opb:"incline less",opc:"flop to the other side",opd:"return to the angle of loll",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are fighting a class 'B' fire with a portable dry chemical extinguisher. The discharge should be directed ____________.",opa:"at the seat of the fire, starting at the near edge",opb:"to bank off a bulkhead onto the fire",opc:"over the top of the fire",opd:"at the main body of the fire",ans:"opa"},{question:"In very deep water drilling, it becomes necessary to reduce tension caused by the weight of the riser joints. This is accomplished by using a(n) ____________.",opa:"aluminum riser",opb:"tapered riser",opc:"buoyant riser",opd:"intermediate tensioner",ans:"opc"},{question:"Stanchions prevent the entire deck load on a MODU from being carried by the ____________.",opa:"bulkheads",opb:"stringers",opc:"frames and beam brackets",opd:"deck longitudinals",ans:"opc"},{question:"When elevating the COASTAL DRILLER in 150 feet of water, the unit should be placed at an air gap of ____________.",opa:"35 feet",opb:"32 feet",opc:"30 feet",opd:"25 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Actuating the CO2 fixed system causes the shutdown of the ____________.",opa:"fuel supply",opb:"exhaust ventilation",opc:"supply and exhaust ventilation",opd:"mechanical and natural ventilation",ans:"opc"},{question:"How is the external flotation bladder of an immersion suit inflated?",opa:"It is inflated by a small CO2 bottle that is automatically tripped when the front zipper is at the top of the zipper track.",opb:"It is inflated by a small CO2 bottle that is manually tripped.",opc:"It is inflated by blowing through an inflation tube.",opd:"It inflates by seawater bleeding into the inflation bladder and reacting with a chemical.",ans:"opc"},{question:"For GMDSS, when may a compulsory vessel not be allowed to leave port?",opa:"When the vessel is in an overloaded condition",opb:"When the vessel has arranged for both duplication of equipment AND shore-based maintenance",opc:"When the vessel has replaced a required piece of GMDSS-related equipment but its performance has not been verified or logged",opd:"When the vessel is carrying only two licensed GMDSS Radio Operators and is capable of performing all required functions",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a MODU crane, the boom indicator tells the operator what the boom angle is compared to the ____________.",opa:"vertical position",opb:"horizontal position",opc:"boom stop angle",opd:"minimum radius angle",ans:"opb"},{question:"The light on a personal flotation device on an OSV must be replaced ____________.",opa:"when the power source is replaced",opb:"each year after installation",opc:"every six months",opd:"when it is no longer serviceable",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 21'-03', AFT 26'-00'. What is the KM based on the tables in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book?",opa:"25.1 feet",opb:"25.4 feet",opc:"25.7 feet",opd:"26.0 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, while in an ocean transit, experiences a single amplitude roll of 8 degrees. What is the minimum period of motion which does not exceed the design limits of the legs?",opa:"10 seconds",opb:"8 seconds",opc:"6 seconds",opd:"4 seconds",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are at sea and not in a special area as defined in ANNEX V of MARPOL. How many nautical miles from land must you be to discharge ground garbage that will pass through a one-inch (25 mm) screen into the sea?",opa:"3 nm",opb:"6 nm",opc:"12 nm",opd:"25 nm",ans:"opa"},{question:"A floating MODU displacing 20,000 long tons with a VCG of 50 feet loads 100 long tons at 100 feet above the baseline and 200 long tons at 130 feet above the baseline. What is the new KG?",opa:"49.0 feet",opb:"50.0 feet",opc:"51.0 feet",opd:"51.8 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"If a drill required by regulations is not completed on a mobile offshore drilling unit, the Master or person in charge must ____________.",opa:"report this immediately to the OCMI",opb:"report this immediately to the Commandant of the Coast Guard",opc:"log the reason for not completing the drill",opd:"conduct two of the required drills at the next opportunity",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which record must be retained onboard after a report of casualty to a MODU?",opa:"Preventive maintenance log",opb:"Storage plans",opc:"Oil Record Book",opd:"Repair record book",ans:"opb"},{question:"The exhaust pipe must be gas tight throughout its entire length otherwise ____________.",opa:"bilge water may enter the exhaust pipe",opb:"entry of air may cause vapor lock",opc:"carbon monoxide may enter the interior of the vessel",opd:"the joint gaskets may be blown",ans:"opc"},{question:"To disengage a survival craft suspended from the cable above the water, you must pull the safety pin and ____________.",opa:"pull the hook release handle",opb:"pull the hook release handle and use the ratchet bar",opc:"use the ratchet bar and depress the retainer",opd:"pull the hook release handle and depress the retainer",ans:"opb"},{question:"Given the same water depth and line tension, the catenary length of a 19 pound/foot wire rope mooring line in comparison to the catenary length of a 90 pound/foot mooring chain will be ____________.",opa:"shorter",opb:"longer",opc:"identical",opd:"indeterminable",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"7.7 feet",opb:"9.1 feet",opc:"9.9 feet",opd:"10.6 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"You board an inflatable liferaft that has been hand launched from a sinking vessel. What should you do FIRST after everyone is onboard the liferaft?",opa:"Cut the painter.",opb:"Operate the radio equipment.",opc:"Open the equipment pack.",opd:"Ventilate the liferaft of CO2.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What are the vertical moments for 14.0 feet of drill water in the COASTAL DRILLER's #1 drill water tank?",opa:"2.455 ft.-kips",opb:"2.543 ft.-kips",opc:"2.725 ft.-kips",opd:"2.997 ft.-kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"Where should life jackets be stowed? (Small Passenger Vessel Regulations)",opa:"In the forepeak",opb:"In the wheelhouse",opc:"Throughout the accommodation spaces",opd:"In locked watertight and fireproof containers on or above the main deck",ans:"opc"},{question:"During cargo operations, your vessel develops a list due to the center of gravity rising above the transverse metacenter. To correct the list, you should ____________.",opa:"shift weight to the high side",opb:"shift weight to the centerline",opc:"add weight in the lower holds or double bottoms",opd:"remove weight from the lower holds or double bottoms",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which condition is necessary for a substance to burn?",opa:"The temperature of the substance must be equal to or above its fire point.",opb:"The air must contain oxygen in sufficient quantity.",opc:"The mixture of vapors with air must be within the 'explosive range.'",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What must be located on the discharge side of the pump in a fire main system?",opa:"Pressure gauge",opb:"Strainer",opc:"Reduction valve",opd:"International shore connection",ans:"opa"},{question:"If the patient vomits during mouth-to mouth resuscitation, the rescuer should FIRST ____________.",opa:"ignore it and continue mouth-to-mouth ventilation",opb:"pause for a moment until the patient appears quiet again, then resume ventilation mouth-to-mouth",opc:"switch to mouth-to-nose ventilation",opd:"turn the patient's body to the side, sweep out the mouth and resume mouth-to-mouth ventilation",ans:"opd"},{question:"The effect of free surface on initial stability depends upon ____________.",opa:"the amount of liquid in the compartment",opb:"the dimensions of the liquid surface and the vessel's displacement",opc:"only the length of the compartment",opd:"the vertical position of the liquid in the vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"In order to carry a cargo of triethanolamine, what hull type is required?",opa:"I",opb:"II",opc:"III",opd:"IV",ans:"opc"},{question:"Given the same water depth and mooring tension, the length of the ground cable of a 19 pound/foot wire rope mooring line in comparison to a 90 pound/foot mooring chain will be ____________.",opa:"shorter",opb:"identical",opc:"longer",opd:"indeterminable",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are running before a rough sea and a strong wind. Your sailing vessel is yawing. If the wind should catch the mainsail on the reverse side you will ____________.",opa:"broach",opb:"tack",opc:"jibe",opd:"go in irons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1171.5 tons",opb:"1311.0 tons",opc:"1503.0 tons",opd:"1912.5 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fire in an engine compartment is best extinguished with carbon dioxide gas (CO2) and by ____________.",opa:"closing the compartment except for the ventilators",opb:"completely closing the compartment",opc:"leaving the compartment open to the air",opd:"increasing the air flow to the compartment by blowers",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"7.7 feet",opb:"9.1 feet",opc:"9.9 feet",opd:"10.6 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"To determine what navigation lights and day-shapes must be displayed on mobile offshore drilling units under tow, you should check the ____________.",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping classification rules",opb:"International Regulations for Preventing Collisions at Sea",opc:"Safety of Life at Sea Convention",opd:"Minerals Management Service rules",ans:"opb"},{question:"The pipe and special fittings used on floating offshore drilling rigs to establish a connection between the top of the wellbore, which is on the ocean floor, and the drilling equipment, located above the surface of the water, is called a ____________.",opa:"marine riser pipe",opb:"marine casing",opc:"guide pipe",opd:"guide base casing",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement about immersion suits is TRUE?",opa:"The suit must, without assistance, turn an unconscious person's mouth clear of the water within 5 seconds.",opb:"The immersion suit seals in body heat and provides protection against hypothermia for weeks.",opc:"The suit will still be serviceable after a brief (2-6 minutes) exposure to flame and burning.",opd:"The collar must be inflated before abandoning ship.",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of a check valve?",opa:"Passes air but not liquid",opb:"Regulates liquid flow",opc:"Permits flow in one direction only",opd:"Passes liquid but not air",ans:"opc"},{question:"How is the Master or operator of a vessel required to keep the crew informed of the regulations concerning the discharging of garbage overboard?",opa:"Give each crewmember a copy of ANNEX V of MARPOL.",opb:"Call an all hands meeting before sailing.",opc:"Keep placards prominently posted.",opd:"Have each person read and sign a copy of the regulations.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the primary equipment for receiving MSI?",opa:"SART",opb:"EPIRB",opc:"NAVTEX",opd:"INMARSAT-B",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), discharges a non-liquid load of 275.8 long tons from a position 130 feet above the keel, 40 feet forward of amidships, and 30 feet to port of the centerline. What is the new KGT?",opa:"52.60 feet",opb:"53.65 feet",opc:"54.31 feet",opd:"54.92 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A ship's forward draft is 22'-04' and its after draft is 24'-00'. The draft amidships is 23'-04'. This indicates a concentration of weight ____________.",opa:"at the bow",opb:"in the lower holds",opc:"amidships",opd:"at the ends",ans:"opc"},{question:"If it is impractical to use the fill line to sound the fuel tank, then the tank should be fitted with ____________. (Small Passenger Vessel Regulations)",opa:"a separate sounding tube or an installed marine type fuel gauge",opb:"An extra five gallon tank for reserve fuel",opc:"A good air vent of sufficient diameter",opd:"A glass tube to visually observe the fuel",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are making tow. A loaded, open-hopper barge with independent tanks has placards, with alternating red and white quadrants, located at each side and end. You inspect the barge and find slight traces of water in the wing voids due to condensation. What should you do?",opa:"Refuse to accept the barge until all wing voids are dry.",opb:"Accept the barge and when weather conditions permit run with the wing voids open to ventilate the spaces.",opc:"Accept the barge and periodically check the wing voids.",opd:"Return the barge to the fleet and depart without the barge.",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a marine surveyor is employed to assist in the move of a mobile offshore drilling unit, he ____________.",opa:"becomes responsible for the safe movement of the rig",opb:"relieves the Offshore Installation Manager at the moment the rig is free from the bottom",opc:"must be designated as the person in charge of the rig",opd:"is a specialist who is hired to provide advice and guidance on aspects of the move",ans:"opd"},{question:"Cargo tanks on barges fitted with goose neck vents and flame screens are limited to carrying which grade of cargo?",opa:"A and below",opb:"B and below",opc:"C and below",opd:"D and E only",ans:"opd"},{question:"Fire protection and manning regulations for towing vessels state that the Master or person in charge must ensure that all crew members who have not participated in the drills or received the safety orientation ____________.",opa:"receive a safety orientation or view a videotape before the vessel gets underway",opb:"view a videotape on safety procedures within 48 hours of reporting for duty",opc:"receive a safety orientation within 24 hours of reporting for duty",opd:"none of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The number of rowing oars that must be carried in a motor-propelled open lifeboat on a cargo vessel is ____________.",opa:"determined by the Master",opb:"specified by the Coast Guard",opc:"specified by the manufacturer",opd:"None",ans:"opc"},{question:"A cargo of 75 tons is to be lifted with a boom located 50 feet from the ship's centerline. The ship's displacement including the suspended cargo is 6,000 tons and GM is 6 feet. The list of the ship with the cargo suspended from the boom will be ____________.",opa:"5.00\xb0",opb:"5.40\xb0",opc:"5.94\xb0",opd:"6.50\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning a combustible gas indicator?",opa:"Several seconds will elapse between the taking of a sample and the reading appearing on the dial.",opb:"The instrument will operate in any atmosphere.",opc:"Toxicity of the atmosphere is measured by the instrument.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which extinguishing agent is effective in combating an isoprene fire?",opa:"Dry chemicals",opb:"CO2",opc:"Foam",opd:"All the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"An 'ABC' dry chemical fire extinguisher would be LEAST effective against a fire in ____________.",opa:"a mattress",opb:"spilled liquids such as oil or paint",opc:"high voltage electrical gear",opd:"a trash can",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are keeping the required garbage disposal records. The amount of garbage disposed must be stated in ____________.",opa:"barrels of 55 gallon capacity",opb:"both kilos and pounds",opc:"both cubic meters and cubic feet",opd:"cubic meters",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel displaces 740 tons and measures 141'L by 34'B. What is the reduction in GM due to free surface if the fish hold (41'L by 30'B by 9'D) is filled with 2.5 feet of water? (Each foot of water weighs 35.1 tons)",opa:"2.14 feet",opb:"2.75 feet",opc:"2.96 feet",opd:"3.18 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"On fire control plans, the dry chemical releasing station is designated by which symbol?",opa:"42",opb:"47",opc:"48",opd:"50",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are making ship-to-shore telephone calls on VHF. You should use the ____________.",opa:"VHF-FM service",opb:"coastal harbor service",opc:"high seas service",opd:"emergency broadcast service",ans:"opa"},{question:"The heavy three-, four-, or six-sided length of pipe suspended from the swivel through the rotary table and connected to the topmost joint of drill pipe to turn the drill stem as the rotary table turns is called the ____________.",opa:"swivel",opb:"bail",opc:"kelly",opd:"cock",ans:"opc"},{question:"Semi-portable extinguishers used on inspected vessels are sizes ____________.",opa:"II, III, and IV",opb:"I, II, and III",opc:"III, IV, and V",opd:"IV and V",ans:"opc"},{question:"An inflatable liferaft is thrown into the water from a sinking vessel. What should occur after the painter trips the CO2 bottles to inflate the raft?",opa:"The sea anchor should be deployed as soon you are away from the vessel.",opb:"The floor will automatically inflate.",opc:"If upside down, the craft will right itself.",opd:"The painter will detach from the raft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Inflatable liferafts are less maneuverable than lifeboats due to their ____________.",opa:"shape",opb:"shallow draft",opc:"large sail area",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 60.0 feet draft in sea water, has VM = 974,441 foot-long tons, LM = 40,301 foot-long tons, TM = 3 foot-long tons, FSML = 30,572 foot-long tons, and FSMT = 18,732 foot-long tons. What is the longitudinal free surface correction to KG?",opa:"0.00 feet",opb:"1.03 feet",opc:"1.69 feet",opd:"2.22 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the contents of the four bulk tanks are back-loaded to a supply boat, what would be the new draft?",opa:"7.16 feet",opb:"10.31 feet",opc:"10.57 feet",opd:"11.19 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which one of the following signals is made at night by a lifesaving station to indicate 'Landing here highly dangerous'?",opa:"Horizontal motion of a white light or flare",opb:"Vertical motion of a white light or flare",opc:"White star rocket",opd:"Vertical motion of a red light or flare",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"595 tons",opb:"870 tons",opc:"1200 tons",opd:"1350 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"The discharge side of every fire pump must be equipped with a ____________.",opa:"gate valve",opb:"pressure gauge",opc:"check valve",opd:"strainer",ans:"opb"},{question:"In battery charging rooms, exhaust ventilation should be provided ____________.",opa:"at the lowest point",opb:"near the batteries",opc:"at the highest point",opd:"only when charging is in progress",ans:"opc"},{question:"The primary reason for placing covers over storage batteries is to ____________.",opa:"prevent the accumulation of explosive gases",opb:"protect the hull from leaking electrolyte",opc:"prevent movement of the battery in rough waters",opd:"protect against accidental shorting across terminals",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel's LCG is determined by ____________.",opa:"dividing the total longitudinal moment summations by displacement",opb:"dividing the total vertical moment summations by displacement",opc:"multiplying the MT1 by the longitudinal moments",opd:"subtracting LCF from LCB",ans:"opa"},{question:"Providing you are not in a special area, such as the Mediterranean or Red Sea, how many nautical miles from land must you be to throw wooden dunnage into the sea?",opa:"25 nm",opb:"12 nm",opc:"6 nm",opd:"3 nm",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which method is used to supply inert gas from a flue gas system to the cargo tanks?",opa:"Exhaust gas pressure from the stack",opb:"High capacity fan",opc:"Inert gas compressor",opd:"Natural aspiration",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many portable fire extinguishers are required to be located inside the machinery space of a small passenger vessel?",opa:"None are required",opb:"One B-I, C-I",opc:"One B-II, C-II",opd:"One B-II",ans:"opa"},{question:"The abbreviation GM is used to represent the ____________.",opa:"height of the metacenter",opb:"righting arm",opc:"righting moment",opd:"metacentric height",ans:"opd"},{question:"A galley grease fire on the stove may be extinguished using ____________.",opa:"water",opb:"foam",opc:"the range hood extinguishing system",opd:"fire dampers",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are approaching another vessel and see that she has the signal flag 'J' hoisted. What should you do?",opa:"Keep well clear of the vessel because she is on fire and has dangerous cargo onboard or she is leaking dangerous cargo.",opb:"Attempt to call the vessel on VHF radiotelephone because she is requesting to communicate.",opc:"Approach the vessel with caution because she is dragging her anchor.",opd:"Proceed on present course and speed since the vessel is requesting a tug.",ans:"opa"},{question:"You discover a leak in the fuel line to the engine. You should FIRST ____________.",opa:"activate the CO2 system",opb:"make a temporary repair with canvas or tape",opc:"start the bilge pump",opd:"close the fuel valve at the tank",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #5 (Survival), suffers major damage which results in flooding in tank C1P. Your best countermeasure is to pump from ____________.",opa:"1P",opb:"3P",opc:"C1P",opd:"C2P",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to 46 CFR Subchapter T the purpose of fuses in electric wiring is to ____________.",opa:"allow for cutting out branch circuits",opb:"prevent overloading the circuits",opc:"reduce voltage to the branch circuits",opd:"permit the use of smaller wiring for lighting circuits",ans:"opb"},{question:"Each small passenger vessel that operates on the high seas, or beyond 3 miles from the coastline of the Great Lakes must have a Category 1 406 MHz EPIRB that ____________.",opa:"is in good operating condition and is stowed near its charger",opb:"will float free and clear of a sinking vessel and automatically activate",opc:"is protected against all physical hazards",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"The service life of distress signals must be not more than ____________.",opa:"forty two months from the date of manufacture",opb:"thirty six months from the date of the last inspection",opc:"twenty four months from the date of approval",opd:"twelve months from the date of purchase",ans:"opa"},{question:"The sounding in tank 1P of the DEEP DRILLER is 7.58 feet. What are the longitudinal moments for this quantity of ballast?",opa:"729 ft.-long tons",opb:"6,707 ft.-long tons",opc:"19,609 ft.-long tons",opd:"27,652 ft.-long tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The order to abandon a MODU should only be given by the ____________.",opa:"Offshore Installation Manager",opb:"Barge Engineer",opc:"Ballast Control Operator",opd:"Rig Safety Supervisor",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the machinery space of all uninspected motor vessels, there must be one type B-II hand portable fire extinguisher for every ____________. (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"500 S.H.P. of the main engines or fraction thereof",opb:"1000 S.H.P. of the main engines or fraction thereof",opc:"500 B.H.P. of the main engines or fraction thereof",opd:"1000 B.H.P. of the main engines or fraction thereof",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have 420 tons of below deck tonnage and 180 tons of above deck cargo onboard. You must load 140 tons of liquid mud below deck. How much more deck cargo can you load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"60 tons",opb:"100 tons",opc:"180 tons",opd:"240 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"Messages concerning weather conditions transmitted by radiotelephone are preceded by ____________.",opa:"MAYDAY",opb:"PAN-PAN",opc:"SECURITE",opd:"SOS",ans:"opc"},{question:"Each hose in the fuel transfer system for helicopter refueling must meet the standards of the ____________.",opa:"Federal Aviation Administration",opb:"Corps of Engineers",opc:"National Fire Protection Association",opd:"National Transportation Safety Board",ans:"opa"},{question:"Lighter longitudinal stiffening frames on the MODU side plating are called ____________.",opa:"stringers",opb:"side frames",opc:"side stiffeners",opd:"intercostals",ans:"opa"},{question:"Among the equipment included in the DEEP DRILLER lightweight are the loading hoses, traveling block in the lowest position, anchors, mooring chain, all machinery with liquids to normal operating level, and ____________.",opa:"derrick",opb:"lower hull fuel",opc:"eight anchor buoys",opd:"normal food supplies for 79 persons",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"4.0 feet",opb:"5.6 feet",opc:"6.0 feet",opd:"6.8 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 18'-03', AFT 21'-09'. What is the KM based on the tables in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book?",opa:"25.2 feet",opb:"25.6 feet",opc:"25.9 feet",opd:"26.3 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"When compared to a high-expansion foam, a low-expansion foam will ____________.",opa:"be dryer",opb:"be lighter",opc:"be less heat resistant",opd:"not cling to vertical surfaces",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 3175 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 25.8 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 26.8 feet",opb:"KG 27.3 feet",opc:"KG 28.2 feet",opd:"KG 28.5 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to bunker with drafts of FWD 14'-04', AFT 18'-08'. After all bunkers are onboard, soundings indicate the tonnages shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the free surface correction.",opa:"1.05 feet",opb:"1.15 feet",opc:"1.25 feet",opd:"1.31 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Injuries resulting in loss of life or incapacitation, aboard vessels, must be reported to the ____________.",opa:"Minerals Management Service",opb:"American Petroleum Institute",opc:"U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"International Association of Drilling Contractors",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the report identifier code for an AMVER deviation report?",opa:"DV",opb:"PR",opc:"FR",opd:"DR",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has a gasoline engine and a mechanical exhaust ventilation system. BEFORE starting the engine, the exhaust blower should be run long enough to ____________.",opa:"warm up the exhaust blower motor",opb:"provide a proper supply of fresh air for the engine(s)",opc:"see the system is in good operating condition",opd:"insure at least one complete change of air in the compartments concerned",ans:"opd"},{question:"One of the signals, other than a distress signal, that can be used by a rescue boat to attract attention is a/an ____________.",opa:"red star shell",opb:"searchlight",opc:"burning barrel",opd:"orange smoke signal",ans:"opb"},{question:"The factor of safety, based on the elastic limit of the material, for the forks used on power operated industrial trucks aboard a MODU must be at least ____________.",opa:"2 to 1",opb:"3 to 1",opc:"4 to 1",opd:"5 to 1",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 16'-02', AFT 18'-02'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the MT1.",opa:"935 foot-tons",opb:"960 foot-tons",opc:"985 foot-tons",opd:"1000 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The angle between the flukes and the shank of an anchor is called the ____________.",opa:"holding angle",opb:"fleet angle",opc:"fluke angle",opd:"shank angle",ans:"opc"},{question:"Given the same water depth and mooring tension, the holding power of a 90 pound/foot chain mooring system in comparison to the holding power of a 19 pound/foot wire rope mooring line will be ____________.",opa:"weaker",opb:"greater",opc:"equal",opd:"indeterminable",ans:"opb"},{question:"Load line regulations are designed to insure that a MODU has adequate structural strength and sufficient ____________.",opa:"lifesaving equipment",opb:"stability",opc:"mooring tension",opd:"riser tension",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which person may command a lifeboat in ocean service?",opa:"Licensed deck officer",opb:"Able seaman",opc:"Certificated person",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When water is used to fight a fire onboard a ship, the effect of the weight of the water must be taken into account. How much sea water will increase the weight displacement by one ton?",opa:"64 cubic feet",opb:"35 cubic feet",opc:"100 gallons",opd:"500 liters",ans:"opb"},{question:"Subtracting the height of the center of gravity corrected for transverse free surface effects from the height of the transverse metacenter of a MODU yields ____________.",opa:"GM",opb:"GMT",opc:"KGT",opd:"KMT",ans:"opb"},{question:"A towing vessel is NOT required to be fitted with radar if it is ____________.",opa:"used solely for assistance towing",opb:"under 65 feet in length",opc:"used exclusively on the Western Rivers",opd:"pushing ahead",ans:"opa"},{question:"The three corners of the main sail are called ____________.",opa:"head, fore, and aft",opb:"luff, leech, and spar",opc:"headboard, foot, and tail",opd:"head, tack, and clew",ans:"opd"},{question:"A MODU displacing 28,000 long tons has a KG of 60 feet. A weight of 500 long tons is discharged from a VCG 150 feet. The change in KG is ____________.",opa:"1.09 feet",opb:"1.60 feet",opc:"1.64 feet",opd:"2.73 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"How should the number '6' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"SOX-SIX",opb:"NUM-BER-SIX",opc:"SOK-SEE-SIX",opd:"NEW-MER-AL-SIX",ans:"opc"},{question:"Buoyant apparatus are required to be fitted or equipped with all of the following equipment EXCEPT ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"life lines",opb:"paddles",opc:"water lights",opd:"painters",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, fuel oil number 6 has a flash point (degrees F) of ____________.",opa:"65",opb:"80 -100",opc:"110 -140",opd:"150 -430(cc)",ans:"opd"},{question:"After reporting a casualty to a mobile offshore drilling unit, which record must be retained onboard?",opa:"Record of drafts",opb:"Hull reports",opc:"Anchor record",opd:"Machinery repair book",ans:"opa"},{question:"The external flotation bladder on an immersion suit should be inflated ____________.",opa:"only after two hours in the water",opb:"only after four hours in the water",opc:"before entry into the water",opd:"upon entry into the water",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which line would NOT be used in handling a mainsail?",opa:"Halyard",opb:"Downhaul",opc:"Uphaul",opd:"Sheet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is drilling while weighing 15,436 kips. LM are 2,006,680 ft.-kips, and TM are -7,718 ft.-kips. What is the port leg reaction?",opa:"3,806 kips",opb:"5,751 kips",opc:"5,879 kips",opd:"7,549 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"The difference between the height of the metacenter and the height of the center of gravity is known as the ____________.",opa:"metacentric height",opb:"height of the righting arm",opc:"fore and aft perpendicular",opd:"height of the center of buoyancy",ans:"opa"},{question:"When you hear three short blasts on the ship's whistle and the same signal on the general alarm bells, you ____________.",opa:"are required to be at your liferaft",opb:"are dismissed from drills",opc:"should point to the man overboard",opd:"should start the fire pump",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a vessel is not in compliance with its Certificate of Inspection, which certificate may be issued to allow its movement to a repair facility? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Change of Employment",opb:"Permit to Proceed",opc:"Application for Inspection",opd:"Temporary Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opb"},{question:"Following a collision or accident, the Master of each vessel involved must render assistance to persons affected by the collision or accident ____________.",opa:"if he can do so without any risk to his vessel",opb:"if he can do so without undue delay",opc:"if he can do so without serious danger to his vessel or to individuals onboard",opd:"without regard to any danger to his vessel",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are underway with a tow consisting of six barges containing hazardous chemicals. Which statement is FALSE concerning a cargo information card?",opa:"It must be carried in the pilothouse, readily available for each chemical carried.",opb:"It must be posted on the lead barge of the tow only.",opc:"It must be posted on each barge on the tow.",opd:"It contains information on procedure for spills or leaks.",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which action is routinely performed at the annual servicing and inspection of a dry-chemical cartridge-operated portable fire extinguisher?",opa:"Test the pressure gauge for correct reading.",opb:"Weigh the cartridge.",opc:"Replace the dry chemical.",opd:"Pressure test the discharge hose.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The purpose of the inclining experiment on a MODU is to determine the ____________.",opa:"lightweight and lightweight center of gravity location",opb:"position of the center of buoyancy",opc:"position of the metacenter",opd:"maximum load line",ans:"opa"},{question:"A moment of 300 ft.-tons is created by a force of 15,000 tons. What is the moment arm?",opa:"50.00 feet",opb:"25.00 feet",opc:"0.04 foot",opd:"0.02 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"A fire main system must have enough fire hydrants so that each accessible space may be sprayed with ____________.",opa:"a low velocity spray applicator",opb:"a water spray or solid stream",opc:"at least two spray patterns of water",opd:"at least 25 psi delivered pressure",ans:"opc"},{question:"Under the Pollution Regulations, garbage disposal records must be retained onboard for ____________.",opa:"one year",opb:"two years",opc:"until the end of the voyage",opd:"until the next Coast Guard inspection",ans:"opb"},{question:"What does the lifesaving signal indicated by a horizontal motion of a white light or white flare mean?",opa:"'Landing here highly dangerous'",opb:"'Negative'",opc:"'Avast hauling'",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"On small passenger vessels if an item of lifesaving equipment is carried but not required ____________.",opa:"the equipment must be approved by the Commandant",opb:"it must be removed from the vessel as excess equipment",opc:"it may remain aboard the vessel as excess equipment regardless of its condition",opd:"it must be destroyed in the presence of a marine inspector",ans:"opa"},{question:"The proper stimulant for an unconscious person is ____________.",opa:"tea",opb:"coffee",opc:"whiskey and water",opd:"ammonia inhalant",ans:"opd"},{question:"Intact buoyancy is a term used to describe ____________.",opa:"the volume of all intact spaces above the waterline",opb:"an intact space below the surface of a flooded area",opc:"an intact space which can be flooded without causing a ship to sink",opd:"the space at which all the vertical upward forces of buoyancy are considered to be concentrated",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 2.8 ft.",opb:"Available GM 3.2 ft.",opc:"Available GM 3.5 ft.",opd:"Available GM 3.8 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), discharges a non-liquid load of 275.8 long tons from a position 130 feet above the keel, 40 feet forward of amidships, and 30 feet to port of the centerline. What is the improvement in KGL?",opa:"0.67 foot",opb:"0.98 foot",opc:"1.15 feet",opd:"2.06 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is moored in 700 feet of water. The tension on anchor line #3 is 200 kips. What is the vertical component of chain tension for that line?",opa:"59.1 long tons",opb:"60.9 long tons",opc:"89.3 long tons",opd:"487.2 long tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the COASTAL DRILLER is afloat, the water for the saltwater eductor system is provided by ____________.",opa:"raw water tower pumps",opb:"fire pumps",opc:"bilge pumps",opd:"mud pumps",ans:"opb"},{question:"A floating jack-up with displacement of 16,200 kips has its LCG 110.37 feet aft of frame zero (AF0). If 200 short tons are discharged from 120 feet AF0 and 400 short tons are discharged from 150 feet AF0, what is the new LCG?",opa:"108.0 feet",opb:"109.2 feet",opc:"110.4 feet",opd:"115.8 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"When discharging cargo from a tank barge, in which case may the cargo pass through or over the towing vessel?",opa:"With permission from the person in charge of the towing vessel",opb:"With permission from the person in charge of the shore facility",opc:"When off-loading grade C cargo",opd:"In no case",ans:"opd"},{question:"What should be your FIRST action if you discover a fire aboard ship?",opa:"Sound the alarm.",opb:"Attempt to put out the fire.",opc:"Confine it by closing doors, ports, vents, etc.",opd:"Call the Master.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The radiotelephone safety message urgently concerned with safety of a person would be prefixed by the word ____________.",opa:"Mayday",opb:"Pan",opc:"Safety",opd:"Interco",ans:"opb"},{question:"What must the Master or person in charge of a MODU enter in the logbook after conducting a boat drill?",opa:"Which survival craft was used in the drill",opb:"The number of each lifeboat not lowered during each drill",opc:"Only the number of each motor propelled lifeboat that is lowered",opd:"The length of time an oar propelled lifeboat is rowed",ans:"opa"},{question:"The premixed foam agent in fixed and semi portable fire extinguishing systems should be replaced ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"every 12 months",opb:"every 18 months",opc:"every 36 months",opd:"only when used",ans:"opc"},{question:"Before operating a non-oceangoing ship greater than 100 gross tons it must have a fixed piping system to discharge oily mixtures ashore. This system must include ____________.",opa:"approved oil-water separating equipment",opb:"a fixed or portable containment system at the shore connection",opc:"a spare pump in case the main pump is inoperative",opd:"at least one outlet accessible from the weather deck",ans:"opd"},{question:"By regulation, your cargo vessel must have ____________.",opa:"sufficient facilities for the crew to wash their clothes",opb:"a wash basin in each room",opc:"separate toilet facilities for engineers where their number exceeds six",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"189 tons",opb:"174 tons",opc:"158 tons",opd:"No loading required",ans:"opc"},{question:"While the COASTAL DRILLER is in normal transit, the roll period is 8 seconds. What would be the limiting angle of pitch which does not exceed the design limits of the legs?",opa:"10\xb0",opb:"8\xb0",opc:"6\xb0",opd:"4\xb0",ans:"opc"},{question:"You discharge garbage overboard at sea. When recording your vessel's position as required, you must include ____________.",opa:"latitude, longitude and approximate depth of water",opb:"latitude, longitude, course, speed, and a copy of that days noon position slip",opc:"latitude, longitude, and estimated distance from shore",opd:"latitude and longitude only",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have 360 tons of below deck tonnage and 145 tons of above deck cargo onboard. You must load 220 tons of liquid mud below deck. How much more deck cargo can you load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"22 tons",opb:"48 tons",opc:"94 tons",opd:"239 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The bottom of the mast rests on a part of the keel called the mast ____________.",opa:"foot",opb:"heel",opc:"step",opd:"sole",ans:"opc"},{question:"Regulations require that cargo tanks carrying grades D or E liquids on tank barges be vented with ____________.",opa:"gooseneck vents and flame screens",opb:"pressure-vacuum relief valves",opc:"branch vent lines and a vent header",opd:"forced draft blowers",ans:"opa"},{question:"You should NOT use a power tool if ____________.",opa:"it has a three-prong plug",opb:"the insulation of the power wires is worn",opc:"hand tools can be used instead",opd:"the power source is alternating current",ans:"opb"},{question:"What organization is approved by the Coast Guard for certifying cranes on mobile offshore drilling units?",opa:"Minerals Management Service",opb:"International Maritime Organization",opc:"American Bureau of Shipping",opd:"Lloyd's of London",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a documented small passenger vessel, what information must be permanently affixed in block-type letters and/or numerals to the main beam or other clearly visible interior structural part of the hull?",opa:"The vessel's name and gross tonnage",opb:"The vessel's official number",opc:"Draft markings",opd:"The vessel's name and home port",ans:"opb"},{question:"According to the regulations for mobile offshore drilling units, 'industrial personnel' are considered to be all persons carried on the MODU for the sole purpose of carrying out the industrial business of the unit, except for ____________.",opa:"the operator's representative",opb:"the crew required by the Certificate of Inspection",opc:"the galley personnel",opd:"the designated person in charge",ans:"opb"},{question:"The definition of 'partially protected waters', as used in the Regulations does not include ____________.",opa:"harbors, lakes and similar waters determined by the OCMI to be protected waters",opb:"waters within 20 nautical miles from the mouth of a harbor of safe refuge",opc:"the Great Lakes during the summer season",opd:"sheltered waters presenting no special hazard",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents the direction of primary means of escape?",opa:"58",opb:"61",opc:"62",opd:"63",ans:"opb"},{question:"Subtracting GM from KM yields ____________.",opa:"BL",opb:"GM",opc:"FS",opd:"KG",ans:"opd"},{question:"With damaged floating vessels, the most important consideration is the preservation of ____________.",opa:"bilge pumping capacity",opb:"reserve buoyancy",opc:"level attitude",opd:"instability",ans:"opb"},{question:"Reserve buoyancy is ____________.",opa:"the watertight part of a vessel above the waterline",opb:"the void portion of the ship below the waterline which is enclosed and watertight",opc:"transverse watertight bulkheads",opd:"a measure of metacentric height",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning life jackets which are severely damaged?",opa:"They should be replaced.",opb:"They must be tested for buoyancy before being continued in use.",opc:"They can be repaired by a reliable seamstress.",opd:"They can be used for children.",ans:"opa"},{question:"The element used to keep weight on the bit at a constant value in spite of up-and-down movement of a MODU during floating drilling operations is the heave or drill string ____________.",opa:"compensator",opb:"tensioner",opc:"stabilizer",opd:"equalizer",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have 160 tons of below deck tonnage and 300 tons of above deck cargo onboard. You must load 110 tons of liquid mud below deck. How much more deck cargo can you load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"55 tons",opb:"99 tons",opc:"140 tons",opd:"360 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"Every seaman injured on a fishing vessel must report the injury to the Master, individual in charge, or other agent of the employer ____________.",opa:"before the end of the voyage",opb:"no later than 24 hours after the vessel docks",opc:"no later than 7 days after the injury occurred",opd:"only if the injury prevents him from working",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the lifesaving signal for 'You are seen -Assistance will be given as soon as possible'?",opa:"3 white star signals",opb:"Horizontal motion with a white flag",opc:"Vertical motion of a white light",opd:"Code letter 'K' by blinker light",ans:"opa"},{question:"Subtracting the height of the center of gravity corrected for longitudinal free surface effects from the height of the longitudinal metacenter of a MODU yields ____________.",opa:"GM",opb:"GML",opc:"KGL",opd:"KML",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 3200 tons of cargo, 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 259 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in fresh water:",opa:"17'-00'",opb:"16'-09'",opc:"16'-06'",opd:"16'-04'",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which two components pass through the shank of an LWT anchor?",opa:"Anchor shackle and stock",opb:"Tripping palm and flukes",opc:"Crown and chocks",opd:"Swivel and stabilizer bar",ans:"opa"},{question:"When fighting a large fire on your vessel and attacking it from ABOVE the space on fire, it is important to ____________.",opa:"rotate personnel, due to heat stress",opb:"stand erect, to avoid the heat of the deck",opc:"cool the deck directly above the space on fire",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"For a MODU not on an international voyage, an approved substitute for an impulse projected rocket-type line throwing appliance is a ____________.",opa:"spring loaded line thrower",opb:"hand thrown buoyant line",opc:"shoulder-type line throwing gun",opd:"heaving line",ans:"opc"},{question:"Spaces containing batteries require good ventilation because ____________.",opa:"ventilation avoids CO2 buildup",opb:"ventilation supplies extra oxygen for the battery",opc:"ventilation avoids flammable gas accumulation",opd:"less water would be used",ans:"opc"},{question:"No 'T-boat', however propelled, may operate with more than six passengers onboard ____________.",opa:"unless the operator has a Coast Guard license",opb:"unless the vessel has a valid Permit to Proceed",opc:"until the Boarding Officer has checked the papers",opd:"until a permit is obtained from the Collector of Customs",ans:"opa"},{question:"A heavy steel device that is set on the sea floor and used as a drilling template in offshore drilling operations is called a ____________.",opa:"temporary guide base",opb:"permanent guide base",opc:"guide frame",opd:"foundation template",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the contents of the #7 drill water tank are discharged, what would be the new TCG?",opa:"-0.15 foot",opb:"0.00 foot",opc:"0.15 foot",opd:"0.29 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"At a speed of 6 knots the fuel aboard a survival craft should last ____________.",opa:"8 hours",opb:"12 hours",opc:"24 hours",opd:"48 hours",ans:"opc"},{question:"When flammable liquids are handled in a compartment on a vessel, the ventilation for that area should be ____________.",opa:"operated continuously while vapors may be present",opb:"operated intermittently to remove vapors",opc:"available on standby for immediate use",opd:"shut down if an explosive mixture is present",ans:"opa"},{question:"A semisubmersible with a displacement of 20,000 tons and a KG of 60.0 feet loads 300 tons at a VCG of 120 feet. What is the change in KG?",opa:"1.32 feet downward",opb:"1.32 feet upward",opc:"0.89 foot downward",opd:"0.89 foot upward",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each fire hydrant must have at least one spanner and at least one ____________.",opa:"hose rack or reel",opb:"all purpose nozzle",opc:"foam applicator",opd:"pick axe",ans:"opa"},{question:"Life floats and buoyant apparatus may be stowed in tiers, one above the other, to a height of not more than ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"3 feet",opb:"4 feet",opc:"5 feet",opd:"6 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which categories of NAVTEX messages may not be selectively rejected through receiver programming?",opa:"Navigational warnings",opb:"Weather warnings",opc:"SAR information",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"A small passenger vessel's Official Number must be marked ____________.",opa:"in block type Arabic numerals not less than 3 inches high",opb:"or mounted so that any alteration, removal, or replacement would be obvious",opc:"on some clearly visible interior structural hull part",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"On cargo vessels, the discharge of the required quantity of carbon dioxide into any 'tight' space shall be completed within ____________.",opa:"1 minute",opb:"2 minutes",opc:"4 minutes",opd:"6 minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"When heated to breakdown, tetraethyl or tetramethyl lead compounds emit highly toxic fumes of ____________.",opa:"hydrogen gas",opb:"lead",opc:"bromide",opd:"phosgene",ans:"opb"},{question:"The minimum number of portable B-II fire extinguishers required in the machinery space of a 199 GT motor towing vessel of 8000 B.H.P. is ____________. (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"3",opb:"6",opc:"8",opd:"9",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has drafts of: FWD 28'-00', AFT 29'-00'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts if you ballast the forepeak with 81.05 tons of seawater.",opa:"FWD 28'-06.2', AFT28'-06.2'",opb:"FWD 28'-06.3', AFT28'-08.0'",opc:"FWD 28'-07.3', AFT28'-07.8'",opd:"FWD 28'-10.0', AFT28'-08.0'",ans:"opc"},{question:"On offshore drilling units, the minimum number of persons required to be trained in the use of fireman's outfits is ____________.",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your tow contains a barge carrying carbon tetrachloride. What is NOT required?",opa:"Cargo warning signs on barge",opb:"Cargo information card on barge",opc:"Cargo information card in pilothouse",opd:"Certificated tankerman on towboat",ans:"opd"},{question:"On a MODU with lifeboats stowed in two different locations, if all the lifeboats are lost in one location then the remaining lifeboats must accommodate what percentage of the persons permitted onboard?",opa:"0.5",opb:"0.75",opc:"0.9",opd:"1",ans:"opd"},{question:"All VHF marine band radios operate in the simplex mode, which means that ____________.",opa:"only one person may talk at a time",opb:"only two persons may talk at the same time",opc:"the radio only transmits",opd:"the radio only receives",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a supply run to an offshore drilling rig. onboard is the cargo listed. What is the height above the main deck of the center of gravity of the cargo?",opa:"3.6 feet",opb:"4.2 feet",opc:"4.4 feet",opd:"4.9 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 14'-04', AFT 17'-08'. The LCG of the forepeak is 200 feet forward of amidships. How many tons of ballast must be pumped into the forepeak in order to have a drag of 18 inches? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"110 tons",opb:"103 tons",opc:"100 tons",opd:"98 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a fire drill is conducted on a mobile offshore drilling unit, the designated person in charge must ensure that ____________.",opa:"all personnel report to their stations",opb:"each hose is brought to full pressure at the nozzle",opc:"at least three portable extinguishers are activated",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is NOT required of the cargo tank venting on a tank barge carrying grade A liquids?",opa:"Each cargo tank must have a vent.",opb:"A vent header must be fitted with a pressure-vacuum valve.",opc:"The diameter of the vent must be greater than 4 inches in diameter.",opd:"The vent must extend to a reasonable height above the weather deck.",ans:"opc"},{question:"A sail plan, including the vessel's itinerary, name, number, and persons aboard, should be filed with ____________.",opa:"the FAA",opb:"the Coast Guard",opc:"U.S. Customs",opd:"a responsible person",ans:"opd"},{question:"One disadvantage of using regular dry chemical (sodium bicarbonate) in firefighting is that ____________.",opa:"it can break down under high heat and emit noxious fumes",opb:"it will decompose under prolonged storage and lose its effectiveness",opc:"fire has been known to flash back over the surface of an oil fire",opd:"it is ineffective in fighting fires in high-voltage electrical equipment",ans:"opc"},{question:"The mechanism that will release the tricing pendant, as shown, is ____________.",opa:"the fore and aft gripes",opb:"the McCluny hook",opc:"a quick release lever",opd:"a 3/4' shackle",ans:"opb"},{question:"Why does a centrifugal bilge pump require priming?",opa:"To lubricate shaft seals",opb:"Lack of ability to lift water level to impellers",opc:"Head pressure must equal discharge pressure",opd:"To overcome resistance of water in the discharge line",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the expected range of a VHF radio transmission from a vessel to a shore station?",opa:"About 20 miles",opb:"50 -100 miles",opc:"100 -150 miles",opd:"150 -200 miles",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which piece of navigational safety equipment is NOT required on towing vessels over 12 meters in length, provided that the vessel remains within the navigable waters of the U.S.?",opa:"VHF-FM radio(s)",opb:"GPS receiver",opc:"Charts or maps of the areas to be transited",opd:"Searchlight",ans:"opb"},{question:"Where is thicker plating usually found in the construction of integral tanks on a MODU?",opa:"On the outside of the tank",opb:"At the bottom of the tank",opc:"At the top of the tank",opd:"At the center of the tank",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents an emergency generator?",opa:"20",opb:"32",opc:"67",opd:"68",ans:"opc"},{question:"Preload tank 22B on the COASTAL DRILLER contains 5.0 feet of preload. It is decided to complete filling the tank. What is the TCG of the added liquid?",opa:"65.60 feet",opb:"65.74 feet",opc:"65.77 feet",opd:"65.83 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"On small passenger vessels, how many supply and exhaust ducts are required in each enclosed space containing gasoline powered machinery or gasoline fuel tanks?",opa:"1 of each",opb:"2 of each",opc:"3 of each",opd:"4 of each",ans:"opb"},{question:"When using the rain water collection tubes on a liferaft, the first collection should be ____________.",opa:"passed around so all can drink",opb:"poured overboard because of salt washed off the canopy",opc:"saved to be used at a later time",opd:"used to boil food",ans:"opb"},{question:"In observing rig motion while under tow, the period of roll is the time difference between ____________.",opa:"zero inclination to full inclination on one side",opb:"full inclination on one side to full inclination on the other side",opc:"full inclination on one side to the next full inclination on the same side",opd:"zero inclination to the next zero inclination",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which radiotelephone transmission may be sent over channel 16?",opa:"Distress signal MAYDAY",opb:"Call to a particular station",opc:"A meteorological warning",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"When displacement increases, the free surface moments of slack tanks ____________.",opa:"increase",opb:"decrease",opc:"are inversely proportional",opd:"remain unchanged",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are scheduled to load 3700 tons of cargo, 45 tons of crew effects and stores and 427 tons of fuel. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the vessel's mean draft in salt water.",opa:"17'-01'",opb:"17'-05'",opc:"17'-10'",opd:"18'-00'",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Coast Guard broadcasts routine weather reports on channel ____________.",opa:"13",opb:"9A",opc:"22A",opd:"44",ans:"opc"},{question:"Who may approve cargo piping to pass through a machinery space for a barge designed to carry only grade E products?",opa:"American Bureau of Shipping",opb:"National Cargo Bureau",opc:"Commandant, U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"Vessel owner",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the contents of #6 and #7 drill water tanks are discharged, what is the new height of the center of gravity corrected for transverse free surface effects?",opa:"47.49 feet",opb:"49.16 feet",opc:"50.82 feet",opd:"50.93 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have abandoned ship and after two days in a liferaft you can see an aircraft near the horizon apparently carrying out a search pattern. You should ____________.",opa:"switch the EPIRB to the homing signal mode",opb:"use the voice transmission capability of the EPIRB to guide the aircraft to your raft",opc:"turn on the strobe light on the top of the EPIRB",opd:"use visual distress signals in conjunction with the EPIRB",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 27'-06', AFT 28'-02'; and the KG is 21.3 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 15\xb0 inclination.",opa:"0.3 foot",opb:"1.3 feet",opc:"1.5 feet",opd:"1.8 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"How many fireman's outfits are required on a MODU?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement about the free surface effect is TRUE?",opa:"It increases in direct proportion to the length of the tank times the breadth squared.",opb:"It decreases at increased angles of heel due to pocketing when a tank is 90% full.",opc:"It decreases in direct proportion to increasing specific gravity of the liquid in the tank.",opd:"In practice, the correction is considered to be a virtual reduction of KG.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The International Regulations for Preventing Collisions at Sea contain the requirements for ____________.",opa:"signals that must be sounded when being towed in restricted visibility",opb:"minimum hawser lengths when being towed",opc:"lights that must be displayed on anchor buoys",opd:"mooring procedures for support vessels when transferring cargo",ans:"opa"},{question:"The bottom of the mast rests on a part of the keel called the mast ____________.",opa:"foot",opb:"heel",opc:"step",opd:"sole",ans:"opc"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is elevated while preparing for the passage of a severe storm. With ideal loading, the static loading on each of the three legs would be 4,715 kips. However, the LCG is 121 feet AFO and TCG is 0.5 foot to starboard of the centerline. By how many kips does the starboard leg reaction exceed the ideal loading?",opa:"00 kips",opb:"32 kips",opc:"149 kips",opd:"181 kips",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 6048 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 270.89 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 263.4 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 266.6 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 267.8 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 269.4 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A distress signal ____________.",opa:"consists of 5 or more short blasts of the fog signal apparatus",opb:"consists of the raising and lowering of a large white flag",opc:"may be used individually or in conjunction with other distress signals",opd:"is used to indicate doubt about another vessel's intentions",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the minimum number of portable fire extinguishers required onboard a 45-foot towing vessel having a fixed fire system onboard? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"1 B-I",opb:"2 B-I",opc:"3 B-I",opd:"4 B-I",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 08'-11.5', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"2.15 feet",opb:"2.05 feet",opc:"1.95 feet",opd:"1.75 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"When chipping rust on a vessel, the MOST important piece of safety gear is ____________.",opa:"a hard hat",opb:"gloves",opc:"goggles",opd:"a long sleeve shirt",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which small passenger vessel(s) is/are NOT required to carry a Category 1 406 MHz EPIRB?",opa:"A coastwise vessel whose route does not take it more than three miles from shore",opb:"A vessel operating on lakes, bays, sounds, and rivers",opc:"A vessel operating within three miles from the coastline of the Great Lakes",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The shut off valve at the gasoline tank which can be operated from outside the tank space ____________.",opa:"controls the amount of gasoline to the engine",opb:"shuts off the gasoline supply at the tank",opc:"is used if the gasoline tank leaks",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"At each initial and subsequent inspection for certification, all carbon dioxide fire extinguishers aboard a vessel are ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"checked for pressure loss",opb:"discharged and recharged",opc:"sent ashore to an approved service facility",opd:"weighed",ans:"opd"},{question:"The color of rockets, shells, or rocket parachute flares used to indicate that the vessel is in distress and requires immediate assistance is ____________.",opa:"white",opb:"green",opc:"red",opd:"yellow",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the report identifier code for the first AMVER report sent at the start of a voyage?",opa:"DP",opb:"DR",opc:"PR",opd:"SP",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is level at a draft of 60 feet in calm water. What is the value of the righting moment?",opa:"18,118 foot-tons",opb:"9,059 foot-tons",opc:"4,529 foot-tons",opd:"0 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #5, loads 275.8 long tons. The resulting trim by the stern is 3 feet and list to port is 2 feet. What is the draft at the starboard aft draft mark?",opa:"44 feet 6 inches",opb:"47 feet 0 inches",opc:"47 feet 6 inches",opd:"48 feet 6 inches",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the reduction in metacentric height due to free surface when a tank 60 ft. wide and 60 ft. long is partially filled with saltwater? (The vessel's displacement is 10,000 tons.)",opa:"3.00 feet",opb:"3.09 feet",opc:"3.15 feet",opd:"3.20 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"In any major injury to a person, first aid includes the treatment for the injury and ____________.",opa:"application of CPR",opb:"removal of any foreign objects",opc:"administration of oxygen",opd:"for traumatic shock",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are FWD 20'-09', AFT 21'-01'. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final drafts if: (1) 320 tons are loaded 47 feet forward of amidships; (2) 82 tons are discharged 110 feet forward of amidships; and (3) 50 tons of fuel are pumped 60 feet forward.",opa:"FWD 21'-05', AFT21'-00'",opb:"FWD 21'-06', AFT21'-02'",opc:"FWD 21'-04', AFT21'-05'",opd:"FWD 21'-04', AFT21'-06'",ans:"opb"},{question:"Remote controls for quick-closing shut off valves are required in how many location(s)?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER at survival draft loads 2,068.1 long tons of ballast. What is the new draft?",opa:"30.0 feet",opb:"45.0 feet",opc:"60.0 feet",opd:"75.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"According to 46 CFR Subchapter T, rigid plastic and other nonmetallic piping materials ____________.",opa:"may replace metal pipe or tubing in any installation",opb:"may not be used on inspected vessels",opc:"may only be used in non-vital systems",opd:"are preferable to steel pipe",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the metacentric height is small, a floating MODU will ____________.",opa:"be tender",opb:"have a quick and rapid motion",opc:"be stiff",opd:"yaw",ans:"opa"},{question:"When taking soundings on a floating MODU, the tape should be lowered and brought back quickly to ____________.",opa:"reduce the time the sounding tube is open",opb:"avoid creating a spark",opc:"lessen the effect of roll or pitch on the reading",opd:"lessen the effect of heave on the reading",ans:"opc"},{question:"When underway at a draft of 10.5 feet in a severe storm, the COASTAL DRILLER has a maximum allowed KG of ____________.",opa:"40 feet",opb:"50 feet",opc:"55 feet",opd:"65 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 4145 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 25.5 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 25.0 feet",opb:"KG 25.6 feet",opc:"KG 26.2 feet",opd:"KG 26.8 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of vertical moments for Fuel Oil if the entire contents of Tank 4P are transferred to Tank 4S?",opa:"3,493 foot-tons",opb:"1,797 foot-tons",opc:"1,748 foot-tons",opd:"100 foot-tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"The signal for a fire emergency on an OSV is ____________.",opa:"a 30 second on 30 second off alternating signal",opb:"the continuous blast of the ships whistle for not less than 10 seconds supplemented by the continuous ringing of the general alarm bells for not less than 10 seconds",opc:"an intermittent ringing of the general alarm for not less than ten seconds",opd:"announced over the PA system",ans:"opb"},{question:"On a vessel of 10,000 tons displacement, compute the reduction in metacentric height due to free surface in a hold having free water on the tank top. The hold is 40 feet long and 50 feet wide. The reduction in metacentric height is ____________.",opa:"1.1 feet",opb:"1.2 feet",opc:"1.3 feet",opd:"1.5 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"How should the number '5' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"FIVE-ER",opb:"NEW-MARL-FIVE",opc:"NUM-ERL-FIVE",opd:"PAN-TAH-FIVE",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have approximately 24 tons of fish on deck. What will be the shift in the center of gravity after you shift the fish to the fish hold, a vertical distance of 8 feet? (total displacement is 540 tons)",opa:"0.14 foot",opb:"0.23 foot",opc:"0.36 foot",opd:"0.44 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"A tank with internal dimensions of 40 feet X 20 feet X 12 feet is pressed with fuel oil weighing 54 pounds per cubic foot. What is the weight, in short tons, of the liquid?",opa:"518.4 short tons",opb:"259.2 short tons",opc:"135.0 short tons",opd:"11.3 short tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the best instrument for establishing a safe working area before welding in a confined space?",opa:"An oxygen indicator",opb:"A combustible gas indicator",opc:"A combination combustible gas and oxygen indicator",opd:"A flame safety lamp",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have just abandoned ship and boarded a raft. After the raft is completely inflated you hear a whistling noise coming from a safety valve. You should ____________.",opa:"not become alarmed unless it continues for a long period of time",opb:"plug the safety valve",opc:"unscrew the deflation plugs",opd:"remove the safety valve and replace it with a soft patch",ans:"opa"},{question:"The size of fire hydrant hose connections must be either 1-1/2 inches or ____________.",opa:"1 inch",opb:"2-1/2 inches",opc:"3 inches",opd:"3-1/2 inches",ans:"opb"},{question:"A moment is obtained by multiplying a force by its ____________.",opa:"couple",opb:"lever arm",opc:"moment of inertia",opd:"point of application",ans:"opb"},{question:"You have 60 tons of below deck tonnage and 220 tons of above deck cargo onboard. You must load 240 tons of liquid mud below deck. How much more deck cargo can you load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"65 tons",opb:"85 tons",opc:"110 tons",opd:"125 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"The location of a spare set of fire control plans onboard the vessel is designated by what approved symbol?",opa:"1",opb:"30",opc:"37",opd:"69",ans:"opa"},{question:"You operate the lever shown when the lifeboat is ____________.",opa:"in the secured position",opb:"at the embarkation deck",opc:"being lowered to sea level",opd:"waterborne",ans:"opd"},{question:"When picking up a lifeboat at sea with way on the ship, the sea painter should be secured ____________.",opa:"well forward in the lifeboat",opb:"about amidships in the lifeboat",opc:"well aft in the lifeboat",opd:"only after the falls have been attached",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER has a KGT of 52.90 feet while at a draft of 58.0 feet. List is 2.0 feet to port. What is the value of TCG?",opa:"-0.10 foot",opb:"-0.13 foot",opc:"-0.16 foot",opd:"-0.19 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has drafts of: FWD 22'-03', AFT 24'-00'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts if you ballast the forepeak with 100.7 tons of seawater.",opa:"FWD 23'-00.3', AFT23'-05.0'",opb:"FWD 23'-01.0', AFT23'-05.7'",opc:"FWD 22'-11.3', AFT23'-04.0'",opd:"FWD 22'-10.3', AFT23'-06.0'",ans:"opb"},{question:"To determine the number of industrial personnel allowed on a mobile offshore drilling unit, you should check the ____________.",opa:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opb:"Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opc:"Certificate of Inspection",opd:"Operations Manual",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which tank barges require draft marks?",opa:"Notch barges over 1000 GT",opb:"Tank barges over 100 GT",opc:"Tank barges over 50 GT",opd:"All tank barges",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 24'-04', AFT 25'-10'; and the KG is 23.5 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 37\xb0 inclination.",opa:"1.9 feet",opb:"2.1 feet",opc:"3.5 feet",opd:"4.2 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"A person reports to you with a fishhook in his thumb. To remove it you should ____________.",opa:"pull it out with pliers",opb:"cut the skin from around the hook",opc:"push the barb through, cut it off, then remove the hook",opd:"have a surgeon remove it",ans:"opc"},{question:"A MODU having continuous closely spaced transverse strength members is ____________.",opa:"longitudinally framed",opb:"transversely framed",opc:"cellular framed",opd:"web framed",ans:"opb"},{question:"Progressive flooding on a MODU may be indicated by ____________.",opa:"ballast control alarms",opb:"excessive draft",opc:"excessive list or trim",opd:"a continual worsening of list or trim",ans:"opd"},{question:"Because there is a possibility of fuel oil being discharged overboard from a full fuel oil tank, it is decided to transfer 25 kips from tank #14 to tank #20. See COASTAL DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What would be the change in longitudinal moments with this transfer?",opa:"565 ft.-kips",opb:"900 ft.-kips",opc:"2603 ft.-kips",opd:"3168 ft.-kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are the operator of a 295 GRT uninspected towing vessel. Which type of fire extinguishing system is required on your vessel, if its construction was contracted for before August 27, 2003? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"Type B-V semi-portable OR a fixed fire-extinguishing system",opb:"Type B-IV semi-portable OR a fixed fire-extinguishing system",opc:"Type B-III semi-portable AND a fixed fire-extinguishing system",opd:"Fixed CO2, AND another fixed fire-extinguishing system",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each ship having an inert gas system must have a portable instrument to measure concentrations of hydrocarbon vapor in inert atmospheres and also to measure ____________.",opa:"nitrogen",opb:"oxygen",opc:"carbon dioxide",opd:"water vapor",ans:"opb"},{question:"The Master or other vessel representative must contact the nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety Office within five days of a(n) ____________.",opa:"grounding",opb:"injury which requires first aid",opc:"accident which requires $(SA)2500 of repairs",opd:"All of the above are correct.",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the COASTAL DRILLER is elevated, the water for the saltwater eductor system is provided by ____________.",opa:"raw water tower pumps",opb:"fire pumps",opc:"bilge pumps",opd:"mud pumps",ans:"opa"},{question:"An obstruction light on a mobile offshore drilling unit on the waters of the U.S. Outer Continental Shelf, shall have a lens that is visible over an arc of ____________.",opa:"60\xb0",opb:"90\xb0",opc:"180\xb0",opd:"360\xb0",ans:"opd"},{question:"The 'off-load' release system on a survival craft is designed to be activated ____________.",opa:"when there is no load on the cable",opb:"when there is a load on the cable",opc:"only when the doors are closed",opd:"when the engine is started",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the primary purpose of a splint applied in first aid?",opa:"Control bleeding",opb:"Reduce pain",opc:"Immobilize a fracture",opd:"Reset the bone",ans:"opc"},{question:"Where would you find the 'call sign' or 'call letters' of the radio station on your rig?",opa:"In the rig safety manual",opb:"On the Certificate of Inspection",opc:"On the Ship Station License",opd:"On the rig Watch Bill",ans:"opc"},{question:"Failure of both port ballast pumps on the DEEP DRILLER prevents their use. To deballast from tank 1P, you may use the ____________.",opa:"port saltwater service pump",opb:"port drill water pump",opc:"port bilge pumps",opd:"starboard ballast pump and the crossover system",ans:"opd"},{question:"Before starting a gasoline engine on a motorboat, you should make sure for safety that ____________.",opa:"the gasoline tank is full",opb:"the bilges, cabins, etc. are thoroughly ventilated",opc:"you have fresh water onboard",opd:"Each of the above is followed",ans:"opb"},{question:"Whenever practicable, the Certificate of Inspection must be posted ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"as high as feasible in the pilot house",opb:"near the area where passengers embark",opc:"in any location desired",opd:"in a conspicuous place where it will most likely be observed by the passengers",ans:"opd"},{question:"The VHF radiotelephone calling/safety/distress frequency is ____________.",opa:"156.8 MHz (channel 16)",opb:"156.7 MHz (channel 14)",opc:"156.65 MHz (channel 13)",opd:"156.6 MHz (channel 12)",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER at a draft of 58.0 feet loads 68.94 long tons of ballast. What is the new draft?",opa:"52.0 feet",opb:"57.5 feet",opc:"58.5 feet",opd:"64.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"What type of vent is required on a barge transporting No. 6 fuel oil?",opa:"Gooseneck vents fitted with flame screens",opb:"Pressure-vacuum",opc:"Branch vent line",opd:"Vent header",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is loaded with the cargo shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the amount of liquid loading required in the double bottom tanks to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"280 tons",opb:"395 tons",opc:"750 tons",opd:"990 tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the minimum number of fire pumps required on a cargo vessel of 2,000 GT?",opa:"1",opb:"2",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opb"},{question:"When using the combustible gas indicator, a special filter for filtering the incoming sample must be used if the atmosphere being tested contains vapors of ____________.",opa:"sour crude",opb:"leaded gasoline",opc:"CO2",opd:"chlorine",ans:"opb"},{question:"The sounding for Drill Water Tank #18 for the Coastal Driller is 1.25 feet. It is decided to fill the tank. What is the vertical center of gravity for the added liquid?",opa:"3.13 feet",opb:"2.50 feet",opc:"1.87 feet",opd:"0.63 foot",ans:"opa"},{question:"Among the possible causes of unexpected rapidly increasing inclination of the DEEP DRILLER while in transit is ____________.",opa:"consumption of onboard variables",opb:"miscalculation of loads",opc:"external environmental forces",opd:"flooding due to lower-hull damage",ans:"opd"},{question:"While loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #5 (Survival), an estimated 250 long tons of snow and ice accumulates on the DEEP DRILLER at an estimated height of 127 feet. Assuming no corrective ballasting, what is the margin on maximum allowable KG?",opa:"1.55 feet",opb:"1.23 feet",opc:"0.50 foot",opd:"-1.45 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"AMVER is a system which provides ____________.",opa:"satellite communications",opb:"navigational information",opc:"weather information",opd:"position reporting service",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have 400 tons of below deck tonnage and 230 tons of above deck cargo onboard. You must load 220 tons of liquid mud below deck. How much more deck cargo can you load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"60 tons",opb:"180 tons",opc:"240 tons",opd:"none",ans:"opd"},{question:"The MOST important element in administering CPR is ____________.",opa:"having the proper equipment for the process",opb:"starting the treatment quickly",opc:"administering of oxygen",opd:"treating for traumatic shock",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 22'-09', AFT 23'-07'; and the KG is 24.2 feet. Use the selected stability curves in the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the righting arm at 18\xb0 inclination.",opa:"0.7 foot",opb:"1.3 feet",opc:"2.0 feet",opd:"2.3 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the most important difference between the bow type anchor shackle and the D-type anchor shackle?",opa:"The bow type shackle provides a superior connection.",opb:"The D-type shackle is weaker than the bow type.",opc:"The bow type shackle is weaker than the D-type.",opd:"The D-type shackle provides an inferior connection.",ans:"opc"},{question:"If you came into contact with nitrobenzene while disconnecting the cargo hose, you should be aware that it is ____________.",opa:"highly toxic when absorbed through the skin",opb:"a blood poison",opc:"a nerve poison",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"If more than one raft is manned after the vessel has sunk, you should ____________.",opa:"go in a different direction in search of land",opb:"spread out to increase the possibility of a search aircraft finding you",opc:"reduce the number of rafts by getting as many people as possible into as few rafts as possible",opd:"tie the rafts together and try to stay in a single group",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which conditions will normally cause a SART to operate in the active mode?",opa:"It will respond only to interrogation by 9-Ghz radar signals.",opb:"A SART will normally respond to interrogation from a searching vessel's radar if the radar antenna is at least 15 meters high.",opc:"A SART will normally respond to interrogation from a searching aircraft's radar if the radar's output power is at least 10,000 watts and the aircraft is at a height of 3000 feet and within 30 nautical miles.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"How are lifelines attached to a life float?",opa:"By serving",opb:"By splicing one end of the line around the apparatus",opc:"Securely attached around the outside in bights no longer than three feet",opd:"With an approved safety hook or shackle",ans:"opc"},{question:"The litter on a MODU must be able to ____________.",opa:"carry at least two injured persons",opb:"float for at least two hours",opc:"be used on the types of helicopters serving the unit",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning fuel vapors on a vessel?",opa:"Fuel vapors gather in the lowest portions of the vessel.",opb:"Fuel vapors can only be ignited by an open flame.",opc:"Vent outlets should be located above the level of the carburetor air intake.",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your drafts are: FWD 16'-02', AFT 20'-08'. Use the blue pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the MT1.",opa:"920 foot-tons",opb:"935 foot-tons",opc:"960 foot-tons",opd:"980 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Radiation spreads a fire by ____________.",opa:"transferring heat across an unobstructed space",opb:"heated gases flowing through ventilation systems",opc:"burning liquids flowing into another space",opd:"transmitting the heat of a fire through the ship's metal",ans:"opa"},{question:"Towing vessel fire protection regulations apply to vessels operated ____________.",opa:"for restricted service such as making up or breaking up larger tows",opb:"for assistance towing",opc:"for pollution response",opd:"on the Western Rivers",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 3224 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 29.8 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 27.2 feet",opb:"KG 27.8 feet",opc:"KG 28.4 feet",opd:"KG 29.0 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"A fire starts on your vessel while refueling. You should FIRST ____________.",opa:"stop the ventilation",opb:"sound the general alarm",opc:"determine the source of the fire",opd:"attempt to extinguish the fire",ans:"opb"},{question:"A MODU displacing 10,000 long tons with KG 20.0 feet, uses its crane to lift a 40 long ton load from dockside and place it onboard at a VCG of 5.0 feet. When lifting, the head of the crane boom is 50.0 feet above the keel. During the lift, what is the apparent increase in KG?",opa:"0.02 foot",opb:"0.12 foot",opc:"0.18 foot",opd:"0.20 foot",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER has a trim of 2.13 feet by the stern. The draft in sea water at the forward draft marks is observed to be 8.0 feet. The KMT is ____________.",opa:"153.73 feet",opb:"160.42 feet",opc:"179.41 feet",opd:"203.97 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"A virtual rise in the center of gravity of a MODU may be caused by ____________.",opa:"filling a partially filled tank",opb:"using fuel from a pressed fuel tank",opc:"emptying a partially filled tank",opd:"transferring pipe from the setback area to the pipe rack",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which procedure should NOT be done for a person who has fainted?",opa:"Revive the person with smelling salts.",opb:"Loosen the clothing.",opc:"Lay the person horizontally.",opd:"Give pain reliever.",ans:"opd"},{question:"Reserve buoyancy is the ____________.",opa:"unoccupied space below the waterline",opb:"volume of intact space above the waterline",opc:"excess of the buoyant force over the gravity force",opd:"difference in the buoyant force in salt and fresh waters",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents the best means to extinguish a LARGE Class Bravo fire?",opa:"44",opb:"39",opc:"36",opd:"14",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is TRUE concerning immersion suits and their use?",opa:"Only a light layer of clothing may be worn underneath.",opb:"They provide sufficient flotation to do away with the necessity of wearing a life jacket.",opc:"They should be tight fitting.",opd:"A puncture in the suit will not appreciably reduce its value.",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the Vapor pressure of ethylene oxide at 46\xb0 C?",opa:"10.9 (psia)",opb:"38.5 (psia)",opc:"48.0 (psia)",opd:"15.2 (psia)",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the best procedure for picking up a lifeboat at sea while utilizing the lifeboat's sea painter?",opa:"Place the lifeboat ahead and to windward of your vessel with the wind about broad on the bow of your ship.",opb:"Place the lifeboat ahead and to leeward of your ship with the wind about broad on the bow of your ship.",opc:"Place your ship to windward of the lifeboat with the wind on the quarter to allow your ship to drift down to the lifeboat.",opd:"Place the lifeboat ahead and to windward of your ship with the wind about broad on the quarter of your ship.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of longitudinal moments for Fuel Oil (Table 2) if the entire contents of Tank 4P are transferred to Tank 4S?",opa:"000 foot-tons",opb:"3,992 foot-tons",opc:"7,984 foot-tons",opd:"15,968 foot-tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"A jack-up with displacement of 10,000 kips has its LCG 100 feet aft of frame zero (AFO). If 200 kips are loaded at 60 feet AFO and 100 kips are discharged from 20 feet AFO, what is the new LCG?",opa:"100.0 feet",opb:"100.4 feet",opc:"100.8 feet",opd:"101.2 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Until a change to lightweight has been approved, the weights and center of gravity locations for the changes to lightweight shown in the permanent record for the Deep Driller are treated as ____________.",opa:"variable load",opb:"fixed load",opc:"basic load",opd:"gross tonnage",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER departs a fresh water port at a draft of 20 feet. What will be the draft in sea water?",opa:"19.0 feet",opb:"19.3 feet",opc:"19.6 feet",opd:"20.4 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"When elevating the COASTAL DRILLER in 100 feet of water, the unit should be placed at an air gap of ____________.",opa:"35 feet",opb:"32 feet",opc:"30 feet",opd:"25 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to sail with the load shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the available GM.",opa:"Available GM 4.1 ft.",opb:"Available GM 4.3 ft.",opc:"Available GM 4.7 ft.",opd:"Available GM 5.1 ft.",ans:"opa"},{question:"To assure safe boarding and launching of a davit-launched liferaft from a MODU, preparation should include ____________.",opa:"load testing the davit arm and the painter system",opb:"removing any side protective rails and checking that the overside and surface level are clear",opc:"testing the spring loaded drum to assure it will retract the fall release hook",opd:"testing to assure that the required lamps are functioning properly",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is moored in 600 feet of water. The average line tension is 190 kips. What is the total vertical component of chain tension?",opa:"55.3 long tons",opb:"428.8 long tons",opc:"442.4 long tons",opd:"678.4 long tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"The spray of water in low-velocity fog will have ____________.",opa:"greater range than high-velocity fog",opb:"lesser range than high-velocity fog",opc:"about the same range as high-velocity fog",opd:"greater range than a solid stream",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are loading in a port subject to the tropical load line mark and bound for a port subject to the summer load line mark. You will enter the summer zone after steaming four days. You will consume 41 tons of fuel, water, and stores per day. The hydrometer reading at the loading pier is 1.000 and the average TPI is 55. What is the minimum freeboard required at the start of the voyage?",opa:"55 inches",opb:"49 inches",opc:"44 inches",opd:"41 inches",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the minimum period of time that the air supply for a self-contained breathing apparatus is required to last?",opa:"10 minutes",opb:"15 minutes",opc:"30 minutes",opd:"45 minutes",ans:"opc"},{question:"Damage stability of a MODU is the stability ____________.",opa:"which exists when the wind speed is less than 50 knots",opb:"before collision",opc:"after flooding",opd:"at survival draft",ans:"opc"},{question:"The bottom of the mast rests on the ____________.",opa:"foot plate",opb:"sole plate",opc:"hounds",opd:"mast step",ans:"opd"},{question:"The person in charge shall insure that each lifeboat on a MODU is lowered to the water, launched, and operated at least once every ____________.",opa:"month",opb:"2 months",opc:"3 months",opd:"6 months",ans:"opc"},{question:"The International Oil Pollution Prevention (IOPP) Certificate required by MARPOL is issued to U.S. flag MODUs by the ____________.",opa:"International Maritime Organization",opb:"U.S. Coast Guard",opc:"American Bureau of Shipping",opd:"Environmental Protection Agency",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are the operator of a 296 GRT uninspected towing vessel. Its construction was contracted for after August 27, 2003. In addition to the hand portable fire extinguishers, how much other fire extinguishing equipment are you required to have onboard? (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"Either an approved B-V semi-portable fire-extinguishing system or a fixed fire-extinguishing system",opb:"Both an approved B-V semi-portable fire-extinguishing system and a fixed fire-extinguishing system",opc:"An approved water mist fire protection system and a fixed CO2 fire-extinguishing system",opd:"Both an approved B-V semi-portable fire-extinguishing system and an approved water mist fire protection system",ans:"opb"},{question:"A semisubmersible with a displacement of 20,000 tons and a KG of 60.0 feet loads 300 tons at a VCG of 120 feet. To maintain draft, ballast is discharged from a height of 20 feet. What is the change in KG?",opa:"1.5 feet upward",opb:"1.5 feet downward",opc:"0.8 foot upward",opd:"0.8 foot downward",ans:"opa"},{question:"When will the float-free emergency position indicating radio beacon be activated after abandoning ship?",opa:"Immediately after floating free",opb:"After about one hour when the salt water activates the battery",opc:"Only when keyed by the radar of another vessel",opd:"Only when daylight activates the photovoltaic cell",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel will be entering the navigable waters of the United States. You are required by regulations to ____________.",opa:"test the primary and secondary steering systems no more than 8 hours before entering",opb:"correct the charts of the area to be transited using the Notice(s) to Mariners or foreign equivalent reasonably available",opc:"have a copy of Radio Navigational Aids",opd:"check the magnetic compass for the correct deviation",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are fighting a fire in the electrical switchboard in the engine room. You should secure the power, then ____________.",opa:"use a portable foam extinguisher",opb:"use a low-velocity fog adapter with the fire hose",opc:"use a portable CO2 extinguisher",opd:"determine the cause of the fire",ans:"opc"},{question:"A welding procedure used for joining dissimilar metals used on a MODU would be recorded in the ____________.",opa:"welding plan",opb:"ASTM specifications",opc:"construction portfolio",opd:"Coast Guard file",ans:"opc"},{question:"Aboard small passenger vessels which type(s) of ventilation must be provided for enclosed spaces containing gasoline engines or gasoline fuel tanks?",opa:"Natural supply and mechanical exhaust",opb:"At least one opening to the exterior of the hull",opc:"Mechanical supply and natural exhaust",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"The lifesaving signal indicating 'You are seen -Assistance will be given as soon as possible' is the ____________.",opa:"vertical motion of white flags",opb:"vertical motion of a white light or flare",opc:"firing of a green star signal",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"What periodic inspection is required in order to remain in compliance with the regulations regarding GMDSS ship radio station inspections?",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard annual inspection",opb:"An inspection at least once every 12 months by the FCC or a holder of a GMDSS Maintainers license",opc:"FCC inspection every five years",opd:"Periodic inspections not required if onboard maintainers perform routine preventive maintenance",ans:"opb"},{question:"A report of casualty to a mobile offshore drilling unit must be made in writing to which office?",opa:"Commandant of the Coast Guard",opb:"Owner of the unit",opc:"Nearest Coast Guard Marine Safety Office",opd:"Captain of the nearest port",ans:"opc"},{question:"What should you do if you have transmitted a distress call a number of times on channel 16 and have received no reply?",opa:"Repeat the message using any other channel on which you might attract attention.",opb:"Key the microphone several times before transmitting again.",opc:"Turn up the volume on the receiver before transmitting again.",opd:"Report the problem to the head electrician.",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which radio call-in plan is the most prudent?",opa:"There must be a designated responsible person who will be available to receive your call at anytime.",opb:"There must be specific instructions for the designated responsible person to follow if your call does not come in on schedule.",opc:"The designated responsible person must be instructed to call the Coast Guard search and rescue authorities immediately if your call does not come in on schedule.",opd:"The designated responsible person should be over 18 years of age.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 60 feet, has -3,600 ft.-tons of transverse moments. How much ballast should be transferred between tanks 10P and 10S to level the unit in list?",opa:"25.1 long tons",opb:"50.2 long tons",opc:"62.8 long tons",opd:"252.1 long tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is maximum power allowed by the FCC for VHF-FM radio transmissions?",opa:"One watt",opb:"Five watts",opc:"15 watts",opd:"25 watts",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is meant by the term 'overhaul' in firefighting?",opa:"Slow down the spread of fire by cooling adjacent structures",opb:"Cover the fire with foam",opc:"Smother the fire with a blanket or similar object",opd:"Break up solid objects to ensure that any deep seated fires are extinguished",ans:"opd"},{question:"The center of the underwater volume of a floating vessel is the ____________.",opa:"center of buoyancy",opb:"center of flotation",opc:"uncorrected height of the center of gravity of the vessel",opd:"center of gravity of the vessel corrected for free surface effects",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which document will describe lifesaving equipment located aboard your vessel?",opa:"Muster List ('Station Bill')",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Forecastle Card",opd:"Clearance Papers",ans:"opb"},{question:"If the low side bilge pump fails and the high side bilge pump has insufficient suction to dewater the low side of the COASTAL DRILLER when afloat, you should use the ____________.",opa:"saltwater eductor system",opb:"raw water tower pumps",opc:"mud pumps",opd:"preload pumps",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which action is routinely performed at the annual servicing and inspection of a dry-chemical cartridge-operated portable fire extinguisher?",opa:"Insure the chemical is powdery.",opb:"Replace the cartridge.",opc:"Pressure test the discharge hose.",opd:"Test the pressure gauge for proper operation.",ans:"opa"},{question:"In order to determine the health hazard data for carbolic acid, you would use that information contained in the Chemical Data Guide for which chemical?",opa:"Acetic oxide",opb:"Carbinol",opc:"Carbon bisulfide",opd:"Phenol",ans:"opd"},{question:"While drilling ahead with 60 foot draft, the DEEP DRILLER encounters lost circulation and loses 460 barrels of 16 pounds per gallon mud to the hole. What is the resulting draft if no additional ballast is taken on?",opa:"57 feet",opb:"58 feet",opc:"59 feet",opd:"60 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"By day, the horizontal motion of a white flag, or arms extended horizontally, by a person on the beach indicates ____________.",opa:"'Haul away'",opb:"'Tail block is made fast'",opc:"'Negative'",opd:"'Affirmative'",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the navigable waters of the United States, Annex V to MARPOL 73/78 is NOT applicable to a(n) ____________.",opa:"recreational yacht",opb:"uninspected towing vessel",opc:"uninspected passenger vessel under 100 GT",opd:"U.S. government vessel in non-commercial service",ans:"opd"},{question:"When the longitudinal strength members of a MODU are continuous and closely spaced, the vessel is ____________.",opa:"transversely framed",opb:"longitudinally framed",opc:"intermittently framed",opd:"web framed",ans:"opb"},{question:"When hoisting a boat on gravity type davits using an electric motor driven winch, the davit arms should be brought up ____________.",opa:"to their final position with the winch operating at slow speed",opb:"to the bar stop, and then hand cranked to their final position",opc:"until just before they make contact with the limit switch, and then hand cranked to their final position",opd:"to the embarkation deck, and then hand cranked to their final position",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are loading in a port subject to the summer load line mark and bound for a port subject to the winter load line mark. You will enter the winter zone after steaming four days. You will consume 35 tons of fuel, water, and stores per day. The hydrometer reading at the loading pier is 1.0083, and the average TPI is 65. What is the minimum freeboard required at the start of the voyage?",opa:"74 inches",opb:"78 inches",opc:"80 inches",opd:"86 inches",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the height of the metacenter is greater than the height of the center of gravity, the upright equilibrium position is stable and stability is ____________.",opa:"unstable",opb:"neutral",opc:"negative",opd:"positive",ans:"opd"},{question:"When may a work vest be substituted for a required life preserver?",opa:"To replace a damaged life preserver",opb:"For use during fire drills",opc:"For use during boat drills",opd:"At no time",ans:"opd"},{question:"On an OSV, how many ring buoys are required to have a buoyant line attached?",opa:"One ring life buoy",opb:"One ring life buoy on each side of the OSV",opc:"Three ring life buoys",opd:"Two ring life buoys on each side of the OSV",ans:"opb"},{question:"A semisubmersible with a displacement of 20,000 tons and KG of 52 feet discharges 300 long tons of barite from P-tanks located 120 feet above the keel. Ballast added to maintain draft has a VCG of 20 feet. What is the change in KG?",opa:"0.49 foot increase",opb:"0.50 foot decrease",opc:"1.50 feet decrease",opd:"1.80 feet decrease",ans:"opc"},{question:"The space containing the cylinders for the carbon dioxide (CO2) fire extinguishing system must be designed to preclude an anticipated ambient temperature over ____________.",opa:"80\xb0F",opb:"95\xb0F",opc:"130\xb0F",opd:"150\xb0F",ans:"opc"},{question:"When a standard in the fire protection regulations for towing vessels is 'incorporated by reference,' it means that the ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard accepts a commercial or military standard as part of a specific regulation",opb:"standard is readily available to the public",opc:"standard, and where it can be obtained or referred to, are listed in the Code of Federal Regulations",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are running before a strong wind in a sloop. The most dangerous thing to do is ____________.",opa:"jibe",opb:"tack about",opc:"reef the mainsail",opd:"strike the jib",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which tank barges require draft marks?",opa:"All tank barges",opb:"Notch barges over 1000 GT",opc:"Tank barges over 100 GT",opd:"Tank barges over 50 GT",ans:"opa"},{question:"All self-propelled vessels on an international voyage must be equipped with how many Emergency Position Indicating Radio beacons (EPIRB)?",opa:"One approved Category 1 EPIRB",opb:"Three approved Category 1 EPIRBs",opc:"One approved Class B EPIRB",opd:"Two approved Class B EPIRBs",ans:"opa"},{question:"To determine the number of inflatable liferafts required on a mobile offshore drilling unit, you should check the ____________.",opa:"load line certificate",opb:"Operations Manual",opc:"stability letter",opd:"Certificate of Inspection",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessels Certificate of Inspection will show the ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"crew requirements",opb:"minimum fire fighting and lifesaving equipment",opc:"route permitted",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Recharging a previously used cartridge-operated dry-chemical extinguisher is accomplished by ____________.",opa:"authorized fire equipment servicing personnel only",opb:"replacing the propellant cartridge and refilling with powder",opc:"puncturing the cartridge seal after installation",opd:"recharging the cartridge and refilling it with powder",ans:"opb"},{question:"After receiving your distress call, the U.S.C.G. may ask you to switch to which SSB frequency?",opa:"2570",opb:"2670",opc:"2770",opd:"2870",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a helicopter is lifting personnel from an enclosed lifeboat, the other individuals in the boat should ____________.",opa:"enter the water in case the person being lifted slips from the sling",opb:"stand on the outside of the boat to assist the person being lifted",opc:"remove their life preservers to prepare for their transfer to the helicopter",opd:"remain seated inside to provide body weight for stability",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 6584 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 277.84 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 271.2 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 272.1 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 273.6 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 274.6 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"A special device that, when fitted into the rotary table, transmits torque to the kelly and simultaneously permits vertical movement of the kelly to make the hole is called a ____________.",opa:"master bushing",opb:"kelly slips",opc:"kelly bushing",opd:"rotary bushing",ans:"opc"},{question:"What causes cavitation in a centrifugal pump?",opa:"Vapor pockets in the flow stream",opb:"Rough impeller surfaces",opc:"Worn wearing rings",opd:"Heavy fluid in the flow stream",ans:"opa"},{question:"Reducing free surfaces has the effect of lowering the ____________.",opa:"uncorrected KG",opb:"virtual height of the center of gravity",opc:"metacenter",opd:"metacentric height",ans:"opb"},{question:"During jacking operations and transit, empty void spaces in the hull of a jack up MODU provide ____________.",opa:"buoyancy",opb:"extra storage space",opc:"additional tank capacity",opd:"reduced stability",ans:"opa"},{question:"While proceeding to a distress site, you hear the words 'Seelonce mayday' on the radiotelephone. Which action should you take?",opa:"Resume base course and speed as your assistance is no longer required.",opb:"Acknowledge receipt and advise your course, speed, and ETA.",opc:"Relay the original distress message as no other vessel has acknowledged it.",opd:"Monitor the radiotelephone but do not transmit.",ans:"opd"},{question:"A large valve, usually installed above the ram preventers, that forms a seal in the annular space between the pipe and wellbore or, if no pipe is present, on the wellbore itself is called the ____________.",opa:"annular blowout preventer",opb:"annulus",opc:"accumulator",opd:"automatic choke",ans:"opa"},{question:"What happens to the pulling power of a winch when retrieving wire rope?",opa:"It increases",opb:"It decreases",opc:"It remains the same",opd:"It fluctuates, depending on the gearing system",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol(s) represent part of the vessel's ventilation system?",opa:"69",opb:"34",opc:"18",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which VHF channel should you avoid using as a working channel?",opa:"7A",opb:"8",opc:"9",opd:"16",ans:"opd"},{question:"What is the minimum number of ring life buoys required onboard a 275-foot cargo vessel engaged in coastwise trade, under the alternatives for cargo vessels in a specified service?",opa:"6",opb:"8",opc:"12",opd:"14",ans:"opa"},{question:"Immersion suits must be stowed ____________.",opa:"in the pilothouse",opb:"on top of lockers",opc:"where readily accessible",opd:"on open deck areas",ans:"opc"},{question:"In the event of fire in a machinery space, ____________.",opa:"the fixed carbon dioxide system should be used only when all other means of extinguishment have failed",opb:"the fixed carbon dioxide system should be used immediately, as it is the most efficient means of extinguishment",opc:"water in any form should not be used as it will spread the fire",opd:"the space should be opened 5 minutes after flooding CO2 to prevent injury to personnel",ans:"opa"},{question:"In addition to weighing the cartridge, which other maintenance is required for a cartridge-operated dry chemical extinguisher?",opa:"Weigh the powder in the canister.",opb:"Discharge a small amount to see that it works.",opc:"Check the hose and nozzle for clogs.",opd:"Check the external pressure gage.",ans:"opc"},{question:"On tank vessels, fully charged fire extinguishers are considered semi-portable when they have a gross weight of more than ____________.",opa:"55 pounds",opb:"75 pounds",opc:"95 pounds",opd:"125 pounds",ans:"opa"},{question:"Life preservers must be marked with the ____________.",opa:"stowage space assigned",opb:"vessel's name",opc:"vessel's home port",opd:"maximum weight allowed",ans:"opb"},{question:"On small passenger vessels, all spaces containing gasoline-powered machinery or gasoline storage tanks must be ventilated with ____________.",opa:"mechanical air supply fans and natural exhaust",opb:"natural air supply and mechanical exhaust fans",opc:"cowls and scoops which can be closed during foul weather",opd:"air conditioning to control moisture",ans:"opb"},{question:"Mechanical gearing of deck machinery such as the windlass or towing engine should ____________.",opa:"be open to view so, if a foreign object gets in the gearing, the operator can immediately stop the machinery",opb:"have a guard over the gearing",opc:"be painted a contrasting color from the base color in order to call attention to the gearing",opd:"not be operated if there is any crew within 10 feet of the machinery",ans:"opb"},{question:"The height of a VHF radio antenna is more important than the power output wattage of the radio because ____________.",opa:"VHF communications are basically 'line of sight'",opb:"the air is more dense the higher you go",opc:"salt water is a poor conductor of sound",opd:"sea water absorbs the radiated energy",ans:"opa"},{question:"On a vessel making a voyage more than 48 hours long, regulations require that ____________.",opa:"a lifeboat drill be held within 12 hours prior to departure",opb:"fire pumps be tested by starting within 12 hours prior to departure",opc:"the emergency generator and lighting system be tested by starting and operating within 12 hours prior to departure",opd:"the entire steering gear be tested within 12 hours prior to departure",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which is NOT a symptom of traumatic shock?",opa:"Slow, deep breathing",opb:"Pale, cold skin",opc:"Weak, rapid pulse",opd:"Restlessness and anxiety",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #2 (Ballast to Survival), suffers major damage which results in flooding in tank 1S. Your best countermeasure is to ____________.",opa:"pump from 2S",opb:"pump from C1S",opc:"pump from 1S",opd:"counter flood in 10P",ans:"opa"},{question:"You have abandoned ship and are in charge of a liferaft or survival craft. How much water per day should you permit each person to have after the first 24 hours?",opa:"1 can",opb:"1 pint",opc:"1 quart",opd:"1 gallon",ans:"opb"},{question:"When taking soundings on a MODU, coating the tape with chalk helps to ____________.",opa:"better identify the correct reading",opb:"show the depth of any water in an oil tank",opc:"make the tape roll easier",opd:"reduce possibility of sparks",ans:"opa"},{question:"For emergency communications, vessels operating on oceans, coastwise, or Great Lakes routes, on runs of more than 30 minutes shall carry in a portable watertight container at or near the operating station ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"six orange hand smoke distress signals",opb:"six red hand flare distress signals",opc:"one 3-cell flashlight",opd:"six red hand flare distress signals and six orange hand smoke distress signals",ans:"opd"},{question:"A person may operate an air compressor in which of the following areas onboard a tank barge?",opa:"Pumproom",opb:"Generator room",opc:"A space adjacent to a cargo tank",opd:"A space two meters from a cargo valve",ans:"opb"},{question:"Number 3 lifeboat would be ____________.",opa:"the forward boat on the starboard side",opb:"behind boat number 1 on the port side",opc:"behind boat number 1 on the starboard side",opd:"behind boat number 2 on the port side",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are on a supply run to an offshore drilling rig. onboard is the cargo listed. What is the height above the main deck of the center of gravity of the cargo?",opa:"1.76 feet",opb:"1.97 feet",opc:"2.21 feet",opd:"2.32 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 08'-11.5', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"3.15 feet",opb:"3.00 feet",opc:"2.90 feet",opd:"2.80 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"If you are forced to abandon ship in a liferaft, your course of action should be to ____________.",opa:"remain in the immediate vicinity",opb:"head for the nearest land",opc:"head for the closest sea-lanes",opd:"let the persons in the boat vote on what to do",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each inert gas system must be designed to supply the cargo tanks with a gas, or mixture of gasses, that has an oxygen content by volume of ____________.",opa:"5% or less",opb:"10% or less",opc:"15% or less",opd:"20% or less",ans:"opa"},{question:"A yawl is a sailing vessel with ____________.",opa:"a single mast",opb:"two masts: with the mizzen stepped abaft the rudder post",opc:"two masts: with the mizzen stepped forward of the rudder post",opd:"two masts: a foremast and a mainmast",ans:"opb"},{question:"Towing vessel fire protection regulations define a 'fixed fire-extinguishing system' to include all of the following EXCEPT a ____________.",opa:"carbon-dioxide system",opb:"halon system",opc:"manually-operated clean-agent system",opd:"manually-operated water-mist system",ans:"opb"},{question:"How many portable fire extinguishers are required in the cargo tank area of an unmanned tank barge during cargo transfer, if the barge has no cargo pumps of her own?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"None",ans:"opa"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of vertical moments for the Stores & Supplies if paint weighing 3.48 tons is added to the paint locker?",opa:"13,346 foot-tons",opb:"5,054 foot-tons",opc:"964 foot-tons",opd:"292 foot-tons",ans:"opa"},{question:"A locker with additional breathing apparatuses can be found in what location designated by this symbol on the ship\u2019s fire control plan?",opa:"30",opb:"58",opc:"59",opd:"60",ans:"opc"},{question:"The jettisoning of topside weight from a MODU serves what purpose?",opa:"It returns the MODU to an even keel.",opb:"It reduces free surface effect.",opc:"It lowers the center of gravity.",opd:"It raises the center of gravity.",ans:"opc"},{question:"When personnel are lifted by a helicopter from an inflatable liferaft, the personnel on the raft should ____________.",opa:"deflate the floor of the raft to reduce the danger of the raft overturning",opb:"inflate the floor of the raft to provide for additional stability",opc:"remove their life preservers to prepare for the transfer",opd:"take in the sea anchor to prevent fouling of the rescue sling",ans:"opa"},{question:"Spontaneous combustion is most likely to occur in ____________.",opa:"rags soaked in linseed oil",opb:"overloaded electrical circuits",opc:"dirty swabs and cleaning gear",opd:"partially loaded fuel tanks",ans:"opa"},{question:"How do you know how many passengers you may carry? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"As many as possible",opb:"The amount on the Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Use your own judgment",opd:"No more than 40 passengers",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the minimum length of a life floats paddle on a small passenger vessel?",opa:"Three feet",opb:"Four feet",opc:"Five feet",opd:"Six feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the change in longitudinal moments for the Coastal Driller if 2.0 feet of drill water is transferred from a full drill water tank #23 to an empty drill water tank #6?",opa:"7,990 foot-kips increase",opb:"7,990 foot-kips decrease",opc:"8,502 foot-kips decrease",opd:"16,041 foot-kips decrease",ans:"opb"},{question:"Vessels operating in warm water whose routes are restricted to 20 miles from a harbor of safe refuge shall carry life floats or buoyant apparatus for not less than ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"25% of all persons onboard",opb:"50% of all persons onboard",opc:"75% of all persons onboard",opd:"100% of all persons onboard",ans:"opb"},{question:"To determine the number of portable fire extinguishers required on a mobile offshore drilling unit, you should check the ____________.",opa:"hot work permit",opb:"Certificate of Inspection",opc:"Safety of Life at Sea Certificate",opd:"Operations Manual",ans:"opb"},{question:"A vessel is equipped with cross-connected deep tanks. In which situation should the cross-connection valve be closed?",opa:"The tanks lie above the waterline and are filled.",opb:"The tanks are partially filled with dry cargo.",opc:"The tanks are partially filled with liquid cargo.",opd:"The tanks are filled and lie below the waterline.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Each buoyant work vest on a MODU must be ____________.",opa:"Coast Guard approved",opb:"marked with the name of the unit",opc:"equipped with a water light",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"A complete set of spare batteries for a fireman\u2019s outfit can be found in what location designated by this symbol on the ship\u2019s fire control plan?",opa:"30",opb:"58",opc:"59",opd:"68",ans:"opb"},{question:"Distress signals may be ____________.",opa:"red flares",opb:"smoke signals",opc:"sound signals",opd:"Any of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"You have 360 tons of below deck tonnage and 210 tons of above deck cargo onboard. You must load 100 tons of liquid mud below deck. How much more deck cargo can you load? (See illustration D036DG, stability letter for M.V. Hudson.)",opa:"25 tons",opb:"65 tons",opc:"95 tons",opd:"175 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The distress message of a ship should include considerable information which might facilitate the rescue. This information should ____________.",opa:"ALWAYS be included in the initial distress message",opb:"be sent to a Coast Guard station FIRST",opc:"be transmitted as a series of short messages, if time allows",opd:"include the vessel's draft",ans:"opc"},{question:"During counter flooding to correct a severe list or trim aggravated by an off-center load, a MODU suddenly takes a list or trim to the opposite side. You should ____________.",opa:"continue counter flooding in the same direction",opb:"continue counter flooding, but in the opposite direction",opc:"immediately stop counter flooding",opd:"deballast from the low side",ans:"opc"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER at a draft of 60.0 feet discharges 68.94 long tons of ballast. What is the new draft?",opa:"66.0 feet",opb:"60.5 feet",opc:"59.5 feet",opd:"55.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Each emergency light must be marked with ____________.",opa:"the letter 'E'",opb:"an arrow pointing to the nearest exit",opc:"a no-smoking symbol",opd:"the word 'DANGER'",ans:"opa"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 14'-04', AFT 17'-08'. The LCG of the forepeak is 200 feet forward of amidships. How many tons of ballast must be pumped into the forepeak in order to have a drag of 2 feet? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"62 tons",opb:"65 tons",opc:"72 tons",opd:"75 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents a fire main with fire valves?",opa:"17",opb:"34",opc:"51",opd:"56",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have approximately 14 tons of fish on deck. What will be the shift in the center of gravity after you shift the fish to the fish hold, a vertical distance of 6 feet? (total displacement is 210 tons)",opa:"0.2 foot",opb:"0.3 foot",opc:"0.4 foot",opd:"0.5 foot",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which installed equipment must be tested and logged when a new Master assumes command?",opa:"Internal communications, including sound-powered telephones",opb:"Navigational lights and search lights",opc:"Vessel control alarms",opd:"All of the above must be tested",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, while loaded as shown in the Sample Load #5, discharges 275.8 long tons. The resulting trim by the stern is 3 feet and list to port is 2 feet. What is the draft at the port aft draft mark?",opa:"43 feet 6 inches",opb:"45 feet 6 inches",opc:"48 feet 0 inches",opd:"49 feet 6 inches",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER has a trim of 2.13 feet by the stern. The draft in sea water at the forward draft marks is observed to be 8.0 feet. The KML is ____________.",opa:"286.27 feet",opb:"299.09 feet",opc:"316.67 feet",opd:"355.42 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"The effects of free surface on initial stability depend upon the dimensions of the surface of the free liquids and the ____________.",opa:"volume of liquid in the tank",opb:"volume of displacement of the vessel",opc:"location of the tank in the vessel",opd:"height of the center of gravity of the vessel",ans:"opb"},{question:"Records of tests and inspections of a cargo vessel's fire extinguishing systems shall be kept onboard ____________.",opa:"for 1 year",opb:"for 2 years",opc:"until the next Coast Guard inspection",opd:"until the vessel's Certificate of Inspection expires",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of EPIRB must each ocean-going ship carry?",opa:"Class A",opb:"Class B",opc:"Class C",opd:"Category 1",ans:"opd"},{question:"The liquid mud tanks on your vessel measure 20'L by 18'B by 7'D. The vessel's displacement is 986 T and the specific gravity of the mud is 1.6. What is the reduction in GM due to 2 of these tanks being slack?",opa:".09 foot",opb:".45 foot",opc:".88 foot",opd:"1.35 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 6285 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 272.45 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 271.2 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 272.1 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 273.6 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 274.6 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"What would be used to call all stations in your vicinity by radiotelephone?",opa:"Calling all stations",opb:"Charlie Quebec",opc:"Alpha Alpha",opd:"Kilo",ans:"opb"},{question:"Gasoline tanks should be filled ____________.",opa:"to the top to expel all vapors from the tanks",opb:"to the top so the operator is certain how much fuel he has aboard",opc:"with only sufficient fuel for the planned trip so excess gasoline is not carried",opd:"to near the top with some space allowed for gasoline expansion",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are in a tank wearing the self-contained breathing apparatus and you desire to return topside. How many tugs of the lifeline mean to take up the slack?",opa:"One",opb:"Two",opc:"Three",opd:"Four",ans:"opc"},{question:"When fire pumps are used for other than firefighting services, each pipe connecting the other service (except for branch lines used for deck washing) must have a ____________.",opa:"check valve installed in the line",opb:"shut off valve at a manifold near the pump",opc:"quick disconnect union within ten feet of the pump",opd:"regulator in the line set at 125 psi",ans:"opb"},{question:"The requirements for obstruction lights on mobile offshore drilling units apply on all waters ____________.",opa:"outside the boundary lines that are covered by International Rules of the Road",opb:"outside the lines of demarcation that are covered by the U.S. navigational rules",opc:"over the Outer Continental Shelf and on waters under the jurisdiction of the United States",opd:"over the prohibited zone defined in the Oil Pollution Control Act of 1961",ans:"opc"},{question:"A call between any two ship stations on an intership working frequency shall have a maximum duration of ____________.",opa:"2 minutes",opb:"3 minutes",opc:"4 minutes",opd:"5 minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"Hydrogen sulfide in explosive concentrations has been detected on the drill floor. The abandon rig signal has been sounded. To evacuate the rig, the crew should use ____________.",opa:"all survival capsules and liferafts",opb:"only the leeward survival capsules and liferafts",opc:"only the windward survival capsules",opd:"only the windward liferafts",ans:"opc"},{question:"The sea anchor shown as item number 18 will NOT ____________.",opa:"check the liferaft's way",opb:"keep the liferaft end on to the sea",opc:"reduce the possibility of capsizing or broaching",opd:"right the raft if it inflates inverted",ans:"opd"},{question:"A semisubmersible floating in sea water displaces 20,000 long tons. She has vertical moments of 1,000,000 foot-long tons. What is the change in KG if 500 long tons are placed aboard at a KG of 120 feet?",opa:"1.22 feet upward",opb:"1.71 feet upward",opc:"1.75 feet upward",opd:"2.93 feet upward",ans:"opb"},{question:"A fishing vessel casualty must be reported to the Coast Guard if it involves ____________.",opa:"loss of life",opb:"an injury requiring only first aid",opc:"$(SA)10,000 in property damage",opd:"loss of equipment which doesn't reduce the vessel's maneuverability",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 08'-11.5', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"3.10 feet",opb:"2.45 feet",opc:"2.00 feet",opd:"1.50 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Because there is a possibility of fuel oil being discharged overboard from a full fuel oil tank, it is decided to transfer 25 kips from tank #14 to tank #13. See COASTAL DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What would be the change in transverse moments with this transfer?",opa:"56 ft.-kips",opb:"979 ft.-kips",opc:"1035 ft.-kips",opd:"2010 ft.-kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"After abandoning ship which action should be taken IMMEDIATELY upon entering a liferaft?",opa:"Open equipment pack.",opb:"Issue anti-seasickness medicine.",opc:"Get clear of the ship.",opd:"Dry the liferaft floor and inflate.",ans:"opc"},{question:"Aboard a MODU, multiplying a load's weight by the distance of the load's center of gravity from the centerline results in the load's ____________.",opa:"LCG",opb:"transverse moment",opc:"righting moment",opd:"inclining moment",ans:"opb"},{question:"The number of fire axes required to be carried on a cargo vessel of 14,000 GT and on an international voyage is ____________.",opa:"4",opb:"6",opc:"8",opd:"12",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are operating a non-ocean going vessel, how much of the accumulated oily waste must you be able to retain onboard?",opa:"0.25",opb:"0.5",opc:"0.75",opd:"1",ans:"opd"},{question:"A fuel line breaks, sprays fuel on the hot exhaust manifold, and catches fire. Your FIRST action should be to ____________.",opa:"batten down the engine room",opb:"start the fire pump",opc:"apply carbon dioxide to the fire",opd:"shut off the fuel supply",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which type of marine sanitation device (MSD) is used solely for the storage of sewage and flush water at ambient air pressure and temperature?",opa:"Type I",opb:"Type II",opc:"Type III",opd:"Type IV",ans:"opc"},{question:"A jack-up 210 feet in length is level during transit. The LCF is 140 feet aft of the bow. How much weight should be applied at the bow to level the jack-up if 150 kips are loaded at the transom?",opa:"50 kips",opb:"75 kips",opc:"100 kips",opd:"200 kips",ans:"opb"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in ocean transit at a draft of 10 feet 6 inches with winds greater than 70 knots, has a KGT of 38.7 feet and a KGL of 38.2 feet. The margin on the maximum allowable KG is ____________.",opa:"26.8 feet",opb:"26.3 feet",opc:"1.8 feet",opd:"1.3 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Where are the draft marks required to be displayed on a ship?",opa:"Deep tanks",opb:"Voids",opc:"Midships near the waterline",opd:"Area of water line near stem and stern",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER departs a fresh water port at a draft of 19.5 feet. What will be the draft in sea water?",opa:"18.7 feet",opb:"19.1 feet",opc:"19.4 feet",opd:"19.8 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which equipment is not a source of locating signals?",opa:"EPIRB's that transmit on 406 MHz",opb:"Survival craft VHF transceivers that provide a beacon on121.5 MHz",opc:"COSPAS-SARSAT EPIRBs",opd:"SARTs operating on 9 GHz",ans:"opb"},{question:"How does a coast radio station communicating by HF radio normally identify itself?",opa:"By its subscriber number",opb:"By its call sign",opc:"By its MMSI",opd:"By its MID",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown is Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the change in vertical moments for Fresh Water if the entire contents of Drill Water Tank 5P are transferred to Drill Water Tank 5S?",opa:"5,683 ft.-tons",opb:"2,689 ft.-tons",opc:"306 ft.-tons",opd:"000 ft.-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"Safety goggles or glasses are NOT normally worn when ____________.",opa:"using a rotary grinder with an installed shield",opb:"letting go the anchor",opc:"handling wire rope or natural fiber line",opd:"painting with a spray gun",ans:"opc"},{question:"Under extremely heavy weather on the DEEP DRILLER, when operating conditions are too severe to permit the drill string from being tripped out of the hole and laid down in the pipe racks, it may be ____________.",opa:"hung off",opb:"placed in the setback",opc:"supported by the lower marine riser package",opd:"supported by the tensioners",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are on a supply run to an offshore drilling rig. onboard is the cargo listed. What is the height above the main deck of the center of gravity of the cargo?",opa:"2.15 feet",opb:"1.83 feet",opc:"1.64 feet",opd:"1.19 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel has 3 lifeboats on each side. The middle boat on the starboard side is designated as boat number ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"2 STARBOARD",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opc"},{question:"A series of trays with sieves that vibrate to remove cuttings from the circulating fluid in rotary drilling operations is called the ____________.",opa:"shale shaker",opb:"settling pit",opc:"desilter",opd:"desander",ans:"opa"},{question:"To what chemical family does ethylene oxide belong?",opa:"Glycol ethers",opb:"Alkylene oxides",opc:"Esters",opd:"Alcohols",ans:"opb"},{question:"Buoyancy is a measure of the ship's ____________.",opa:"ability to float",opb:"deadweight",opc:"freeboard",opd:"midships strength",ans:"opa"},{question:"What form of venting of cargo tanks is allowed for a tank barge certificated to carry grade B petroleum products?",opa:"Gooseneck vents only",opb:"Gooseneck vents with flame screens",opc:"Individual pressure-vacuum relief valves with flame screens",opd:"Straight vents with flame screens",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have sent a visual signal to an aircraft. The aircraft then flies over your position on a straight course and level altitude. What should you do?",opa:"Repeat your signal.",opb:"Send any more signals necessary.",opc:"Change course to follow the airplane.",opd:"Prepare for a helicopter pickup.",ans:"opa"},{question:"According to the Chemical Data Guide, which extinguishing agent is NOT recommended for use on a retinol fire?",opa:"Dry chemical",opb:"Foam",opc:"CO2",opd:"Water spray",ans:"opd"},{question:"Of the required ring life buoys for an OSV, how many must be equipped with a waterlight?",opa:"8",opb:"4",opc:"2",opd:"1",ans:"opc"},{question:"Persons who have swallowed a non-petroleum based poison are given large quantities of warm soapy water or warm salt water to ____________.",opa:"induce vomiting",opb:"absorb the poison from the blood",opc:"neutralize the poison in the blood",opd:"increase the digestive process and eliminate the poison",ans:"opa"},{question:"The sailing drafts are: FWD 22'-08', AFT 23'-04' and the GM is 4.6 feet. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, to determine the available righting arm at 20\xb0 inclination.",opa:"2.1 feet",opb:"2.4 feet",opc:"2.8 feet",opd:"3.2 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"Structural stress levels in a MODU are the sum of loading stresses and stresses due to ____________.",opa:"environmental loads",opb:"variable loads",opc:"ballast loading",opd:"mooring loads",ans:"opa"},{question:"When communicating on the radiotelephone using plain English, what procedure word indicates the end of my transmission and that a response is necessary?",opa:"Out",opb:"Over",opc:"Roger",opd:"Wilco",ans:"opb"},{question:"The KG of the DEEP DRILLER increases from 57 feet to 59 feet while drilling at a 60 foot draft during an ice storm. What action should be taken?",opa:"Continue drilling operations while waiting for the ice to melt",opb:"Reduce the deck load until you reach the allowable KG for draft",opc:"Notify the USCG that the rig is temporarily above the allowable KG",opd:"Deballast to reach the allowable KG",ans:"opb"},{question:"Support of MODU side plating is provided primarily by transverse ____________.",opa:"beams",opb:"girders",opc:"frames",opd:"bulkheads",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is ready to load the cargo listed. There is already 2464 tons of cargo onboard with a KG of 27.3 feet. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final KG of all the cargo after loading is completed.",opa:"KG 27.0 feet",opb:"KG 27.8 feet",opc:"KG 28.6 feet",opd:"KG 29.8 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The nautical term 'lee shore' refers to the ____________.",opa:"shore on the lee side of the vessel",opb:"shore that is in the lee",opc:"western shore of the Lesser Antilles",opd:"shore in a harbor of refuge",ans:"opa"},{question:"When sending a DSC call, the vessel's ____________.",opa:"position will automatically be sent",opb:"position will automatically be sent if the vessel is sending a 'Distress Hot Key' alert",opc:"MMSI will indicate its ocean region",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the chief advantage of an SCR or AC-DC system over a straight DC system for powering drilling rig machinery?",opa:"Commutators are eliminated.",opb:"Several machines can be operated from a DC bus.",opc:"SCR systems are simpler.",opd:"Required power can be drawn from a common AC bus.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The object of plugging holes below the waterline on a MODU should be to ____________.",opa:"eliminate all water entering the hole",opb:"only plug holes in machinery or other vital spaces",opc:"reduce the entry of water as much as possible",opd:"plug the largest holes first",ans:"opc"},{question:"An effective braking system for windlasses on rigs in deep water is a(n) ____________.",opa:"larger chain stopper",opb:"disc backstopping brake",opc:"hydraulic clutch",opd:"electrical regenerative braking system",ans:"opd"},{question:"Where are self-closing doors required on a MODU?",opa:"In the galley",opb:"In each stair tower",opc:"To each sleeping room",opd:"To the engine room",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at a draft of 60 feet, has a KGL of 55.4 feet and an LCG of 2.43 feet. What is the trim angle?",opa:"2\xb0 by the head",opb:"2\xb0 by the stern",opc:"4\xb0 by the head",opd:"4\xb0 by the stern",ans:"opa"},{question:"The lifeline which is part of a fireman's outfit must be ____________.",opa:"made of steel or bronze wire rope",opb:"corrosion resistant",opc:"not less than 50 feet in length",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of transverse moments for the Stores & Supplies (Table 6) if paint weighing 3.48 tons is added to the paint locker?",opa:"592 foot-tons",opb:"296 foot-tons",opc:"148 foot-tons",opd:"000 foot-tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Each person on a MODU carrying immersion suits must wear the immersion suit in a boat drill, or participate in a drill which includes donning the suit and being instructed in its use at least once every ____________.",opa:"month",opb:"2 months",opc:"3 months",opd:"6 months",ans:"opa"},{question:"Which radio call-in plan is the most prudent?",opa:"The designated responsible person must be instructed to call the Coast Guard search and rescue authorities immediately if your call does not come in on schedule.",opb:"There must be a designated responsible person available at all times to receive your call.",opc:"There must be a designated responsible person who knows they are expecting your call at a certain time.",opd:"Two responsible persons should be designated so that one can relieve the other as necessary.",ans:"opc"},{question:"To get low-velocity fog from an all-purpose nozzle, you would ____________.",opa:"attach the bronze nozzle tip to the fog outlet of the nozzle",opb:"attach an applicator to the nozzle in place of the bronze nozzle tip",opc:"attach an applicator to the solid stream outlet on the nozzle",opd:"simply move the handle to the vertical position on the nozzle",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which instrument is suitable for determining the presence of explosive concentrations of fuel oil vapors in tanks?",opa:"A flame safety lamp",opb:"A combustible gas indicator",opc:"A liquid cargo meter",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"When a rescue vessel approaches a survival craft in heavy seas, the person in charge of the survival craft should ____________.",opa:"tie up to the rescue vessel",opb:"transfer only those personnel who are not seasick",opc:"wait for calmer weather before transferring personnel",opd:"transfer all personnel immediately",ans:"opc"},{question:"Among the valves to open when deballasting using tanks 1P and 10P of the DEEP DRILLER is ____________.",opa:"2 Port",opb:"24 Port",opc:"48 Port",opd:"44 Port",ans:"opc"},{question:"You detect an odor of burning electrical insulation and then notice smoke coming from an open laundry room doorway. After activating the fire alarm, which of the following is the LEAST likely of your next actions?",opa:"Close the door to the room.",opb:"Locate the nearest CO2 or dry chemical extinguisher.",opc:"Secure power to the washers and dryers.",opd:"Break out the nearest fire hose.",ans:"opd"},{question:"When the height of the metacenter is less than the height of the center of gravity of a vessel, the upright equilibrium position is ____________.",opa:"stable",opb:"neutral",opc:"unstable",opd:"positive",ans:"opc"},{question:"You hear on the radiotelephone the word 'Securite' spoken three times. This indicates that ____________.",opa:"a message about the safety of navigation will follow",opb:"a message of an urgent nature about the safety of a ship will follow",opc:"the sender is in distress and requests immediate assistance",opd:"you should secure your radiotelephone",ans:"opa"},{question:"Topside icing that blocks freeing ports and scuppers ____________.",opa:"is usually below the center of gravity and has little effect on stability",opb:"will cause water on deck to pocket and increase stability",opc:"may decrease stability by increasing free surface effect due to water on deck",opd:"increases the effective freeboard and increases the wind-heel affect",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol signifies equipment you would use if your fire pump(s) failed?",opa:"22",opb:"21",opc:"19",opd:"54",ans:"opc"},{question:"If the metacentric height is large, a floating MODU will ____________.",opa:"be tender",opb:"have a slow and easy motion",opc:"be stiff",opd:"have a tendency to yaw",ans:"opc"},{question:"Because there is a possibility of fuel oil being discharged overboard from a full fuel oil tank, it is decided to transfer 25 kips from tank #14 to tank #13. See COASTAL DRILLER Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). What would be the change in longitudinal free surface moments?",opa:"1492 ft.-kips increase",opb:"1034 ft.-kips increase",opc:"674 ft.-kips increase",opd:"404 ft.-kips increase",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which is the lifesaving signal for, 'This is the best place to land'?",opa:"Red star rocket",opb:"Orange smoke signal",opc:"Green star rocket",opd:"Horizontal motion of a flag",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have abandoned ship and find yourself aboard a lifeboat in a heavy sea. Your boat is able to make way through the water. To prevent broaching, you should ____________.",opa:"put the sea on your stern and run as fast as the boat will go",opb:"take no action to prevent broaching as this is a recommended maneuver in a heavy sea",opc:"head the boat into the swells to take them at a 30 to 40 degree angle on either bow and run as slow as possible without losing steerage",opd:"place everyone as far forward in the boat as possible to keep the bow heavy",ans:"opc"},{question:"While the DEEP DRILLER is operating as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling), casing is accidentally dropped over the starboard side. If the starboard forward inclination is slowly increasing, which tank is probably damaged?",opa:"1S",opb:"2S",opc:"3S",opd:"1P",ans:"opa"},{question:"The center of flotation of a vessel is ____________.",opa:"the center of volume of the immersed portion of the vessel",opb:"the center of gravity of the waterplane",opc:"that point at which all the vertical downward forces of weight are considered to be concentrated",opd:"that point at which all the vertical upward forces of buoyancy are considered to be concentrated",ans:"opb"},{question:"Who is charged with appointing persons to be in command of the lifeboats and(or) liferafts on a mobile offshore drilling unit?",opa:"Rig superintendent",opb:"Tool Pusher",opc:"Company man",opd:"Designated person in charge",ans:"opd"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #3 (Drilling), discharges the bulk in Bulk Tanks 1 and 2. What is the new LCG?",opa:"124.97 feet AFO",opb:"125.09 feet AFO",opc:"127.70 feet AFO",opd:"130.42 feet AFO",ans:"opa"},{question:"Under Annex V to MARPOL 73/78, garbage discharged from vessels that are located between 3 and 12 nautical miles from nearest land must be ground to less than ____________.",opa:"1'",opb:"1-1/4'",opc:"1-1/2'",opd:"2'",ans:"opa"},{question:"The capacity of any liferaft onboard a vessel can be determined by ____________.",opa:"examining the Certificate of Inspection",opb:"examining the plate on the outside of the raft container",opc:"referring to the Muster List ('Station Bill')",opd:"referring to the shipping articles",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the vessel\u2019s fire control plan, which symbol represents a fire damper?",opa:"32",opb:"33",opc:"34",opd:"53",ans:"opa"},{question:"Aboard a cargo vessel, the supply of carbon dioxide used in a fixed extinguishing system MUST at least be sufficient for what space(s)?",opa:"all the spaces of a vessel",opb:"all cargo spaces",opc:"the engine room and largest cargo space",opd:"the space requiring the largest amount",ans:"opd"},{question:"Whenever your marine radio is on, FCC Rules require you to monitor ____________.",opa:"a commercial ship-to-ship channel",opb:"the last frequency that was used",opc:"the distress and calling frequency",opd:"the radio only if expecting a call",ans:"opc"},{question:"You are monitoring VHF Channel 16 when you receive a call to your vessel, TEXAS PRIDE. What is the proper way to answer this call?",opa:"'This is TEXAS PRIDE. Pick a channel.'",opb:"'This is TEXAS PRIDE on Channel16. Come back.'",opc:"'This is TEXAS PRIDE, WSR 1234,reply Channel 10.'",opd:"'Please stand by. We're busy right now.'",ans:"opc"},{question:"The independent-leg drilling unit is the best jack-up rig selection for drilling at locations with ____________.",opa:"soft even bottoms",opb:"firm uneven bottoms",opc:"deep water",opd:"shallow water",ans:"opb"},{question:"Size I and II fire extinguishers are designated as ____________.",opa:"portable",opb:"semi-portable",opc:"fixed",opd:"compact",ans:"opa"},{question:"When a vessel signals her distress by means of a gun or other explosive signal, the firing should be at intervals of approximately ____________.",opa:"10 minutes",opb:"1 minute",opc:"1 hour",opd:"3 minutes",ans:"opb"},{question:"The painter on a life float or buoyant apparatus shall ____________.",opa:"have a minimum breaking strength of 3,000 lbs. if the capacity of the lifesaving gear is 50 persons or greater",opb:"be resistant to ultraviolet sunlight deterioration",opc:"be stowed to pay out freely if the vessel sinks",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"Both an approved B-V semi-portable fire-extinguishing system and a fixed fire-extinguishing system are required to protect the engine room on towing vessels whose construction was contracted for on or after ____________. (Uninspected Vessel Regulations)",opa:"1-Feb-02",opb:"27-Aug-03",opc:"29-Apr-04",opd:"29-Apr-05",ans:"opb"},{question:"If you were to jibe in a strong wind, the part of the rigging most likely to fail would be the ____________.",opa:"forestay",opb:"backstay",opc:"jumper stay",opd:"halyard",ans:"opb"},{question:"A chain stripper is used to ____________.",opa:"prevent chain from clinging to the wildcat",opb:"clean the marine debris from the chain",opc:"flake chain from a boat's chain locker",opd:"clean chain prior to an x-ray inspection",ans:"opa"},{question:"When required, the steering gear, whistle, and the means of communication between the pilothouse and the engine room on a passenger vessel shall be tested by an officer of the vessel within a period of not more than how many hours prior to departure?",opa:"4",opb:"8",opc:"12",opd:"24",ans:"opc"},{question:"A fire in a ballast pumproom can be brought under control with minimal impact on stability by ____________.",opa:"cooling the outside bulkheads with water",opb:"shutting all sources of air into the compartment",opc:"closing the sea chest",opd:"flooding the compartment with salt water",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is the minimum required number of ring life buoys on an OSV certified for ocean service?",opa:"4",opb:"8",opc:"12",opd:"16",ans:"opb"},{question:"A jack-up has 8 inches of trim by the stern. Calculations show that the moment required to change trim one inch (MCT1') is 500 foot-kips. To level the unit, how far must a weight of 50 kips be transferred toward the bow?",opa:"10.0 feet",opb:"62.5 feet",opc:"80.0 feet",opd:"100.0 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"A portable dry chemical fire extinguisher discharges by ____________.",opa:"gravity when the extinguisher is turned upside down",opb:"pressure from a small CO2 cartridge on the extinguisher",opc:"air pressure from the hand pump attached to the extinguisher",opd:"pressure from the reaction when water is mixed with the chemical",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the KG of the liquid load.",opa:"2.6 feet",opb:"2.8 feet",opc:"3.1 feet",opd:"4.3 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The Certificate of Inspection issued to a vessel carrying more than six passengers must be ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"posted onboard under glass, if practical",opb:"posted on the dock where passengers are embarked",opc:"retained at the owner's principal place of business",opd:"kept on file by the Collector of Customs",ans:"opa"},{question:"Hand tillers are only accepted as an auxiliary means of steering if ____________.",opa:"they are at least 6 feet long",opb:"they are not operated through a reduction gear",opc:"they are found satisfactory by the cognizant OCMI",opd:"Both A and C above",ans:"opc"},{question:"The National Weather Service differentiates between small craft, gale, whole gale, and hurricane warnings by the ____________.",opa:"amount of rain forecasted",opb:"wave heights forecasted",opc:"amount of cloud cover forecasted",opd:"wind speed forecasted",ans:"opd"},{question:"A sloop is a sailing vessel with ____________.",opa:"one mast",opb:"two masts: with the mizzen stepped abaft the rudder post",opc:"two masts: with the mizzen stepped forward of the rudder post",opd:"two masts: a foremast and a mainmast",ans:"opa"},{question:"Who is required to prepare and post Emergency Instructions in a conspicuous place accessible to crew and passengers? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"The builder of the vessel",opb:"The owner or Master of the vessel",opc:"The U.S. Coast Guard",opd:"The classification society",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 21'-08', AFT 24'-02'. The LCG of the forepeak is 200 feet forward of amidships. How many tons of ballast must be pumped into the forepeak in order to have a drag of 15 inches? (Use the selected stability curves in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"72 tons",opb:"77 tons",opc:"82 tons",opd:"87 tons",ans:"opc"},{question:"On surface type offshore drilling units, each survival craft must be capable of being launched to the water at the minimum operating draft, under unfavorable conditions of trim and with the unit listed not less than ____________.",opa:"14\xb0",opb:"20\xb0",opc:"26\xb0",opd:"32\xb0",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the bypass valve of a self-contained breathing apparatus is opened, the mainline valve should be ____________.",opa:"completely open",opb:"completely closed",opc:"pinched to check the air flow",opd:"immediately disconnected",ans:"opb"},{question:"When dry chemical extinguishers are used to put out class B fires, there is a danger of reflash because dry chemical ____________.",opa:"is not an effective agent on Class B fires",opb:"does little or no cooling",opc:"dissipates quickly",opd:"is rapidly absorbed by the liquid",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your tow includes a barge carrying chlorine. Which special requirements must be observed?",opa:"The wing voids shall not be opened when underway.",opb:"You must post a deckhand to keep a special watch on this barge.",opc:"A cargo information card for chlorine must be in the pilothouse.",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the increase in transverse moments for the Coastal Driller if 2.0 feet of drill water is transferred from a full drill water tank #23 to an empty drill water tank #6?",opa:"4783 foot-kips",opb:"3446 foot-kips",opc:"2109 foot-kips",opd:"1234 foot-kips",ans:"opa"},{question:"In the illustration, the sea painter is number ____________.",opa:"1",opb:"12",opc:"16",opd:"18",ans:"opc"},{question:"The vessel's Emergency Position Indicating Radio beacon (EPIRB) must be tested ____________.",opa:"weekly",opb:"monthly",opc:"every 2 months",opd:"every 3 months",ans:"opb"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of longitudinal moments for the Stores & Supplies (Table 6) if paint weighing 3.48 tons is added to the paint locker?",opa:"5,996 foot-tons",opb:"1,688 foot-tons",opc:"495 foot-tons",opd:"115 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 5577 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 275.55 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 271.2 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 272.1 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 273.6 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 274.6 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are towing a 1000 gross ton gasoline tank barge. Regulations say that cargo tank hatches, ullage holes, and Butterworth plates may remain open without flame screens ONLY ____________.",opa:"if the barge is towed on a hawser astern",opb:"if an approved type B-II fire extinguisher is provided",opc:"when the open tanks are gas free",opd:"for periods not to exceed five minutes",ans:"opc"},{question:"A person with diabetes has received a minor leg injury. The symptoms of the onset of a diabetic coma may include ____________.",opa:"reduced appetite and thirst",opb:"sneezing and coughing",opc:"only a low grade fever",opd:"slurred speech and loss of coordination",ans:"opd"},{question:"Annex V to MARPOL 73/78 contains requirements pertaining to the discharge into the marine environment of ____________.",opa:"oil",opb:"garbage",opc:"noxious liquid substances",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Your vessel has 3 lifeboats on each side. The middle lifeboat on the port side is designated as boat number ____________.",opa:"2",opb:"2 PORT",opc:"3",opd:"4",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER is loaded as shown in Sample Load Form #4 (Drilling). What would be the new sum of transverse free surface moments for Fuel Oil (Table 2) if the entire contents of Tank #4P are transferred to Tank #4S?",opa:"0 foot-tons",opb:"1,189 foot-tons",opc:"2,378 foot-tons",opd:"7,984 foot-tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are aboard a vessel which is near a platform engaged in oil exploration. Under U.S. pollution regulations, you may NOT discharge garbage if you are within ____________.",opa:"1650 feet (500 meters)",opb:"1750 feet (533 meters)",opc:"1970 feet (600 meters)",opd:"2500 feet (762 meters)",ans:"opa"},{question:"In illustration D041DG, the symbol for the reference from which the height of the center of gravity is measured is ____________.",opa:"5",opb:"4",opc:"3",opd:"2",ans:"opd"},{question:"A semisubmersible with a displacement of 18,117.7 long tons and a KG of 52.0 feet discharges 200 long tons from a KG of 130 feet. To remain at draft, ballast is added at a height of 10 feet. What is the change in KG?",opa:"1.32 feet downward",opb:"1.32 feet upward",opc:"0.87 foot downward",opd:"0.87 foot upward",ans:"opa"},{question:"Each buoyant work vest must be ____________.",opa:"U.S. Coast Guard approved",opb:"marked with the name of the vessel",opc:"equipped with a water light",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"What is the purpose of the liferaft's hydrostatic release?",opa:"To release raft automatically as the ship sinks",opb:"To inflate the raft automatically",opc:"To test rafts hydrostatically",opd:"None of the above",ans:"opa"},{question:"When would a jack-up drilling rig be considered 'underway' under the International Rules of the Road?",opa:"When it is being towed to a new location",opb:"When it is elevated and taking on preload",opc:"When it is elevated and engaged in drilling",opd:"When it is moored to a dock in the shipyard",ans:"opa"},{question:"By day, the signal meaning, 'This is the best place to land' is a ____________.",opa:"vertical motion of a red flag",opb:"vertical motion of a white flag or the arms",opc:"white smoke signal",opd:"white star rocket",ans:"opb"},{question:"When drilling from a MODU the weight in air of tubular goods on the racks is reduced when run into the drilled hole because of the effect of ____________.",opa:"drill string compensators",opb:"formation pressure",opc:"buoyancy of the mud",opd:"vessel motion",ans:"opc"},{question:"In heavy seas the helmsman should steer the motor lifeboat ____________.",opa:"into the seas",opb:"broadside to the seas",opc:"in the same direction as the seas",opd:"in a series of figure-eights",ans:"opa"},{question:"First aid means ____________.",opa:"medical treatment of accident",opb:"setting of broken bones",opc:"emergency treatment at the scene of the injury",opd:"dosage of medications",ans:"opc"},{question:"What percentage of the breaking strength is the generally accepted safe operating load of an anchor cable?",opa:"0.1",opb:"0.25",opc:"0.35",opd:"0.5",ans:"opc"},{question:"Thirty-five percent of the breaking strength of an anchor cable is generally accepted as the ____________.",opa:"safe operating load",opb:"normal operating tension",opc:"emergency working load",opd:"allowable storm load",ans:"opa"},{question:"If you must jump from a MODU, your posture should include ____________.",opa:"holding down the life preserver against the chest with one arm crossing the other, covering the mouth and nose with a hand, and feet together",opb:"knees bent and held close to the body with both arms around legs",opc:"body straight and arms held tightly at the sides for feet first entry into the water",opd:"both hands holding the life preserver below the chin, with knees bent, and legs crossed",ans:"opa"},{question:"Up to two thirds of a survival crafts required drinking water may be produced by a manually-powered reverse osmosis desalinator if it can be done in ____________.",opa:"12 hours",opb:"1 day",opc:"2 days",opd:"4 days",ans:"opc"},{question:"Large quantities of gas in the shale shaker area may be an indication of ____________.",opa:"a break in the riser system",opb:"low formation pressure",opc:"a break in the drill string",opd:"high formation pressure",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER, at 58.0 feet draft in sea water, places 275.8 long tons onboard. What is the new draft?",opa:"56 feet",opb:"58 feet",opc:"60 feet",opd:"62 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"For most MODU engines, the fuel is ____________.",opa:"natural gas",opb:"diesel oil",opc:"propane",opd:"bunker fuel",ans:"opb"},{question:"On the all-purpose nozzle, the position of the valve when the handle is all the way forward is ____________.",opa:"shut",opb:"fog",opc:"solid stream",opd:"spray",ans:"opa"},{question:"When approaching a fire from windward, you should shield firefighters from the fire by using ____________.",opa:"low-velocity fog",opb:"high-velocity fog",opc:"a straight stream of water",opd:"foam spray",ans:"opa"},{question:"It is the responsibility of the person in charge to ____________.",opa:"revise the operating manual when rig personnel change",opb:"be fully aware of the provisions in the operating manual",opc:"maintain the rig's construction portfolio",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opb"},{question:"Before any machinery is put in operation, you should ____________.",opa:"ventilate all compartments, see that the machinery is clean and there are no obstructions",opb:"just turn the key and start up",opc:"take for granted that there are no fuel leaks",opd:"assume there are no volatile fumes in the engine space",ans:"opa"},{question:"EXCEPT when suffering from a head or chest injury a patient in shock should be placed in which position?",opa:"Head up and feet down",opb:"Head down and feet up",opc:"Flat on back with head and feet elevated",opd:"Arms above the head",ans:"opb"},{question:"A wobbling tail shaft is an indication of ____________.",opa:"shallow water",opb:"an engine that is misfiring",opc:"a tight tail shaft gland",opd:"worn stern bearing or misalignment",ans:"opd"},{question:"To prevent the riser system from buckling under its own weight, upward tension is provided by the ____________.",opa:"riser stabilizers",opb:"guideline tensioning system",opc:"riser tensioning system",opd:"guideline stabilizers",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the correct interpretation of the flag hoist F 2 1 3 second substitute?",opa:"F2131",opb:"F2132",opc:"F213213",opd:"F213F213",ans:"opa"},{question:"A neutral equilibrium position for a vessel means that the metacenter is ____________.",opa:"lower than the keel",opb:"at the same height as the center of gravity",opc:"exactly at midships",opd:"at the center of the waterplane area",ans:"opb"},{question:"Which statement concerning maintenance requirements is FALSE?",opa:"Compulsory vessels sailing in Sea Areas A1 and A2 must provide any one of the three maintenance options which are duplication of equipment, shore based or at-sea maintenance capability.",opb:"Compulsory vessels sailing in Areas A3 and A4 must provide any two of the three maintenance options which are duplication of equipment, shore based or at-sea maintenance capability.",opc:"If shore-based maintenance is used, maintenance services do not have to be completed or performance verified unless the vessel will be sailing to a non-US port.",opd:"Equipment warranties do not satisfy GMDSS maintenance requirements.",ans:"opc"},{question:"For use as protection from gas leaking from a refrigeration unit, each MODU must be equipped with a ____________.",opa:"portable ventilation system",opb:"flame safety lamp",opc:"self-contained breathing apparatus",opd:"gas mask",ans:"opc"},{question:"A person who gets battery acid in an eye should IMMEDIATELY wash the eye with ____________.",opa:"boric acid solution",opb:"water",opc:"baking soda solution",opd:"ammonia",ans:"opb"},{question:"That center around which a vessel trims is called the ____________.",opa:"tipping center",opb:"center of buoyancy",opc:"center of gravity",opd:"turning center",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER is partially loaded with a GM of 2.9 feet and drafts of: FWD 17'-10', AFT 19'-04'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine what tanks you should ballast to increase the GM to 3.9 feet.",opa:"Tanks: DB4, DT6",opb:"Tanks: DB3, DB5, DT8",opc:"Tanks: DB6, DT7",opd:"Tanks: DB2, DT1, DT6",ans:"opa"},{question:"When the height of the metacenter is greater than the height of the center of gravity, a vessel is in ____________.",opa:"stable equilibrium",opb:"neutral equilibrium",opc:"unstable equilibrium",opd:"negative equilibrium",ans:"opa"},{question:"A semisubmersible floating in sea water displaces 20,000 long tons. She has vertical moments of 1,000,000 foot-long tons. What is the new KG if 300 long tons are added at a VCG of 50 feet?",opa:"49.2 feet",opb:"50.0 feet",opc:"50.8 feet",opd:"57.5 feet",ans:"opb"},{question:"When shoring a damaged bulkhead on a MODU, effort should be taken to spread the pressure over the ____________.",opa:"maximum possible area",opb:"minimum possible area",opc:"nearest watertight door",opd:"nearest longitudinal girder",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER, in field transit at a draft of 10 feet 0 inches with winds less than 70 knots, has a KGT of 39.0 feet and a KGL of 38.6 feet. The margin on the maximum allowable KG is ____________.",opa:"3.0 feet",opb:"3.4 feet",opc:"26.0 feet",opd:"26.4 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"The sailing drafts are: FWD 25'-03', AFT 26'-03' and the GM is 3.5 feet. Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book, to determine the available righting arm at 25\xb0 inclination.",opa:"0.8 foot",opb:"1.4 feet",opc:"2.0 feet",opd:"2.6 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is NOT a motion of the vessel?",opa:"Pitch",opb:"Roll",opc:"Trim",opd:"Yaw",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which signal is used by a rescue unit to indicate, 'Avast hauling'?",opa:"Firing of a green star signal",opb:"Firing of a red star signal",opc:"An orange smoke signal",opd:"Three white star rockets fired at one-minute intervals",ans:"opb"},{question:"A jack-up displacing 15,000 kips has a KG of 20 feet. The legs weighing 3,500 kips are lowered 100 feet. What is the new KG?",opa:"23.33 feet",opb:"18.67 feet",opc:"4.67 feet",opd:"-3.33 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-00', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1.80 feet",opb:"1.89 feet",opc:"1.98 feet",opd:"2.05 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"What is the average range of vessel-to-vessel VHF-FM radio communications?",opa:"15 to 20 miles",opb:"60 to 90 miles",opc:"90 to 120 miles",opd:"120 to 150 miles",ans:"opa"},{question:"The regulations governing the sleeping accommodations of a cargo vessel are found in ____________.",opa:"46 CFR subchapter S",opb:"46 CFR subchapter T",opc:"46 CFR subchapter B",opd:"46 CFR subchapter I",ans:"opd"},{question:"Signaling by flag hoist is completed by the vessel hoisting the ____________.",opa:"signal AR",opb:"code flag N",opc:"code flag R",opd:"answering pennant",ans:"opd"},{question:"The liquid mud tanks on your vessel measure 32'L by 15'B by 8'D. The vessel's displacement is 640 tons and the specific gravity of the mud is 1.8. What is the reduction in GM due to 2 of these tanks being slack?",opa:"0.74 foot",opb:"1.24 feet",opc:"1.41 feet",opd:"1.66 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"When checking the oxygen content of the cargo tanks prior to loading cargoes requiring vapor recovery, the atmosphere must be sampled ____________.",opa:"one meter from the tank bottom and one meter below the tank top",opb:"one half the ullage of the tank and one meter below the tank top",opc:"one half the ullage of the tank and one meter above the tank bottom",opd:"at three meter intervals from the tank top",ans:"opb"},{question:"A negative metacentric height ____________.",opa:"should always be immediately corrected",opb:"will always cause a vessel to capsize",opc:"always results from off-center weights",opd:"All of the above are correct",ans:"opa"},{question:"Assuming that the recommended hatch loading sequence is followed, how many long tons of iron ore may be loaded through hatches 5 & 7 while using a single belt loader, to arrive at a desired mean keel draft of 25'-02'? (Use the Guidance Manual for Loading M.V. GRAND HAVEN.)",opa:"1410 tons",opb:"1450 tons",opc:"1490 tons",opd:"1520 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"Lifesaving regulations in Subchapter W require that a fire drill include ____________.",opa:"starting the fire pumps",opb:"checking the operation of watertight doors",opc:"checking arrangements for abandon ship",opd:"All of the above",ans:"opd"},{question:"The connection facilities for the international shore connection must be located to provide access ____________.",opa:"to each side of the vessel",opb:"as close as possible to the house",opc:"on the main deck",opd:"on each level of the accommodation space",ans:"opa"},{question:"The required number and type of hand portable fire extinguishers required for a galley having an area of 3,500 square feet is ____________.",opa:"one B-II",opb:"one C-II",opc:"two B-II's or C-II's",opd:"two A-II's or B-II's",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel's drafts are: FWD 21'-08', AFT 24'-02'. The LCG of the forepeak is 200 feet forward of amidships. How many tons of ballast must be pumped into the forepeak in order to have a drag of 18 inches? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"53 tons",opb:"57 tons",opc:"61 tons",opd:"65 tons",ans:"opd"},{question:"In the illustration, which item number correctly identifies the ballast bags?",opa:"2",opb:"12",opc:"13",opd:"22",ans:"opc"},{question:"Leg penetration to depths which require pullout forces greater than that which can be supplied by the buoyancy of the hull may exist in ____________.",opa:"soft mud",opb:"sand",opc:"silt",opd:"soft to firm clays",ans:"opd"},{question:"Which Fire Control Plan symbol represents an international shore connection?",opa:"54",opb:"53",opc:"51",opd:"49",ans:"opb"},{question:"A safety feature provided on all inflatable liferafts is ____________.",opa:"overhead safety straps",opb:"built in seats",opc:"internal releasing hooks",opd:"water stabilizing pockets",ans:"opd"},{question:"A virtual rise in the center of gravity of a MODU may be caused by ____________.",opa:"filling a partially filled tank",opb:"using an onboard crane to lift a freely swinging heavy object",opc:"emptying a partially filled tank",opd:"transferring pipe from the setback area to the pipe rack",ans:"opb"},{question:"The number of pounds of carbon dioxide required for each cargo space on a cargo vessel is equal to ____________.",opa:"the gross volume of the space in cubic feet divided by 100",opb:"one pound of CO2 per cubic foot of space",opc:"one pound of CO2 per square foot of deck area",opd:"the gross volume of the space in cubic feet divided by 30",ans:"opd"},{question:"When a lifeline is required to be attached to a ring life buoy it must be at least ____________.",opa:"30 feet long",opb:"60 feet long",opc:"90 feet long",opd:"120 feet long",ans:"opb"},{question:"You are sailing in a strong wind and may accidentally jibe when ____________.",opa:"reaching",opb:"tacking",opc:"running-free",opd:"in irons",ans:"opc"},{question:"On small passenger vessels painters fitted to life floats shall be at least ____________.",opa:"20.0 meters (65.5 feet) in length",opb:"30.5 meters (100 feet) in length",opc:"10 fathoms (60 feet) in length",opd:"90 feet (27.5 meters) in length",ans:"opb"},{question:"A right-handed propeller will cause the survival craft to ____________.",opa:"walk the stern to starboard in reverse",opb:"walk the stern to port in reverse",opc:"run faster than a left-handed propeller",opd:"right itself if capsized",ans:"opb"},{question:"When administering first aid you should avoid ____________.",opa:"any conversation with the patient",opb:"instructing bystanders",opc:"unnecessary haste and appearance of uncertainty",opd:"touching the patient before washing your hands",ans:"opc"},{question:"On a vessel of 12,000 tons displacement, a tank 60 feet long, 50 feet wide, and 20 feet deep is half filled with fresh water (SG 1.000) while the vessel is floating in saltwater (SG 1.026) What is the reduction in metacentric height due to free surface?",opa:"0.97 ft.",opb:"1.01 ft.",opc:"1.35 ft.",opd:"1.44 ft.",ans:"opd"},{question:"The design of a spring buoy helps ____________.",opa:"to retrieve the anchor",opb:"to prevent chafing at the lower end of the pendant",opc:"to mark the rig's approach to the location",opd:"an anchor handling vessel back toward the rig",ans:"opb"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has onboard 4824 tons of cargo with an LCG-FP of 277.45 feet. See the distribution of the cargo to be loaded. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the final LCG-FP of the cargo.",opa:"LCG-FP 267.7 feet",opb:"LCG-FP 268.4 feet",opc:"LCG-FP 269.2 feet",opd:"LCG-FP 270.6 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"It is recommended that drip collectors required on all updraft carburetors be drained by ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"a device to automatically return all drip to the engine air intakes",opb:"no means whatsoever",opc:"a separate pipe leading to the bilges",opd:"a pump leading to a point outside the hull",ans:"opa"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has drafts of: FWD 16'-10', AFT 19'-04'. Use the white pages of the Stability Data Reference Book to determine the drafts if you ballast the forepeak with 73 tons of seawater.",opa:"FWD 17'-05.8', AFT18'-10.9'",opb:"FWD 17'-06.2', AFT18'-10.4'",opc:"FWD 17'-06.8', AFT18'-09.8'",opd:"FWD 17'-07.4', AFT18'-09.2'",ans:"opa"},{question:"Required lifesaving equipment on existing vessels may be continued in use on the vessel if ____________.",opa:"kept onboard no more than 2 years",opb:"inspected and serviced every 6 months",opc:"destroyed if more than 5 years old",opd:"maintained in good and serviceable condition",ans:"opd"},{question:"In the event of a fire, the doors to a stair tower must be closed to prevent the spread of fire by ____________.",opa:"ventilation",opb:"radiation",opc:"convection",opd:"conduction",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is 79 feet long with 20 people aboard. The coaming of a deck above the lowest weather deck (except an exposed forecastle deck) must be at least ____________.",opa:"6' high",opb:"12' high",opc:"24' high",opd:"Not required",ans:"opd"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the following drafts: FWD 09'-00', AFT 15'-11.5'. Upon completion of loading and bunkering the items listed will be onboard. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the minimum GM required to meet a one compartment standard.",opa:"1.82 feet",opb:"1.96 feet",opc:"2.05 feet",opd:"2.17 feet",ans:"opa"},{question:"You intend to discharge medical or hazardous wastes ashore. MARPOL Annex V requires you to notify a receiving port or terminal in advance. How much advance notice is required?",opa:"12 hours",opb:"24 hours",opc:"48 hours",opd:"Advance notification is not required.",ans:"opb"},{question:"The distance between the bottom of the hull and the waterline is called ____________.",opa:"tonnage",opb:"reserve buoyancy",opc:"draft",opd:"freeboard",ans:"opc"},{question:"Your vessel is limited to a maximum draft of 26'-03'. The present drafts are: FWD 22'-10', AFT 23'-08'. How much more cargo can be loaded and where should it be located if a drag of 18 inches is desired? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"875 tons 6 feet aft of amidships",opb:"950 tons 8 feet forward of the tipping center",opc:"1323 tons 7 feet aft of the tipping center",opd:"1452 tons 7 feet aft of the tipping center",ans:"opc"},{question:"When threatened with a severe storm while operating in 250 feet of water, the COASTAL DRILLER should be placed at an air gap of ____________.",opa:"35 feet",opb:"32 feet",opc:"30 feet",opd:"25 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"A semisubmersible, while floating level, displaces 20,000 long tons. LCB is 3.0 feet forward of amidships. Bulk, weighing 300 long tons, is placed in P-tanks located 40 feet aft of amidships. What is the new LCG?",opa:"3.64 feet forward of amidships",opb:"2.45 feet forward of amidships",opc:"2.36 feet forward of amidships",opd:"0.55 foot forward of amidships",ans:"opc"},{question:"A stored-pressure water extinguisher is most effective against fires of class ____________.",opa:"A",opb:"B",opc:"C",opd:"D",ans:"opa"},{question:"You are fighting a fire in a watertight compartment using hoses and salt water. Stability may be reduced because of ____________.",opa:"progressive downflooding",opb:"reduction of water in the storage tanks",opc:"increase in free surface which reduces the metacentric height",opd:"reduction of KG to the minimum allowable",ans:"opc"},{question:"The greatest effect on stability occurs from loose liquids flowing ____________.",opa:"from side to side in the tanks of the vessel",opb:"from fore to aft in the tanks of a vessel",opc:"in and out of a vessel that is holed in a wing tank",opd:"in and out of a vessel that is holed in a peak tank",ans:"opc"},{question:"In accordance with SOLAS, the batteries that power interior lighting in inflatable liferafts can be made to last longer by ____________.",opa:"unscrewing the bulb during the daylight",opb:"switching the light on only when necessary",opc:"taking no action as there is no way on saving power",opd:"taking no action as they shut off automatically in daylight",ans:"opb"},{question:"A Certificate of Inspection for vessels of less than 100 gross tons carrying more than twelve passengers on an international voyage will be issued for a period of ____________. (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"four years",opb:"three years",opc:"two years",opd:"one year",ans:"opd"},{question:"Your vessel is greater than 100 GRT and carries more than 12 passengers. In addition to the licensed deck officer in the pilothouse, there should be on watch an additional crew member ____________.",opa:"in or near the pilothouse",opb:"on the bridge wing",opc:"always in the pilothouse",opd:"only when another vessel is in sight",ans:"opa"},{question:"How should the letter 'T' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"TEE",opb:"TA HO",opc:"TANG GO",opd:"TU TU",ans:"opc"},{question:"The SS AMERICAN MARINER has the liquid loading shown. Use the white pages of The Stability Data Reference Book to determine the LCG-FP of the liquid load.",opa:"271.2 ft.",opb:"260.3 ft.",opc:"251.9 ft.",opd:"247.2 ft.",ans:"opc"},{question:"When would it NOT be necessary to immediately notify the U.S. Coast Guard? (small passenger vessel regulations)",opa:"Loss of life",opb:"Major damage affecting the seaworthiness of a vessel",opc:"Damage amounting to $2,000",opd:"Injury to a person which requires medical treatment beyond first aid",ans:"opc"},{question:"Steering a motor lifeboat broadside to the sea could cause it to ____________.",opa:"capsize",opb:"run smoother",opc:"run faster",opd:"sink",ans:"opa"},{question:"A semisubmersible, while floating level, displaces 25,000 long tons. LCG is 2 feet forward of amidships. Bulk, weighing 300 long tons, is placed in P-tanks located 50 feet aft of amidships. What is the new LCG?",opa:"1.43 feet forward of amidships",opb:"1.38 feet forward of amidships",opc:"0.62 foot forward of amidships",opd:"0.57 foot forward of amidships",ans:"opb"},{question:"When the owner or Master inspects his/her towing vessel before embarking on a voyage of more than 24 hours, he/she must check all terminal gear EXCEPT ____________.",opa:"the connection of the bridle and towing pendant",opb:"chafing gear",opc:"quick release towing hook and control system, to see that it operates properly",opd:"the winch brake, if installed",ans:"opc"},{question:"When the handle of an all-purpose nozzle is in the vertical position and without an applicator, the all-purpose nozzle will ____________.",opa:"produce high-velocity fog",opb:"produce low-velocity fog",opc:"produce a straight stream",opd:"shut off the water",ans:"opa"},{question:"How should the letter 'Z' be pronounced when spoken on the radiotelephone?",opa:"ZEE BR AH",opb:"ZEE ZE",opc:"ZE HE",opd:"ZOO LOO",ans:"opd"},{question:"The DEEP DRILLER departs a fresh water port at a draft of 20.5 feet. What will be the draft in sea water?",opa:"18.2 feet",opb:"19.4 feet",opc:"19.7 feet",opd:"22.8 feet",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which product(s) is(are) compatible with the product ethylene cyanohydrin?",opa:"Sulfuric acid",opb:"Nitric acid",opc:"Isocyanates",opd:"Ammonia",ans:"opd"},{question:"Among the possible causes of unexpected rapidly increasing inclination of the DEEP DRILLER while on location is ____________.",opa:"consumption of onboard variables",opb:"miscalculation of loads",opc:"external environmental forces",opd:"flooding due to column damage",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are on a supply run to an offshore drilling rig. onboard is the cargo listed. What is the height above the main deck of the center of gravity of the cargo?",opa:"2.15 feet",opb:"2.05 feet",opc:"1.85 feet",opd:"1.52 feet",ans:"opd"},{question:"You are sailing before the wind in heavy weather. The failure of what will affect the vessel's safety most?",opa:"The main halyard",opb:"The jib sheet",opc:"The helm",opd:"The outhaul",ans:"opc"},{question:"A cutoff valve in the fire-main system of a MODU may be closed to protect the portion of the system on an exposed deck from ____________.",opa:"damage from crane operations",opb:"being used for wash down purposes",opc:"accidental diversion of flow to wrong location",opd:"freezing",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel is limited to a maximum draft of 26'-03'. The present drafts are: FWD 21'-04', AFT 24'-06'. How much more cargo can be loaded and where should it be located if a drag of 1 foot is desired? (Use the reference material in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"1676 tons 18 feet forward of amidships",opb:"1676 tons 18 feet forward of the tipping center",opc:"1972 tons 16 feet forward of amidships",opd:"1972 tons 16 feet forward of the tipping center",ans:"opb"},{question:"What is NOT a requirement for storage batteries on tank barges?",opa:"They may be located in cargo handling rooms",opb:"They must be located in well ventilated spaces",opc:"Each battery box must have a watertight lining",opd:"They must be secured against movement",ans:"opa"},{question:"The COASTAL DRILLER is loaded as shown in the Sample Load Form #1 (Rig Move). If the entire contents of the port pipe rack are back-loaded to an offshore supply vessel, how much drill water would have to be transferred from tank #1 to tank #26 to level the vessel in trim?",opa:"62.7 kips",opb:"64.4 kips",opc:"111.4 kips",opd:"114.9 kips",ans:"opd"},{question:"A vessel's drafts are: FWD 14'-04', AFT 15'-08'. How much more cargo can be loaded to have the vessel down to the freeboard draft? (Use the information in Section 1, the blue pages, of the Stability Data Reference Book)",opa:"7280 tons",opb:"7879 tons",opc:"8004 tons",opd:"8104 tons",ans:"opb"},{question:"The center of flotation of a vessel is the point in the waterplane ____________.",opa:"about which the vessel lists and trims",opb:"which coincides with the center of buoyancy",opc:"which, in the absence of external forces, is always vertically aligned with the center of gravity",opd:"which is shown in the hydrostatic tables as VCB",ans:"opa"},{question:"A storm is forecast for the area where your vessel is moored. For its safety you should put ____________.",opa:"more slack in the mooring lines",opb:"a strain on the mooring lines",opc:"chafing gear on the mooring lines",opd:"grease on the mooring lines",ans:"opc"},{question:"Which statement is TRUE concerning small oil spills?",opa:"They usually disappear quickly.",opb:"They usually stay in a small area.",opc:"They may cause serious pollution as the effect tends to be cumulative.",opd:"A small spill is not dangerous to sea life in the area.",ans:"opc"},{question:"What does the DSC control unit do if the GMDSS Radio Operator fails to insert updated information when initiating a DSC distress alert?",opa:"It will abort the transmission and set off an audible alarm that must be manually reset.",opb:"It will initiate the DSC distress alert but, as no information will be transmitted, rescue personnel will not be able to identify the vessel, its position or its situation.",opc:"It will initiate the DSC distress alert and default information will automatically be transmitted.",opd:"It will initiate the DSC distress alert, but any station receiving it will have to establish contact with the distressed vessel to determine its identity, position and situation.",ans:"opc"},{question:"You have determined that a cargo space on a freight vessel is 45 feet by 36 feet by 62 feet. How many pounds of carbon dioxide is required for this space?",opa:"1674",opb:"2511",opc:"3348",opd:"5022",ans:"opc"},{question:"Most recreational sailing craft have triangular sails and are said to be ____________.",opa:"Gaff rigged",opb:"Spinnaker rigged",opc:"Marconi rigged",opd:"Square rigged",ans:"opc"}]}ngOnInit(){this.data=[...this.data,...this.data1,...this.data3,...this.data4,...this.data5]}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275cmp=Os({type:e,selectors:[["app-root"]],decls:6,vars:1,consts:[[1,"container"],[1,"text-center","mt-1","text-danger",2,"font-size","60px"],[1,"text-center","mt-1","text-info"],["class","card mt-1",4,"ngFor","ngForOf"],[1,"card","mt-1"],[1,"card-header","bg-white"],[1,"p-1","m-1"],[3,"ngClass"]],template:function(t,a){1&t&&(xe(0,"div",0),xe(1,"h4",1),No(2,"Created with \u2665 by Guru"),Fe(),xe(3,"h3",2),No(4,"All Deck Questions"),Fe(),function tc(e,o,t,a,n,s,i,r){const l=b(),p=W(),h=e+H,d=p.firstCreatePass?function yy(e,o,t,a,n,s,i,r,l){const p=o.consts,h=Ct(o,e,4,i||null,Lo(p,r));Qi(o,t,h,Lo(p,l)),un(o,h);const d=h.tViews=On(2,h,a,n,s,o.directiveRegistry,o.pipeRegistry,null,o.schemas,p);return null!==o.queries&&(o.queries.template(o,h),d.queries=o.queries.embeddedTView(h)),h}(h,p,l,o,t,a,n,s,i):p.data[h];po(d,!1);const c=l[I].createComment("");Mn(p,l,c,d),_e(c,l),Pn(l,l[h]=yd(c,l,c,d)),sn(d)&&$i(p,l,d),null!=i&&Ki(l,d,r)}(5,oA,13,9,"div",3),Fe()),2&t&&(Xe(5),Xo("ngForOf",a.data))},directives:[tf,of],styles:[".active[_ngcontent-%COMP%]{background-color:green;color:#fff;padding:4px;border-radius:5px}"]}),e})(),aA=(()=>{class e{}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275mod=ta({type:e,bootstrap:[tA]}),e.\u0275inj=st({providers:[],imports:[[H1]]}),e})();(function qq(){M_=!1})(),U1().bootstrapModule(aA).catch(e=>console.error(e))}},Q=>{Q(Q.s=959)}]);